very nice little
analytical piece
Hello ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the right opinion the home of a twat with too much free time
And today we talk about the dying trend of Jake Paul now
I could have chatted about him while he was at the peak of his popularity
But unfortunately, I had no use and no idea what I could talk about that would be unique to my channel
However, the tides have definitely turned and as he slowly grows cold, I've decided to take a pop at one Pacific aspect of him
His media persona. Yes, he never seemed to shy away from the coverage it gave him
But what has really interest me is the multiple directions
He has taken his manipulation in and now that the Jake Paul saga has existed long enough for me to analyze the directions and not
Seem like a simple cash in that's what I'm going to do
The first time Jake Paul had his full-blown run-in with the mainstream media was when they went to report on his supposed neighborhood
Disturbances and the undeniable commotion that he was instigating now the news sources that reported painted a fairly negative picture and appropriately
So his actions were completely reckless and when the news crews were there, he didn't do anything to contradict that idea of him
So, how did he respond? Well, let's talk about that now
You have to know the Jakey here has completely fickle fans who will eat up whatever he dishes out
This is important because they need to be completely committed so that even when he acts like a total jerk
They're there to dab on the haters or as I like to call them critics
So I expected a wholly overblown response in video form and that is what he gave us
However, he coasted off a very sneaky narrative
We all know that trusted mainstream media is at an all-time low. That's nothing new, but Jake Paul made it something new
He worked off the flawed enemy of enemy narrative and faked a police incident to serve as example for how the media can exploit
Misreporting escapades this narrative worked for his fans. They ate it up because mainstream media is bad
But even though mainstream media is undeniably terrible a broken clock is still right twice a day and just because like you and I
They hate the mainstream media doesn't mean that it vindicated any of Jake Paul's irresponsible actions
Now I considered Jake Paul a bit of a malleable character
He evolves into every situation the persona that he portrayed on his channel was one of extreme calculation
He knew that he could get away with such
fallacious behavior there and then and this is important to note because during his appearance on the h3 podcast he acts completely different and
This vivacious big kid is replaced by a moderately remorseful gentleman who daments over his actions
Like most regular people would suddenly because he's on h3's patch and he knows that he'll have a lot of people who are skeptical
He not only sees it as a way to scrounge whatever reputation he has but also a way to attain some new
Subscribers through emotional outreach and now we talk about his third maneuver the phase banks assault claims now
Jake Paul knows that he wasn't positioned too strongly within the media with regards to this
So, how does he create drama and still keep everyone on their toes exactly? Well very smartly indeed
He first brings the alleged victim into his video and does the normal shtick of being Solomon serious and talking about how these things
Are wrong, however, he knows that he's not really a voice of legitimacy beyond his channel
So what he does is he throws Erica Castell in there not only because she's not him
But also because females are normally better for discussing these situations and attracting sympathy
It also helps that Erica Castell is a newer face to the media and therefore a lot of people who are not familiar with team
10 beyond Jake Paul won't immediately judge her like they do with our little title character here
The estrangement is essential for this message to connect and this signifies a trend for Jake Paul
His channel messages are very shallow and vapid they're easy to pick apart and childish
But he can do them on his channel because he's watched by a bunch of children
however
as soon as he steps outside the domain of his channel he has to drop that facade and act like an adult or get other
People to act like adults for him if his reputation is too tainted in that area already
I have no time for Jake Paul or any of his antics
He's a cunt for money and then acts all humble as soon as he steps outside his channel on a side note the most
Loathsome aspect of him is the fact that he always uses good deeds as
scapegoats for being a cunt if you do a few good deeds here and there it doesn't undermine the numerous times you've acted like a
Juvenile manchild, but that's a different point for a different day and probably for a different channel
Anyway, when for something a bit more YouTube related as I felt I could pull it off
I hope you enjoyed and if you have any additional thoughts drop them my way until then
I'm the right opinion and I'll see you in the next one