Human society is extremely complex and fragile, built upon various pillars.
One of them is the honeybee. One out of three meals eaten by humans is made possible by honeybees.
They are so important that if all the honeybees were to die out,
thousands of plants would follow, which could lead to millions of people starving in the following
years. On top of that, honeybees have a huge economic impact. The dollar value of plants
pollinated by them each year is around 265 billion. Food we take for granted would just
stop existing without them, or there would be a massive decrease in productivity. Food including
apples, onions, pumpkins, and also plants used for feeding livestock are thus extremely important for
our milk and meat. Einstein is often quoted as having said, if honeybees die out, humans will
follow a few years later. Actually, he probably didn't say that, but there might be some truth
in the statement. It's unsettling, but honeybees have started to disappear. Millions of hives have
died in the last few years. Beekeepers all over the world have seen an annual loss of 30 to 90%
of their colonies. In the US alone, bees are steadily declining, from 5 million hives in 1988
to 2.5 million today. Since 2006, a phenomenon called colony collapse disorder has affected
honeybees in many countries, and we're not entirely sure what's causing it. All we know
is that it's pretty serious. Over the last few decades, bees have seen an invasion of very
dangerous foes. Parasites straight out of a horror movie, like a carapace woody. Microscopic mites
that infect the trachea, that's the breathing tubes, of bees. Here, they lay their eggs and
feed from the fluids of their victims, weakening them considerably and spending their whole life
inside the bees. Or Varroa destructor, a fitting name because they can only reproduce in honeybee
hives and are one of the bee's greatest enemies. The female mite enters a honeybee brood cell and
lays eggs on the bee larva before it's about to pupate and before the hive bees cover the cell
with a wax capping. The eggs hatch and the young mites and their mother feed on the developing bee
in the safety of the capped cell. The bee is not normally killed at this stage, just weakened,
so it still has enough strength to chew its way through the wax capping and release itself from
the cell. As it does, it releases the mother mite and her new offspring from the cell and these are
free to spread across the hive, starting the process over again in a cycle of about 10 days.
Their numbers grow exponentially and after a few months, this can lead to the collapse of the
entire beehive. Once outside of the cell, adult mites also suck the bodily fluids of bees and
weaken them considerably. To make things worse, they also transmit viruses that harm the bees
even more and can lead to birth defects like useless wings. But there are other threats too,
such as viruses and fungi. Under normal circumstances, these phenomena should be
manageable and are not enough to explain the horrendous amount of dying going on in bees.
Over recent years, new insecticides have been introduced that are deadly to bees.
Neonicotinoids, a chemical family similar to nicotine, was approved in the early 1990s as
an alternative to chemicals like DDT. They attack insects by harming their nervous systems. Today,
they are the most widely used insecticides in the world. Globally, they saw sales of 1.5 billion
euros in 2008, representing 24% of the global market for insecticides. In 2013, neonicotinoids
were used in the US on about 95% of corn and canola crops and also on the vast majority of
fruit and vegetables like apples, cherries, peaches, oranges, berries, leafy greens, tomatoes,
potatoes, cereal grains, rice, nuts, grapes, and many more. Bees come into contact with the toxin
while collecting pollen or via contaminated water, often bringing material into the hive
where it can accumulate and slowly kill the whole colony. The toxins harm bees in a variety of
horrible ways. In high enough doses, it quickly leads to convulsions, paralysis, and death. But
even in small doses, it can be fatal. It may lead to bees forgetting how to navigate the world,
so bees fly into the wild, get lost, and die alone, separated from their hives. If this happens
often enough, a hive can lose its ability to sustain itself. We know that neonicotinoids
are harmful to bees and that we urgently need an alternative to it. But there are billions of
dollars to be made in delaying this. Studies sponsored by the chemical industry magically
appear to prove a much lower toxicity to bees compared to those produced by independent
scientists. There are even more factors contributing to the demise of bees, like too
much genetic uniformity, crop monocultures, poor nutrition due to overcrowding, stress because of
human activities, and other pesticides. Each of those factors on its own is a major problem for
bees, but together, they probably account for colony collapse disorder. With parasites upping
their game in recent decades, the honey bees are now fighting for survival. It would be a
catastrophe if they lost this fight. This is a conundrum we have to solve if we want to continue
living with a relative abundance and diversity of food. Humanity is deeply interconnected with
Earth and the other life forms on it. Even if we pretend that we're not, we have to take better
care of our surroundings. If not to preserve the beauty of nature, then at least to ensure our own
survival. This video is supported by the Australian Academy of Science, which promotes and supports
excellence in science. See more at nova.org.au. It was a blast to work with them,
so go check out their site. Our videos are also made possible by your support on patreon.com.
Recently, we passed an important milestone, which is why there will be an additional video in July.
If you want to support us and become part of the Kurzgesagt bird army, check out our Patreon page.