Hello ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to The Right Opinion, the home of a twat with
too much free time. And my oh my, do we have a topic on our hands today. I know this is
late but honestly it's a subject that has taken made twists and turns, that it was worth
waiting just in case any final revelations were brought forward, and obviously this video
does not exempt the fact that there may be further twists and turns in the case, and
also does not mean that any new unrelated information may compromise the character of
those involved. So let's talk about gaming festivals, who loves them? I mean honestly
I think gaming festivals would be really swell if there were less people, or no people even,
because I do like video games but I don't like having to wait to play them, often I just find myself
aimlessly wandering and occasionally bumping into people who I may have seen at previous
events and retaking the same photo, just this time with a slightly greater inkling of fatigue
reflected in my weary smile. The pinball machines are good though, especially when you don't
have to pave them, hooray for free things. Anyhow, the gaming festival that is of interest
is Insomnia Gaming Festival 64, abbreviated to i64, this ran from the Easter weekend from
the 19th to the 22nd of April, I saw a lot of close friends again, and met a lot of great
creators. It's always nice to do so, because it humanises all these people, and puts the
internet into perspective. One of these people I met at the event was a bloke called Michael,
known online as Slazo, he was pleasant, I had some facetious flirtatious exchanges with
him, and after the event my life carried on, I knew some of the creators that I had met
there were going to London afterwards, Slazo included, and I would have joined them, but
alas, I had university to complete, and I still felt that YouTube was an unstable source
of income, so I wanted something to fall back onto in case everything fell apart. A few
weeks later, around mid-May, I was alternating between university work and checking my social
blade when one of my acquaintances messaged me quite shocking news, apparently Slazo,
the person who I'd met at i64, was going to be exposed, as a predator, he was just
as surprised as I was, apparently these claims were going to be published on a twitlonger
in the following week. So I waited with anticipation, as I hadn't actually seen any of the evidence,
I didn't really talk to anyone about it, although I did tell one of my friends who
was making a documentary about i64 to perhaps consider excluding any footage with him in,
in case it might taint the finished product, more as an act of caution really. So I waited,
and waited, and waited. A month later a twitlonger was published by a person named Fizzypop,
who goes by the name of Che, it documented the allegations against Slazo, these allegations
painted him as a sex-hungry predator who exploited the innocence and inexperience
of a younger individual in the relationship, aggressively obtaining gratification when
she didn't want to offer it. This was met with immediate support from the community,
including many large youtubers, it was clearly a very emotional topic for many people and
many wanted to show their support for a victim. Alongside the twitlonger, there was a substantial
amount of screenshots that appeared to provide irrefutable evidence that Slazo was behaving
in just this fashion, including multiple allusions to sexual assault which seemed to
corroborate her testimony. I may naturally hesitant person however, so I decided to wait
a bit more. Obviously I didn't really blame anyone who wanted to show their support because
many of them are clearly invested, and many people behind the scenes may have information
that I may not be privy to, and the screenshots themselves were undoubtedly compelling. It
was a few days later that DramaAlert reported on the situation, with a screenshot of Slazo's
initial statement. It was nothing too revealing, said some of the claims were false or exceptionally
misleading, and understandably said that he would be working on a reply that would take
a little more time. He also said that he was caught off guard by these claims as he had
met Che since the relationship and supposedly put it all behind them. My judgement was skeptical
of his statement at this point, but if he was prepared to reply then I expected him
to have something at least. However then Fizzy Pop decided to release an additional response
to Slazo's statement. It is stated that they had a conversation on Instagram in which Slazo
did not deny any of the claims that she made, thus incriminating him further. Many people
once again stood behind these claims and supported Che with what she was saying, no one with
any decent amount of common sense was going to instigate grief onto a possible victim
of sexual predation. However, behind the scenes something didn't sit right with me, I already
mentioned this in a previous video and I'll go into more depth later, but looking at the
conversation something about the tone of Che just made me uncomfortable, so I confronted
Slazo and told him that, although he's deserving of some very genuine criticism, if it had
been taken out of context like he claimed, in spite of the risk, it would be worth showing
the additional content because the importance of protecting your social image is vital.
These are things that will stick with someone for life, and if she has shown what would
frame you as terrible, if you say you want to show evidence but then don't, people will
take that, well as it seems, incriminating. Our conversation ended and I waited for his
video, and on the evening of June 27th he finally responded, it was a strong video,
I had to watch it a few times through, and once again I'll save my thoughts for later
on. Although I was pleased he had managed to present his side, I was also anticipating
possible additional responses, as said, at this point in time it felt like a situation
that was mostly between him and Che, although it had caught my attention that certain people
had openly taken credit when the initial statement came out, I assumed that their involvement
would be addressed when we had assessed the validity of the claims. However, what quickly
happened was a descent into community civil war, many people who had been involved in
the release of the original statement decided to tweet out further comments, many of these
people decided to continue backing Che, however, many of their statements were vague and also
frustrated many audiences. This led to pressure on creators to hashtag apologize to Slazo,
the messy responses provoked videos and streams from many smaller creators placing pressure
and stimulating further attacks which caused significant sub losses, particularly for one
creator, I Am Ali, the creator involved with the largest social presence. Nonetheless,
this whole situation hit a multitude of creators involved, with incriminating screenshots and
additional claims affecting their image and causing more and more drama which escalated
to the climax that left us where we are today. But what exactly happened, and why did it?
Well let's have a discussion, as a freeface I do know many of the creators personally,
and therefore, I will naturally seek to defend their character, however, criticism is criticism
and there is a lot to dish out, and a lot of information out there to clear up as well,
so let's go to the beginning of this story.
As said, I had heard about these allegations a month before their publication, however,
there wasn't really much I could do as I had seen no evidence, however, when the allegations
were initially released, they were pretty much supported universally, with a few exceptions,
and understandably so, however, with the knowledge that we have now, that this wasn't exactly
representative of the truth, I want to reflect on the original Twitlonger. The first thing
that I really want to do here is the premise for the Twitlonger's existence, this is both
mentioned at the start and at the end, typically, when we come forward with public claims against
a person, we might want to justify why these claims are necessary. Now I'd argue sometimes
a justification isn't necessary, in cases of severe trauma, it might take a while to come forward
with such allegations, however, it's clear that Che felt that there were conditions that needed to be
fulfilled, in the Twitlonger's instance, the point was that she had been informed Slazo had been
repeating a trend of creepy behaviour that he exhibited to her during a relationship that was
rather predatory and abusive. Now these claims do not directly imply that Slazo has been repeating
this exact pattern of behaviour, but what the author of the Twitlonger implied was that as a public figure,
if Slazo has an incapability to behave responsibly, then he shouldn't be in a position of power at all.
As I mentioned in my Austin Jones video, the sort of dedication that many stans might have influences
their judgement, and therefore, many girls may be susceptible to a predator in a powerful position.
Therefore, with the assertion that he is up to no good, Che presents a testimony that paints Slazo
in a particularly negative light. You have two sides to this Twitlonger, the stories and the screenshots,
now normally the screenshots would be used to substantiate the individual claims, however, with regards to
these screenshots that Che posted, they are more to corroborate the idea of credibility, this is mainly
because many of the testimonies provided are anecdotal, and it would be difficult to directly corroborate them.
The screenshots in this instance set the foundations that Slazo would be someone likely to commit behaviour
reported on in the Twitlonger. DMs will never directly reflect what happens in real life, but whatever they
showed, it revealed someone very forceful in what they wanted from Che. Probably the most incriminating
screenshots are shown at the top, that seem to show Slazo and Che discussing a non-conceptual act from the
position of hindsight, and although it seemed like he was regretful of it, it also seemed to yield a strange
obsession from an urge, as he said it. That urge seems like something that is hard to control, and appears to be
the greatest threat if he is continuing to behave with the mentality that he has expressed in these messages.
Many people took this as definitive evidence that Slazo was a predator, but there were a few details that
made me rather hesitant at the time. The first was that I had been told of additional details when I was informed
in May that didn't make it in the first Twitlonger, arguably this evidence that I was told of was some of the
most incriminating, and although I reserve thought for the possibility that these may be held off due to
possible police involvement, the fact that they had not been mentioned at all, not even in the context of the
idea that they had been passed on to the relative authorities, confused me. Once again, I was not certain about
the circumstances surrounding that information, and the evidence was still convincing on its own terms, but it
was a personal note I had to take. However, something that was a bit more publicly identifiable was a weird
contradiction that caught my attention. This was the talk about how people could change, and although I agree
that people can change, if what was claimed was true, it would be less of a case of whether he had changed,
and more of a case of at least being somewhat accountable for causing a substantial amount of trauma.
It is important to note that at the time of the relationship, Slazo was 16, and Che was 14, and therefore,
although we don't expect Slazo to be the perfect boyfriend, there is a level of responsibility on him.
Anyone with any amount of critical thinking could see that regardless of what he might be up to currently,
he deserves to face some retribution for his transgressions here as well, because it's clear he's done a lot of damage.
People aren't ignorant to moral repercussions, but this is also what confused me, I passed off at the time as Che
tried to sound reasonable, but rereading it, it just seemed rather discordant, and this is something that I
followed through into the second Twitlonger, because in response to Slazo's statement to Drama Alert,
alongside another Twitlonger statement, Che posted screenshots from Instagram from a conversation with Slazo
when he had heard that the first Twitlonger was in the works, these were claimed to incriminate Slazo further.
However, the main premise of these screenshots were, as Che stated, that Slazo appeared to deny none of the claims.
However, when reading this additional statement, I took immediate issue with this premise because there was no guarantee
that Slazo would have known the claims that Che would be making in her original Twitlonger,
as the Instagram conversation had occurred before it, so I found this rather strange.
With this in mind, the DMs themselves don't prove much, however, when you assess them more closely,
I'd argue they make Che look worse, mainly because there are multiple DMs in which Slazo seems to be
desperately asking for these people who have made these claims, and although I completely understand
why the anonymity of victims who haven't gone public yet needs to be protected, there was an evasiveness
about her answers that made me very uncomfortable. After numerous amounts of questions, and lack of answers,
Che changes the topic completely to the damage that he had caused, and it just felt dishonest,
because alright, if you say it publicly, I can see you're trying to present reasonability to the audience,
however there's no reason to say that in this conversation, it's just Slazo.
Who knows what he's done regardless, she had no reason to present reasonability, she could have just vented
that what he did was wrong, but the fact that she tried to play the I heard things about you card,
and then defaulting when Slazo tried to ask further, seemed very suspicious.
It felt disingenuous to me, which is what inspired me to reach out to Slazo, it felt like she knew
the nothing Slazo had done was as terrible as she framed it, and was trying to look for justification
to release these claims when it just wasn't there, while still exaggerating what happened.
And honestly, I didn't really want to speak to someone who had possibly done terrible things,
they provoke an emotional reaction from me and people know my personal history with it,
but it seemed like so many people had preemptively condemned him for something that just wasn't as it seemed,
and I felt he could use a bit of advice, after all, it was advice that would only work if he was truly innocent.
At the end of the day, if you're a popular creator, and you're publicly called out,
it is extremely important that you can defend yourself, these are allegations that will follow you around
because many people will look up your name, someone will recognise your face, it is a matter that extends
into your private life. Whether that defence takes a few days or a couple years sometimes,
these things will take some time to consolidate, just don't rush a statement, or don't try and cut something halfway,
or else people will just think you're trying to get away with it by downplaying it.
By promising that he'd be responding further but not saying too much, he didn't let people take his response apart,
and this gave him maximum scope for a full response.
I wanted to make a video regarding the situation, um, as of a couple weeks ago,
some of you might be wondering why it took so long to make this response.
I've spoken about the aesthetics of his response in a previous video, so I won't go in it too deep,
but there's a lot of points to be taken away, nonetheless relating specifically to the situations in question.
One thing that Slazo couldn't really dispute was the actual content of the DMs, however there was a lot he could dispute,
and we'll discuss how much the DM content was actually compromised.
But we'll look at the video for now. There are two separate things he could do,
firstly present a perspective that makes his story look legitimate, or go the extra mile and disprove the opposing perspective.
Although Che provided DMs, as noted they were much more to construct an image of a character that would imply he's capable of doing those acts,
there was no real evidence with direct reference.
So firstly, Slazo goes in for the anecdotal evidence, he doesn't directly contradict every story,
but he does manage to provide enough evidence to show that some of these stories aren't exactly as they were presented.
She pulls my hand down and says to touch her, which is a pretty long way from how she portrays it in her version of the story.
In fact, she was actually the one who brought up the entire idea of doing anything in the cinema.
It was her idea and I had no reason to believe she wasn't as in on this as I was.
But I do have plenty of evidence from very early on in the relationship where she clearly made no intention to wait until 16.
That was never clear to me, I never got that impression and I don't know why she's saying that.
She also mentions later in the post that she's never been in a relationship before, this isn't the impression that I was under.
I was under the impression from these screenshots here that she's had at least two boyfriends and one girlfriend before we ever met.
This is important because none of the stories were proven necessarily, so the fact that Slazo could at least provide contradiction for some of them
was enough to undermine a key factor necessary to Che's testimony, credibility.
On one hand, Slazo could have straight up denied these claims and left it there,
but the evidence he provided actually showed that Che had not presented these claims in good faith.
Probably the most incriminating factor was that the evidence that he provided was DM related,
and given the fact that Che clearly went through the DMs fairly meticulously to collect as much evidence against Slazo as possible,
it seems she must have avoided a lot of DMs that would show her as not being as helpless as she framed herself as.
Memories can be clouded and inaccurate, but the problem was the memory had become so biased that for many people,
whether Slazo intended to or not showed the claims as released in bad faith.
The same DMs that had incriminated Slazo a few weeks later had suddenly exonerated him.
But previous to these messages, I'd mentioned something, a complaint I had that I probably should have kept to myself,
it was... it's embarrassing for her, and she's saying that she wasn't too keen on doing that thing in the first place,
and now she's embarrassed. Anyway, around here she crops out around 11 minutes of conversation between us,
where I apologize and try to get her side and understand how she feels.
I wasn't very good at it, but I tried.
In the video where she's scrolling through her messages here to prove that they're real,
she also goes nearly up to where I apologize and try to understand her point of view, but then quickly scrolls down.
Ultimately, what made it look the worst for Che was the situation regarding the DMs.
This was arguably the most incriminating interaction that she had published,
yet she still withheld 10 minutes of conversation without any information.
This is content that could not have been merely missed.
This brought every claim into contention, and gave Slazo the chance to craft the image from his perspective,
and he knew that he messed up, so he owned up.
This put him in a position where he was able to apologize but simultaneously from a sympathetic position,
as the subject of a smear campaign in a way.
I think there's some legitimate criticism here, you know, something has happened,
and Slazo may have acted inappropriately, but we'll discuss the problems with this in a bit.
about that um she is is very much on board with it with the messages from the time where it actually
happened and the way she talks about it then is very different from the way she talks about it in
hindsight she also mentions me taking off her bra while she's crying firstly i would never do this
if i ever suspected that she didn't want any advance i was making i would stop and also the way
she talks about it in the messages from the time gives the impression that i i wasn't even
intentionally trying to take off her bra which i wasn't this situation by this point bothered me
a lot because allegations shouldn't be botched and they were here with the assumptions that the
allegations were purposely misleading which given what we've observed today would be hard to deny
it undermined any legitimate criticism that may have been warranted but also showed that this was
a situation best left private it was clear from both statements the parties involved had met up
and resolved this as people and although the idea that maybe one of them was manipulating the other
to think that it was all right seems to be a possibility it seems to me that both of these
people have been influenced by the distance placed between them i do have texts from the time that
proved the general tone it it felt very comfortable and i felt that she was completely fine with me by
this point i felt that her past was behind us and we were just putting the final nail in the coffin
by meeting up i really thought this was the case where she says how are you how are you feeling
about it all and i said it's nice it's like a weight's been lifted yeah it's great how are
you feeling about the stuff we talked about towards the end here she's referring to being
friends in the future and maybe getting back together at some point that's what this is
referring to oh like the future and stuff yeah um i feel the same as you really would be really nice
to be friends again for now obviously it's nothing definitive it's nothing concrete but there's that
so take whatever conclusion you will from that believe it or not i've been in a fair share of
drama and conflict in my time i have people who i haven't liked on a personal basis however meeting
them in person often reminds me that these people are mostly decent no one's perfect and if i thought
someone was then i'd probably be a bit more suspicious honestly flaws always exist sometimes
they're just a bit more well hidden than others and in spite of these flaws i can share many
positive experiences with a person even if i have bad memories with them too i wouldn't expect two
people like slather and che to ever be particularly close but it's important to remember how separation
might affect your judgment of a person it was clear that it reached a point that che was under
the impression that slather was a person deserving to suffer to the point where exaggeration was
considered fair game i guess the thing i'm most confused about in this whole thing is
why why would she lie why would she why would she say that she'd never been in a relationship before
never kissed before intended to wait until 16 and twist the truth of what happened in person and
make it and make out like she never wanted to do anything and this wasn't a two-way thing especially
at the beginning it it paints a very black and white picture of me being the predator and her
being the prey it cuts out all nuance of me not knowing what i'm doing and being an idiot which
obviously doesn't excuse what i've said and you know how i've made her feel but
it's a very condemning picture that she's painted and the things she said and the things that she's
implied that i've done can can very well follow me for life it's never fair game with all the
community backing she had falsifying claims that could be disproved with such unbelievably risky
business it wasn't a case of possible perspective with reasonable doubt it was a case where she
actively omitted content and expected that somehow that would help falsifying claims is
never a good idea in the instance that slazo is a predator well congratulations you've let a
predator get away and if he's not well that's terrible you just tried to end someone's career
over false allegations in the instagram conversation that che and i had before this all went live
which is now public record um she expresses concerns that i've been weird with other people
and that she's concerned i'll do it again um she doesn't specify who despite me asking a few times
and and she also says that she's concerned i have stan accounts and people who are probably willing
to send me things for my attention um i said that i've never taken advantage of this and
i even offered her my login to prove that i've never done this and wouldn't immediately after
offering my login the problem quickly becomes more that i didn't take responsibility and that i need
to suffer consequences for my actions um yeah the the reason for it going public quickly changes
and yes the whole twitlonger was released under the premise that he had been continuing this trend
of behavior but it just seems that he hasn't been no additional evidence has come forward suggesting
that he has and it seems strange if someone's prepared to allege that he's been continuing this
behavior as reason to come forward regarding this then that should be part of the evidence
if you're implying that publicizing your experience wouldn't be necessary if he wasn't
continuing this behavior then at that point with your own credibility in serious disrepute it would
be incumbent on these new people to come forward to imply that he might still be a threat but
unfortunately if they exist and they're not prepared to speak up and many people felt at
this point the original claims held no water whatsoever and with the release of slanzo's
video angry people flooded over to deal a torrent of criticism towards che but it was soon about to
be much bigger than her there had been discussion about the actual formulation of the twitlonger in
question because normally when someone makes claims you'd expect them to be the curator of
these comments however in this situation it seems like there were a few more people involved this
was implied when a couple people commented that they'd been involved but this didn't come under
the microscope until after slazo's response after slazo's response many felt like he had made a
compelling case for himself and people felt that providing the situation remained as it was that
he was entitled to an apology or at least a retraction from those who supported the original
twitlonger i don't think people had a particularly high bar because those who had endorsed one opinion
shouldn't remain supporting that opinion if they now see it as false in case new fans come along
and receive a false impression an apology or attraction is one of the ways that this can be
resolved however to many people surprised a few creators involved decided that actually they
didn't want to apologize to slazo initially the people who put out public statements were quite
blues dank dolan dark westerner i'm alex and king annie although these responses were different
shades of tone many found these responses inadequate or misleading some of these responses
are not worth talking about such as quites because he just said he wanted to wait for more information
which is completely fair however there were a few that did strike me as slightly off well first take
a look at king annie someone who i have met and found thoroughly pleasant however the situation
didn't do so great for her firstly she had this monumental take that quotes innocent people don't
stay quiet for this long a day before slazo released his response and then in response to
slazo's video decided to say this a lot of people were pretty focused on alex's take which we will
discuss later but i do think this one is significantly worse michael is still guilty for
what he did in the past yes we are all guilty for what we've done in the past the question was
what exactly happened he did admit to some things most notably a quote complaint he had but it
would be incumbent on the people involved to try and exactly pinpoint what the context for
this situation is because he said himself that he didn't want to mention it specifically
so you have the chance to clarify what this actually was and you didn't no one is glossing
over it it's just people can't go after him until they know the specific context until then people
will be looking towards you for elaboration and then we have this gaslighting comment which i
found rather strange gaslighting is when you make a person doubt their own experiences through
manipulation but i don't think she knows what that means also i find it strange that her language
implies the fact that she can label this as gaslighting suddenly means it's manipulation
and not just manipulation on its own terms it's a strange way to express your position it's like
she thinks that people just identify the word manipulation rather than the underlying processes
people aren't the smartest sometimes but they're a bit smarter than that then she goes for the
mentality argument and yes there was a responsibility on slazo that he failed as a
boyfriend there was an age gap frankly put more weight on him but the problem was that it seemed
that they were both ignorant in a way that would make their judgment poor other factors like
experience also have to be taken into account secondly that's not how i remember it is not a
shit rebuttal at all without the evidence sometimes it's the only rebuttal and it's the only way people
can defend themselves when they have unsubstantiated claims made against them they cannot directly
disprove then we have the final statement that annie makes which brings it back to this notion
mistakes and it's okay if you want to stand by your friend i completely understand that
that's your choice but these aren't mistakes example in the original twitlonger che states
that this was her first relationship in an attempt to make her perspective seem more innocent this is
not a passive omission this is not something that she could forget it is an active lie that
was contradicted by slazo in his response these mistakes are all over the twitlonger and you can
stick up for a character in public but you should have a very stern talking to her in private because
given the twitlonger have been in the works for around a month and you took credit for helping
her you really should have made sure there wasn't room for such mistakes she ends by saying she
hopes he can get some therapy issues that as he has presented the argument seem to be resolved
as said i met annie after the statement and she completely defined my expectations i really
enjoyed her company and she may genuinely believe this but if she does then i'd really recommend
withholding judgment of situations in the future not because she's a friend but because she's a
public figure and that sort of exercise of power is obviously going to have a huge influence on
someone's judgments plenty of people have spoken to me and said that they think che was manipulated
and i think that's very possible too even unintentionally the sort of pressure from
such powerful figures to put a statement out would be crushing chase twitlonger is not the
sort of thing that people can continue backing even if it's just for the sake of personal pride
even if you want to continue backing che as a person even if you don't like slazo even if you
find him creepy there's such a dynamic of power in this situation that shouldn't have been used
wiesner was the other person who made noteworthy comments in response to this situation and
honestly when breaking his comments down they're not that different to annie's okay so i just
watched slazo's video his response to his ex-girlfriend che's accusation that he was
uh emotionally and perhaps even sexually abusive and my conclusion is that he is just gonna have
to learn from his mistakes i mean he fucked up it looks like he's still gonna fuck up again
he gives me a lot of impressions that he's definitely manipulator he even owns up to it in
his video he definitely seems like the person to to gaslight his partner make them think that
things happen differently from what they remember in order to manipulate them and make them
apologize for something that wasn't even their fault um i don't want to believe that che is just
an outright liar but there was this one clip that always stuck out to me slazo did admit that he was
controlling he used the word controlling he didn't say manipulative now all the youtubers are
manipulative that's how we got to where we are we manipulate an audience day to day for money i mean
like this is what we do i know it has a negative connotation to it but it just is what it is this
was not a good thing to say firstly equivocating being controlling and being manipulative and then
equivocating being manipulative in the past tense and being manipulative in the present tense
we made two huge logical jumps to justify a point of view that we cannot be remotely sure of at all
to be honest i think his statement wasn't the worst even though he made that stupid comment
about people being manipulative because he did seem to acknowledge that a lot of the information
was wrong and it should have remained private but his opinion still just seems to be parroting
other people without knowing what those words actually mean it seems like a lot of people
involved were just trying to make what he admitted appear worse than what he actually did without
proving it was a lot worse despite having the opportunity and people saw through it and people
were asking for more and well they got more but not exactly in the way they'd hope all right i'm
gonna head to the con in a second of sunburn madam's apple look like a lobster
i'm in a lot of pain we go again see you all soon
the problem is that when people started making statements like these people saw it as them
trying to cover their backsides and for justified reasons the people involved all knew che and if
che had more evidence that she was prepared to release other people involved were either better
off staying silent or at least informing the audience that there would be more evidence to
come however they spoke as if this was it at least for now and people picked up on that one
of the most confusing things for me as a viewer was that people who had openly reacted with such
shock and surprise when these allegations were first released when many of these claims were
counted or disproved suddenly changed their tune as if they knew he was a terrible person anyway
and the fact that the claims were falsified oh that doesn't matter as someone who might be a
friend to someone like slazo as someone who was not present in the original relationship as
someone who felt the shock and surprised i'd be relieved when he put out his response but this
was the sort of response that makes people think there's another motive something else behind it
i'm alex was another person who honestly i didn't expect to be involved and i really wish he wasn't
i've known him for ages and he's been having a rough time recently so i don't want to give him
grief he has apologized since but it would be dishonest for me to pretend he doesn't exist
he was one of the people who decided that the public deserved a response and whether they did
or not it probably wasn't the one that alex should have provided hello guys um i i want to try and
put this in as concise way as possible uh but this is my response to michael and slazo's video
uh there's a limit on this so if i'm brushing other things i'm trying not to i just want to
put everything in here in a place that is easy for people to get to um i want to make a statement
because of the fact that obviously i came out and supported che when she posted her to it longer
um and obviously now michael's video has come out where he's debunked um some of the things
that were put in there my problem with michael was him admitting to doing things that he knew
che may not have wanted to do and being incredibly forceful and almost demanding which he admitted
to doing in his video which for me is still disgusting um i don't believe he's innocent
i i don't think he's innocent at all uh che may not also be innocent and i may have hid stuff and
and used jokes to try and maybe push a certain agenda but at the same time the stuff that michael
admitted to is stuff that makes me not want to be friends with somebody who is capable of doing
those things once again it felt like he'd read a tldr of the video and attempted to derive some
conclusions from there it wasn't a good response and admittedly it did confuse me to an extent
i'm alex has been covering youtube drama for ages and surely he'd know the do's and don'ts responses
in an ideal scenario if there was no more information the best thing to do is to say
that you were misled and apologize you don't have to be friends with the person you don't even have
to believe that they're a good person but you have to say what you got wrong alex spoke like someone
who knew more information was preparing for more information yet as mentioned earlier if there was
more information the best thing would be just say nothing at all or to tell people to hold their
horses on the other hand i thought there must be more to this because someone wouldn't pick such an
obviously bad response when they've been covering responses since the dawn of time but even then
putting out an awful response receiving a little backlash only to wait a few weeks and suddenly
drop some evidence that will turn the case on its head is a terrible way to go about it as well
because people will just be pissed off and ask why on earth you didn't just say there's more to come
this gives me the impression that no one was actually certain of additional evidence to be
released but was hopeful that there would be some killer response that would make their critics look
like idiots sexual misconduct allegations aren't about the gotcha moments with all this in mind i
put out a tweet venting my frustration about the handling of the situation and in light of this
some people involved reached out to me in private regarding the claims but what they said is there
would be a lot more additional evidence and claimants with a high level of certainty this
caused me a lot of confusion because as aforementioned with their current statements
people involved were about to receive a lot of criticism but who was the main recipient of the
sites of the ravenous commentator our friend alex people were not happy about his response in
particular but why well as noted earlier he is a commentator who is renowned for his takes on
youtube drama in fact many people view him as one of the most credible commentators in the community
and therefore his fumbling was a huge stain on his takes this was brought forward in tandem with
his james charles take which many people criticized him about honestly i thought his
original video was a fairly natural reaction to a situation that seemed pretty different to the
truth and to be fair he did actually apologize for that take although some people felt that
his original video should have been removed and that was a justified position too that i agree
with these back-to-back situations someone who people seem to have much higher standards for
made the criticism a lot more stinging on top of this there are people who have some pretty
personal grudges against him two of those creators being kavos and keemstar the kavos
feud has been a long personal conflict originating way back from when kavos made a video on wild
spartans i'm alex's then friend a while later i'm alex then clapped back with a video of his own
which kavos replied to when keemstar shafted kavos over a dispute regarding drama channels i'm alex
actually intervened and defended kavos which seemed to put the conflict to rest with kavos
even suggesting that he was happy that alex's channel was doing well however this will fall
apart when both the creators appeared to intend to meet each other but never did
with alex claiming that he tried to meet him multiple times and kavos saying that this just
wasn't true this new situation gave kavos a whole new round of ammunition to take aim at alex with
the backing of keemstar what he's done i think we can all agree is just inexcusable and there
needs to be some sort of consequence for that you can't just go around doing this be a commentary
youtube over 1.6 million subs and do that how can anyone trust him again how can he have any
credibility that is what you need as a commentator how can he be a commentator after all of that
keemstar on the other hand has hated alex fairly consistently for a long time from a situation
rooting back to keemstar's beta podcast a podcast featuring keem fellow british commentator
colossal is crazy and drama streamer tommy c after a conversation alex reported that keemstar
was the instigating factor for its demise he made a twitter video when he knew clown
couldn't defend himself accusing him of asking for more money and accusing clown of refusing
to cooperate when in all reality it was king keemstar since claimed that alex is a social
climber who will only use people for his opportunistic game last night you said the
reason why i don't like you is because you don't like me that's that's retarded you're actually
retarded look dude the reason why i don't like you is because you uploaded a video and you made
up a bunch of lives about me that was the start of it um then you kept doing this repeatedly then
you started fucking leeching off people and using them to kind of get where you were ironically this
situation spurred members of the community on so much that keemstar and tommy c long opposed to
each other put their differences aside and reunited with colossal to record an episode
of the baited podcast relating specifically to this situation if the community all starts hating
pewdiepie one day he would hate pewdiepie right if the community starts loving pewdiepie he loves
pewdiepie like dude this guy is a flip-flopping piece of i hate him he's not a real person he's
not a real person with real opinions and real thoughts boogie does the same thing always goes
with the popular vote and he'll retract his opinion in a heartbeat well his heart beats
pretty fucking fast to be honest with the clear evidence that there was some fuel in the tank
other smaller creators jumped on the opportunity to upload videos on i'm alex claiming either his
disloyalty to slazo or his hypocrisy regarding situations the reason he had become the target
was mostly circumstantial nothing he'd done at this stage was different to many other creators
and i was concerned that people would forget about the greater points that were to be made
my concerns were confirmed when alex unwisely decided to speak to some of these smaller creators
in a private call which would honestly not remain private for long he allegedly disclosed
multiple details regarding the situation these creators then decided that they would do what
they know best talk about it and oh dear oh dear oh dear in this call it is alleged that all sorts
of information was divulged the prime recipient of this information was a youtuber slash streamer
named nicholas diorio who then went and passed on alex's numerous comments to various creators
some who were directly referenced and others for video purposes i have no clue why alex thought
this was a good idea but it wasn't people are always nicer in conversation than when they're
publicly talking about you and it seems that alex was under the impression that if he told them
aside they'd be a bit softer on him in public unfortunately that was not the case diorio took
alex's comments regarding slazo straight to slazo and conducted an interview in which he asked
slazo his opinions on these takes alex claims that you had been rough and forceful with a girl
while staying with him he claimed you were completely sober and forcefully getting this
woman drunk allegedly alex had to step in and remove the girl from the situation as you begun
kissing and sent her home in an uber alex also claimed he told you we don't do that shit around
here man and bullied you for the next few days yes um yeah this was really confusing to hear
honestly um this is a complete um embellishment of what happened he also took comments about
other people to the parties mentioned and informed them too we'll return to this point later but it
was basically the release of a pandora's box of information into the community and provided plenty
more content for creators to nor on one of these creators was turkey tom who for legal reasons i
must disclose isn't actually a turkey and why is your name turkey tom but you're not a turkey
all right if you really wanted to pull this off and brand it right you'd be a fucking turkey
he was making a video on the slazo situation covering the various responses and one of the
people who had been regularly mentioned in private but not so much in public was a creator by the
name of hyojin it was claimed that among other things alex had implied various facts about hyojin
in a call with oreo which were then publicized subsequently although i cannot confirm whether
alex actually said this many people seem to believe that he did given their own personal
relationships with him and some even publicly reacted with hostility when a certain situation
that we'll talk about later transpired these claims also seem to be unsubstantiated and many
others involved said they simply weren't true hyojin is a creator slash artist who is closely
associated with che she hasn't been too vocal about the situation however have been involved
in assisting the release of the twitlong behind the scenes she was named and saved and what
happens when a creator is called out is that often people like to go one step further and see what
other shady behavior they may be partaking in when hyojin's name was dragged out under the sun
a lot followed a lot of offensive dms a lot of testimonies from people who had negative experiences
and some further rumors some of this stuff was definitely warranting criticism for example an
nsfw blog in which she posted explicit art of people from within the community some of these
people were quite underage and others definitely didn't consent to it however other claims were
slightly more shaky and also rather invasive in a person's private life so where does turkey tom
come into this well he uploaded a video on the situation in which he addresses the involvement
of many individuals and one of them is hyojin this was not too long after the information of
her involvement had been floated from the private call besides the multiple other allegations
regarding her behavior in tom's video he made some very fair points that would deserve criticism for
the parties involved however when going through hyojin's involvement although mostly focusing
on the content that was fairly verifiable he divulged two pieces of psa that were probably
rather inappropriate the first was a rumor regarding an affair that should not have gone
in a public video and the second was a set of allegations regarding animal maltreatment
relating back to the claim by an anonymous source that she was not just unpleasant but had a habit
of picking up a dog and placing it on its back now i cannot comment on the verifiability of these
claims but the problem was the second claim was so outlandish and ridiculous that it immediately
caught the most attention despite arguably being the least relevant now normally with such a claim
we would think about it critically innocent until proven guilty however people were so caught up in
the sentiment of criticizing kyojin that it was just lumped in there with all the actual other
legitimate criticism and because it is arguably the strangest claim it became the claim that was
referenced the most and ultimately became a focus alongside the already existent criticism of her
content in the situation it finally provoked a response from her however these responses were
not well received because they weren't very good and people continue to lump pressure onto her
creators made additional videos turkey tom made a second video in which he responded to heojin's
comments and provided further elaboration to his points and although there was still attention on
other people involved it's clear that a lot was said about heojin and she became a very easy
target due to her incompetence in dealing with this however it's clear that people had become
too carried away on the basis of some shaky criticism and some character and it was easy
to witness ultimately the sort of mob had turned on heojin and it was becoming very toxic and after
a few days she blacked out her twitter and it was reported she'd attempted to take her own life
fortunately she survived and was hospitalized however this provoked a lot of further conflict
from within the community at first there was an immediate reaction an outpouring of support in the
hashtag love for heojin movement trying to reverse what it had become but soon enough people began
to make more provocative statements maybe people began to turn on those who had rustled up this
scenario stating that they were partly accountable for this terrible situation however in response
to this many of the lead critics asked if the attempt really changed any of the points that
were being made against her it's a tough discussion because both of these points are
extremely sensitive but neither of them are entirely invalid if someone did something
terrible and attempted on their life no it does not change the terrible thing they did
but i also think the point of criticism is to improve someone not drive them off the edge
and mixing in unsubstantiated rumors in there just generally harmed the case that could have
been much more focused on what actually happened and not drive someone's image down as some sort
of dog tipper it's why we should always make our criticism as clear as possible from a personal
perspective we will always provoke some backlash onto a person if we criticize them however firstly
we want to make sure that we don't cause harassment and secondly we don't want to provide
backlash on the basis of false information nonetheless that does not mean that harassment
is accountable to the original critic because there will always be some people who look for
an excuse to harass people regardless and there has to be some level of personal responsibility
for such behavior in this situation i don't think anyone maliciously intended to provoke harassment
nor do i think anyone can singly be blamed for reporting on a lot of this but going in with
outlandish rumors at a time where people saw a lot of the claims as flying regardless of whether
they had wings or not was probably not the best shout try and make sure that what you're basing
your content off is as well founded as they come it doesn't just help the person you may be
criticizing but it helps your case too and prevents this sort of situation coming back today
to tom's credit he has actually made changes to his videos that remove the unsubstantiated claims
and anyone who also did that should receive their fair credit it's an emotional situation and people
do feel really strongly about it i respect that when people made their videos i don't think it
came from a place of ha ha drama let's cash in i genuinely think this mattered to people because
people did feel strongly about being in a position where you would be exposed for something that you
didn't do and you could have your whole career ruined that provoked strong feelings understandably
so however although this was the situation that brought the drama to a halt it was still a very
small part of a very complex puzzle because there were still so many unanswered questions regarding
how and why this happened and what exactly was going on behind the scenes and that's what i want
to discuss now why is arguably the most important question that one can ask because once you find
the underlying roots of a scenario then you might be able to exactly understand the cause for these
situations and hopefully work on avoiding them in the future that's important for anyone involved
at the end of the day the goal is to make sure that anyone who is a threat to those around them
is addressed properly and innocent parties are left alone so that we can elevate victims and
make sure that they have a voice there are many reasons that people have hypothesized how this
has happened one of the more popular theories is that of competition and although it would be
certainly an interesting albeit sinister twist i don't think that is the case i don't think those
creators were threatened by the prospect of another creator covering a similar genre and
slazo wasn't a similar genre to many of the creators involved anyway it would certainly
take a very elaborate plan to take out someone for the mere reason of being competition i also
don't think it's a group conspiracy i don't think that everyone involved in the release of the
statement had malintent it seems plausible that one or two people color the perception of the
party but it seems unlikely that we'll be able to work out exactly who in light of the situation
we've seen a few party members involved openly apologize their involvement this seems like the
right thing to do at this point however it still doesn't really answer why a couple people doubled
down at the time some have stated that they thought they'd heard more stories but it just
seems confusing that if the first claims were disproved they'd stand by these additional
claims and openly call out slazo if they were unsubstantiated which is what they seem like
on top of this a fair few people still defend che's intentions or say that they thought she
genuinely didn't have the idea of leaving out all this evidence and once again although someone may
be genuinely hurt it really can't excuse what happened it really can't change the fact that she
would have had to have gone through all these messages and she didn't just accidentally miss
out 10 minutes of dms it's impossible to really work around it doesn't really excuse what happened
and doesn't really make sense either the fact that someone just accidentally left out 10 minutes of
conversation i can't look inside their soul and completely deduce what was going on which made
so many people desperate to justify that slazo wasn't a good person but given the similarity
of all the responses and the general misuse of terminology it seems like it was just a case of
group think with some people's ignorance taken advantage of by a less than well-meaning actor
perhaps but that's just a theory some people haven't commented further that will be for better
or for worse some people have like westner i love you i don't understand priming's video
makes you sound evil uh yeah it's just some fucking guy some fucking content content vulture
this is yeah i mean what do you expect making video about the drama like a month after it
happens quick point buddy primink isn't a content vulture he's a guy who cares a lot about a
situation that you claim to care about too and the fact that you have the nerve to judge people's
character on the basis of them calling out is pretty rotten if you don't feel like there's
anything more to say then don't say anything more there were also some people claiming that
people at the actual insomnia event knew which i can't say i agree with either even if people were
unsure at the time i don't think they would have invited him over with that knowledge with that
said there were definitely people who have known for a while who were not at the event and that
does bother me because no one thought to tell me or many other people what was going on people know
that there are people there with strong history with sexual misconduct and even when i was told
personally i was still not meant to know and even then if he was a threat people really sat
on this evidence for such an exceptionally long time as if he wasn't going out and about in his
daily life interacting with multiple females it all felt so fine-tuned it was more designed to be
a spectacle than an actual post and that's what bothered a lot of people myself included in my
opinion there have been people trying to get individuals to disassociate from slazo due to
how they perceived his behavior and it reached a person who insisted that they needed to go public
with this information but unfortunately it just wasn't there and you know i do believe that people
act with earnest intent when trying to bring these things to light i will defend many of those people
but the fact is that it took a month to come out with a much less than adequate allegations
embellished with evidence that had clearly not been closely looked at i mean it's infuriating
and it has taken its toll plenty of people have lost subscribers plenty of people haven't been
doing mentally well out of all the drama watching this one was probably the most painful but i felt
it was worth saying something because as someone who saw a lot of it going on in the inside it took
a toll not just on the people directly involved but on a lot of the people around and the
relationships they had i've now heard multiple contradicting statements from people involved
which don't add up people who i believe i could trust i heard them out i believed them and
supported them but since then i've had to take a step back and ask myself who i put my faith in
it's draining it makes me miserable and i'll always stand up for the people who are my friends
if anyone asks me about the intentions of people involved i defend them to the bitter end but there
are some things that never sat right with me throughout this all and nothing has really
righted those feelings of discontent there were people who did not treat those around them like
friends a lot of youtubers should look at the slazo situation and take a long hard look at
themselves and the way they treat their friends as for slazo well i want to take a brief moment
to critique him independently it's clear he's had some problems but i don't think those problems
are problems that he's not been working on and it's clear he acknowledged that he's behaved as
a bad boyfriend in many ways being controlling is a poor show and there are definitely certain
things that he has admitted to that would be worthy of criticism floating the idea that his
girlfriend should take different antidepressants that would aid her sex drive like she said the
thing i didn't go there when she was on a period i suggested at one point that she go off her
antidepressant well i suggested she'd go to another one but at other points i insinuated
that it might be a bad thing that she was on these antidepressants why first her sex drive
yeah like she said oh two so your intention was to amplify it or to decrease it to em to
yeah to amplify it yeah all right that's that's the point against you i would say
it was exceptionally inappropriate and we don't know the context of this he may have just
suggested it one time passing or it may have been a more coercive problem but he's been given a
chance to address himself in this situation and i am pleased with that he has the chance to improve
himself and work on his image i do not believe he's a bad person though that's just my opinion
and i may have been duped the slazo may not be the change man that i view him as now and i'll
have to hold my hands up and that's okay because we get things wrong sometimes i've got things
wrong i'm probably gonna get things wrong again we can't expect to get everything completely right
but if we end up in a situation that is so much bigger than us where a person's career might rely
on our own conduct then we need to hold our hands up and if there's more to come then just let
people know if you think that holding off information and surprise releasing it in bits
is gonna own your critics you are really wrong allegations are not film sequels although i have
spoken about my involvement in this it would be unfair to not note the work of the many people
who did provide slazo with the support when certain creators continued to turn on him in
spite of his rather conclusive response with what we know i do believe they did the right thing and
provided substantial criticism to names who would have otherwise gone unchecked and i must give them
their due credit to finish i definitely urge people to take a bit more of a careful response
to allegations in the future there's nothing wrong with throwing your weight behind and taking a
stand and making creators address these things at the end of the day i do believe it's their
responsibility but definitely don't go on a clowning stampede the main goal should be to
have people address it and if they can't they've messed up then we can enact what we view as a
proportional response justice is a responsibility incumbent on the community creators and audiences
it's a shame that it was misused in this instance but hopefully it's at a close now and we can all
move forward so yes that's the video i hope you enjoyed it was definitely a difficult one to
write but we got there in the end i really want to give a big shout out to the editors who once
again done a fantastic job definitely check them out i'll leave their links in the pinned comments
it just wouldn't be possible without them i also want to give a big shout out to my patreons some
10 patreons up on screen right now but i have to give a personal special thanks to my 50 patreon
some hullabaloo the spectre angel bow right rocket ralph nico de shan sarah elizabeth and caroline
thank you so much guys it genuinely means so much to me i also want to give a very special thanks to
my hundred dollar patreons brandom adam michael and christopher karass once again it's a contribution
that genuinely makes a huge difference and gives me a lot more license on what i want to make
videos on it gives me more creative freedom and i really appreciate it if you want to contact me
on twitter i at the right opinion if you want to reach out to me on facebook uh my links will be
there too discord as well i'm there i'm on the ball uh well sometimes not always but regardless
hopefully there's a way you can reach me anyhow i don't think i have too much else to add apart from
you know i hope you guys are having a lovely week whenever this is released and if you're normal i
hope it made this week a little nicer otherwise take care lots of love and i'm the right opinion
and i'll see you in the next one
you