So everything is up on the Bitchute channel, finally, it's all, it's all been uploaded.
If you've been watching the feed on your Bitchute account and wondering why
it's basically been spammed by my uploads, it's because I've uploaded the entire backlog,
so if anything doesn't work, let me know and I'll re-upload it. But this should be everything.
The next site I'm working on uploading everything to is Odyssey, that's odyssey.com,
and they have a real handy feature that Bitchute says it has, but it doesn't really
work all that well in my opinion. It's the auto-uploader, and actually Odyssey's will just take
the entire account, so that's currently happening right now. All 463 videos are being uploaded to
my Odyssey channel, so I won't have to do it manually, that's quite nice. And any videos
that happen to be missing I'll just put up manually, it's not a big deal. And here it is,
it's at odyssey.com slash at, short ferotaku, there's an at in the URL, okay I guess, I mean,
alright, so that's what it is. Just look up short ferotaku, you'll probably find me on there.
Continue setting up your account, what's this, I thought I finished it.
It's just confetti. There's nothing here, it's just confetti. Okay, well anyway, head over to
short ferotaku on Odyssey, that will be another alt-tech platform that I'm currently prioritizing
once I start making content again, which by the way will be very soon. Basically once I have all
my alt-tech channels set up, if YouTube hasn't re-monetized me by then, I'll just forge ahead
on these ones, because frankly, these places seem to be the future, don't they? Alright guys,
I'll see you later, thanks very much, I love you.