People of YouTube, it is I, EmperorLemon
and you're gonna have to excuse this video for the lack of visual editing
because I want to get this out quickly
I'm recording this on December 12, 2018
during what should be a very momentous moment
I'm recording this as the 2018 rewind is surpassing Justin Bieber's baby music video
as the YouTube video with the most dislikes on the website
now you may think that the rewind getting so many dislikes
may have something to do with the tank the rewind movement that I started last year
but I'm not going to take credit for any of that
because doing so would be like taking credit for predicting a flood after a hurricane
the tremendous backlash surrounding the YouTube rewind this year
is indicative of a far more pressing problem
whether you realize it or not
we are currently standing at the precipice of the next great YouTube war
it's a war that for all intents and purposes has already begun
and this isn't one of those petty little skirmishes
involving YouTube drama and diss tracks
and topically hating on one YouTuber for making a stupid mistake
this war extends far beyond that
this is a war about the culture of the internet
so allow me to explain to you guys the series of events that has led me to this conclusion
first and foremost
on December 11th 2018
my good friend and fellow YouTuber Mumpke Jones had his two main YouTube channels terminated
each channel Mumpke Jones and Mumpke Jones 2 received three community guidelines strikes
all within a very short time period of each other
one of the strikes the one that ultimately terminated Mumpke's main channel
was done so on a private video with zero views
meaning that this video in particular was not actually flagged by any viewer of Mumpke's videos
and rather it has been terminated by YouTube's own system
and based on this information and the fact that so many of Mumpke's videos
got terminated around the same time
I would say that it's very reasonable to infer
that Mumpke's termination is entirely and solely YouTube's doing
now keep in mind these weren't new videos or anything
these videos had been up on Mumpke's channels for months
some of them were up for over a year
and it just so happens that coincidentally they all get taken down at the same time
and in enough of a volume to terminate Mumpke's channel
Mumpke has been attempting to appeal the decision
he's been having a back and forth with the Team YouTube Twitter account
and so far it appears that YouTube has no intentions of restoring Mumpke's channel
now at this point a lot of you who are familiar with Mumpke's content may be thinking
well Mumpke is a pretty edgy YouTuber
so perhaps it's possible that the videos that got taken down
did actually violate YouTube's guidelines
but the problem with that is it's not true
the videos that got taken down off of Mumpke's channel
were all Elliot Rodger related
and each of them got taken down for reasons of either hate speech or promoting violence
so looking at YouTube's reasoning here
it's first of all very obvious that these videos do not have anything to do
with violating YouTube's hate speech policy
for anyone familiar with Mumpke's recurring series on Elliot Rodger
it is painfully obvious that any possible interpretation of hate in those videos
is directed towards Elliot Rodger
anyone who watches Mumpke's videos on Elliot Rodger could clearly see
that they have nothing to do with hate or discrimination
towards any marginalized group of people
it's totally obvious that they don't
the other reason listed for some of the takedowns
were that they were promoting violent and harmful acts
but once again you don't have to be a genius to watch these videos
and realize that Mumpke Jones is not at all condoning the actions of Elliot Rodger
the videos are presented in a documentary format
and pretty much the only humor in them is done at the expense of Elliot
once again it's painfully obvious to anyone watching these videos
that Mumpke Jones is not promoting the act of mass shootings
as a matter of fact several videos in the series
actively bring up solutions to how mass shootings
like the one perpetrated by Elliot Rodger could have been prevented
another important detail that I'd like to add about this case
is that the privatized video on Mumpke's channel that ultimately led to his third strike
was a short two-minute long skit of Mumpke basically screwing around with an Elliot Rodger body pillow
and as a matter of fact an identical version of that video
had been uploaded to Rusty Cage's channel
considering those two collaborated on the project
so just to be clear here Mumpke Jones and Rusty Cage
both uploaded two versions of the same video
Mumpke's video got taken down that led to his channel termination
and the video on Rusty Cage's channel was completely unaffected
when Mumpke Jones then linked the Rusty Cage video to Team YouTube
showing them that the video had been wrongfully taken down on Mumpke's channel
YouTube decided to double down on their decision
and take down the Rusty Cage version of the video and give his channel a strike
YouTube's reasoning for this is that the video promotes violent acts
even though there is zero violent or graphic content in the video
the only possible interpretation that could even slightly lead to this conclusion
is the inclusion of Elliot Rodger
and based on the fact that pretty much every video that was terminated from Mumpke's two channels
were Elliot Rodger related
it becomes clear that YouTube has some vendetta against Elliot Rodger content
Mumpke's termination and Rusty getting a strike
are almost certainly the result of YouTube's internal people pulling some strings
because if YouTube actually cared about taking down violent and graphic content
then they should probably explain to me how a plane crash compilation
showing the actual violent deaths of hundreds of people is allowed to stay up on the platform
and for most of its lifetime by the way it was running ads on the platform
it's currently at over 25 million views and YouTube has done nothing about it
maybe YouTube should explain how they've allowed an entire sub-genre
of women pretending to have miscarriages
and have done nothing to prevent this violent and graphic content
just a reminder to you guys that miscarriage pranks
and plane crash compilations are a-okay according to YouTube
but Mumpke Jones dancing around in his backyard with an Elliot Rodger body pillow
is somehow too violent and graphic to stay up on the platform
when you consider all these factors it becomes painfully obvious
that this isn't about some YouTuber uploading videos of a school shooter and getting banned
it has become painfully clear that people like Mumpke Jones
and people like Rusty Cage are not welcome on the platform according to YouTube
it doesn't matter how many fans love and support their content
and watch ads and generate revenue for YouTube
it doesn't matter how content like this was thriving on the platform just two years ago
it has become painfully clear that YouTube views alternative edgy channels like Mumpke Jones
as a threat to their image and they want channels like that removed
regardless of how many individuals and fans get ripped off
And with that being said, I think the real question on everyone's mind
is why would YouTube, a company that thrived on edgy and alternative content
during the entire time it was growing as a platform
why would a company like that suddenly care so much about expunging the site
of the entire genre of content that popularized them
and let me tell you folks, the answer to this is the very thing I brought up at the beginning of this show
we are currently embroiled in a culture war
and YouTube has decided that Mumpke Jones is on the wrong side of it
allow me to explain this further
in the first week of December 2018
PewDiePie launched a campaign that raised over $200,000 for children in India
$200,000 plus raised and donated to charity instantly
of course all of you probably know that PewDiePie is currently in the middle
of the great subscriber battle versus T-series
and this is an event that's one of the most incredible awe-inspiring things I've ever seen as a YouTuber
it's an event that's unifying the entire YouTube community behind PewDiePie
the channel that everyone who makes YouTube content loves and respects
and as some of you know this whole movement has caused PewDiePie to gain a ton of subscribers
over the past couple of months
so PewDiePie, like the charitable guy he is, decides to share this newfound subscriber boost
with small YouTubers who he felt deserved it out of the goodness of his heart
so keep these in mind
two events PewDiePie raises and donates $200,000 to Indian kids
PewDiePie, to show his gratitude to the YouTube community rallying around him
decides to shout out dozens of small YouTube channels
now I don't know about you, but if you ask me
these sound like the actions of a pretty good dude
so based on these two events, how do you think the online news media reacted to it?
well shit they're calling him a fucking racist and a fucking Nazi
just like they've been doing for the past year and a half
publication after publication reporting that PewDiePie shouts out a racist Nazi channel
oh what's this PewDiePie donates $200,000 to kids in India
crickets, nothing, you don't hear a peep about it
from the fucking blue checkmark so-called online journalists
oh but PewDiePie shouts out a channel that sometimes makes edgy jokes
oh sound the Nazi alarm we found ourselves another Nazi
I can't believe it you guys PewDiePie wants minorities to die in a hellfire
and it's not just one or two publications reporting on this
it's all the online publications
all going after PewDiePie having him and the word racist in the same headline
just a week after PewDiePie raised $200,000 for kids in India
and then you got blue checkmark cocksuckers like Joe Bernstein
trying to piggyback off the controversy and producing blatantly deceptive posts
quote-unquote reporting about the PewDiePie controversy
hey man I really appreciate your content
you've gotten me through some tough times and I respect the
and then when it gets called out on his obvious deceptive reporting
he just calls all of his opponents triggered
well isn't that nice Joe
I want to be totally straightforward with you
you will you will never in a million years
get a job at a publication as prestigious as the New York Times
that will that little pipe dream is never gonna happen
you will be blogging and tweeting until you are dead and nobody will care
nobody will ever read anything you wrote and say to themselves
this is important I need to know more about this
nobody's ever going to read a page that you wrote
and say to themselves damn I'm glad I read that
they're just gonna it's just fucking popcorn
you write the mental equivalent of popcorn
white male
I agree with that
and this is the thing I want to talk about most in this video
what happened to Mumpke and what happened to PewDiePie this week
are both aspects of the same thing
both PewDiePie and Mumpke were subject to coordinated attacks by cultural opponents
as each day goes on on the internet
it's becoming painfully obvious that the internet has now separated into two groups
there's people that get it
there's people that understand internet culture
and then there's everybody else
there's the deadbeat generation of millennials who know how to use the internet
but don't actually get the internet
you have this group of people who thinks that the internet is nothing more than Netflix and cat pictures
and hey guess what these people are running all the online news publications
and they're running youtube
you want to know why youtube rewind this year was an unmitigated disaster
and resembled a pile of steaming horse droppings
well it would seem that the people in charge of it don't actually understand the culture of youtube
and they're just a little bit out of touch with what youtubers actually want
and that brings me to the ultimate point of this video
youtube and the news media have teamed up to attack and deplatform their cultural opponents
in an attempt to engineer and transform the culture of youtube into something they deem fit
i saw this coming back in july when youtube teamed up with the legacy news media
it shouldn't be much of a coincidence that after that point
whenever something bad happens on youtube it's never youtube's fault
it's always the evil racist youtuber who's the problem
and needs to be deplatformed and have their channel terminated
and get called anti-semitic by every publication under the sun
and by every time you retweet one of these things or every time you promote this idea
you are promoting ignorance racism genocide anti-semitism
these are all things that you are putting forward when you are doing anything that promotes pewdiepie
so be careful about this if someone decided that if something were to happen if pewdiepie were to
be sued for this you could be complicit if you retweet it they could make you pay a fine as well
because you have officially published anti-semitic things so if you are republishing this stuff you
could get in trouble for it this is a message to everyone listening to this right now we are at
war the people in charge of these publications and this website have retracted themselves into
an ideological bubble and they are attempting to expunge this website of any influential person
who doesn't fit into their utopian vision of the site call me a conspiracy theorist if you will
but when you witness two attacks one right after the other so coordinated and so absolutely wrong
and unfair in their approach something is going on the youtubers have rebelled against this year's
youtube rewind literally as i was recording this it has become the most disliked video of all time
the youtube community has completely rejected youtube sanitized and pc version of the youtube
rewind and frankly we're not going to stand for it anymore we as a youtube community need to unite
against this threat i don't want to hear it if you don't like mumke i don't want to hear it
if you don't like pewdiepie if you in any way support the termination of mumke or the smear
campaign against pewdiepie i got news for you buddy you're next they're going to be coming for
all of us next and we need to stick by each other and have each other's backs to make sure that
whoever youtube and the news media decide to target next as a part of their agenda isn't going
to be forced to disappear it's time to put aside our differences it's time to forgive the logan
pauls forgive the rice gums and defend ourselves from this much greater problem it could be you
it could be me that specific video violated our policies on harmful slash dangerous content
so this was supposed to be the part of the video where i tell you guys to subscribe to
mumke's new channel but unfortunately youtube saved me the trouble by banning all of mumke's
remaining accounts at this stage mumke appears to be completely banned from youtube the fact
that youtube has doubled down so hard on banning a channel that is so clearly innocent from what
they're accusing him is absolutely outrageous and i cannot reiterate enough how horrific of a
precedent this sets for youtube youtube is basically saying that they can go behind the
scenes and delete any channel they want with impunity and completely circumvent any system
of due process since mumke's deletion other decently sized youtube channels have also
been deleted for seemingly no reason in all eight years of making videos on this platform i have
never seen a situation as potentially dangerous as this one where at least in the past it seems
like you had to make a ton of people mad to false flag your videos and take down your channel now
all it takes is one single person at youtube who doesn't like you to completely destroy your youtube
career now in the time since mumke's ban a few people like tim pool have come out to report on
the story but other than that there's been a shocking lack of concern over what's happened
here i really don't think youtubers are treating this as seriously as they can and like i said
earlier it shouldn't even matter if you don't like mumke or if you thought his termination was
justified the fact that we are simply giving youtube the power to terminate any channel they
want with no due process is terrifying and everyone out there who even cares a smidge
about this website should be completely up in arms about mumke's takedown this isn't an issue
just affecting mumke this is an issue affecting every single person on youtube it doesn't matter
if you think you're following the rules mumke thought he was following the rules many of his
videos that got taken down were so called manually approved as ad friendly your channel termination
could come from out of nowhere with no warning for no reason and there will be nothing you can do
about it it's clear that youtube isn't doing this because they actually want to enforce guidelines
last time i checked the plane crash compilation is still online even after youtube claimed to
remove 58 million infringing videos this is about the unfair targeting of individual people this is
a threat to potentially every creator on the platform and it must not be ignored in a just
world mumke would have all of his channels restored but based on some of the slimy stuff
this website has perpetrated in the past year i'm not sure that's gonna happen so in the meantime
make sure you follow mumke on twitch because youtube is too authoritarian to let him stay here
i really hope they don't ban me for even advertising anything on twitch because they've
done it before also if you want to have a look at the last place on youtube where mumke isn't banned
you can check out the state of the youtube podcast also featuring me and rusty cage the only reason
this channel hasn't also been banned is because mumke doesn't own it but hey i wouldn't put it
past youtube to unfairly take this down too fuck this website and now please enjoy some patron
sponsored content hey guys this is babalu productions i'm a small youtuber that makes
cartoons i do random skits and things like that if you guys could check out my channel that would
be greatly appreciated or you can go to pornhub instead i mean if you do i don't blame you
midget porn is a lot more appealing than my videos will ever be because they look like they were made
in powerpoint but why not both the link to my newest video called if ea made a dildo featuring
the act man is down below check it out if you've got time and finally thank you to emperor lemon
for giving me a chance to be here