Hey guys, no full video today, partially because yesterday's video kind of took a lot out of me,
I don't know if you noticed, but also because D&D is happening pretty soon, and I'm getting ready
for that, and after D&D I'm going to be streaming some Donkey Kong 64, so I already kind of have a
full day planned ahead of me. Speaking of streaming, I'm sure some of you guys have noticed
that PewDiePie has decided to prop up DLive as a Twitch alternative, mainly because it's
blockchain-based, and I do think that this is an incredible opportunity, so usually I stream on
this Twitch channel, Game Boomers. What I'm going to do this time around is I'm going to stream on
my new Game Boomers DLive, so that's dlive.tv slash Game Boomers. Oh look, Odin just followed,
gay. Thanks, Odin. Anyway, I do want to support anything that smashes the current tech oligarchies,
so I'm going to give DLive a try for my game streaming around seven o'clock PM EST.
Hope to see you there. I love you.