Hey guys, Dev here.
My previous indefensible video, titled Imigos Insanity, the legacy of Don Thacker, has been
taken down by YouTube.
YouTube claims that it's violated its community policies and that my channel has been given
a community guidelines strike.
When I went to go appeal the strike, there was no option to do so and my channel panel
shows no community guidelines strike, leaving me with no way to appeal a strike that doesn't
exist but very clearly my video is still down.
It's possible that Don Thacker himself filed the strike with YouTube in order to try to
silence me.
It's also possible that one of the anonymous sources used in the video filed the strike,
because two of them actually emailed me, stating that they were very disappointed that the
information they gave Musical Antihero was used in his and my videos.
Now those people requested to remain anonymous and I did leave them anonymous, but if their
objection is that the information that they gave us was anonymously used, then the only
thing I have to ask is why they gave it to us in the first place.
In any case, I don't intend to be silenced.
The video will be going up on an SFO backups channel and if it gets taken down there, I'll
put it up on Vimeo or I'll put it up on Dailymotion or I'll put it up on Bitchute, I'll put it
up wherever and I give everybody who's currently watching this full permission to mirror and
re-upload this video as you see fit.
A link to the backup channel as well as the video itself should be in the description,
it should be in the card section of this video and it should be on screen right now
as part of the end slate.
So click that link and enjoy guys.