Let's shrink Earth to half its size. It now has a diameter of roughly six thousand four hundred kilometers and only one-eighth of its former
mass is left. Just like a rotating ice skater that pulls in their arms,
the decreased size leads to faster rotation. One full day now lasts only 45 minutes. Also,
gravity changes. On a half-sized Earth, all objects would be half as heavy. With lower gravity,
walking or running consumes less energy and we can cover longer distances on foot.
However, we'd also be a bit slower.
Furthermore, large parts of our atmosphere would fade away into space since gravity isn't strong enough to hold it.
Less atmosphere means less oxygen and CO2, so you should bring an oxygen mask to your next outdoor activity
if you don't want to risk suffocating. Also, with the weaker pull of gravity, the bones and muscles of humans and animals would become thinner
and weaker, and the size and shape of trees would change significantly due to lower gravity in the thinner atmosphere.
Overall, we'd live in a very different world.