Spending your entire life in space.
If there's another planet suitable for humans, it will be quite a long journey to get there.
Even traveling at 1% of the speed of light, it would still take 10,000 years to go only 100 light years.
This means that the people who get on an interstellar spaceship will not be the ones who arrive.
Such a ship requires everything needed for a journey lasting thousands of years,
meaning you have to take everything on board.
New parts for repairs, food, and even new crew to replace you when you die.
Hundreds of generations may live and die knowing only a spaceship is their home.
You might be okay with leaving Earth never to return,
but that means you're making the same decision for your children and grandchildren.
Is that ethical?
Imagine if your entire purpose in life was to just maintain the life support systems on a spaceship
so that one day your descendants could see a new world.
Would you be okay with someone deciding before you're born that you're going to be...