What's the smallest possible black hole?
Well, anything can be turned into a black hole if you squeeze hard enough, even dark.
All matter has some gravity, and that gravity depends on the mass of the object and how far away it is.
The further, the weaker.
For example, when you feel Earth's gravity, you're already feeling the gravity of all the planet's atoms.
The ones close to you under your feet, and the ones far away on the other side of the planet.
But if you squeezed Earth, making it smaller, all those atoms would be closer together,
meaning they're closer to you, so you'd feel stronger gravity on Earth's surface.
So the trick to making a black hole is getting a lot of mass close enough together.
When duck is regular-sized, you don't notice its gravity.
But if you squeeze it to the size of one micron, a bacteria standing on it experiences gravity comparable to Earth's.
Keep squeezing until duck is a trillion times smaller than a proton.
Its gravity will become so strong, not even light can escape, collapsing duck into a black hole.
So black holes can be any size, but good luck squeezing hard enough to make one.