Gee, it sure is boring around here.
I just wonder what my YouTube comments are up to.
...
stragJews
A
a
are
claiming to know in culture don't cringe is
too strong with this want go back to
means cool go back to you means cool
WTF this is absolute cringe
what time we haha me quickly game absolute
Cringe. I think behind the meme are cringe, but so are you.
Personality picked straight from 4chan, except you aren't funny.
Cringe as fuck. You're LITERALLY exactly as cringe as behind the meme.
VIGORITIVELY
Jesus, this video is cringe.
JESUS
Hearing people actually talk about memes out loud makes me cringe so bad,
I couldn't make it to the end of this video.
JESUS
Dot, dot, dot...
Cringe.
The way this guy glorifies outsiders is so fuckin' cringe-worthy.
It's Hannah Baker level of cringe.
Why is this part of my recommended?
Why did I watch the whole goddamn thing?
This in itself is boring and cringe.
You are being pretentious about a dude trying to explain the joke
The older ways of acting are out of your mind, how are your description of an outsider followed?
Drama only worsens the situation.
I found ant farm videos more entertaining than I HATE FUCKING ANTS!
Hey man, that's not cool.
This is fucking cringe.
The fact that anyone actually takes meme culture seriously is the true cringe.
Cringe.
I know the word cringe is inherently cringey, but this video and they way you act is cringey.
The fact that there needs to be an argument about memes is sad.
Calm the fuck down about normies.
It's just cringe.
I'M A COLD BASTARD!
This is just...
Cringe.
Wow, this is fucking cringe.
I love anime!
To be honest, I hate using the word normie.
It sounds cringey.
My lord, why is this person such an elitist?
Nothing is black and white, people are fluid.
Most people fall somewhere in between normie, cringe, and outsider.
Just fucking let people enjoy the content they want to enjoy.
It's a wonderful thing more people are being exposed to a greater variety of content.
A GREATER VARIETY OF CONTENT!
Jeez.
The problem behind this video is there's why too much ear rape, cringe moments,
and things that really make behind the meme angry.
What?
You take memes way too seriously and it comes off as sad and cringe.
BUT I MEAN IT!
Cringe.
My god.
The cringe in this video.
Get a fucking life instead of screeching like an
AUTIST
when people don't respect retarded jokes on the internet.
You should just stick to YouTube poops.
Your attempt at a roast was cringey.
Oh, you gods!
My roast is ruined!
This is so cringey, son.
These folk are katanas from Usha.
Their subsidiary of Musashi, focusing on budget katanas,
ranging from about $40 to $100 in price.
This is so goddamn cringey.
Cringey shit!
This would be cool unless Cringey used a different word than normie.
The fucking WWE editing is cringey.
This is, hands down, the cringiest thing I've ever watched.
The cringiest thing I've ever watched.
Jesus fuck, this was cringey.
JESUS FUCK
Six minutes in and I have second hand AUTISM.
Behind the meme is boring, but this was really cringey.
You're cringey.
This is such a cringey video from a cringey channel
talking about another equally but different cringey channel.
This is so fucking cringey.
This video is pretty cringey to be honest.
OH MY GOD
This video is so cringey.
People who say cringey need to fucking stop.
Yes! Thank you!
Fucking god it's cringey.
Stop saying with an E it's fucking cringey.
And now, ladies and gentlemen.
The moment you've all been waiting for.
We've saved the best for last.
Let's get ready to rumble!
Poor behind the meme.
He isn't that bad.
Sentence shifting.
I really don't get.
I don't understand.
How you hate him you know.
He's actually pretty good.
Behind the meme is about memes and their history.
Not being cringey or something.
There it is!
Mama memes.
Not cringey.
Behind the meme does his job really well.
The know your meme webpage dedicated to the topic.
Helping people who have no idea.
I don't know what that means.
About some of the memes and their meanings.
But you.
You have no idea what your video is about.
I know what I see.
All I heard was distorted voices and bright obnoxious colors.
I got dizzy and after a while.
I swear that my ears started to bleed.
Are you jealous of behind the meme?
Because you are hating him for literally no reason.
I watched this vid twice and I still don't get why you hate him.
I will say this one more time.
Behind the meme is about fucking teaching you about memes.
And he is just trying to help people who have no idea what half the memes are.
You are a fucking dick.
You know.
You don't know.
People will respect you if you actually did something properly.
Like actually having a reason to hate him.
Oh yeah.
No one does.
We paid nine dollars for this?
I paid FIFTEEN.