Okay, this is going to be a little bit weird.
Check this out.
Alright, today is March 17th, this package was delivered from Newegg.
March 17th, there's everything right there.
It is an Xbox 360 connect extension cable.
Nothing too crazy, right?
Take a look at what I received.
This is the package that came in here, it's just a, it looks like it would hold a cable,
right?
But this is what was inside of it.
I haven't even opened these yet, but like, they're like cloths with a code on them, and
it's like a person's family photo.
No clue who that is.
Let me show you this one.
Just no idea.
What the fuck?
Okay, I'm going to open these and try to take a look at them.
Is my cable inside of it?
No, I got, what is that, a pencil?
What is this?
And there's beads.
What the fuck is this?
Come on.
It's going to be the same thing, isn't it?
Just a bunch of weird beads and shit.
Yep, same thing came out.
It's definitely for me, there's my name.
So what the fuck is this?