What's up guys? So it's always been a dream of mine to become a pro YouTube gamer.
So today I'm coming at you with a fresh new gameplay commentary.
Now the game we're going to be playing today just came out.
There's tons of hype surrounding it. It's a class-based first-person shooter.
It's TF2. Why would it be anything other than TF2?
I can just get a clear shot! Oh, a headshot!
Oh, epic sentry kill!
Oh, mid-dude! Oh, a headshot!
Whoa, this guy has a cool font in his name. How do you do that?
Fucking McJuggins?
Hey there Juggies, it's your old pal McJuggins.
Should I take it? I'm going to take it.
Alright, let's see what this black box can do.
I don't like the way you said black box.
What's up guys, and welcome to another Team Fortress 2 gameplay commentary.
Team Fortress.
Wait, is this the same spy? Ah!
RKO out of nowhere! RKO!
Hey, we were getting stomped last round, so...
Tables have turned.
Oh god, no, he's going to kill me! Ah!
Like, auto-balance!
Tables have turned.
Ayy, oh wait, let's use him now.
The tables are turning!
Can you feel the tables?
The tables turned so hard that you launched me.
The fucking tables!
Look at the tables! Ah!
That table didn't turn.
I don't want to live on this planet anymore.
Hey there Juggies, it's your old pal McJuggins.
Fucking McJuggins.
God, I can't hit him.
McJuggins! Damn you McJuggins!
Thanks for the dispenser, bro.
You're just awesome, man.
Really good dispenser, buddy.
Ooh, sorry about that.
Oh my god, this medic!
Ah! Look at this medic!
Stand back to the...
No sign of intelligent life, is there not?
Whoa, whoa, what's over here?
I'll find your super medic when I can.
What's over here?
Aw, man.
Look.
It's in this room.
What is that room for?
It's me, Austin!
Aw, son of a bitch!
Amazing legendary spy who has senpai in his name.
What the fuck is this anime shit? Get that off the screen.
Oh my god, Cleveland is just destroying Toronto.
It's just like the Cleveland Cavalier is hunched over the Toronto Raptors,
just letting out a giant Cleveland steamer.
Ah! Headshots, ah!
Oh my god!
Hey there, Juggies, it's your old pal McJuggins!
Okay, um...
Where'd he go? Wait, what?
Pyro?
Okay...
Um...
Wait, fuck, he's got unusuals. What am I supposed to do?
Alright, gums up! Let's do this!
And feel the power!
Down goes Fraser! Down goes Fraser!
Ah!
It doesn't matter what he's got.
Get fucking back burned!
Get back burned!
Alright, who's next?
You're next!
Ah!
Ooh, that's a lot of people.
Ah-ha!
Look who's taunting! Oh!
Oh god!
This is bad!
Fucking bad!
Oh god! Oh god!
They're chasing me!
Oh! Bad assist! I did four! Four!
I'm not gonna fight you.
Ooh, this is not a safe space.
This is not a safe space.
Ah!
I am going to tear down your safe space!
I'll take care of him, Jenny!
You can't ruin our lives, reality!
Our safe space will keep you out!
Rot!
Just kidding, I'll tear that out real quick.
Shut the fuck up!
Ah.
Oh.
Oh, you wanna fight?