hello hey it's just me today no Lilith okay that's all right it's been a hyper
busy time for me and I basically only have like an hour or two tonight to
squeeze this in that's okay that's okay I appreciate taking the time regardless
and yeah I'm sorry for taking so long to getting back to you it's just things
have been rough right now oh it's everything all right sir oh yeah
everything's fine just very busy okay yeah I know there's there's a lot of I
was like the end of February I was laid off from my job but I found a job like
maybe about a month later so and I know I'm not the only one that's experienced
that so yeah yeah you've you've moved back to the States at this point yeah
sadly COVID I think ruined the economy a bit too far along so you know it being
able to make money is much easier to do than it was on the island so but the
good news is is that everything is pretty solid here I've got my own place
again and bought a car and cash so I can't complain so I mean same here
actually YouTube is doing well enough that I have a car I'm looking to get a
house like it might be yeah things might be okay at least for me yeah yeah you
and me both I mean like I've been waiting or following the market for
years now and it's like given that the interest rates are going up the price is
going to have to correspond with we go down I know we're in a bit of a strange
situation right now but that's the that's the goal because otherwise I'm
gonna have to build a cabin somewhere I mean with any luck it's gonna sound kind
of strange but with any luck there'll be another housing crash like in 2008 and
then the next generation of people can buy houses cheaper you know yeah cuz
like I had a friend of mine who ended up buying a house in like 2009 and he ended
up paying like $87,000 for it in st. Paul and now that house is probably
worth 300 so yeah it's like I yeah yeah you just sort of keep saving keep saving
and then yeah it's now it's like it's I'm priced out so what one nice thing
about being a youtuber is that you have a much higher ceiling it's based just in
your popularity right your popularity so there's some there's some luck
involved there's definitely some skill involved there's some charisma involved
so but it's not like you're you're at a job where you know your union contract
says that you get five raises over the course of ten years and that's it you
know what I mean exactly and and you know we can get into it with the comic
thing but yeah like the free market is a little bit carved up right now as it is
because it's rough out there but yeah it's good to hear that you're growing
and all that I mean I I the whole trans shooting thing I goddamn it's so many
people came out were like Liz you got to make a public statement or something I'm
like what are you talking about a public statement I'm gonna disavow a terrorist
like what is this about it's it's funny because you and I are both from that
previous era of the internet where you know you weren't online all the time you
weren't expected to be online all the time and you didn't have to give a take
on every single news story that hit yeah yeah but for some reason like every like
because it's a trans shooter and it's like I I have to you know what I don't
get I don't get people's mindset anymore I think people are just poisoned with
group politics so it's like what do you want I I don't identify with any of
these people they're they're crazy you know they're in a cult yeah so why
would I number one stick my neck out for me I know that I'm I'm basically a
broken record at this point but one big reason that I was a leftist in the early
2000s is because the left back then was highly individualistic and now it's not
it's yes we changed absolutely like I I used to be on the left as well too and
in part because the right had the the pearl clutching tipper gore variety type
that were always wanting to take away everything that I thought was cool I
love Dungeons & Dragons I left heavy metal I loved video games and they were
always like oh yeah well you can't have that you can't have that and it's like
well screw you I freedom is great freedom of speech is great and it was
what it was all about and now it's the opposite now it's you can't do anything
that that doesn't toe the line of whatever insane thing we've decided now
I mean in Canada we really didn't have quite the same level of right-wing
crazies that you guys did yeah I do I do remember watching like old spoonie
videos to bring it to bring it back to your era of the internet and your
section of the internet I remember watching old spoonie videos where he
would talk about the problems that he had playing like D&D and magic cards in
school and playing video games and I had the same issue yeah yeah I had my books
confiscated and by my global studies teacher who was convinced that I and
and like sat down with me is like is everything okay you talking about why
did you take my books away fortunately I had another teacher who was cool but got
them back for me because he was also a geeky geeky guy that played Dungeons &
Dragons but yeah yeah like like the 700 Club era you know yeah no no that was
very much a thing now granted spoonie Granite grew up in like you know
Arizona Utah and that kind of a Southwest with that but even up north
even up in a quote-unquote liberal state there were still teachers that were like
no well we have to confiscate you know any questionable material because it
might corrupt you somehow so yeah yeah for me basically I I just I skipped
school a lot I just played a lot of video games kind of on my own with my
friends you know mm-hmm I was never the guy to like bring a game boy to school
cuz I didn't want getting swiped by somebody else like a bigger kid so I
kind of but I still would like you know what I know that no one likes video
games and I got I definitely got teased and bullied for being a gamer when I was
when I was young exactly exactly that was taboo that was not oh and now and
now gamers are you know right wing right there right wing gamer gate Nazis now
that's what they oh it's like everything goes back to gamer gate and I know given
that the news cycle has made people have an attention span of like a fucking
goldfish at this point but gamer gate was a decade ago like are you guys gonna
get over it like at what point is this you know the I think that was just when
when I think that was the the first real time that anybody told them no yeah it
told them no and it kind of stuck you know cuz it it didn't really stick with
with comics comics game basically lost it didn't really stick with the
tabletop stuff because if you look at that now it's it's definitely been woke
a fine yeah yeah you know atheism became atheism plus you can go to you can go to
like old early internet rationalist spaces like the rationalist wiki now
sorry you know but but gaming I made a video on this a year ago my hypothesis
is that because gaming is inherently competitive there has to be some sort of
meritocratic aspect to it and that and that basically provided a bulwark
against let's say this sort of hyper woke stuff from really seeping in too
much and that's why if you look at you know really woke games they're walking
simulators and you know what there's actually some pretty decent walking
simulators like I'm not gonna like I like visual novels I like you know a
quick point-and-click games investigative games like there's there's
a place for those yeah yeah but uh man the people I don't know if you if you
saw this but like the Elden Ring discourse or people were complaining it
was too hard and then they framed it as an accessibility thing so it's like well
you're being you're being ableist if the game is right and it's like right what
are you saying about yourself that you're retarded like what's the story
here yeah well it's it's always that the standards have to be lowered and
everything has to cater to my whims yeah they're used to and that's that I think
is in part because of victim culture and you know it used to be that you
celebrated greatness you know the the people who are the top athletes on the
Wheaties boxes right or that was something to aspire to now it's it's the
opposite you don't get claim in accolades for being excellent you get
claim in accolades for being a wuss you know being a an ugly person instead of
being a beautiful person or being a mediocre person instead of greatness you
know but everyone's beautiful now yeah except they're not we know that's not
true yeah and in psychology and selective breeding and the rest of that
stuff yeah I mean try to you can try to push that all you want but you can't
bully men and going on the dates with you so that'll be the next frontier I
can't well that's what they look you know it's already here it's it's like
you you have overweight women saying that oh well it's it's fat phobic to not
going on a date with me and your beauty standards are based on a system of
oppression so I'm going to blackmail you into trying to it's like what are you
doing you're insane you're insane and you do you do see the same thing with
trans women too right where they say well if you if you don't if you don't
like the trans woman's dick that means that you're you're being trans phobic
and it's like well what if I'm just not into guys well she's not a guy it's like
okay I get your point but like I still don't want to have sex with a penis like
that's what a straight guy would say and that's completely fine but now it's
bigoted right or then you know Aiden Peledon actually did an episode about
that many years ago and and it was about you're not entitled to another person's
body yep right and that's that's what it amounts to that it amounts to is to I
want to have sex with you you don't want to have sex with me but you have to
otherwise agree because of reasons it's like yeah know that you you don't have
the right to enslave you don't have the right to another person it's ridiculous
it's like that's used to be but undergoing this path was a series of
opportunity cost choices where it's like you're yeah if you go down this road
even if you're post-op you will have a much reduced dating pool and at least at
the time that was something that people took into effect and they said well it
doesn't matter so much as I have to sort this out otherwise I'm not gonna make it
but now we live in a situation where anybody that has auto gynophilia or has
been sexually groomed or any of these other issues that are so far away from
the estimated one in a hundred and fifty thousand in men and one in a
hundred and three hundred thousand in women which is what the original numbers
were we're so far away from that that those original people have been
overshadowed by a order of magnitude by these new people that are degenerates or
abuse victims yeah well you're seriously like you're gonna be caught between a
rock and a hard place right because there's gonna be a lot of right oids who
would say that's what you are you're degenerate oh I've had that argument
many times I've noticed the the backlash towards trans people especially after
the shooting especially in the past two years you know you're seeing I'm seeing
a lot more of an adoption of left-wing mentality where it's group think it's
it's group this person is this therefore we judge them as that we don't treat
them as an individual anymore there's a movement away from the Goldwater style
Republican that was more libertarian mindset and more personal freedom
mindset and Liberty mindset towards collectivism and I'm seeing that on the
right they're adopting those tactics as well so they like you go on these I've
been around in some of these channels that where they go on these unhinged
rants it's like all trans people should be you know jailed or locked up or
institutionalized or thrown in a closet it with with a Bible and not come out
until it's like they're fixed it's like they're justifying their abuse because
it's you know it's it's reactionary and pissed off thinking and and it's like I
always do the the Grandpa Simpson meme where he's walking into the door of the
strip club and Bart's sitting there at the chair on the chair you know and he
just puts his hat on the rack sees Bart and then walks out and it's that sort of
thing and it's like yeah it's there there's very much that that thinking
and I've seen more and more of it but I think that's just as a it's people are
sick of this stuff there is no compromise there is no different
differentiation between the sex pests and people that are suffering from a
complex medical biological problem right there is no discussion about whether or
not this is Munchausen by proxy with children or whether or not this is
motivated by a corrupt medical industry that gets paid a ton of money to promote
this and if you trans a child you are guaranteed to have an income source for
for the rest of your life or their life there's no discussion about the ethics
of prescribing pymazide which is an anti psychotic that's used in treating
Tourette's syndrome which has been shown to be very effective in treating gender
dysphoria so those who receive it kind of lose that you know there's no
discussion about auto gynophilia or and whether or not this is a sexual kink
versus you know this is a a psychological need to like if it's not
met then then there's really no way out but there's none of this discussion is
going into it you either accept everything in anything or you are the
same moral equivalent of you know dragging a person behind a truck and a
gravel road right or throwing them in a gas chamber and people are sick of that
they're sick of this this this moral extortion game so this is what I've been
working on I've been I've been trying to do a video on everyone says you know
trans ideology or LGBT ideology you know well you know what is that actually and
I've I'm I'm not gonna make a statement on what it is yet I'm gonna wait for my
video to come out because I'm doing a lot of a lot of reading and a lot of
research but one thing that I've kind of unearthed is that there's a section of
the left liberals liberals like me you know non socialists non progressives
just just liberals liberals like me in the classical sense yeah yeah you know I
I was and still am completely on board with with the gay marriage argument
because it was it was an argument from innate biology it's like well you're
born gay or or you can't change being gay however you happen to become gay
right you can't change it you're born this way yeah yeah that's a biological
essentialist argument however the the constant affirmation you can self ideas
whatever you want that's completely against biological essentialism and what
I've as I've been like digging in and reading and looking through things I've
I've discovered that there is a section of a very radical component of the left
where they they never believed in the I was born this way argument they used it
as a tactical deployment to subvert liberals yeah and it's like oh it was
really I saw like that literature I was like oh that's very interesting well see
I view it I view this stuff as just Marxism with another coat of paint you
know Marxism is all about deconstruction and deconstructing established things
right so it deconstructs societal norms it deconstructs you know social
relationships and biology is just another front for them to deconstruct
right there is no such thing as gender as sex there you know like except there
is there are biological differences between the sexes there are you know
evolutionary pressures for that and like you said they've gone from a I was born
this way mindset towards human beings are complete blank slates and if that's
the case then you can then you're essentially supporting the get the you
know then you can pray the gateway right that that is a method that works if
we're just blank slates that are the victims of a authoritarian patriarchal
system that has subverted everything natural or right about ourselves then we
can just create a brand new system from the top down and reprogram human beings
in any way we want and it but it doesn't work that way and it never has
worked that way I think what they like to rely on is the fact that you can't
really be objective which is true because we're all humans and we all
exist only in one location so none of us can actually be objective but they take
that to mean that there is no objective reality outside of any one human's
perception which is obviously false right right moral relativism is yeah
you know you know if if a hundred people look at the same thing and describe the
same thing there's probably something outside of the hundred people that
exists you know it's not just a hundred delusions that happen to line up so
right right right yeah even though we can't really truly access the objective
world and any because our senses are also subjective so we can't access the
objective world but it does exist and so basically a lot of the the biology the
philosophy the morality of a lot of these a lot of these people that say on
the blank slate left it completely falls apart because of that reason you
know what really I think as it's funny you bring this up because I think I
think how we got here to the idea that we're now calling women birthing
persons because is because in the leftist side that or at least the
traditional classical liberal mentality is that it's very much like a just you
do you and and you know live and let live in a lot of ways you know and I
think following most liberal-minded people's good nature it and I've heard
this myself I've heard you know talking to people like being post-op and whatnot
and and I'm like yeah I'm post-op trans post-op trans woman and then they'll
like like well I think you're female it's like okay well that's great but I
think that has gone to a such a degree where it's like no that person if they
identify as trans actually is that way and so when you do that that's where
they say well men can get pregnant too because the trans woman or trans man has
identified himself as being met a man despite having a womb and producing eggs
that doesn't make it's like yeah it's like the the open-mindedness has
resulted in people like having their brain fall out absolutely instead of
differentiating between a person having some dignity and saying okay fine you
know I will treat you the way that you wish to be treated it's gone to well now
we have to completely rewrite language and biology just to pacify a
statistically insignificant populace it's no fuck that yeah it's it's move
it's moved from treat other people polite to you must view them the way
that I want you to view them like inside exactly in the privacy of your
own head yeah right um so I did a video uh it was our trans woman actually woman
that was the that was yes I watched that I watched what you think of it um I
agree with you oh well thank you I do be honest it's not it's not all entirely my
idea um I got a lot of it from dr. Thomas
pagardas is paper on the subject if you read that or if you know what him I
don't know that one no okay um he kind of conception he conceptualized the idea
that because the definition is circular and then of course if you talk to like a
lefty they'll say what who cares the definite circle well it actually matters
that if it's just circle because what that means is that you can't actually
identify what a woman is you can't you can't point to a list of qualities that
woman refers to so if there's no qualities you can't actually have any
woman the woman can't exist which is why this is this is all they don't even
believe that trans women are women they simply use that to backdoor in gender
abolitionism right yeah yeah um but one of the things I pointed out in that
video was that um if we're talking about any other animal aside from humans we
talk about sex we're talking about gamete production we're not talking about
hormones we're not talking about we're not talking about chromosomes we're not
talking about social roles we're talking about gamete production and that's it
and we're also not afraid to point out that you have you know the male of an
animal and the female of an animal and then the neuter of an animal when for
some reason or another they don't produce any gametes mm-hmm and however
once you start talking about humans that that becomes kind of a spicy take when
you say well a trans woman who is post-op isn't male because they don't
produce small gametes and isn't female because they don't produce large gametes
they're neuter because they don't produce any gametes and even though
that's scientifically accurate you will get crucified if you say that right and
moreover too I can't change my chromosomes I also can't change my
skeletal structure or my morphic traits in my musculature so you know I always
I've been saying this now for ages but it's like you know I present myself as
female but technically under biology I'm not and that's not to say that you
can't respect me and treat me as female if that's what I choose to do but it
becomes a level of delusion if you try to suggest that yeah all it takes is
some some hormones and surgery and then we can go bango there you go and
moreover it's it doesn't it's this isn't helping anybody I think at the end of it
because encouraging this stuff even with trainees such as myself there is
it there's such an extremely high rate of suicide is still in the community so
if I were a moral person I would not want to be promoting this in any way
shape or form because I know that maybe inadvertently you create a social
disease maybe inadvertently you create gender dysphoria and when you create
gender dysphoria you are creating something that has a almost a fifty
percent suicide rate well if there is nothing moral or ethical about that if
you happen to believe that more trans people existing is good and less trans
people existing is a trans genocide then you actually might think that creating
more trans people is good and spreading gender dysphoria if it could be spread
is good what you're doing is you're creating more suicides though I mean
they don't care about that at the end of the day right that's the black pill
is that there's a part of the left that just doesn't give a shit about that well
yeah if I if I were a a conspirator really minded person I would suggest
that this is just yet another front towards the leftist mentality that
humans are a cancer on the world and they're they're trying to engineer so
that the birth rates further collapse you know if I were to to go down that
rabbit hole I think this is just yet another thing to try to get people to
not have children and reduce pop global population I don't know about that one
that that one sounds a bit far-fetched to me I honestly I think I think that's
happening you know fast enough without throwing this into the mix exactly I
mean you look at the gym you look at the demographics and in you know in 50 years
yeah the population is naturally going to fall off a cliff there's no need to
tinker with the birth rates or any of that when that's gonna happen naturally
so but it does seem a sense of nihilism or insanity behind it and there's this
is not motivated I think the trans ideology is not motivated by compassion
or empathy or kindness it's in it's motivated by entitlements self
righteousness money and greed this there's there's nothing compassionate
about it like I think if you were truly wanting to help somebody you would be
honest with them and you would have transparency and there's nothing like
that in this in this movement transparency not that that show that was
out there for a while transparent it was the guy from curb your enthusiasm I
think or no is the the the the dad character from what's that arrested
development he played a brands gendered parent and there was a drama show about
that man I so I've been recently watching house I haven't seen house
before okay sure and that was I think it started in what like 2004 2008 or yeah
yeah that was that was yeah before the 2008 collapse yeah yeah and there's a
few trans characters and a few like jokes at the expense of trans people in
that show man you couldn't say that shit on TV today or show what they showed on
TV it was it was funny as fuck but I'm like wow this I'm surprised it's on
it's still on like streaming services in 2023 you know what I mean like Jesus
it's it's so nefarious that you bring that up because I was listening to a
youtuber talk about how I think Jennifer Aniston was saying that you couldn't
make friends as a show anymore because of the cut kind of like 90s humor that
that exists you know like that that's not allowed anymore you're not allowed
like Joey the the guy on that show or he'd be he'd be homophobic and there'd
be you know a mass outrage and it was interesting because the people now that
are writing TV and cinema are because you know like Millennials or or Gen Xers
that grew up with that stuff and were you know laughing at it and having a
grand old time with it but now they're the ones that are saying oh well that's
not allowed so I don't yeah yeah it bothers me that we have very much of the
mindset of oh we have to judge the past on our current sensibilities and more
often than not that leads to you know iconoclastic ideas where it's like oh
well we have to tear down these statues because they're offensive to our
sensibilities now it doesn't matter they've been sitting there for for 150
years or they're a part of the history you know we've we've deigned them impure
they therefore they have to be destroyed just like this is yeah yeah iconoclasts
never are received well in history I've been so this is my good reason what to
because I recall hearing stories of my dad when he was in his teens and 20s
getting into hockey brawls he was a amateur hockey player yeah okay very
Canadian you know yeah yeah yeah oh very cool I'm gonna drink some molesons after
cool yeah but by the time I came along he wasn't that guy anymore he had kind
of settled down right yeah and I recall being like 10 or 11 and I'm at the
knock you know I was younger than that I would have been like 7 or 8 and we were
at the theme park and my dad really wanted me to go on these crazy
rollercoasters with him and I was too young to go and I was like I can't
handle this I'm way too young but then once I'm 16 and 17 we're back at the
same theme park and then my dad won't do it now he's too old nice old right
yeah and he's like well like my tastes have just changed it's like okay wait
and then now I'm thinking like well firstly my tastes now that I'm in my
30s my tastes haven't changed when I was in my teens or 20s I mean they changed a
little bit but like not much I can still like go back and watch jackass or
something or MX yeah you know those old with the edgy shows or um but I realized
that I think what's happened is basically a lot of people my age a lot
of the Millennials they had their fill of edgy content when they were younger
and now that they've grown up and maybe now they're they're a bit older maybe
they have houses or they have partners they have kids or they're they're in
they're in the workforce they're you know out of school by at least a decade
or more now they're like oh well now I'm getting older and I'm becoming more
responsible but I'm still a millennial because the millennial it's a phrase it
has like a certain weight to it you know yeah yeah well I've noticed that like a
lot of people and I'm also guilty of this to it some extent what do my age we
still act like we're the youngest generation but we're not anymore yeah I
don't know if it's with you but it's kind of psychological with me where it
feels like I'm still 25 and I'm not yeah yeah and I think a lot of the reason why
Millennials are they're basically discarding all the humor that they grew
up with in the 90s and the 2000s is because their tastes have changed as a
natural result of growing up and they think that all that all of society
should change with that because they're still the the youngest they're still the
center of society see I think I think it's something different I think it's
sort of a I see you'd mentioned certain milestones that they've gotten you know
they've had relationships or that they have of houses and families and jobs and
whatnot well Millennials are kind of the lost generation in that way
Millennials have a lower participation in the job labor force than Jen Z or
Gen Z does when it comes to a percentage of wealth owned Millennials have the
like the lowest by comparison to boomers and Xers which makes sense but even Gen
Zers have a little bit more wealth to it because fewer of them are going to
college and getting debt-trapped so what I think you have is kind of a quasi
state of arrested development for some and in others it's I don't actually own
anything the kind of work that I'm doing is you know unfulfilling and low paying
and I think maybe there's a sense of a strive for something greater as you get
older certainly you fill that hole with family and relationships and obligations
but if you can't actually achieve those milestones I think maybe it's filled
with with politics or this quasi sense of morality I kind of get that feeling
so well speaking of Millennials writing things yes what an excellent transition
or segue again there's that word again so last time we talked yeah you had
decided you you you opened up some sort of fundraiser was it I forget which one
it was was a go-fund-me or was a Kickstarter it was an Indiegogo actually
right okay sorry sorry yes yes yes you started up an Indiegogo for the first
issue of Linkara's your expert from a long time ago Lightbringer comic and it
was issue one yeah and the from what I remember the Indiegogo was going well
and I don't hit your goal right it's been funded so if yeah the and and I'll
certainly provide you the link to the but you but yeah we funded it the the
first comic is out there no way you haven't sent him a copy because I
suspect you'll just throw it away but yeah we were successful in it so yeah I
I do recall trying to find out what he thought of this well I was telling what
we thought about it and in fact that's kind of one of the motivators that we
have from one of the add-ons on this campaign well so okay so following the
change the channel drama that took place right there was a youtuber by the name
of V infuso and V infuso made a bunch of really good videos that that kind of
chronicled the events as they were unfolding and he spoke directly with
Mars girl obscures Luppa Ollie Brown the HR lady like he was kind of seen very
very well amongst that group so when it came time to kind of announce this this
thing I reached out to him and asked hey would you be willing to go like have a
stream or something that I can talk about it and just sort of catch up from
where we were at is from change the channel he's like oh I'd love to so we
have this stream and from what I understand somebody tweeted Linkara
about it Linkara then flagged it really and yeah he flagged it and I don't know
if he got a strike or not but he flagged it and then on Twitter he called
me a piece of shit so yeah I have the receipts I can dig him up for you but
sure it amounted to he apparently lost a lot of respect for me after I voted for
Trump and he went on this you know mean-spirited rant so seven years ago at
this point Jesus yeah yeah so we we we decided to kind of roll into that spin a
little bit so now we have make light bringer great again hats so we call
amalgam hats so one of the tiers we have is at the top there you know I just like
to so people have asked me so are you gonna send him one it's like again he's
probably gonna throw it away I know there's probably people out there who
would ask to have it signed at a con and would film themselves doing that I
certainly can't you know endorse you doing that or you know I'm not
encouraging you to troll by any stretch but I would like to see the the video if
it were to come out I'm just saying that does the car even go to cons anymore I
mean it's not that I don't know I'm easy well I don't try to follow him for what
he does a lot of the time anything any developments I get about his life are
kind of forwarded to me by third parties because again I can't ever really get
off the internet and I think or get free of the old stuff that I did I think
having realized that it's gotten a lot more expensive with the economy slowing
down and the costs have gone up as compared to last year I'm really
considering getting backing into streaming and or at least doing
something so that I can reestablish myself again so I don't have to you know
hop around on to other people's channels and just sort of get back into it myself
but yeah I know that he did some streaming and he people asked him about
oni plays and he got really upset about it you know they're always making fun of
me and you know he's just not Doug Doug Walker had a redemption arc and I didn't
think that was possible after the change the channel stuff so I got a respect for
it no mad respect for them for Doug he's he's he's managed to clause place back
on the internet and considering how he didn't die after the wall video it's
like the man's not human right like so good good for him so yeah but but
leycarra it just seems like I don't see it getting any better and yeah I wish
him the best I really do I'm not trying to hold grudges but he's he's turned
into this person that that is one of those types we were talking about so
yeah you know I mean it's it's so strange to think that like you know a
decade ago or I guess even more than a decade at this point yeah I really
looked up to channel awesome like I was a I you know the I told you the story
last time you were here but I'll recap it real quick just for the sake of this
video um 2009 I I really liked a VGN and I really really like spoonie and I
wanted to be on channel awesome so so me and my friends were you know running
around the suburbs with that with a with a camera shooting some really dumb
videos didn't really go anywhere yeah and then like I after the the angry
reviewer thing died off I did some let's plays and those kind of gained some
traction and I did some gamergate stuff and that gained a lot of traction and I
made friends with Sargon and I started doing politics and like yeah so I kind
of made my own way and and now like I'm I'm surprisingly bigger than spoonie
when spoonie was the guy that made me not not made me that sweet was the guy
that inspired you yeah yeah it's funny because like you can go back and watch
John Tron's from John Tron's first video and he's like spoonie inspired me
it's like damn yeah yeah and and now all these people are like they're kind of
it's it's it's it's really mean to say but they're kind of like washed up you
know or yeah yeah they've not really gained anything and I think that's one
of the biggest tragedies for the change the channel movement is that you saw the
main players of it and I didn't I guess I didn't realize this at the time but I
came at it as from an angle of yeah they did wrong but now that they've you know
like here's here's the various reasons why but maybe this is gonna be a good
lesson for all of us to kind of hold ourselves to a higher standard you know
now that we have the warning signs of abusers in our midst which is kind of
what the whole G Wario thing was as well as the management was maybe we're not
gonna tolerate this stuff anymore maybe we're gonna use this as an inspiration
for our own works and really strive to become something better but in reality I
think it was just another casualty or at least like a me too equivalency
because now now that it's been so far out there's another youtuber called that
the almighty lolly who did a good kind of breakdown of the document and said
well this isn't support there's no evidence for this claim there's no
evidence for this claim this is hearsay there's that this is one person's opinion
this is one person's like for me I had the receipts like everybody saw me get
my knee kicked in you know we when we posted the the the waiver they had a
sign for oh well we're not you if you get injured on site you know you you
know it's not our fault and we're not gonna help you because we have no
insurance and and you know yeah it's very easy to prove that they didn't have
filming permits for this stuff but that's all that you could like but yeah
so the fact that you were there you saw things and spoke to people and you can't
really reproduce that as evidence you know right and that's what I've said to
where it's like I'm putting my integrity on the line because I literally had I
can't prove that I picked up Juario's phone and you know trying to figure out
whose phone it belonged to it's it had a listing for my wife and my slave in it I
can't prove that so I'm going to come out of the woodwork and say well here's
what I've experienced I have nothing to gain from this and only to stand to lose
on this so if you don't believe me that's fine I get it but that was
actually that I had to do it in in my in the video I recorded today where
basically I had to point out that um if you if you go anywhere on the internet
it's just it's a slight side story it's okay if you go anywhere and you look up
the the phrase cultural Marxism okay you find that it's it's considered you know
an alt-right anti-semitic conspiracy theory and it's it's nazism in there
however you know I was in introductory to critical theory first year university
course in 2007 where the professor said that this was cultural Marxism and I had
a positive connotation and that is you will not find that on the Wikipedia
article not anymore you you could find that you know ten years ago in the
computer article not anymore not not not since Jordan Pearson started talking
about it on his on his YouTube channel you know in like 2016 or whatever it was
so you it's one thing that I've that I've been completely unprepared for as
I've gotten older is hat the way that like younger people or even just
uninformed people or misinformed people will come to me and describe to me
historical events that I was present for right with such like insane inaccuracy
like they're just they're so wrong and they're so sure of themselves and I'm
like I was there that's not how that was you know exactly exactly it's yeah yeah
you're right it there's sort of a weird reprogramming of events or just history
itself which is why it's so horrifying that even when it's as simple as
something with like a rolled doll book or dr. Seuss you know they they go back
and they try to change it that is so yeah that's yeah disgusting that's right
out of 1984 now I completely agree um when it comes to the the channel awesome
stuff I mean you know Doug still doing well Lindsay Ellis still seems to be
doing well angry Joe's doing okay really see I thought she quit the internet I
thought yeah she she got a contract with nebula and so she does content on nebula
now but for her yeah I'm glad to hear that yeah because I know the last time I
looked in her she she kind of she made an oopsie in her fans can't cancel there
so yeah well she kind of cultivated that like lefty can wall and base no kidding
you live by social justice you died by social justice so you know but she kind
of she left YouTube but she got a contract with nebula so she makes videos
on nebula now I've never heard of that thing so I don't know that nebula is
it's like a Netflix service where you pay monthly to get access to the videos
but it's for you total okay legal legal makes videos there Lindsay Ellis makes
videos there okay cool there's a bunch of creators that use it but I don't know
any more outside from those two but it is like a pretty decent stable of people
over there okay yeah I'll have to check it out I was yeah if it's well okay good
yeah every Joe is still relevant to and it's in some ways too but you know I
know like um Brad Jones he's he's kind of like yes grown but he hasn't really
shrunk he's just kind of been doing his own thing in his own sphere but like
aside from those four I think everyone has just collapsed like Linkara has a
subs and spoon he still has a subs and like the VGA guys they still have their
subs but no one watches their stuff anymore you know right their viewership
has gone down and I know that you know one of Linkara's and again there's a
youtuber by the name of Kinky Linky I know who Kinky Linky is yep yep yep and
he kind of chronicles some of the stuff but like there was a message that or a
tweet that that Linkara put out where it's like oh my history of the Power
Rangers made like $500 and oh yeah I'm totally not making it and I'm totally
poor ha ha ha ha I'm doing it but like the fact that yeah the Patreon amount is
really not gotten to like it's certainly not keeping up with inflation the
viewership has gone down I know we had to go to a dental college to get his
wisdom teeth out and you don't do that if you have dental coverage and right
you're like you don't show you what is dental college so the dental college is
okay so you go to a dentist to get your wisdom teeth out right you need an
orthodontist yet that right well dental college is just like that where if
you're an aspiring dentist or oral hygienist or or any of that stuff you
go there and you act as sort of like a practice guinea pig for the the learning
students and it's at a reduced cost of course because they're less professional
okay and yeah all right yeah yeah it's the sort of thing you do where if you
don't have dental coverage do stuff like that or if you can't afford the
painkillers afterward you you just take a bunch extra strength Tylenol right
like you can't afford the the Percocet or whatever it is they give you and the
big one for like I know this is a little bit old but like there was a point in
time where he shilled his fans for $7,000 to pay his taxes like a like a
few days before they were due it's like you're not in a good place if you're
doing stuff like that and I'm not saying that to be petty or spiteful
spiteful or vindictive despite everything Linkara does have a great
work ethic you know he does his videos on a very clockwork basis but at this
stage every and you probably know this as well too the youtubers really only
have three to five years of their golden years and then they just sort of are on
decline or they're struggling for relevance I think he should have gotten
off the wagon a while ago and just tried to find either work in the
industry or recommitted himself to more of a day job because at least in a day
job you have paid time off you have health and medical insurance benefits
you have a 401k stuff and you know your your rates are at least competitive to
the market so you're you'll compare pay rates five years ago where they are now
and they are higher because of inflation and because of other economic pressures
you really only get a pay rate if you can get more subscribers more viewers
or more patrons yeah and now easy to do I think that that's kind of true a lot
of youtubers do fall into that trap where they they go through a boom and
then they're now they have a bunch of subs but no one's really tuning in
anymore they're all dead subs and they're wondering like hey I have like a
500,000 sub channel how come I get you know five viewers a stream or how come I
get like a thousand viewers a video however I do think at this point
youtubing as a career has been developed enough that I think we know how to get
out of that trap okay what are your thoughts on it I'm genuinely curious
well you can you can see like you see guys like destiny for example or he like
reinvented himself every few years and that's kind of what kept him going you
know you look at yeah Sargon or red letter media they both decided to turn
like corporate where they started a company they got like a warehouse or
an office and they are they they actually reinvested it didn't just coast
that's how you get out of the trap is if you take you know oh you know a big
payday maybe you get like $5,000 or $10,000 in one month though it's a big
payday you know you don't party it up or you don't like cozy you have you take
that money and maybe you hire somebody maybe you try to expand your business
like there's there's get an editor yeah yeah yeah there's like I'm looking at
this this new crop of streamers who are coming up you know and they're all doing
that now like Chedlogic hired an editor yeah right you got like 500 viewers a
stream but he hired an editor and it's you know it's working out for him um
there's oh man who else who else could I name drop here real quick well yeah no I
agree with you that's that's what separates I think red letter media from
from channel awesome is that they did that they they don't what made red
letter media famous was the most little merciful planker revealer from our
he hasn't done a mr. Plinkett review in years and he's last year he did like the
how little Halloween mini skit but that's about it yeah you're right so so
he's that character is pretty much dead by all intents and purposes but he did
use that theme to create half in the bag to create several movies that they that
they released exactly all this other stuff that they do now a wheel of the
worst now they they've managed to grow it from you know certainly they invested
in their equipment the studios and they they have upped their game but if you
look at the quality of videos that when car is doing it's exactly the same thing
now as it was ten years ago so that's probably I think at some point you have
to stop doing the fight with yourself skits in your living uh-huh right or if
you're if your movie is gonna be you saving the world because what you do is
so important you know I I would love to see maybe not given the original comic
books creation but like if Linkara really did want to break into comics or
get into the industry he should have tried to develop his own comics years
ago and he or he should be doing what I'm doing and you know take either
light bringer or revolution of the mask or some of these other ones that he's
he's done and try to redo them to a more professional degree and see what he can
create he has the audience for it he has the you know he could raise it like I
don't have any doubt that he could hit the targets that I'm aiming for and he'd
probably actually be able to make some money off him too so it's a shame to see
him give up on his own IPs it's a shame to see him you know be this reviewer but
at the same time I do think it's something too smart to be said about
well if you can't create criticize and maybe that's the case if you're right
but that's not to say you can't improve everybody's gonna slam on light bringer
the original one or his his original fantasy novels but but remember that the
original light bringer was made in like what 2007 it's like 15 years ago you as
a writer could have grown by that point how old is he back in 2007 he's probably
gosh he's a few years younger than me so 15 years so probably young 20s or late
teens yeah I know that this point I'm a completely different person from where I
was back then literally and physically and physiologically as well too I might
add so the fact that you can you know if you have some of the the intellectual
humility to try to redo that yeah he was able to successfully raise $60,000 for a
movie why not try to create a comic again if you don't know how to do it
then then do the due diligence do the research treat it like a craft but
you're like you say you're never gonna stagnate and just do the same shtick
anymore it's like yeah I did you hit lightning in a bottle in 2010 but it
ain't 2010 anymore so yeah yeah oh man so actually there was a period of time
where I'd been confusing Linkara with what was his name
Kyle Callahan Oh Kyle Callahan yeah yes was that the
brows held high guy I think so I think so yes I think yeah this is gonna sound
kind of me but there's no real there's no real nice way to say it Linkara's
current girlfriend is that overweight black woman right that's his wife
actually wife now okay yes okay so Kyle has a very similar like looking you know
in shape kind of girlfriend okay and there was yes physique yes there was
actually a controversy I don't know if you remember this with Kyle where and I
thought it was Linkara till I had to like I'd like double-check but it was it
was Kyle um where basically he tweeted out that he hated his life he was
depressed about his relationship and his girlfriend has been forcing him to like
parrot her very progressive politics on his Twitter and on his channel when he
had a channel and that basic because like he had an obligation to make the
world a little bit better with with the platform that he had and that this was
this was one of the main reasons why he basically self-destructed and destroyed
his platform and he hated her for it and these tweets you know she put them out
they didn't really go viral because he doesn't have that reach anymore no one
cares about channel awesome anymore but people noticed and then they were they
were like quickly deleted you know mm-hmm and yet no over time that story
kind of morphed into Linkara but it was actually Kyle well two things first with
Kyle is that the the limited information or interaction I had with him he always
seemed like a very unhappy person I don't I really do have a lot of empathy
for him because having suffered from depression and I'm sure you've been in
your low points as well too you know it sounded as though he had some really bad
situations with some of the people he dated I think you know I don't want to
air any dirty laundry or anything but yeah he seemed like somebody that really
needed to kind of take a step back and re-examine where he was going so it's
not surprising to me that he tweeted that because yeah he was also very much
inundated with social justice when when it was still kind of getting started or
at least when I was noticing it which I guess are two separate things yeah the
other thing though with with so Linkara's wife that deep lore goes down
so okay the when I broke up with with Linkara we kind of or you know we ended
our relationship and I did that she was actually a superfan of his she managed
one of the tumblr accounts for it is this like that like an April von Lon
situation where like you don't don't hate the fans do not date yeah it kind
of is where but she she actually married him he married her I don't know I don't
know the specifics but she went to started going to he she figured out all
the conventions he was going to and started to kind of go to the same ones
that he went so she could kind of insert herself into this and that sounds yeah
yeah I had a mutual friend of mine that worked on a she worked as a person on
Linkara's production for his movie she also managed I think his Twitter she
she was connected with him and she did some work for him she was paid for it
too so but she was starting to warn him about her because she had something of a
double you know a public face and a private face and she was you know very
aggressive towards this this lady who was female and all that and she was
trying to warn him about it but he wouldn't really listen to it and I
remember meeting her for the first time she did like a size you up sort of look
and I thought that was really weird and I'm like and then she got really kind of
like PDA on Linkara and I'm like honey you don't need to worry about that I'm
not here to steal your man I'm not I'm just you know how many how many years
after you'd broken up was this oh gosh probably four or five it was a while I
mean it was beyond it was after my surgery it was it was beyond that point
and you know I thought that was really strange and again I don't want to go
into specifics just made like I should given how nasty he's been to me I feel
as though I probably should drag him through the mud a little bit but I still
think it's not classy to talk about some some stuff but regardless of the fact he
ended up marrying her they live together they do their thing I don't think they
get along well with or her parents approve of that situation I know his
when cars own mother is is she's very pro-trump and I think they don't speak
or on or are on good terms and some of the kinky-linky videos or people that
are kind of associated with that like there used to be a point and I've kind
of noticed this too like there used to be a point in time when we were dating
that he was very much like that he didn't want to be like oh I'm the
Christian kid or anything but he didn't swear willy-nilly he didn't he was
trying to keep it clean right he didn't go on the swearing tangents or whatnot
but that has absolutely changed I think since he got with Vega where he just
goes on these filthy sailor just f you and nasty mean-spirited rants about
people so that that didn't seem like his character back then so I don't know I
I'm not trying to psychoanalyze anybody but one of the reasons I ultimately
decided channel awesome wasn't for me was because people were living in these
egocentric bubbles right you get the feeling like if everybody's telling you
you're great and awesome and amazing you start to think your shit don't stink and
it absolutely does and you should have people that are calling you out for your
nonsense but if you label anybody that calls you out for your nonsense as being
a troll a hater or whatever you're you're you're giving your self an
excuse not to ever have any self-reflection or improve and I think
given his circumstances with his his wife I I get the feeling that there's
probably a lot more of that even worse going on so you know objectivity goes
out the window in that case so but it's a grass like I said the floor goes even
worse well actually I have one question and I'll cut I'll cut this part out if
you don't want it publicly so yeah but this is okay but still I'll cut it out
if you want it if you want to cut it okay no problem what considering that
Linkara's mother was you know very very Christian it sounds like and like you
know voted Trump and all that how did she react to you we don't know or I don't
know because here's what I'll say about Linkara's parents is they never ever
treated me any less than being very kind and equitable and friendly and supportive
and I'm I'm sure that conversation happened at some point and I don't know
when it happened but Avanel was nothing but kind to me and in fact the there was
there was a point in time when we were still kind of starting to date right or
just early in the relationship and his brother got bought a house he and his
wife bought a house and there was you know there's some old they needed some
help with some renovations there's this old disgusting wallpaper and I remember
having like this this like humidifier gun thing that you just sort of ran
against the wall that had a bunch of steam so it would loosen all the glue
and you'd peel it off really kind of gross and disgusting work right so I go
over there and I'm like okay well Linkara is you know doing a little bit
I'm like I'm not just gonna stand around and I'm gonna help you know so I
I go inside of this bedroom and got the the the thing to peel the wallpaper off
the wall and I remember talking to Avanel and she was very very friendly and
sweet to me she was very we talked about you know how I had an investment at the
time that was doing okay despite it being 2009 or whatever it was with the
economy crashed and you know she seemed very supportive now I don't know I don't
want to stick myself in because it's like we we've been not dating for so
such a long time but I get the distinct feeling that she does not approve of
Vega and that ironically she met with she would probably approve of me or did
approve of me back then I don't know but yeah definitively his parents were very
kind to me and I never had any reason like even back then before all this
stuff was mainstream that they didn't treat me like a decent person so okay
funny how that works that was just more for my own curiosity then well see I
would love to like reach out to her and be like hey you know if you want a
Malga hat or your here's your son's IP she might get a kick out of it and you
know I I get the distinct feeling even to this day we the two of us would be
able to sit down and have a great conversation and have a good laugh and
you know there'd be no problems there I don't I don't think at all so hmm yeah
great question though that's the first time anybody's asked me that do you want
me to leave that in okay okay okay that's kind of well it's kind of a
personal question it's up to you I don't care that much yeah well I mean you see
I've gotten more questions where it's like oh so how many times and Linkara go
down on you it's like I'm not it's saying any of that no but yeah it does
make me wonder about what that dynamic looks like but who knows yeah I'm sure
I'm sure as hell not gonna reach out so so yeah you are doing because late
bringer one was successful you're now doing light bringer two that's right so
so I'm not sure when this will get out but we are kind of on the last legs of
the campaign where we've we're about 70 as of this call where it's six or 78
percent there so last period last time we had around five thousand or so that
we were asking and if that's what we were asking for we would hit it but
because our costs went way up this year we were asking for 6700 so we're still
under that we've got about a week left to go so any sort of if anybody's
interested in this you know please please help us out if you if you if you
miss the first one we do have a digital catch-up for it we do have a limited run
of the first book and you can get the second book it with it or if you really
want to help us out you can back it with some some artwork or the the searing
light of justice tear which will have everything that we're offering in the
campaign with it so yeah no it's it's the campaign ends on the 12th right yeah
or it's six days from now so it's on the 11th on the 11th okay yeah yep since
next Tuesday from here right yeah this is coming out on Friday so okay yeah so
you have the weekend basically in like the Monday to to get in on this if you
want to so we'll see what happens I mean typically near the end of it we'll get
you know some last-minute people we might have a few more streams we can go
on to you know I think if we do get out where it's gonna be down to the wire so
so here's hoping knock on wood that we can because we've we've really upped the
game with this one we the art has gone up a significant notch we have a
different artist this time because the original artist had his own campaign
that he did and he got too busy so we had to pick up Dean James and Dean isn't
he's incredible so you know you can see some of the example pages that we've got
and yeah yeah so how we can absolutely get this going I'd love to see it be
realized so how how does it actually work like if you don't hit your 6700 do
you lose all the money or like what's the actual yeah it more or less gets
refunded back so they have they have two options right so they have it where
and this is where your reputation has to be sterling with it where you have two
options where if you don't hit your goal everything gets refunded in the washes
you have the second option where even if you don't get your goal you kind of keep
what you were able to raise the downside though is that that option has been sort
of abused by enough people where people are kind of sketchy if you are wary to
back that just because a lot of people or at least enough in the past took the
money and ran and never produced anything right so you know the last
thing I want to ever do is take people's money and then not produce anything
about anything I put my name on I want to have to be the highest level that I
can manage with it so I'm not sure we'll have to talk I'll have to talk with
Anthony my producer about it where maybe we can try to see if we can figure it
out a way to still do it or have it go to fulfillment or or what needs to be
done to we're very close we're less than 1,500 there so it's still within the
realm of possibility that we can get it through so all right well but yeah I
appreciate you taking the time and allowing me to shill my shit on your
street videos of course of course I mean I've listen I've as you know when I was
that when I was a youngster I really enjoyed the the channel awesome ecosystem
yeah and and now that I'm like it's it's never gonna be not strange that I'm
bigger than some of my heroes when I was younger you know it's always gonna be a
weird feeling so yeah and you never know I maybe one day I can get back up on
that horse I do have other projects I'm working on you know part of the part of
the the homework I put for myself was to up my writing style or my skill in it so
I started I've been working on some TV TV pilot episodes I've a friend of mine
and I are working on a movie script too so you know I'm not saying it'll amount
to anything but I am trying to still chase that skill set so that what if and
when opportunity strikes I'll be ready so yeah and you know you could always
just play you could always just play your identity go to Hollywood you're
trans you'll get right in there I mean yeah it's it's about who you know so
yeah yeah it is nice to be to refer to myself though is like an established
writer though I were you we were an author I got like bringer one out there
and I see this thing as a as a 24 issue arc or season like this whole thing that
I have in my mind definitely this first story is gonna be a three-parter so we I
come hell or high water even if we can't get it done and it turns into a
vanity project I still want to do it because the last one of my personal
failings in the channel awesome day was that I would start things and not finish
them so even if it cost me money even if I don't make any money off of it I still
believe enough in light bringer just to want to see it shine so yeah yeah I know
exactly you know I mm-hmm I've man when I was you know in high school I was like
programming video games always wanted to make my own games ended up you know
that got swept away just by life because like I went through so many just other
phases of what I was doing but man if I could get to like a million subs on
YouTube who knows if I don't happen but if it did I would definitely reroute
some of that some of that income into like making a game I would love to
actually make a video game you know absolutely that'd be the dream well
but uh you know V is V yeah yeah the Romanian guy V yeah yeah yeah oh he is
yeah yeah yeah well he's that he's now making a game oh good for him yeah he's
he's managed to pull it off and I'm like damn you're doing what I've always
wanted to do yeah I mean if I had to choose anything that I would love to do
that would be like a passion project it would be to do a battle tech TV show TV
show and I have two these are the projects or several of them that I would
be that I've been working on and the first one would be like set in the
fourth secession war and all that stuff and the second one would be set in the
periphery following a mercenary company and you could set it up as like a you'd
pitch it as a Game of Thrones but in space so all the fun jazz that you can
do with that you can have action if you wanted it you could have intrigue if you
wanted it you could there's so many things you can do with it but that would
that would be my rolling you know a lucky seven or just rolling a natural 20
how about that analogy if I could do that I would die a happy person so well
okay I think we might have run out of topics to a talk about and also I only
have 15 more minutes before I have to go yeah well here's the thing well here's
something that's interesting here I'll go back to more channel awesome one last
time to the channel awesome well of course because no offense to Brad Jones
I love his stuff but he's he's kind of stagnated a bit I've decided to try to
do the midnight screening format okay well you know you hop into a van or you
hop into a car and yeah you go talk about it yeah yeah and you're and you
know I've done it a few times now and it's actually kind of it's very um not
spooky here you know the liminal space is bought it's very liminal yes all
right okay okay cuz you're sitting in a car in the middle of an empty parking
lot everyone is gone the city is just dead quiet and you're talking about a
movie at 3 a.m. you know it's a very strange it's very fun I know what you're
talking about yeah yeah that was one of the downsides of working the the
reviewer stuff that we did where you know when Cara would shoot shows at like
1 in the morning and then we'd go out for grocery shopping at 3 and it's like
yeah everybody's asleep right it's this weird yeah that made me wonder about
that that idea always sort of stuck with me if you were a vampire right where
you'd see all these stores that you would never be able to go into because
they're closed when you're active so yeah it is a weird liminal feeling it's
a very surreal experience it lets the mind wander so yeah I like that kind of
insomnia horror where it's stuff like that that actually reminds me of
something uh okay so it's the as I mentioned at the start of this what I
started with was anime reviews it was me and two friends running around with a
camera we were we were young and stupid and we wanted to join channel awesome
and never did wait I did tell you the story where I got accepted and then
rejected them right yes yes yeah that was like in 2014 or something that was
just for fun but um so 2009 we're we're being dumb we're making anime reviews
um however two out of the three of us were only back in my hometown for for
one summer right okay had to so we had to like write all the scripts and shoot
all of the live-action parts of the episodes over the course of the summer
and then we would like edit them over the year right so yeah yeah shot like a
whole bunch of episodes we had it all planned out it was very it was very
ambitious for our very first project doing this together yeah but we did it
and we got to the point where we had released so we shot everything in that
summer and then we started releasing it in the fall in the winter and the spring
it was very strange shooting the Christmas episode in like July because
we were just sweltering but we had you're like you're like pretending to be
cold like wearing robes and like shivering looking out a window and we
cut we would cut in like snow later but like it was so hot but the final episode
of the season we realized we didn't have some of the shots that we needed oh crap
so and and at this point the third person had moved away he had moved out
of his parents house we shot the show because two of us were coming to town
for seasonal work and the third guy lived there and he was still he was
still he was still living with it with his um his um his parents right yeah
yeah he hadn't gone to school yet but basically what was going on was his
parents because they they have a boat so they would go Friday to Sunday every
weekend they'd go on the boat and they'd you know boat around the Great Lakes
because they yep that was nothing um yeah so he always had he hadn't he had
so much time alone so we would like every weekend we would redecorate his
his living room to be the set of the show and then we put it back but before
his parents got home because his parents did not approve they really didn't
approve um okay it was really fun sneak around it was probably not very good but
it was fun um yeah but it's part of the experience it is yeah it is I'm sure
like to do I'm sure if you know you probably have some gorilla filmmaking
experiences that are kind of like this oh yeah yeah yes so we got to a point
where we were putting out the final episode and we realized we just we were
missing some key shots like it just wouldn't work and at this point he had
moved away so we decided to go back to our home to his hometown and break into
his parents house I was just about to say yeah break in yes we did we knew
where the hidden key was we broke in we like oh my god we we set that we set
everything up we shot the shots that we needed we filmed from like 1 a.m. to
like 5 a.m. because we just didn't want anyone to see us coming in they're
really nosy neighbors the whole thing so broken we uh when we left we like took
all of our garbage with us we didn't leave a single trace of anything we put
everything back exactly and then we went back to like my parents house so oh god
that's a fantastic story yeah and then he didn't tell his parents for like like
I think seven or eight years that we had done that you broke into your that's
great yeah it was fun do when you're following what you want to do yeah and I
think anyone who's done any sort of like small project gorilla filmmaking knows
exactly the kind of feeling I'm talking about exactly that was that was filming
to boldly or suburban nights where you know they don't have permits to any of
this we're walking around in the in the park and all that you know it it's just
okay that's what you have to do running across the the goose shit-covered fields
and yeah it's like alright hope that no one like calls the cops and you or hope
no one shows up to tell you to move on exactly exactly did that ever happen to
just did he ever get like you ever get in trouble doing that did anyone ever
show no no the police are well the police in Chicago I'm sure have better
things to do but that's you know there were several times though where it's
like okay we have to stop what we're doing because there are people going
through right and it's one of the criticisms of dog is like oh there was a
random people that walked by and he was trying to give them like no no don't do
that walk through like this I'm giving you stage no from my experience on that
on that shoot we were filming in a couple parks around I think it was
around Easter so a lot of people were out and about and it was super wet and
soggy because you know the reason we were on such a tight film schedules
because we got rained out for a couple days so it is that sort of thing where
you know art through adversity a little bit which is where people were feeling
with that shoot but the next one not so much but yeah we never got we never got
thrown out for anything but I think that we did hop the chain fence to get inside
of one of the parks early in the morning before it opened so yeah yeah um hey
that was just a strange side what I actually wanted to bring up is that I've
decided to start doing um the midnight screenings because I wanted to
experience what it was like and that was always that was always like the show
that I really tuned in for Brad Jones was that was minutes I loved the
screenings even more than cinema snob um and actually I'm going to do that in
about 15 minutes with my girlfriend and some friends of mine because we're
watching the Mario movie tonight so oh well watch you I'll watch you what you
have to say oh well it's opening it's already open so but we're going to like
the latest possible show so you can try to get that same feel so that that's why
I only had like an hour and a half to do this but okay no trouble well I'll let
you get going but yeah thanks again it's good to catch up yeah it's always it's
always good it's always good for it's always good talking to you and yeah what
light bringer to light bringer to electric boo no it's like but yeah
please check it out and I appreciate it all right my friends that was my talk
with iron Liz make sure to go check out and support light bringer volume to link
in the description also that Super Mario Brothers movie midnight screening you
want to watch that click the card on screen right now go check it out on the
side channel the dev kit I will see you over there have a good one I love you