Before I get started guys, I want to point out that yes I have been demonetized, no I
have not been told why, I don't know what video did it, I don't know what part of what
video did it, they simply said hate speech and I don't know anything, I've been told
nothing by YouTube and frankly I might be financially fucked if this sticks.
So please consider checking the description of this video because I've put links to support
the channel down there, they're also on screen too so if you want to financially support
what I'm doing, thank you very much.
Again even in a time like this please don't feel obligated, I know people are out of jobs,
I know people are getting sick, I know things are generally on a downturn for everyone,
before you give me anything make sure you take care of yourself okay?
By the way yesterday's video got a lot of people angry and I mean fair enough, but like
I've said I've always been neutral on Trump, I will give him the benefit of the doubt but
I will give anybody the benefit of the doubt, nobody's perfect.
If you're subbed to this channel for unapologetic god emperor simping, you're in the wrong place
unfortunately.
That being said the main reason that I released it the time that I did is because basically
I had recorded it before my demonetization and frankly guys that kind of hit me pretty
hard I mean like motivationally you know?
I definitely just took some time off and you know it is actually a little bit harder to
get the gumption to do this sort of thing when you know that YouTube's still running
ads on your videos and just taking 100% of the revenue, but I took a couple days off
and I said you know I've got to do something I guess, I mean I have some kind of appeals
process working so hopefully it'll work out but in the meantime I've got to do something
right?
So I took this video that I had recorded you know a day or two earlier and I finally finished
the editing and put it out.
Of course bad timing because at the same time Donald Trump tested positive as well as his
wife for coronavirus.
We will begin our quarantine and recovery process immediately we will get through this
together holy shit dude.
Stock futures sharply fall after President Donald Trump tweets that he has tested positive
for coronavirus.
Now this happened shortly after the debates and everyone was thinking oh no does Joe Biden
have coronavirus?
But it turns out that Joe Biden says or rather the person who runs his Twitter account because
we all know he doesn't actually use his own Twitter they say I'm happy to report that
Jill and I have tested negative for COVID.
Thank you to everyone for your messages of concern I hope this serves as a reminder wear
a mask keep social distance and wash your hands unless you're going to a protest.
Of course not everyone is civil here's Ilhan Omar as someone who lost my own father to
this virus and seeing the pain it causes I don't wish on anyone.
Over 200,000 people have now died while this administration actively ignores public health
guidance and suppresses science.
For months we have been hoping for a simple acknowledgement from the president to hear
the words we will get through this together and now we only hear those words when it is
about him not the hundreds of thousands of people who have lost their lives and the millions
whose families have been touched by it because of his malfeasance.
You know considering that you are a representative in the House you should understand that the
presidency the office of the presidency does not have the power to do the things you're
asking of it.
It's in the 10th amendment the states have to handle this the state governors the state
governments the president of the United States and Republicans in Minnesota are actively
spreading a deadly virus they are a risk to the public health of my constituents and our
country Republicans are the ones that are spreading the virus around not the protesters
and yes we're going to be going back to that protester well quite a bit because there's
going to be some serious problems here Republicans asking for decorum and empathy like they didn't
wish violence on protesters lmao also he's a white supremacist running a fascist government
and 209,000 people have died due to his mismanagement and peddling that it's a hoax I have zero
sympathy for these assholes it's pretty amazing you can you can tell who the people are that
don't actually get their news from multiple sources they get it from one ideological source
or they just filter what they get through that ideological framework because you get
nonsense like this I know I'm not a Republican but I don't wish violence on protesters I
don't even wish violence on rioters I would rather the riot not happen I would rather
the riot stop before violence self-defensive violence becomes necessary but having the
fortitude to use violence to defend yourself does not mean that you wish for violence and
frankly these idiots don't know what fascism is like I recall the right calling Obama a
fascist back when the Democrats kept winning this happens all the fucking time it happens
every single every single election cycle every single time there's been like a presidential
shift the op the opposition is like all those guys are fashy taking away our rights and
it's like no no I mean Obama did some some terrible stuff obviously but no no one's a
fascist dude so just a quick question on a scale of one to ten is this your favorite
or most favorite October surprise in the history of electoral politics for me personally
I think it ranks pretty high up there but you know love to hear your thoughts but of
course we know it's not about civility to these people they think civility is white
supremacy or something it's entirely about power that is the point of the Marxist lens
is to frame everything in terms of power politics well more specifically class conflict but
that just boils down to power politics in reality for example a certain mold of liberal
sees the right as a jousting partner to have eternal sparring matches with in the effervescent
marketplace of ideas rather than a class enemy to be defeated by any means necessary and
most efficiently this explains a lot of their behavior this is because liberals understand
that their political opponents are generally not evil like sometimes you get the occasional
evil person but most of the time the real functional answer to any given problem is
somewhere between the liberal and conservative positions additionally most socialists and
most fascists probably aren't bad people either they're just horribly misguided but when everything
is class conflict when it all boils down to power politics when all war is a war over
material conditions this is the kind of brain-dead attitude that you get the reason that you
have eternal sparring matches within the marketplace of ideas is because none of us none of us
including the socialists know what the right answer is have no idea what the right answer
is some people think that they do some people think that they can take any topic but pick
up a pick a topic doesn't matter filter it through the Marxist lens and out comes a pre-packaged
proper answer for it but of course in reality that almost never actually works you find
the truth not by following a dogma but by taking every single fact you can and clashing
them against each other until what remains is a pure product the truth that is what the
marketplace of ideas is and that is why you need those eternal sparring matches to simply
view those who oppose you as your eternal enemy even in those cases where they're factually
correct means that you're not interested in truth you're interested in power and of course
this squirrel person here is kind of a known socialist on Twitter and they post their own
take along with some other takes from neo libs who are wishing Trump a speedy recovery
and the message is clear civility compromise coming to at the very least a reasonable understanding
if you don't always agree making up becoming friends again these things are the antithesis
of the idea that everything is power politics Trump went to Bedminster and exposed staff
and fundraiser attendees when he already knew he had COVID when he was already symptomatic
and receiving treatment dude this this isn't true man like we're gonna go over some articles
and some sources a little bit later but yeah this isn't true you don't need to all caps
a bunch of false shit and then make that go viral because people are just literally looking
for anything that they can grab onto at this point and seriously this is on both sides
like here's what Greg Gutfield said on Fox News to the point about the script being flipped
the reason why it flipped and maybe it's a flaw of Trump is that he didn't hide from
the virus the reason he didn't hide from the virus is that he didn't want America to hide
from the virus if he was going to ask America to get back to work and experience a risk he was
going to do the same thing so I think he put himself on the line and that the flaw being that
as an optimist as somebody who was trying to convey a message that we are going to get through
this and things are gonna be better he had to walk that walk and he had to do that you could
have scared the crap out of everybody but he refused and it goes back to his original point
about trying to make sure that the positive attitude is maintained along with a sense of
concern so he took the risk he got the virus but he was doing it for us this is some mega
cope dude come on like I definitely don't believe with the leftist point of view of shut down
everything forever this is the new normal if you don't wear the mask at all times even when you're
sleeping or having sex then you want grandma to die but at the same time I think this Trump got
sick for us kind of idea is is a bit stupid sometimes you get sick it's just how it is
sometimes you take precautions and get sick anyway and sometimes you don't take precautions
and you're fine the virus is not a entirely controllable variable here and it is a product
of our own arrogance to think that we can manage this any more than we have frankly and of course
we do have the mirror universe gaslighting from you know the usual sources this one's from the
Washington Post but they're all very similar after Trump's positive test conservative media
goes after liberal critics real and imagined you know if that happened I haven't really seen it
what I have seen is a lot of people who are saying lol I can't wait for Trump to die they're writing
their weird Trump fan fictions about how hopefully he's rotting away at the hospital and he's like on
life support for like the next 50 years or something and how RBG comes back from the dead
to go to the Supreme Court and then give the election to Biden or some nonsense like this it
is kind of crazy the the level of conspiracy theory I've seen online I wonder if we'll approach
QAnon levels maybe if Trump's in the hospital for a while like check this fucking clown I don't want
to be alarmist but a GOP source just told me this Trump's condition is serious he can go either way
despite all the meds and the presidential care they could lose him within three to four days
they're trying to make his condition look good to reassure his base I have no way to confirm this
report but I felt like I should pass it along of course you did you dude you're literally on team
Joe like look at this yeah hashtag team Joe formerly chair of the Democrat coalition national
finance chair for draft Biden 2016 Long Island campaign chair for Barack Obama do you think you
are a reasonable unbiased source of information this is literal do to trust me bro levels of
sourcing pretty sure Trump boarded marine one with a portable oxygen concentrator in his pocket
with the nasal cannula was it can I don't know that is cannula going up his back hidden in his
hair and tucked under his mask he is not as well as they say liar-in-chief look at this dude look
at this fucking tweet like that this is just Trump being fat all right this is just Trump
being fat this is literally just a piece of hair you guys need to calm the fuck down man this is
not like a nothing tweet like this took off but yeah apparently he was feeling bad enough that
he had to go to the hospital so he hopped on marine one and went out there and the media
wasn't happy about it here's CNN's chief White House correspondent Trump did not stop for questions
dude he's got fucking coronavirus he's going to the hospital fuck you this is from the physician
to the president this afternoon in consultation with specialists from Walter Reed and John
Hopkins University I recommended movement of the president up to Walter Reed National Military
Medical Center for further monitoring this evening I'm happy to report the president is doing very
well he is not requiring any supplemental oxygen but in consultation with specialists we have
elected to initiate remdesivir therapy which I assume is some kind of therapy they've developed
for coronavirus he has completed his first dose and is resting at comfortably yeah back in June
remdesivir was being reported on as potentially a treatment for coronavirus it's normally an
Ebola medication so all right okay of course at the same time we were also getting this video so
geez who knows dude uh Jim you were there when the president walked out of the White House and
Border Marine one yeah I know you have some new reporting on his condition yeah Anderson I talked
to a Trump campaign advisor just a short while ago who said that this is serious that the
president has been having some trouble breathing that he's been very fatigued today very tired and
you know emphasized that you know this is not just a run-of-the-mill trip up to Walter Reed
that this is a serious situation talked to another source familiar with this situation this evening
who said that there are serious concerns among White House staffers about the president's
condition as a recording this is the most recent update on Trump's status which I mean there's so
much floating around right now from both sides people wanting him dead people like thinking
there's a conspiracy people saying that he's doomed people saying that he deserves it people
saying that he's he's on his deathbed and the government's hiding it people saying that he's
actually just fine like everything is being said right now but this clip is the most recent
concrete word that we have I recommended we bring the president up to Walter Reed as a
precautionary measure to provide state-of-the-art monitoring and any care that he may need just 72
hours into the diagnosis now the first week of kovat in a particular day 7 to 10 of the most
critical and determining the likely course of this illness at this time the team and I are extremely
happy with the progress the president has made Thursday he had a mild cough and some nasal
congestion and fatigue all of which are now resolving and improving nevermind while I was
editing this video this came out this is in fact the newest bit of information that we have from
Trump himself take a look I want to begin by thanking all of the incredible medical professionals
the doctors the nurses everybody at Walter Reed Medical Center I think it's the finest in the
world for the incredible job they've been doing I came here wasn't feeling so well I feel much
better now we're working hard to get me all the way back I have to be back because we still have
to make America great again we've done an awfully good job of that but we still have steps to go and
we have to finish that job and I'll be back I think I'll be back soon and I look forward to
finishing up the campaign the way it was started and the way we've been doing the kind of numbers
that we've been doing we've been so proud of it but this was something that happened and it's
happened to millions of people all over the world and I'm fighting for them not just in the US I'm
fighting for them all over the world we're gonna beat this coronavirus or whatever you want to call
it and we're gonna beat it soundly so many things have happened if you look at the therapeutics
which I'm taking right now some of them and others are coming out soon that are looking like frankly
they're miracles if you want to know the truth they're miracles people criticize me when I say
that but we have things happening that look like they're miracles coming down from God man he's
quite fatigued isn't he like I know that he's trying to hide it but his voice is a little bit
gravelier than usual he's slouched over in front of a table he's not standing up he's got like he's
not wearing a tie probably because of the fever I think he's trying to put on a brave face but I
actually do think he's quite sick damn so there we go I mean it's not unlike the situation when
Boris Johnson got coronavirus in the UK people treated him like shit too there was there was
tons of stuff going around on Twitter about it from the so-called more compassionate side of
politics that apparently cares a lot about everyone's health and well-being when it comes
to their political opponents they just don't give a shit I recall seeing nobody except the most vile
people on the right dancing on RBG's grave and yet it seems to be every single leftist like every
single leftist with a few only a few exceptions that are like I hope Trump dies dude hashtag
kovat caught Trump it's honestly disgusting it reminds me of the way that the old right
behaved during the Obama era when they wanted Obama dead however what people are focusing on
are Trump's behaviors leading up to his getting tested Trump kept his regular schedule after
learning his close aid Hope Hicks had kovat US President Donald Trump learned on Thursday
morning that his aid Hope Hicks tested positive for coronavirus yet continued on with a full
schedule of events including a fundraiser at his New Jersey resort that raised five million dollars
Trump's movements are being closely scrutinized since he later tested positive for coronavirus
announcing the news shortly before 1 a.m. Friday Washington time the White House has not said when
Trump first tested positive for the virus but Trump said on late Thursday he was awaiting the
results in between learning the news of Hicks's infection Thursday morning and announcing his
own early Friday Trump stuck to his prepared schedule it is not known whether Trump was
tested Thursday morning after receiving the news of Hicks's positive test as soon as he found out
he was tested and as soon as he tested positive he went into quarantine said Larry Kudlow his
director of the National Economic Council I can't give you the chronology because I wasn't there on
Thursday Trump had no publicly scheduled events that morning after a late-night return from a
rally in Minnesota a trip that Hicks also attended she was separated from the rest of the White House
staff on Air Force One on the trip home Wednesday night after falling ill the press secretary
Kayleigh McKinney held a briefing shortly before noon on Thursday taking the podium without a mask
at that time she did not know Hicks had tested positive Trump left the White House at 1 p.m.
Thursday not stopping to speak to reporters before boarding his helicopter he flew on Air Force One
to New Jersey and then by helicopter into his Bedminster golf club before a fundraiser and this
seems to be the point of contention did Trump know that his aide Hope Hicks had been diagnosed by 1
p.m. on Thursday that's still something we don't really know the answer to just yet but what we do
know is that people online are losing their minds they're saying that Hope Hicks was a plant to try
to get the the president killed they're saying that Trump knew like two or three days ago he
just didn't care and he was going around speaking to everybody some people are saying Trump knew
before the debate like before you and Hope Hicks got it like crazy stuff right and none of this
has any proof from from either side it's all just literally people losing their minds and now they're
calling all of Trump's events like super spreader events and and stuff like this and it's like come
on you guys have been promoting these fucking riots where there's thousands of people out in
the streets throwing molotovs burning buildings down attacking people shooting people but anyway
like I always say we have to behave better than our opponents there is no reason to celebrate when
anyone gets coronavirus I would not be happy if Joe Biden caught it I would not be happy if Bernie
Sanders caught it and I'm not happy that Trump caught it I don't want my political opponents to
simply die but right now that is the attitude of a lot of people on the left and like I said
there's no surprise that attitude has manifested in street violence that has taken lives because
the honest truth is if you are at the point where you simply want your political opponents to die
there is no compromise with them there is no back and forth as lay socialist squirrels said there's
no marketplace of ideas it's all it all just boils down to class conflict eternal power struggle no
reasoning no coming together just fight until one side is completely extinguished if that is where
the left is right now then the only reason they haven't started a civil war yet is because they
are complete cowards and they know they would lose it is one thing to have a political opponent you
can debate with that you can compromise with that has a legitimate point of view that you can at
least understand if not agree with it's another thing entirely to have a political opponent that
simply wants you dead whether that's for racial reasons or class reasons or political reasons
doesn't matter if their baseline of politics truly is convert or die and they're too inept to
actually convert people and too cowardly to actually enforce the die part then they're
honestly just a bunch of fucking losers aren't they anyway let's hope Trump gets well let's
hope any leftist who catches the virus also gets well and let's please bring politics back to a
sensible location where we're not cheering for random chance to potentially kill those
that we disagree with please can we get back to that