Have you ever noticed how people who are particularly ignorant of the internet call 4chan or Newgrounds
a social media platform?
I've heard this from boomers who still think that TV is a new technology.
They have no idea what the internet is, and they're just using the terms they hear their
grandkids saying.
But I've also heard it from zoomers who only consume online content through whatever
apps come preloaded on their smartphone.
To them, the entire internet is literally just whatever is in front of the curtain.
I guess as a millennial, I got lucky.
My youngest years were in an era before the internet, and I still got a taste of that
it's summer, go outside with your friends and be home by dinnertime experience.
But when I finally did make my way online, it was amazingly decentralized.
Each community had its own website, its own form, its own type of service, when nowadays
they're all on Twitter or YouTube or whatever.
You can definitely see different species of sites emerge as time went on.
We call Twitter a social media platform, but what it really is, is a microblogging service.
A place where you can post short length random thoughts in a timeline structure.
Facebook operates this way too, same with Gab, Parler, Getter, and Truth Social.
They're all microbloggers.
To contrast, YouTube and TikTok, though they're also considered social media, they're not
microbloggers.
4chan's an image board, like 2chan and 7chan and 420chan and all the other chans that have
popped in and out of existence.
And hey, just as a side note, do you remember that one 4chan April Fools prank where Moot
added a cross post to Facebook option and a bunch of retards thinking it was a troll,
ended up putting porn and shit all over their normie Facebooks for their parents to see?
Ah, that was good times.
Point is, the phrase social media seems to have morphed into a Gen Z term for what we
used to call a website when there's actually multiple different types of sites.
From forms to blogs to video platforms.
The streamer Destiny's website, destiny.gg or DGG, was kind of hard to quantify using
this paradigm, at least for me.
Here was my thought process on it.
It's certainly a repository of his stream and YouTube content, but it also serves partially
as his blog, his merch store, and even his forums.
And it's got a particular, slick feeling that makes it stand out beyond other portals,
like Channel Awesome or Newgrounds.
Also, as somebody who's not really a part of the Twitch politics side of the internet,
when I first noticed that Vosh's website, VGG, was basically a carbon copy of Destiny's,
I figured that this was some sort of shared plugin system or drop and run setup that was
common among this community.
I don't know, is it called a GG site, is that what we're talking about here?
That's when I discovered what I thought was the source of these sites.
A service called White Leaf or White Forest, run by a person named White Nervosa.
Turns out, White Leaf is the type of website, White Forest is the company providing it,
and White Nervosa is the person.
White Forest is legally a worker co-op, with nine members, one member, one vote.
They operate White Leaf sites, as well as doing merch fulfillment, thanks to the financial
support of Vosh.
Their stated goal is to provide an accessible and independent platform for content creators.
And they do have an extensive list of reasonably high-profile leftist people they host.
The ones that I recognize personally are Vosh, Shuonhead, Kefls, Chrisraygun, The Surfs,
Dylan Burns, Konur, who is some femboy in Vosh's Polycule, Merrick, Xanderhal, The
Deer Girl, Demon Mama, and Counterpoints, who's actually a Burkean conservative, not
a leftist.
Which initially made me think this service might have been apolitical, just used primarily
by leftists.
But of course, that's actually not the case.
Although the White Forest company is kept afloat by patrons, it's also directly funded
by Vosh.
The fine print reads, no White Leaf users are necessarily affiliated with or endorsed
by White Nervosa or other members of White Forest.
The only content creators that pay White Forest are Vosh or those who choose to be a patron.
And then I noticed another interesting tidbit down there.
Website framework is a derivative work from DGG, Creative Commons Attribution, Share Like
3.0.
That's right!
DGG is not on the list of White Leaf sites.
DGG isn't a White Leaf site, all the White Leaf sites are ripoffs of DGG.
There's a fella in Destiny's community named Cake.
He does a lot of the tech work over there.
I've had a couple of casual conversations with him, nice guy, seems competent.
He put out a history of DGG to set the record straight.
The code behind DGG was open source and available for anyone to use, because Destiny wanted
other content creators to have something they could use for themselves to help bootstrap
their own careers.
In early 2019, White Nervosa took the DGG code and made a variant of it for Vosh, VGG,
which eventually became the White Leaf template.
There was actually early drama between Cake and White Nervosa, as Cake provided his assistants
believing his work was going towards White Nervosa's own site, not Vosh's site, or
to create a service for many other creators.
As somebody relatively new to this section of the internet, this stunned me.
How the hell was it that all of these people who hate Destiny have the gall to blatantly
rip off his site code, even going so far as to say Destiny's got nothing to do with
it?
Alright, here's where I would have subbed in that viral clip of Kefl's from last summer,
streaming during the opening of her own White Leaf site, KGG, where she made the claim that
her site was actually not ripped off from Destiny's and he had nothing to do with
it.
I remember seeing that clip all over the place back then.
It must have been retweeted back onto my timeline at least a few dozen times, but by January
2023, it seems to have vanished from the internet.
Ah well, I'm sure you all remember it.
It feels kind of like people trying to say that JK Rowling isn't the real creator of
Harry Potter now that her TERF views have come to light, or the Five Nights at Freddy's
guy doesn't count as the creator after it came out he was pro-life.
It's not hard to see how we got to this point.
I've done a lot of videos on this topic before.
Mindless consequentialism, truth is downstream from power, just make reality whatever serves
the politics, you know the story at this point.
Because of the volatility between Destiny and, like, all of the people using White Leaf
sites, this was obviously going to blow up eventually.
And it did, with the deplatforming of Rose Wriste.
Rose Wriste is some young Shoda kid who used to be a streamer.
I think he gave it up to go to school or something.
He's very progressive, very much a Nordic model kind of guy, but he is not a revolutionary
socialist.
During the Trump era, he and many others like him sided with the socialists online.
But post-Trump, Rose Wriste is another casualty on a long list of casualties from the internet's
socialist-slash-social-liberal split.
Rose Wriste helped Destiny with his huge manifesto on Kefls.
As far as I know, not in terms of digging up information, but in terms of grammar and
spell-checking, and also working over his logical inferences.
In other words, not on content, but on presentation and polish.
In response, Rose Wriste's White Leaf site, roserist.com, I think it was, was made to
redirect to the Drop Kiwi Farms site that Kefls put up.
Here's the DMs between Rose Wriste and White Nervosa.
Did you change my website?
White Forest has voted, worker co-op, remember, to discontinue servers to your site.
I wish you the best of luck.
Okay, I understand.
Can you then fully detach all your stuff from my purchased domain so that it's just a dead
link?
You own the domain.
I know that I'm not particularly adept when it comes to website stuff.
I could probably figure out how to disconnect it myself, but I just wanted to ask.
Cake charges $3,000 and then $150 a month for the services you were given.
You cannot ask me for help, no.
Okay, so to be clear, you won't even detach the stuff you've attached to my domain after
you decided to drop it?
To be clear, it is your domain.
If you don't understand that I can't detach it from my servers, that's not my problem.
Sure, but you're doing something to redirect it to Drop Kiwi Farms, right?
Good luck.
Thanks for all your help over the past two years.
I appreciate it.
Your words ring hollow, but I hope you grow to understand my position.
Here's the tech explanation of what's going on.
When you put in a website into your browser, Google.com for example, your computer communicates
with a domain name registrar.
Google owns the domain name Google.com, and the registrar links that domain with an IP
address, in this case 142.251.42.100.
If you were to type that set of numbers into your browser, you'd go to the Google homepage.
And believe it or not, in the very early internet, there was no domain names, only IP addresses.
You had to memorize which addresses led to which sites, like telephone numbers without
profiles attached.
So, the IP address is the number of a physical computer somewhere on the internet that hosts
the website.
And the domain name is a shorthand for that address, registered with the registrar.
Rose Wriste owns the domain name RoseWriste.com, and he asked his registrar to have it point
to the IP address of his White Leaf site hosted by White Forest.
But what White Nervosa did was have the IP address on White Forest's end redirect to
the Kefl's Drop Kiwi Farms page.
All Rose Wriste had to do to remedy the situation was to log in to his registrar and have it
point at a different IP.
But Rose Wriste, not being very tech-savvy, didn't know any of this.
Something that White Nervosa knew he was ignorant of.
That's why the only reply given when Rose Wriste asked, you're doing something to
redirect it to Drop Kiwi Farms, right, was, good luck.
No admission of guilt or innocence, no confirm or denial, just have fun figuring it out,
fuck you.
I should point out that Rose Wriste, like every other creator with White Forest, with
the exception of Vosh, didn't pay for a White Leaf site.
And White Nervosa retains the right to stop working with anyone at any time.
Nothing illegal has been done here, but it's certainly pretty scummy behavior, taking advantage
of Rose Wriste's ignorance on tech topics.
And eventually, Rose Wriste released a detailed manifesto describing his experience working
with White Forest, where it became clear that this wasn't the only scummy thing White
Nervosa had done.
Here is a list of 9 complaints Rose Wriste had regarding his time affiliated with White
Forest.
1.
He was not given an opportunity to make his case when White Forest voted to discontinue
2.
He was not even given notice that such a vote was happening
3.
He was not even given notice that services to his website had stopped and only found
out several days later 4.
He did not consent to White Forest and White Nervosa changing the server connected to his
domain to make it redirect to a website that they knew he was opposed to
5.
He was not given notice that this redirection was happening
6.
He was treated rudely by White Nervosa when he inquired into the changes
7.
He was publicly ridiculed for this interaction by White Nervosa
8.
He did not receive any follow-up regarding the handling of sensitive connections or information
of his or of the users who used his website 9.
He did not receive any assistance with resetting the DNS setting from White Nervosa who knew
he was incapable of doing so.
As a client of White Forest, you can, without notice or chance to defend yourself, have
your services discontinued, because the 9 members of the co-op have decided to vote
you out, and you won't even be told about it.
You can have your domain redirected to a website you are publicly opposed to.
You can be humiliated, publicly and privately, by White Nervosa herself.
You can be ignored when you ask about the handling of sensitive information stored on
the site.
And you can be left high and dry in trying to undo the damage they've caused.
White Forest's stated goal of providing an accessible and independent platform for
content creators seems to be a false one, at least if you happen to assist the guy who
originated the code they aped in the first place.
After this whole thing blew up and White Nervosa was dragged on Twitter for it, Rose Wriste
received an apology DM saying, I truly don't wish you deplatformed.
Yeah, alright.
Also, White Nervosa admitted to being drunk during the whole thing, which is, um, okay.
However, the apology only applied to the public ridiculing.
White Nervosa doubled down on everything else.
In one Twitter exchange, White Nervosa says, Rose Wriste agreed to our standard operating
procedure.
Is asked, is your standard operating procedure to redirect someone's domain name to a completely
different website they don't want to be affiliated with?
A White Nervosa supporter chimes in with, this is industry standard operating procedure.
When you suspend a service, it is not uncommon to redirect it to the provider's homepage
or a contextually relevant site, and is replied to with, the drop Kiwi Farms site is absolutely
not contextually relevant.
White Nervosa says, he called Kefles a terrorist for attempting to get Kiwi Farms taken down.
It is absolutely relevant.
What actually happened here is that at one point during the Kiwi Farms drama, Kefles
was pointing out that Kiwi Farms was hosted in Ukrainian server farm and then posted its
location, implying that Ukrainian partisans may want to attack it because Kiwi Farms hosts
Russian propaganda.
Destiny described this in his manifesto as calling for terroristic violence, the manifesto
that Rose Wriste edited for grammar and logic, and specifically not content.
To White Nervosa, this was Rose Wriste calling Kefles a terrorist.
The reply guy asks, so you're purposely redirecting his domain name to a website for a cause he
specifically doesn't agree with, and that's somehow morally okay to you?
And White Nervosa simply replies, yes.
White Nervosa also made a big dance around that standing operating procedure of theirs,
stating White Forest discontinues sites that have been inactive for more than 90 days.
When this happens, there is a default screen for if there's nothing to catch the URL.
Rose Wriste had passed the mark, handling over two dozen websites that wasn't a top
priority.
After he contributed to and endorsed a document calling for Cloudflare to protect Kiwi Farms,
it became a priority.
This was Sunday.
He didn't notice until Wednesday, which is when I acted poorly towards him.
I regret that and apologize.
Anybody who claims it's because he dared attack Kefles ignores that he streamed in
July critiquing Kefles.
This was not an issue.
You literally just mentioned one tweet ago that it was about the Kefles document.
Of course, people began to notice all the holes in this argument.
The dear gender person hadn't streamed in six months, but is still on White Forest.
White Nervosa replied, oh, it's because she's still getting automated donations.
This idea that Rose Wriste wasn't getting any automated donations is weird to me.
Rose was small but still doing well, well enough to have some automated subs or something.
But White Nervosa, who is the only one with access to the logs, stated, nope, Rose had
no donos, don't question it, even though Rose Wriste provided proof of many donations
during that time.
Moreover, Rose Wriste did in fact stream during the 90-day period, nine times, and you can
see the distinctive White Leaf chat overlay in those streams.
White Nervosa then claimed that Rose Wriste asked for a site to be deleted, which Rose
Wriste's own DMs disprove, and then finally claims that it actually is about Kefles, saying
it would not be brought back up assuming he maintained his endorsement.
Dude, at this point, just bite the bullet.
Say it was a power move and that you did it because you're in charge and you didn't
like what Rose Wriste did off platform.
We know that's why you did it.
You know that's why you did it.
All this dancing around just makes you look like even more of a fucking snake.
For a while, I believe that White Nervosa as a person was just a side story to the larger
Kefles drama.
A little extra bit of an intermission in between the real happenings.
But now, I think White Nervosa is actually a lolcow in her own right.
And the reason I've come to that conclusion is the Chud logic drama.
All the stuff with Rose Wriste was months ago.
It was involving White Nervosa's capacity at the head of a business, and it involved
Kefles.
But now, White Nervosa herself is just going nuts over literally nothing.
Let's check it out.
On January 17th, White Nervosa tweeted this.
I'm out of my mind, Chud logic, but is there any reason you're paying a person who felt
the need to tweet this twice?
Are you too lazy to find another editor?
Are they doing it for scraps off the plate so it's worth it?
Is there no connection you feel?
This is in response to DriftKingEdits, also known as DK, Chud's editor, tweeting the
following in quick succession.
Not really sure what's going on, but Andrew Callahan definitely didn't rape that young
lady.
Followed by, not really sure what's going on, but Andrew Callahan definitely raped that
young lady.
Now, I'm not really sure what's going on with Andrew Callahan, but I'm pretty sure
this is a joke.
It's literally the cover all your bases thing.
And White Nervosa was offended by it, to the point that she went to Chud logic and did
the cancel culture, why is he your editor thing.
Chud's response was to point out that while White Nervosa is tagging him into the tweet,
making it look like to her followers that she's inviting him to have a conversation,
she's actually got him blocked.
He can't see it, so it looks like he's ducking her.
But he replied anyway, simply saying, I will never kowtow to the gay retarded sensibilities
of leftoids based, always reject the struggle session.
The Twitter canceling attempt went nowhere.
So White Nervosa took it a step further by reporting Chud's Twitch channel to Twitch
because he called her a gay retard on Twitter.
And even though Twitch's off platform policies can be kind of ridiculous, even they weren't
ridiculous enough to take this bait.
Twitch has explicitly told me that it's okay that the partner Chud logic has called me
another partner, a gay retard.
Take that as you will and do as you wish off platform, as long as it's not an imminent
threat.
Yeah, Twitch's off service conduct policy states that Twitch will ban you if you do
any of the following off platform.
1.
Engage in deadly violence or terrorism or terroristic recruiting.
2.
Explicit and or credible threats of mass violence.
3.
Explicit and or credible threats against Twitch.
4.
Leadership, membership, sponsorship of a known hate group.
5.
Carrying out or acting as an accomplice to sexual assault.
6.
Sexual exploitation of youth.
7.
Compromising the physical safety of the Twitch community.
8.
Harmful misinformation.
And any of this stuff applied to Chud logic calling White Nervosa a gay retard.
It's not terrorism or violence, it's not a credible threat, it's not membership
in a hate group unless you count the Chud nation, it's not sexual assault or exploiting
youth or threatening the safety of Twitch, and perhaps most explicitly of all, it's
not misinformation either.
White Nervosa continued to complain about Twitch refusing to take action on offsite
behavior beyond what's listed.
And the reason why is explicitly because she wants Chud logic deplatformed.
Hey, and like with Rose Wriste, at least she has the balls to say it directly this time.
Or maybe it's because Chud's an easier target among leftoids than Rose Wriste was.
Who knows.
Chud's reply was to call White Nervosa a disgusting freak who has no problems with
abusing power and is now making a concerted effort to deplatform him.
White Nervosa mocks the concerted effort bit by saying she sent one email and she actually
doesn't really care.
Despite, of course, being the one who started the Nothing Burger and pushing her followers
to go at it.
Chud's editor, DK, returned to write a lengthy anime villain post about how basically, White
Nervosa is a fraud hack who will fade away because everything she's ever done that's
noteworthy has been stolen by others and the next wave of innovation will be the end
of her 15 minutes of fame.
The backlash White Nervosa received from all of this nonsense was enough to make her leave
Twitter for a few days.
But only a few.
These people always come back eventually.
White Nervosa is also a moderator for Vaush's community, though she may be on a break from
that position for a while.
She's friends with him.
She still runs his site.
She gets paid by him.
And was a mod for a long time.
While White Nervosa was offline, some other Vaush mod, Thena, publicly continued the crusade
in her place, repeating the calls for Twitch to ban Chud.
But more notably, she went into Vaush's community and began petitioning Vaush viewers to join
in on the dogpile, saying that Chud is violating his Twitch partner contract by harassing her
over her gender identity.
Excuse me, but where the fuck did this happen?
Come on, you really think you can just go on the internet and make shit up?
Afterward, Thena banned Chud from VGG and the Vaush subreddit, as well as a bunch of
other people who aren't even in these communities but have publicly spoken out against White
Nervosa, most notably Stardust, who's been laughing at all this nonsense on her stream.
Now, these people have the right to run their shitty little communities however they like.
But this is just like 2015, 2016 all over again, where the leftoids won't tolerate
anybody who disagrees with them even a little bit and will go scorched earth on everyone
who steps out of line.
And I'm not being hyperbolic.
There was also the White Nervosa deny milkshakes drama.
Deny milkshakes is some other flavor of leftist.
These people always eat each other.
And last fall, these two nobodies were at war.
Deny milkshakes said Japanese nuclear bombings were genocidal terror apologia and he would
block anyone who was partisan in favor of the bombings.
Nervosa replied, calling him indistinguishable from a tanky and that he was making light
of the Holocaust.
Just so we're clear, there's a reason that socialists look at every other socialist
except themselves and see fascists.
White Nervosa, a totally sane person, replied to deny milkshakes by threatening to, if he
did not agree to a streamed debate with her, block him, block his followers, and punish
everyone using White Forest by deplatforming all of them.
Well, hold on there.
I thought this was a worker co-op, White Nervosa.
I thought you needed a vote of the nine crumbtubers who run the whole thing in order to be able
to do something like this.
This is how the leftoid worker democracy always degenerates into an authoritarian shithole,
by the way.
It's always because another leftist disagrees with them and they can't accept disunity
among the proles.
The backlash to this event was severe, way more than anything related to tread logic,
to the point that White Nervosa scrubbed the internet of it in an effort to get people
to forget it ever happened.
But the internet never forgets.
And get a load at what the internet remembered.
To be more specific, they said they were okay with Kefl's, Xanderhal, Roserist, Vosch,
Marek, and several others being deplatformed because they refused to have a conversation
about calling me a genocide apologist.
Are you serious, bitch?
You were the one with the finger on the off switch.
This is nobody else's fault but your own.
Why in the fuck would you ever get yourself a White Leaf site when the dictator running
the whole operation can nuke you off the internet simply because she got into a Twitter
spat with a random person you don't even know?
Now this whole thing so far has just been lame twitter drama.
And if it were only lame twitter drama, it wouldn't really be worth it for me to do
a video on it.
I enjoy watching Chud and Stardust dream about it, it's pretty fun to watch petty drama
sometimes.
But my personal interest on its own isn't enough for me to make a video on the topic.
What I discovered after digging into White Nervosa myself, though, was...
Let's start at the surface level stuff.
Check out Vosha's comments on this shitshow.
Hold on, pause it right here.
Look who posted that Xanderhal tweet in Vosha's chat.
Oh, it's Xanderhal!
The only guy who would ever actually post a Xanderhal tweet anywhere.
He's literally doing the tattletale thing.
And if you look around online, you'll find a lot of these crumbtubers all trying to pile
on Chud and trying to get Vosha to come out against him.
You gotta cancel Chud logic, guys.
Vosha's reply, though, is kind of anemic.
On the one hand, he doesn't seem to care too much about this stuff.
But on the other, he's completely fine with his mods behaving this way.
Now, I personally don't think that's a problem.
What my mods do outside of the context of my community isn't any of my business, and
I extend that chariability to everyone.
But that's not the rules the progs use.
These people are losing their marbles over what DK does and how Chud is obviously co-signing
it all by continuing to employ him.
So by that standard, Vosha is a worse person because of White Nervosa's terrible behavior.
And the Chud deplatforming is just the tip of the iceberg.
It's also how, while trying to get Chud deplatformed, they cry that any pushback they
receive is harassment.
This is literally the Jani cries out in pain as she strikes you.
These people cry about body positivity and bigotry and trans-nonsense while at the same
time using low testosterone as an insult.
These people were the ones who face-doxed Chud logic in the first place.
These people were the ones who thought it was a good idea to try and cover up Vosha's
sexual harassment allegations.
White Nervosa and her White Forest crowd are the gang of people who do the on-the-ground
work of following around leftist streamers, most commonly Vosh, and cleaning up their
messes, while serving as relentless attack dogs against anyone who dares to cross their
parasocial daddies.
Let's rewind.
January 26th, 2018.
Over a year before White Nervosa took the open-source DGG code and made a closed for-profit
fork of it.
She was a member of Destiny's community, no surprise there, and debated him on the
topic of deplatforming.
I can't believe we're here, five years later, having the same fucking conversations.
This stream actually isn't too spicy, and there's not one clip that I can pull out
to explicitly prove what I'm saying.
It's the tone of the thing, you kinda have to watch it for yourself.
White Nervosa is clearly trying to nudge Destiny to the left throughout the conversation, with
the general tenor of the conversation being, well, these rightoids are idiots, so you should
be agreeing more with us leftoids, right?
And Destiny, to his credit, doesn't take the bait.
I need a criterion by which I can deplatform somebody that I can objectively argue for,
which is difficult.
The big problem with me for deplatforming is that, to deplatform somebody, it almost
feels like you're saying, my philosophy is objectively superior to yours, because what
I need is I need an argument by which I can deplatform another that wouldn't allow me
to get deplatformed, because I wouldn't want to be deplatformed, right?
So how would society deplatform people, like, if society were to do it?
For example, Twitter would deplatform people by, if you share fake news or something, like,
these would be my criterion, right?
Like, if you post lies or something like that, you'd be deplatformed on Twitter or something,
they would ban your accounts or something like that.
I don't know.
You'd have to be very rigid and very specific in your set of criteria.
For somebody like Warski, like, how is he supposed to platform somebody responsibly?
Like, what would he do to actually not be a Nazi?
Oh, so I'm not even on that, like, platforming people responsibly?
Like, I, maybe.
I don't know if Andy's, like, if you bring on a bunch of Nazis and you don't challenge
their opinion, I don't consider that to be falling under the purview of what I would
be going after.
It would be going after people who are intentionally or with gross negligence or recklessness spreading
fake news.
That would be, like, my starting ground, and that's the only part that I'm at right now.
So, like, if somebody wants to come on and argue, like, listen, I want to create an ethno-state,
I want to get all the blacks and all the Mexicans out of here, like, fine, that's fine.
That person gets a platform, they can argue their shit, I love free speech.
It's a goddamn beautiful thing.
But if that guy wants to get up and make that argument by spreading a bunch of bullshit
news around, by linking to fucking Breitbart articles that have bullshit sources, by quoting
headlines and sniping data and not really making an honest argument, fuck that guy.
Take him out.
So when you say Worsky doesn't, or he's irresponsibly platforming people, should he not be allowed
to carry on that platform, or?
Oh, no, Andy can, um, Andy can platform whoever he wants.
I just don't like that he doesn't acknowledge the reality of it.
I mean, if he, I don't think it should be, like, illegal.
Oh, yeah, now it's an immoral issue.
Yeah, yeah.
One.
Right, I feel like, though, like, um, some countries really, like, yeah, I feel like
America has a good freedom of press, freedom of speech, and you don't think that any other
country should adopt, or rather, reverse, you don't think we should adopt any of the...
I don't know, like, shit like the Germany shit, like, makes me pretty wary, like, that
you can't even do, like, that hail Hitler salute, or you can get in trouble, you can
get fined for that.
Why does that make you weary?
I don't know, because I, fuck, if I want to go outside and do the hail Hitler salute,
I don't want to get in trouble by the state.
It's fucking crazy to me.
Fuck that shit.
I'm a free goddamn American.
Well, you're a free American who supports responsible platforming.
Yeah, but supporting responsible platforming doesn't mean that I explicitly or implicitly
support, like, throwing people in jail for shit.
Well, wait, there is a, there's a thing where, like, a line that, irresponsible, irresponsibly
speech could get you thrown in prison.
I don't agree with that, unless it's literally, like, direct calls to harm or something.
How indirect could you get?
I don't fucking know.
It's up to the courts to decide.
Like, if there was a, if there was a march, and they chanted, kill all Jews, or killed
the Jews, is that direct, or?
That sounds pretty direct to me, yeah, sure.
Anytime you're saying kill, and then something, it's probably over the line, right?
Yeah, no, yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah.
So what's your opinion of hate speech laws?
I don't know, I would have to think really hard about it.
My gut tells me that I think they're bad.
I feel like the hate speech laws are there to give that pre-, not necessarily preemptive
strike, but, like, when speeches basically kill all, kill all of, you know, this group.
Mm-hmm.
I think, I think that's why the hate speech laws are there, because they're not necessarily
a threat towards any one person, but what do you charge them with otherwise?
I mean, if that's what you mean by hate speech, like, just, like, directly threatening somebody,
then I'm probably- Well, no, no, right, it's, it's, it's more
broad than just that, but- Sure.
I think it covers a lot of, um, areas that need to be covered.
Why aren't you a socialist?
I love capitalism.
Why can't you have a capitalist market system under socialist means?
I mean, doesn't capitalism also speak to things like labor and whatnot?
Which, and it doesn't let all that labor and everything work fundamentally differently
in a socialist system?
Sure, but wouldn't labor be more, um, well, couldn't unions be a form of-
Um, but unions don't oftentimes- Well, hold on, I have to think about whether or not,
do unions represent market power or not?
Um, basically, whenever I ask, whenever I think about a question like this, what I'm
trying to think of is, is there a market failure?
And if there's a market failure, I'm always okay with, with some sort of government intervention,
right?
So, just to trigger x skills me in the, in the chat, something like net neutrality, I
would consider the, um, the natural, the, the ISP's being prone to being naturalistic
monopolies, I would consider that a form of market failure.
And market failures, I think, should always be remedied by some sort of government policy.
So, would a company being too big to have any threat of, of unionizing happen, and where
no other companies could compete?
I mean, if that market failure existed, then yeah, I would be okay with remedying that
with government shit.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah.
Um, a lot of people in chat are bringing up that they live in countries where the lines
are shared and, and ISPs have to rent the lines.
I mean, like, that seems like the reasonable thing for me, like, it's, it's infrastructure
that the whole city should care about because pretty much everybody has internet, so I'm
okay publicly paying for it.
We want to keep the lines running well, and then an ISP can open a data center and they
can run, you know, they can hook up at the last, you know, towards them.
Yeah, yeah.
So, so do you think U.S. should go in that direction?
We should start at least.
Probably.
Yeah.
Well, well, you sounded really hesitant there, buddy.
Well, because everything, everything is informed, everything is informed by the data.
I don't know, like, if, if, if shit turns bad, then no, but like, that seems like a
good, a good thing to me, I think.
That seems like a good direction forward, but maybe there, there might be a better argument
against it, but yeah, because I don't, I don't know what the argument would be for having
independent lines or everybody owning their own lines or whatever.
It just seems like a huge fucking waste.
There's nothing really too bombastic in this video.
No big blowout.
White Nervosa just kind of meekly says, okay, after getting pushed back every single time.
It feels like she wants to pull him to the left, but also doesn't want to jeopardize
her connection to him.
Some of you might be saying, Dev, you're reading into this way too much.
How can you possibly know that?
Well, I know it because of a conversation that White Nervosa had with Vosh on her channel
a year later on March 12th, 2019 titled, um, to kill cops.
This is White Nervosa's first encounter with Vosh, and it's from this meeting that becoming
a moderator and creating his website with the forked code that would eventually become
White Leaf would spring.
There's a few interesting things in this conversation.
One, White Nervosa and Vosh both consider liberals, fascists, centrists, and rightists
to all be the same thing.
Kind of like how some rightoids think that all liberals, socialists, centrists, and leftists
are the same thing as well.
It's just centrism, right?
It's just the typical centrist, right?
That's just like, like until they die, you know, both sides are radical and both sides
are equal and both sides need to come together.
Even though one side is literally Nazis.
Yeah.
Um, I mean, that sounds like some of the centrists that I've discussed in the past.
It is, it is fucking incredible to me.
It's amazing how, um, how subjective centrism is these days.
Um, Nazism sure is closer to the center than I, uh, than I originally interpreted.
Yeah.
Like, holy shit.
I just can't even tokens like Dave Rubin, right?
Like he's a liberal, right?
And like these are his talking points and the same thing with Candace Owens and the
same thing with Ben Shapiro and the same thing with, um, yeah, like it just goes on and on.
But yeah, like I think like the biggest problem is people don't perceive how like harmful
it is to public discourse and like centrism is fucking cancer for that.
Just the ignorance of like, uh, the Overton window and again, like crypto fascism and
I mean, I don't like, I don't know.
Like I fucking hate, I fucking hate him.
I hate him so goddamn much, fascists and centrists.
I don't know.
I don't know how to improve.
It just doesn't make any sense.
Cause I feel like every demonstrable study shows like, like these are, this is supposed
to be the facts over feels crowd.
Nope, centrists have never read a study in their entire life.
You can drop that right now.
None of them have ever read a single study.
Like centrists will acknowledge like psychological pitfalls, but then like they always fall back
on this weird, like, so, so it is like they are still right wing because they still always
fall back onto individual like responsibility.
Like, like, like for fascism, I view the only means is violence.
You can only defeat fascism with violence, right?
There is no argument.
There's no, like, like the centrist will always be drifted towards fascism.
So the only way to combat it is to dissuade fascists from protesting.
So you have to hit them with violence.
Does not exist in America because there is no revolutionary movement and how they want
to be a part of one.
I think like, I don't fucking know.
Like what makes a person want to be centrist?
Is it they, they were like a conservative, but conservatism is a cool because the average
age of Republican in America is 900.
So they want to be like the edgy fucking libertarian centrist.
Is it because they once went to a college campus and they think they're kind of liberal
and then like some, a woman with blue hair yelled at them and now they're assuming like
I don't, I don't know.
Whatever it is, it stems from ignorance or stupidity or fear.
It's like, like a little bit of just stunning Kruger, right?
They, they just know like a little bit about politics and they think they know so much.
Like they think they see like the extreme left and the extreme right, but like they've
just made this like fossil equivocation that just doesn't exist.
Like there is no extreme left.
We will become the extreme left and we will stride across this great land, um, seize the
means of production.
You know?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's well, yeah.
I mean, you know, I mean, I'd say like, you know, the car was going down the wrong street
and you know, Charlottesville, you know, it's just White, Nervosa and Vosh talk about how
while a far left party winning elections would be ideal, a revolutionary movement of working
class people, uh, storming the seat of government is also good too.
As long as they're leftist.
Of course, I think we need at least another century, maybe a century and a half of class
consciousness spreading amongst the pros before we're ready to have a revolution.
And when it happens, I would like it to happen in conjunction with a far left political party
gaining prominence in the legislator, which would be able to secure a clean transition
of power rather than the literal like citizens up revolt against the entire United States
military storming Washington, taking control of the, uh, oval office.
Um, you know, broadcasting a message of victory to the rest of the American people.
I hope that in the future, the material circumstances eventually arrive at a point where, um, where
they feel revolution is possible.
They're okay.
If police die during this uprising, I presume you're not in favor of outlawing armor piercing
bullets.
Fuck that.
The only people who wear armor are cops.
They're hoping for a revolution that may occur in more than a century, but in the meantime,
we have bullets designed explicitly to kill cops.
Oh, I mean, yeah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Just because I advocate for a revolution in the future doesn't mean I'm not okay with
cop killing now.
But at the same time, they also don't want individuals to actually own guns.
They want the guns to be owned by the community and kept in a community armory, which is just
the state owning all the guns again with a new label attached.
But ideally I wouldn't like guns to be kept in the house.
I would like there to be like, uh, community armories, um, that neighborhoods would have
where like, if there was ever a need to, uh, you could go to this like sort of collectively
owned bunker maintained by the community and you've got your fucking mousins and F4s and
shit.
For rebranding, I think like, uh, you could pitch it as just a shooting range, right?
Like you can even own like a automatic weapons, right?
Just lock them up at the shooting range and then you go grenade launchers.
Absolutely own that shit.
Grenade launchers.
I want the fucking anti-tank mines.
I want the God, I want the sniper rifles that can penetrate, um, police, uh, car doors.
I want all that shit.
I want them stock block.
I want the fucking barrel.
I want the barrel, the chamber loaded as you pick up the gun.
I want us to be ready.
They also have no real concern with what happens after the revolution either, as long as it
moves the world ever more leftward.
Is your end game to abolish the state wholesale?
I don't really care what happens after we overthrow capitalism.
The material circumstances of the time will dictate what comes next.
I just want to see us move forward, move leftward.
And by the way, they don't believe that democracy can do this.
I reject the idea that electoralism is the means by which we can overthrow the hold police
have on disenfranchised communities.
And finally, White, Nervosa and Vashj describe hiding their true beliefs and subverting this
system from the outside.
Like, couldn't you like falsely moralize that to yourself though?
Because I feel like I could very easily fall into that like psychological trap where I
could like moralize myself or, you know, say that I'm not doing tangible harm to public
discourse.
I'm just doing it for a paycheck to feed my family and to further like my own personal
goals.
I don't know if I could justify it ethically under my own like personal set of values,
but I do know, I think the only way that I could come away from that thinking like, okay,
maybe I'm not going to blow my brains out in this gas station bathroom.
The only way I could come out feeling like I'm not doing that is if I thought like, okay,
I'm building power from within, but one day I will unveil my true power level.
Personally on a personal level, I do not think that I could do it unless I had some
sort of like secret underlying motive, some way in which I felt I was actually supporting
the leftist cause.
I understand how other people could do it though.
Not everyone is as politically enfranchised as you or I have such strongly formed opinions,
such a firm understanding of theory.
The most refreshing part of all of this is seeing a more mask off Vashj than he is nowadays.
So then if you believe that Republicans have intent right now to bring about an LGBT genocide,
how can you morally object against people right now taking arms and going out and killing
Republican lawmakers?
Exactly.
Yes.
Well, it would be a utilitarian thing, wouldn't it?
Oh God, stop.
Stop.
Which unfortunately I don't really think it's possible to know that because I'm not God,
but as a general rule, that type of thing doesn't tend to work out.
But there are plenty of examples-
Ask him this, if it did work out, if they were able to kill lawmakers with no consequences,
would it be morally justified, question mark?
You know, are a legitimate-
Ask him.
Let's hear it.
Make him answer our question.
... are trying to use that power to suppress minority groups.
You talked about the utilitarian thing before.
So if it would be possible, if it were to be possible to get away with killing Republican
lawmakers with no consequences, would it then be-
Are you actually fed posting at me right now?
You're glowing in this convo.
Wait, are you being fed these questions?
Ah, he won't answer that question.
I knew he wouldn't.
I knew he wouldn't answer that question.
He won't do it.
What a fucking weaselly little coward.
2023, Vosh is too scared to say what he really thinks.
He likes the Twitch bucks too much, so he hides his power level.
And Vosh on IRL panels?
Forget it.
The milk toast progressive opinions you can imagine.
If you look at any major social movement, you will see disinformation.
That was the case with BLM, that was the case with the civil rights movement, the suffragette
movement, the abolitionist movement, the American revolution, and everything prior to it.
Misinformation is just a part and parcel.
If you try to minimize it, but at the end of the day, it is something that will be produced
and sometimes focused on.
You have to take a look at the underlying social motivations and the processes that
led to that.
So with regards to the January 6th stuff, again, you can, as you said, normalize very
terrible stuff with the wrong descriptive understanding of the world.
You can take just about every heinous totalitarian ideology that's ever festered on this planet,
you know, whether you want to go Nazism or Stalinist, Pol Pot, wherever you want to go.
If you fed a person the right set of facts about the world, big air quotes, by the way,
you could approximate those ideologies in them.
Compare that take to this one and you'll see exactly what I mean.
There is not a good base of conservatives in this country.
These people are no different from the Ku Klux Klan.
They are no different from the fucking white nationalists who ran terror campaigns in the
South back during the 1920s, 30s, 40s.
They are absolutely no different from the frothing at the mouth screaming fucking pasty
male people who are throwing rocks at black folk going to integrated schools.
There is no difference.
If you have a conservative family member, I'm sorry, they're part of the problem.
If you have a conservative friend, I'm sorry, they're part of the problem.
History will crush these people beneath its feet.
Every single time a political party has tried this shit, every single time they've gone
down this road, they have been reviled through the generations.
There is no good history for these people.
And every conservative, every Republican is on the hook for this.
Every last one of them.
These people present one view when they're in real life and being challenged directly
and another view entirely when they feel like only their community, their people are watching
and they're safe from the eyes of outsiders.
They are just as subversive as the fascists they claim to oppose.
They tell the big lie just as much.
They too hide their real politics until the moment is right.
Three, stemming from their subversiveness, White-Nervosa and Vosch both admit that the
reason they hang around destiny is to convert him to their political beliefs and to pull
his audience into their sphere of influence.
I've seen like, yeah, you go toe to toe with destiny on economics and I kind of accidentally
push him further away because I pushed him towards getting rid of minimum wage.
Oh no.
I think, I honestly, the best way to radicalize destiny and leftward is to, if you're a leftist,
is to not talk with him because he gets really fucking angry and defensive talking to leftists.
I feel, I almost feel for him because he, he's like, cause he's a lib boy, you know,
he's a good old lib guy and, and because he gets popular debating on these idiot right-wingers,
he'll like sort of throw him in with the lefties.
But now he feels like this performative need to distance himself from them so he can stand
alone on his own little, like, yeah, yeah, he definitely loves, like it, it's almost
like a virtue signal, like that he loves to like say like, oh man, I guess you're a communist,
right?
Like, like, like, uh, in a condescending way in a discussion, um, we'll get them one day.
Yeah.
I mean, well, I, I feel like, like, like, again, like just by accident, right?
Just by him, I mean, cause fuck, he used to be a libertarian, so he's on the right track.
He just has to get there.
White Nervosa also decries the equivalence between the radical left and the radical right
as a symptom of fascism, which destiny did in their previous conversation, but she was
too cucked to speak up about.
Like Dave Rubin, I think it's an easy example that shouldn't have a platform.
Well, no, I'm not sure I would have to think about Ruben.
So again, I want to be really, really, really careful here.
Okay.
So remember primarily my value system is usually going after what is true.
I don't care about political agendas.
I have no desire to push a political agenda whatsoever.
I don't care.
I have no interest, no desire.
So I think that all offensive ideas should be spoken about.
So pedophilia, incest, Ku Klux Klan, Nazism, ethno states, all of that shit, communism,
whatever the fuck.
All of these ideas should be up for discussion.
I'm okay with that.
And I'm okay with people providing a platform to discuss these ideas.
The ideas don't bother me.
It's just engaging in disinformation or misinformation or reckless, like reckless reporting that
is like horrendously disingenuous.
Yeah, I don't have, I don't want to name drop too many people, but the reason I specifically
think of Ruben instantly is because he really, really interviews a lot of people who are
far to the alt-right and even further so, and I feel like platforming those people and
giving them just basically a softball interview to pitch their platform, I feel like really
does a disservice to everybody that's watching.
I don't, I don't agree with that.
I mean, it gets the ideas out there.
Even if you might find them offensive or horrible, it just gets the ideas out.
I mean, do you make all softball interviews illegal then or?
Well, no, not at all, but I mean, isn't that, isn't that your point though?
Cause isn't that sort of fake news on, on steroids.
No, I don't think so.
The pinnacle of that.
Well, like, so here's a question.
If you want to go after people that give softball interviews to extremists, what about somebody
that has a channel where they interview like Contra points or the interview Sean and January
somebody, and they give them all softball questions, would that be no, I feel like that's
entirely different.
If your channel, give me some, wow, very clearly a stilted, uh, slant, you know, you're just
an interview channel.
But Dave Rubin, I don't feel like is presented as such as it's presented as the marketplace
of ideas, which it very clearly isn't.
Yeah.
Maybe.
I don't know.
I guess it's, it's, I like to focus on branding and presentation.
I like to focus on fake news because I can do a hard line objective.
Like this is bullshit.
You're screenshotting article headlines.
You have no fucking idea what you're talking about.
Like you're, you're lying to your teeth.
That's easy to target saying somebody like Dave Rubin, disingenuously, disingenuously
presents as policy.
I feel like that line is a lot harder to walk.
Yeah, maybe so.
Maybe.
So this is all a year and a half before destiny and Vash stopped publicly being friends after
that infamous Kyle Rittenhouse debate destiny always described Vash as his friend, white
nervosa spent time in his community as a noted orbiter, but it seems to be increasingly obvious,
at least to me that these people were simply using him the whole time for, and to tie it
all into one neat package, Vash and white nervosa advocate for direct violence against
fascists, keeping in mind that to them, fascists are not only fascists, but liberals, centrists
and rightists.
And she even readmits as much in the statement.
And I feel like we can win on like, like socialism because emotional appeals or emotional propaganda
is very, very easy.
How do you win on like against fascism?
Like, because that's a really tough, like, you know, they, they show like the other and
they're going to take, you know, your kid's job, like, I mean, I don't, I don't think
you can argue with fascists.
I think they just need to be killed or something.
I don't disagree with you, but I mean, like from a, like for attacking, uh, like centrists,
like how do you attack, especially since it's so crypto in the first place, like, like it's
not usually Charlottesville and like it's a wordness.
I mean, ideally I think a lot of centrists are crypto fascist too, and they get the bullet
as well.
But the system we live in today is full of violence as it exists.
And to ignore that.
Yeah.
Oh God.
That fucking triggers me.
This is literally nothing.
Well, like, I mean, people don't realize that a government is just a society agreeing on
violence.
Like, you know, like, like if guns are being passed around, like fucking, I mean, I, like,
I don't know, fucking well, like let's go.
What matters is if you see me in the street with my Mosin, okay, what matters is that
I join you with two.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
My fucking comrades.
Hey, destiny being a liberal is only there to either be subverted or destroyed.
And because they both failed to subvert him and they're both too bitch baby to actually
do anything outside their own houses, destroying him online is the next best thing.
With all of this additional context, look at white nervosa statement on the Rose wrist
thing again, allow this to be a larger statement on those who look towards DGG for a place
to be rather than a place to move on from.
They don't watch your content.
Never.
You're nothing but a tool to them.
This isn't picking sides.
This is understanding that DGG isn't a place for growth.
On the one hand, you're entirely wrong.
There's a ton of content creators who have benefited greatly from the destiny bump, erudite,
stardust, counterpoints, even vosh, but the difference is that they took the exposure
destiny gave them and then made something that was new, something that was them using
the opportunity properly.
White nervosa didn't like DK said, everything she's done is simply a copy of the work of
better people.
On the other hand, though, this mindset of white nervosas pretty much proves my point
that her and her crowd are just users.
To them, DGG is a stepping stone to appeal to when it builds them up and to attack when
it builds them up.
Vash and Asan did this to destiny.
A bunch of crumb tubers did it too, book smarts, Merrick, Xanderhal.
This is also what's happening to chud logic right now.
And now that twitch politics has become an insular lefty only space, they're turning
on each other for clout as they always do.
Right now, as I'm recording this bad bunny and keffles are getting into a fight because
they're both fucking irrelevant, contributing nothing of substance to anything.
And despite their public exclamations of commitment to the leftist cause, they're only here
to make money.
And yes, underneath all of the rhetoric, that's all it is for any of these leftoids.
You don't need to actually build socialism if you're a rich socialist because you've
got the correct beliefs.
So whatever is a good consequentialist end for you is what the good is.
In fact, with white nervosa, it's even more blatant because the main reason she even tried
to be a streamer before the whole white forest thing is so that she could stream snipe other
people's auto-hosts and turn those donations into cocaine.
And no, this isn't just some Kiwi Farms rumor, though they get a kick out of it too.
This is something that is actually confirmed by her.
Yeah, I mean, I just love the EU streams, I'm trying to jack the auto-hosts from everybody
else so, you know, we start early as fuck.
Listen, just know that if you support the White Leaf Project, all that money is going
straight up her nose.
At this point, let's check out the big picture.
White Nervosa is a core part of Vasha's community, paid by him to rip off Destiny's
code for his, and later, all of BreadTube's use.
This entire group shares the same ethics, which constitute a violent support of revolutionary
leftism without any concern of the actual behaviors involved, or concern for any of
the outcomes beyond what is simply good for them.
And beneath that mask, what is good is whatever makes them money.
And people who disagree with what they consider the good to be exist only to be exploited
by them, to either be converted to their cause or discarded and destroyed.
And in order to accomplish all of this, these people are willing to lie, to cheat, to steal,
to attack you in the street if they had the opportunity, to deprive you of your income
so that you and your dependents starve, to go against every stated value that they claim
to hold, including things like universal human rights or democracy.
There is a direct throughline between the rhetoric these people used in 2018 and 2019
and their morally reprehensible behaviors today.
They were always going to become this.
This is why people in my area of the internet spoke out about it all those years ago.
We all told Shu on head she was going to get backstabbed.
She didn't believe us.
And here we are.
She was scamming chudlogic in like April 2022 or something, saying, I bet demon mama backstabs
you within the next six months.
And he was like, I don't know, man.
And lo and behold, she did.
When I spoke to Dylan Burns, I told him there will probably eventually be backlash for you
and I talking, especially if you do it regularly.
And it hasn't come yet.
But, you know, it will.
I don't agree with Sargon or ArchWarhammer all the time.
We have some very rowdy debates in private, but we never violate the meta-ethic that is
the friendship.
Over some political disagreement, why would we?
Even though they're drifting away from me politically, and I agree with them less and
less over time, they are vastly better people than any of these BreadTube fucks.
White Nervosa herself is just a blip on the radar.
She will fade in the same way that Kefles is fading, now that her Drop Kiwi Farms campaign
has failed spectacularly.
Even if you were braindead enough to be interested in the BreadTube socialist type of thing,
all of her content is just what the larger BreadTubers say, only strictly worse.
Her only claim to fame is exactly as DK said.
She stole the work of better people.
She enriched herself, temporarily, off that work.
She has no ability to innovate on that foundation.
And so, when the ecosystem moves on, she will be left behind.
Her one claim to fame is fleeting fast, and nothing else she's ever done has any substance
whatsoever.
She will one day wake up and discover that the cocaine money has dried up, nobody's
keeping up with her anymore, nobody's using the few dollops of value she stole from others
anymore.
Theirs is a community of users, in many ways.
And White Nervosa is rapidly reaching the end of her usefulness.
I don't know why she thinks she won't be discarded, in the same way that she and
her ilk have discarded so many others.