Hey guys, I was gone for a day because I was having new internet installed, but in the
interim I have since signed up to Parler!
That's right, that app that is currently going viral as a Twitter alternative.
Who knows how good it is, I'll dig into its depths a little bit later, but for now I have
reviewed or reserved my username and I'll be using it at least a little bit.
So I'm at parler.com slash profile slash short fat otaku.
I figure if you just search for short fat otaku it should probably come up.
Wait, hold on, I didn't type this, this isn't my first message, my first message was hi.
Did it automatically tweet this or I guess Parler it for me?
Okay well anyway, let's send that.
Yep, I come up as the only user under the name of short fat otaku, so if you use Parler,
if you're getting on the twigzit as they're calling it, you can find me there and hopefully
I'll see you over there.
Check you out later, I love you.