Hey everyone! Between this video today and the garden video yesterday I bet some people are asking
where's the politics content? Don't worry the politics content hasn't gone anywhere the weekly
sip is still happening tomorrow and there will be new 10 minute take politics videos and other
types of politics videos coming next week. The reason that I'm doing this sort of stuff is well
one I wanted to get out the garden video yesterday because frankly my grandmother is
she's she's in her 90s now and we we don't know when she's going to pass on so I would like her
to see at least some of the garden stuff she absolutely loves those garden videos I don't
want to wait until the end of summer this time to actually put one out I'd rather just do you know
a spring one and a summer one and an autumn one just in case she doesn't she doesn't last
throughout 2022. I know that sounds harsh but you mean you you know what I mean but as for this
video if you go into the backlog of this channel I'm talking way back way before SFO was ever about
politics this is pre-gamergate stuff you'll find at least a few videos I think are still online
of me and Dave doing a series called trailer talk and I think we talked about uh man of steel back
when that was a new movie we talked about star trek into darkness I think we did one about the
hobbit you know this is all you know stuff that was nine or ten years ago and all of those trailer
talks were basically recorded as soon as possible right when we left the theater so we could
actually give like an honest opinion of it we always kind of envisioned a trailer talk to be
the kind of thing where we go to explicitly a very late night screening maybe even like a midnight
show of a movie and then in the darkness of the parking lot or in one case in the darkness of our
backyard we talked about the movie in the middle of the night and it was supposed to be kind of
this quiet private intimate little discussion about movies and the main reason we kind of let
that series die around 2014 is because none of us had a car anymore to go to the movie theater
but now that we have a car and now that covid is no more I do want to revive the trailer talk series
I'm not going to revive it on SFO this is still a politics channel I'm uploading the first new one
right here just to let you know and any future trailer talks are going to appear over on the
dev kit channel the dev kit channel is basically my personal channel where I do tech stuff I do
unboxings I do reviews I do trailer talks now basically anything that's not politics and that
isn't part of the game boomers you know let's play thing I'm gonna put up on dev kit it is a channel
that is mainly my personal channel and not necessarily you know SFO the brand but nonetheless
I would still appreciate it if you decided to follow it and keep up with what I'm doing there
because I know that Naomi likes going to movies so whenever we go to a movie maybe we'll shoot
a trailer talk who knows but anyway I'm putting the first one up here just to let you know hope
you enjoy it and if you want to see any more please head over to dev kit thank you very much
guys new politics content coming after this I really appreciate you sticking around I'll see
you next time I love you so we're back at this it's been about 10 years since we've actually done
this this show on the channel 10 years years so for those of you who have been watching long
before the politics stuff long before gamergate Dave and I did a show on this channel we have
a half a dozen episodes or so called trailer talk but what we would do is you would go see
a really late screening of a movie yeah really late and then it's like past past midnight right
now yes yeah and then talk about it like basically the night of I forgot I already had some water
here I'm so I had so much popcorn dude I'm gonna float away why why would you float away because I
feel bloated but wouldn't you just sink instead of floating maybe but anyway we want today
tonight we went out to the old cinema and now it's like 1am or whatever and we had we watched
sonic the hedgehog 2 2 second one okay what the fuck's happening with this thing oh for the love
of god I will open it will you yeah let's see will you yep yeah yep keep talking hold on I
want to see this first free time before we talk about any fucking movie I want to see this shit
will you open it maybe not this is more than the fucking movie was
oh the movie wasn't that bad no it wasn't actually but this is for some reason I'm not opening
well anyway so we saw Sonic the Hedgehog 2 now we also watched Sonic the Hedgehog 1 that came out
like during the pandemic didn't it I don't remember that was eons ago was it it was the
reason we're doing it the night of is because I'll forget yeah I'll forget all my opinions
my tomorrow even though technically it is tomorrow we watched Sonic 1 and how did we both feel about
Sonic 1 we both liked Sonic 1 but it was very obviously a kids movie well yeah and so was this
one well yeah but like like I mean like you can't go into it expecting it to be like like a good
kids movie you know what I mean why not well no no okay no no I mean like a good drink good well
you explained this a good kids movie for adults you know like yes there's references to the actual
Sonic games and the movie but you have to expect going in that yes it's very simplified like there's
lots of funny goofy moments there's no swearing as it's for children specifically it's not for
like teenagers kind of edging on the adults so adults can kind of enjoy it too no it's for kids
yes definitely for children but this look good but you have to make sure that you know that
they're for kids going into it yeah so the first Sonic was
possible
this is all staying in the family no have the water have the water I'm gonna okay so the first
Sonic um Sonic likes to do this thing whenever they do like a like a I wouldn't say movie but
a show or anything else what Sonic likes to do is they like to um basically throw in human characters
and they always do like a Sonic comes to the human world situation happens it was Sonic X
they did it with I think one of the comics they did it with a lot of Sonic properties
because like the actual story of Sonic is Sonic lives in a world where at least the original
Sonics like we're talking like Sonic one two and three and Sonic and Knuckles and um there's there
was a bunch of situations where basically Sonic was fighting Robotnik and there's not much story
to it and there's animal friends and there's there's magic and like Robotnik being the only
human doesn't make any sense but you know what fuck it's it's a video game you know it was made
it was made back in the 90s okay listen no no didn't you say that a premise to the Sonic game
specifically was that they were all mutated animals that was later they added that to try
and explain the original oh wait okay so since since they were trying to explain the original
obviously Robotnik was the only human survivor because he was the only one smart enough to
survive he wasn't it was actually a lot of humans just we don't see them until Sonic Adventure but
yeah never mind basically like the idea from what I understand the whole Mobius which was the planet
that they were all on was actually a far future earth where you have nuclear war and mutated
animals and they're still humans that's why in Sonic Adventure there's like a city with humans
and like a station square there's still a bunch of humans hanging around but there's also animals
too and people are just okay with it because they've gotten used to it and the level of
technology is like equivalent to like 90s earth because they've gotten back to that point but
there's just a bunch of furries running around and so that was like the small furries that was
the deep lore but of course they do for example in Sonic X it was that there was like an alternate
universe there's always alternate universes there's a sonic universe and then there's the
and there's like the human universe and there's always like Sonic gets iskaid over into the human
universe and that's like it's iskaid I thought it was isekaid what a wrong fucking guy
and that is what Sonic 1 ended up being it ended up being exactly what if you were going to do what
every other time you've done Sonic yes they they they did a thing where you know he goes to the
United States he goes to Green Hill the town called Green Hills and like is it Montana I don't
know in the middle middle of trees in the middle of trees that's where it was yep for the rich
people hosts yeah was there any reason for that opening bit in Sonic 2 to be set in Seattle I
don't think so never came back to being in Seattle well no it was to set up the fact that Sonic still
wanted to be a hero but why Seattle like the first movie why Seattle probably because it was semi
close by okay maybe well or he heard that the crime was happening right that second in this
iteration of the story Sonic is from another planet there's rings that the actual rings in
the games they're they're basically teleportation devices you can open portals to go wherever you
want to go they don't really explain it too hard because they're just having a good time
and what ends up happening is Sonic he escaped he's on a planet with an owl mother which is like
a new creation of this game and the Enkidna tribe is coming to kick the shit out of her to try and
get the master mode you'll find out about the first movie but in the first movie he goes to
he escapes he goes to earth he's raised by himself himself for a bit and then eventually
this dude who finds him what was his name again he's so forgettable tom tom he's so forgettable
he doesn't tom tom chowski whichowski or something he he had more of a thing he had more of a part in
the first movie oh yeah no like okay tom guy tom guy he was in the second movie I don't remember
that he was in the second movie and we're just watching okay real quickly first movie he ends
up with tom robotnik is a defense contractor with the us government initially he's making drones and
stuff he's doing his thing um and he ends up he the government wants him to fight sonic because
he's an alien yes something like that but then he also ends he ends up taking the loss personally
and so they had like this giant fight throughout the first movie they fight in san francisco well
i'm just quickly getting through okay okay fine go and then by the end by the end of it um sonic
tricks robotnik into going through a ring yeah and he ends up on a mushroom planet there's literally
nothing about mushrooms it's only mushrooms mushrooms and rock yeah and there's there's a lot
of uh really fun references in both movies actually the second movie had uh uh the um
it's a coffee place called the mean bean which is obviously a reference to dr robotnik's mean
bean machine i don't know what that is but i don't know but nail me are you fucking kidding
the references okay but anyway yeah we're references yes but anyway anyway the point being
is that uh that's the first movie the first movie was actually it was a pretty solid kids movie
it was a bit cringy at times but it was still as all kids as all kids movies yes like you could do
a lot worse with a kid's movie yeah it wasn't stupid no it wasn't um it was a bit too self-referential
it's always this one they both like had too many like breaking jokes
just that like the time when they're going down the um the uh the mountain and sonic
calls knuckles the winter soldier i was like like i i i i get the fourth wall breaking stuff but
you can't do too much of it and sonic always did too much of it always um too much for me but
anyway second movie okay it opened with we opened with um robotnik making mushroom coffee after
having been on the planet for a year trying to rebuild he has like a broken spaceship right
yeah he got sent through with the broken machine it's a mech i think it's a mech something i don't
even remember i think no the fight from during the fight in the first movie oh my god it doesn't
matter he had a mech and the mech went through with him yes whatever the fuck he had in the final
act of the first movie with with him anyway he's using the the parts from that to build a giant
antenna to signal space to see who the fuck comes to the mushroom planet yet he had nothing else
he's like i'm just gonna signal and he had like one of sonic's quills which had the like the sonic
power which was he helped him use the energy from the quill to power the the yeah but basically it's
um eggman robot they use both the robot again yeah they use both yeah but he basically he fires
off this this laser and he's hoping someone shows up yeah and knuckle shows up well you have three
randoms who are never explained show up yeah i don't know who the fuck those guys are they're
they look like humans yeah they look like humans with like bird masks yeah but then then robotnik
more or less kills them yeah yeah not graphically he more or less murders them with just traps
goofy traps yeah and then knuckles comes through and he's like oh and then knuckles is just like
he sees the quill and it's just like oh where did you get that and a black man deep black man voice
i can't do i think it is interest elva who's doing this i don't know i can't do that voice i am not a
man you get the quill sort of yeah anyway where do you get the quill and robot takes the like
it's just like i'll just show you the way to earth let's go you know and and so they go
and i can knuckles go off yeah and cut to san francisco yes seattle whatever it starts
with an s and it's in america god damn it okay so what ends up happening is um
those those three are never seen again that's kind of yeah no that's not explained why
no but it's not explained why they're there yeah and then suddenly knuckles comes through the same
portal yeah like it's not it's not explained at all because spoiler alert really early into this
the entire echidna tribe is dead well they always were though yeah i know yeah
he's always the last kid knows the joke oh fuck okay yeah yeah in sonic 3 here's the thing
in sonic 3 he's the last echidna yeah but then when it comes to um they don't explain that they
explain it in sonic adventures which is like the next game with a story because there's a game in
between like just yes yes there's no story but like in sonic adventure there's like you go to the the
um the temple of the echidnas and it's like overgrown like a big jungle yeah and you see
flashbacks like a bunch of echidnas running around um but anyway the point being what
anyway the point being yeah the point being is that in this movie um sonic's running around
seattle and he's like massively fucking up stopping a robbery of a armored car he destroys
an entire city block trying to stop an armored car and almost kills many civilians many times
and there's like and he's trying to do like the batman thing and they're like cleaning it up
and he's like he's also like justice yeah he's wise cracking a whole bunch yeah like spider-man
except worse yeah yeah but he's trying to be batman but he's more spider-man yeah and then
he like he fucks everything up and he like a bunch of people get hurt but no no no no one got hurt
but he almost killed many people no one can get hurt as a pg movie yeah many people almost got
killed no one actually got killed and a lot of things destroyed an entire city block a lot of
entire city block and then he goes i saved you and they're all like fuck you sonic you know the
tight-up guard was like you're a terrible hero yeah and like sonic not even faze runs home to
green hills or yeah of course it's green hills it was first i don't know are you fucking kidding
me i don't fucking know so okay so he runs home to green hills uh by the next day and he's like
trying to pretend that he's um he was like asleep all night yep he's doing the bruce wayne thing
got caught by and then like his dad i guess um tom is like listen you can't you can't you're
don't be reckless don't be reckless because you're still a kid and yeah sonic's at 16.
sonic was always a kid yeah as long as a kid so he's ariel's age so sonic's a kid who little
mermaid fuck you who wanted to go off into her own thing which was 14 i'm pretty sure
i'm pretty sure in the disney movie she's 16 okay well anyway anyway anyway um
so that whole thing happens and then they they're going off to uh tom and his wife they're going
off to hawaii for a destination wedding and sonic is like i'll just send you there with one of my
teleportation rings and they go and then like sonic's at home and he has he does he destroys
the house yeah he doesn't he destroys the house he does the thing that like every teenager generally
does when they're left alone for the first time is they just fucking party and sonic just fucking
party by himself he partied by himself yeah well i mean fuck he doesn't like he's an alien like
no no i know but like it was actually with a dog he partnered with the dog but you know what's
weird though is that i feel like that was supposed to be like that pitbull yeah the guy who has no
like friends moments but it wasn't sonic was just having a really good fucking time fucking like he
trashes the house with a bunch of food and then he drives the riding lawnmower through the through
the house to like mulch the food up and spread it across the that was hilarious that was so gross
like imagine just like 18 bags of chips ripped open on the ground and then just like
just drive right through everywhere but anyway to skip over the rest of that and he makes like a
foam room with a pool but anyway and then and then he cleans it up all cleans it all up in like 30
seconds when tom calls from hawaii because he can do that because he facetimes because facetime is
a thing so now you actually have to clean up the room before you answer the phone yeah yes um but
anyway what ends up happening is robotnik comes back yeah robotnik shows up with knuckles and
beats the fuck out of sonic yeah knuckles kicks the shit out of sonic and he's fucking done and
then there's tails tails tails never really explained tails does not explain he they give
him like a couple lines where they explain a little bit but he basically shows up the couple
of lines were hey uh you gave up a shit ton of energy and it got to my home planet and i've been
stalking you you're really cool and i love you and i've been stalking you yeah that's the most
strange this is strange um and sonic isn't even a face he's like you even watched me in the shower
and tails is like that's a trick question sonic prefers bubble baths and sonic isn't phased at all
it's weird okay with it that was weird yeah it was weird it was a weird moment and it's never
dressed ever again but like like tails mentions his village once but like we don't get to know
anything about tails you don't know why you don't really why you showed up it's just like i like you
sonic is like okay i guess no he came to warn sonic about knuckles yes he did but like but
you can't say there's no reason for him okay but it's a shitty reason because yes but it's still a
reason like it's shitty it's not there tails is in the movie because they put tails because they put
tails in the script and no no it's because they put tails in the after credit sequence in the
first movie oh that's why tails is in the movie well yes they had to put them in somehow yeah
and they weren't and here's the thing like sonic one is i think just sonic sonic two like the games
sonic two is sonic and tails versus robotnik and then sonic three they're like how about we try a
story and so they add the floating island and the master emerald and they add um and they add
knuckles who's the guardian and then um robotnik like tricks knuckles and it's the same story in
the movie and then eventually um you get to the point where robotnik flies in and that goes to
steal the master emerald and then knuckles is like oh my god sonic you actually weren't evil
and then knuckles like uh sorry uh robotnik tasers him he tasers uh knuckles oh and then there's like
a big fight with all of them at the end against against um robotnik so so they are basically
they're doing the sonic three story they haven't introduced tails because tails is part of sonic
two so tails just shows up and he's like i've been stalking you let me be your pal and sonic's like
okay and then so they're on they bond in russia yeah it's like it's a kid's movie so they're just
gonna be like okay fine but like yeah it wasn't really set up it was not but anyway so now uh
tails shows up tails rescues him they go on like a little chase they get away not much of a chase
how much of a chase but they get away it's pretty it's pretty much tail shows up hit snuggles with
a car and they escape yep then they go to uh tom's friend's place wade yeah wade it's like his
garage i hate him and like yeah he was just there for like a minute because he was from the first
movie but he was just there for a minute and then he was like he's the deputy he's the deputy sheriff
yeah the town he's an idiot but they go to his place because he was in the first movie he knows
he knows what sonic so he goes there and then sonic's like yeah so in the first movie i got
this map and the map is it turns out the map's the map to the master emerald oh and the master
was hidden on earth yeah and it turns out that for just you know sonic touches the map i guess
for the first time for the first time ever even because as soon as he touches it a big hologram
comes out i was gonna point this out of the owl girl you know listen i was gonna point this out
in the theater but i'm pretty sure we literally saw him touch the map earlier in the movie you
think so i'm pretty sure i'm pretty sure he actually opened it up and looked at it in the
earlier part of the movie maybe it's because he touched the part that said master emerald on it
maybe but anyway a coincidence a hologram shows up a hologram shows up of the of the owl of the
owl mom sonic's owl mom and it's like listen listen sonic so if you're reading this if you
if you're hearing this i'm dead master emerald's hidden on earth you gotta go find it find it
there's here's your quest yeah onward and so it's like oh my god this i can finally be a hero
and then so they and wade's like i guess i'm here like wade fucking does nothing
wait wait was annoying that scene would have been better without him yeah but anyway then they go
to russia yeah so they use it turns out that like the coordinates on the map lead to russia russia
and so they go to russia and there's like there's an there's an interlude where they have a dance
off with a bunch of russians they have a dance up like a like a like a dive russian a bar that's
in a really nice building but it's like a dive bar in russia it's in the middle of a snowstorm
in the middle of a snowstorm in the middle of the mountains yeah it's just a dive bar
and there's a dance off because they somehow get a hold of the map they're just through
through shenanigans yeah and they dance us for it and it's like okay so they have a dance off
to summarize it's tales and sonic's bonding moment yeah for the movie it's the bonding moment it's
the bonding moment yeah so they dance they dance off and they get they get the map back but like
there's there's not much to it like it's kind of goofy like they dance yeah because it's a
kids movie you can kind of forgive the fact they go on wild tangents sometimes because uh this
would be not be acceptable in adults but what the fuck is this like yeah it's funny at least it's
funny it's still it's still a fine kids movie um get the map they find a temple in an ice
in the mountains we're assuming in the side of a mountain somewhere they didn't actually show us
how they got into it suddenly they were in the mountain range with the paramount symbol
actually the mount was like the paramount was actually pretty funny and then they're suddenly
in the temple so we're assuming it's in the side of the mountain somewhere so so tails flies holding
sonic you know and in the usual sonic 2 way where he has like his arms they fly into a hole in the
side of a mountain yeah i think i missed that but they fly into a hole in the side of like a big ice
like glacier in a mountain they go in and then okay well i'm still right and they land and then
there's a giant owl door and they're like oh i guess humans never discovered this place before
even though it's like in the russian mountains it's fine well maybe because it's in the Russian
everyone just dies up there okay yeah yeah it's Russia yeah so they go in there um they poke
around the temple they do like the new traps and and puzzles and then Sonic when she finds a compass
and the compass the compass points to the location of the emerald and it's like okay well now we're
one step closer then um yeah then Knuckles and Robotnik catch up and they show they have another
fight everyone gets beaten up everyone gets beaten up but then Sonic decides to escape by using a um
a piece of a mech as a snowboard because he's done that several times in the games so they're
snowboarding down and then Knuckles also does the same thing there's a wave flying in the sky
yeah and snow and Sonic is snowboarding down the mountain while all Robotnik's robots are like
exploding the mountain like beside and behind him there's lots of explosions yeah and then
Knuckles comes and beats him up and then Tails also gets beaten up and Tails becomes unconscious
because he gets hit with rockets yes and then it turns out that um and then both Robotnik and
Knuckles escape with the compass yeah they get away okay hold on I want to tell this part okay
so there's a bit at this point where Sonic's this is like this is the second act of the story
yeah where like Sonic is down and out I want to point out this does not feel like the second act
of the story but it is but it is yeah Sonic's down and out Robotnik and Knuckles are now ahead
in the race to find the master emerald they have the compass and a giant and a giant uh a snow
avalanche a giant giant snowstorm on the mountain a giant avalanche is coming towards
Sonic and the unconscious Tails yeah so Sonic's carrying Tails like this and snowboarding again
yeah and so we're both pretty sure he lost the snowboard he found another one it's fine and
he's like I gotta get the fuck out of here somehow yeah because he lost all of his teleport rings yes
so he calls up Tom Tom who's at who's at Hawaii who's in Hawaii and here's the thing
Tom has one teleport ring to get back from from the trip yeah but he accidentally due to his
shenanigans he mixes it up with the wedding ring yep yeah so Tom is like Sonic calls him
and he's like Sonic's like listen you gotta get I'm gonna fucking die in the middle of the wedding
ceremony yeah and Tom's okay I'll do it and then Tom pulls out the wedding ring and tries to use
it to teleport and doesn't work because it's a wedding ring he's like oh fuck dude so he goes
he runs up to the podium because he got mixed yeah he punches the groom in the face no that's
not right away this is after a bit of back and forth tries to yes this is can I tell this
he punches the groom in the face and then he like he gets the ring and then he throws it
immediately like in front like in front of the wedding of the wedding yeah so the portal opens
up and the entire avalanche comes into the wedding and destroys the wedding not like these
not the entire avalanche enough of the avalanche to destroy the wedding like that was absolutely
fucking hilarious yeah there's some very clever very funny things that happened yeah yeah it was
pretty good yeah it was good but we were both screaming at Tom because we were alone in the
theater because it's such a late movie this kid's movie right there's no one there was dude it was
just us there was no one there it was just you and I and I was like is this even profitable for
these guys that's what they make the money off the popcorn oh yeah we had popcorn fuck
dude popcorn's expensive popcorn's expensive popcorn was always expensive holy shit dude
there's a cab showing up I guess someone else's we just got out yep all right so yeah um once
they get there uh the u.s government it turns out the wedding was actually a sham it was a catfish
operation it was called operation catfish and the the bride's um husband was actually secret agent
and the priest was secret agent and everyone's secret agent everyone was a secret agent and
they're all at the woman it's a woman yeah it's a misogynistic movie guys and they're all working
for gun now name we didn't care no i don't know gun is the guardian unit of nations from sonic
adventure 2 they're the ones that that that did like the whole uh space the space colony
arc and project shadow from sonic adventure 2 like they they have a big place in sonic lore
and so but they made fun of the name immediately like did you call yourself gun really i get
freaking he's like yeah why not but basically uh gun shows up kidnaps sonic entails and also
tom because tom tries to fight them like an idiot tom punches more people in the face because that's
the only thing he's really doing in this movie fucking up and punching people in the face
there's a bit of like a there's like a half action sequence trying to rescue them there's not much
of a one no no no the the action sequence is the two women who were part of the wedding party who
should have been incarcerated with everyone like with the men yeah they just get left to their own
devices so they have tails's technology and they use it to rescue them like by beating up all the
guards yeah they have tails in the backpack here's the thing it's because he i keep saying this they
didn't punch the gun members the way that tom did so they didn't get arrested the guy literally
said this is the last time you're gonna be uh hiding in a bedding an alien you know and then
only takes tom away i don't remember the wife's name you say bedding an alien i don't it's a
bedding not bedding i said a bedding no i i said a bedding i said it with a d oh bedding yeah
okay so anyway there's like a half action sequence that doesn't really go anywhere that where they
rescue they rescue everyone stupid they subdue them misogynistic it was a misogynist it was it
was why wasn't she incarcerated too because i'm just a girl anyway moving on stop thumping the
car you're making the camera move okay actually stop okay you know so what ends up happening
is sonic they're on they're on the shore of hawaii and they see a giant green beam off in the
distance and that's because on a neighboring island the the compass has taken eggman and
knuckles to the location of the master emerald yep and so they put the thing on and there's
a little like a little daze on the beach and they put it in and then like does this giant
uh moses thing where like the sea parts and there's a giant underwater temple yep because
it's under the sea yeah yeah under the sea it's like sure that would have been discovered before
but fine whatever so it's fine they you know what's funny though is that it wasn't even that
far under no it was like 10 feet under yeah it doesn't open that much yeah so the you know um
sonic is like i gotta fucking go over there she goes over there um almost dies almost has no way
but you guys over there and there's like a big sequence under in the temple where there's like
traps and goofiness yes but i i'm still indiana jones for kids i'm complaining because the temple
was dusty and there was roots yep from from plants from plants but it was underwater it was
underwater you know what's actually funny is that there was also plants i think you missed some of
there was also plants in the tunnel in the temple yeah in the tunnel yeah it's like okay but yeah
you know they're they're doing their thing they know their tropes okay fine um and then they get
to the the chamber of the master emerald yep and then sonic comes crashing through the roof
yeah accidentally he's like yeah the chamber somehow there's another sonic and knuckles fight
yep uh which gets interrupted by eggman seeing the emerald because he always was going to
sonic almost dies again yep but sonic rescues knuckles this time knuckles is sad because it
turns out eggman wasn't really his friend yeah they decided to all go and take on um
eggman together yep eggman um he returns to green hills yeah well after letting the emerald like
consume him oh yeah he comes not a different person but he becomes green instead of red
yeah he has like green like lightning bolt powers he's flying around like a god yeah he's doing like
a very god-like things yeah um so god eggman i guess we'll call him i don't know god eggman
works god eggman this is usually where you step in and call him a demigod he always correct me
on those it's god eggman yeah whenever i say he's a god right like oh he's a demigod he said about
sephiroth he said about the dragon spirits and skyward sword what else he said about like he's
a demigod not a god no because okay you know what never mind we'll have this discussion later
my fucking brain is dead from how loud the theater was
our theater's always been this loud i don't know but like when i'm fucking loud when i
myself like a little bit like a week two weeks ago yeah like it was loud like it was just like
in my movie it was quieter it was still really loud yeah so oh by the way just don't go see the
northman it's not that great you want to do a trailer talk in the northman no it's it's not
that great don't go see it okay so what ends up happening guys is they decide to go fight him
together and so tails like this all happens off screen but i think this is what happened
he steals the biplane that was used to fly through the wedding to like to like
rachel slash fiance's name for the number four forever yeah so tails takes the biplane upgrades
it with guns because it's tails and yet he has to he somehow had time to do that he has to have
a biplane yes it's tails it's tails always has a biplane yeah so and then they fly from hawaii
back to what the green hills with a biplane with with the ring that they somehow acquired
did they use the ring they used the ring they used the ring that they somehow acquired even though
son had lost all of this i think knuckles picked them up knuckles picked up all the rings i think
so i don't know because they fell off the cliff no no remember knuckles used a ring to get him
an eggman to the island maybe knuckles picked up his rings like who knows but anyway they have
some rings again whatever they they get back to green hills um and at that point eggman had
returned to green hills because his his uh backup base was that was the mean bean yeah coffee place
yeah and his his henchman is there just like playing playing a bunch of like just doing stuff
and eggman shows up he has like he has no technology anymore because all of his all of
his drones are fucked yeah but then he starts using the powers of the master emerald just to
suck in all the metal in the area so like trains and cars and tanks and stuff this is also yes the
the his base being surrounded by the government yep so he sucks everything all the metal in the
town in into one location yeah and he build and he uses the powers to build a giant mech yeah
and he starts fucking up the town with a giant mech and it's great and then uh sonic tails and
knuckles fly in it on the on the biplane they have their big giant fight it's a this big extended
action sequence um and then it turns out that the master emerald shatters after i think like
knuckles okay okay yeah knuckles punch okay after you know the the huge fight they all they all they
all get defeated by the mech and then you know they all group together and be like we have to
fight him together as a team and then they do and then knuckles punters after sonic distracts
eggman knuckles punches the emerald out of eggman's chest not in a bloody way just
to the chest and emerald comes out the back and then so the mech falls the emerald falls sonic
ends up dragging his half dead body over to it making this a lot more graphic than it actually
so but here's the thing the emerald shatters the emerald the master emerald breaks yes and inside
the master emerald are the seven chaos emeralds yes and i'm just like you have a huge grape
wood i do because the seven chaos emeralds are a different thing than the goddamn master emerald
they are different things but in this movie they're the same thing so the master emerald
breaks it turns out the seven chaos emeralds on the side of it it turns out sonic we already knew
the seven chaos technically inside yeah they mentioned it very early on yeah they got they
got a throwaway line about it yeah um and i was like what the fuck um but then sonic uses the
the the stop shaking the goddamn car jesus sonic uses the um master emerald sorry the chaos emerald
to become supersonic he destroys eggman's mech um eggman somehow gets away of course he does he
didn't they couldn't find his body in the big collapse no no you forgot the most important
part sonic becomes ultimate sonic i said that supersonic oh yeah i didn't hear it you said
ultimate in the theater so i assumed that's what the name was he he uses these i didn't say
he uses the seven chaos emeralds to become supersonic which is the just a super saiyan
super saiyan it's like dragon ball super saiyan but yeah you know what the fuck it is okay so
um everyone but me and then when the power runs out the emeralds scatter because they're
basically dragon balls they scatter um and then they're like well i guess we'll just all live in
green hills now and they do and then actually this is after knuckles somehow fixes the master
emerald with his hands oh he could do that in the games too that's actually fine he just goes
and then it's fine yeah yep and the math but here's the thing he fixes the master emerald
without having seven chaos emeralds in it so it still has some power but it's not the same thing
like i don't know yeah so in in the original continuity um the master emerald kept the
floating island floating yeah and it could also be used to regulate the powers of the seven chaos
emeralds but it was never required to have the master emerald to to become supersonic or to
become no i'm hyper knuckles or any other super forms um jesus christ i fucking remember all this
shit i remember all this shit when i was a kid okay anyway the end of the movie they all live
happily ever after in green hills till the next movie yeah and um including like like tails
knuckles just move in with them i guess they're just all hanging out now they're all kids now oh
and the pivotal emotional moment is when sonic calls tom dad yeah you're my dad and he's like
my son's a freak my son's a fucking alien no it is this is clark kent superman shit this is an
him and his wife are totally fine with it i don't even remember the wife's name
i don't actually think they imagine i'm just surprised that she's black why um because you
don't usually see a white guy with a black girl in like in hollywood yeah but they're trying to
change that now because wokeness yeah which is i i you know what i mean i guess yes okay
non-white guys with white girls that's wokeness white guys with non-white girls that's just based
i'm trolling i'm trolling i swear to god yeah so anyway anyway um the the post credit sequence
is is are the gun guys cleaning up the eggman mess yep and they discover there's a a secret
black site research facility where for 50 years they've been building shadow shadow with a quick
cameo from dr eggman's assistant so we know that dr eggman's definitely alive yeah definitely yeah
um and and here's the thing i said this to you in the in the theater um the story of sonic
adventure 2 which is the shadow story is predicated on sonic adventure 1 yeah because
sonic adventure 1 was was the story of the ancient echidnas and how they had this they fought this um
this primordial this primordial god inside the master emerald called i think it's called chaos
he's like he's like a blue goo man and when he absorbs when he absorbs um emeralds he becomes
stronger and then by the end of the game um there's a giant chaos monster destroying the city
and like millions are dead because it's like flooded and there's like it's fucking awful
and you play super sonic and you and you defeat them i think they just switched it for the owls
yeah but this like if they had actually made sonic adventure the movie that would have been
fucking amazing probably because that game was actually really good it was like it's probably
the best sonic game i think um and then sonic adventure 2 is a direct sequel where the idea
is that robotnik's grandfather was in charge of a satellite um a a space colony called called
space colony arc and they were they were using the knowledge of chaos that the echidnas had
to like they were making like false chaoses to use them as like like weapons um and they but
also at the same time uh they were i think were they trying to clone sonic but basically they
they ended up making shadow as as an experiment with with the emeralds and shadow is just as fast
as sonic he is he's basically what knuckles should have been like you know the coil he's he's just
emo sonic and everyone loves him yes and then he also like falls in love with a human woman
no what happens is um princess nope okay nope so what happens is um this is a robotnik's grandfather
was running the whole project yeah and she he had a daughter and this daughter was growing up
on the space station and she and shadow were friends yep but when they shut the project down
because the chaos creatures went out of control um gun basically went up there and purged everyone
and killed everyone yeah and shadow she like shadow uh was locked away by her i think and so
he was put into a tube for 50 years and she got like all she riddled up with bullets she was
fucking destroyed she was just shot shot the fuck up it was kind of a tragic scene actually um and
then shadow's like you know what i'm just gonna kill all of humanity fuck all of you look what you
fuck you you killed my only friend fuck you that's getting a good villain origin story i'm okay with
that yeah and and what ends up happening is like um in sonic adventure 2 robotnik like turns good
because he's like maybe we should maybe you know okay i mean my grandfather was kind of terrible
because my grandfather after like the grandfather after seeing his daughter died he like he's he
set up a whole bunch of shit that went down 50 years later to try and destroy the world
and robotics like maybe i should stop this so he like helps out robotnik turns good finally
which is not that common in the series actually but he turned good this time oh that's gonna be
weird for them to do that because robotic is like really evil he's really evil he's like he's
significantly more evil than the games like he he's not just like yeah i like was kind of like
uh this not a shitty scientist but i was a misunderstood scientist and now i'm just also
a mad scientist no like he's he's a mad scientist he's he's he's he's chaotic evil
he's actually he's still very funny though he's really goofy like jim carrey does a really good
job yeah i like it a lot he did a great job in the first we did a great job in this movie it's
funny it's really funny when i heard that jim carrey was going to be dr robonic i don't know
that that like to be fair i don't know that much about sonic but from like the little bit i do know
i was like that's gonna be fucking awful like it was actually really good he did such a good job
also because like robotics fat and he's not fat but it's like whatever yeah it doesn't matter
too much yeah it kind of matters but not really like it here's the thing here's the thing they're
still using all like the imagery and everything yeah and and and the thing is if he had done a
bad job i probably matter about the not fat thing but he did such a good job it is such a good job
so there's there's like um there's there's probably the funniest line i think is when
like he's flying around like a god inside of the mech and his assistant who's in like a pilot seat
or like the co-pilot seat is like sir you're magnificent and he's like thank you sycophant
yeah your admiration was inevitable and i was like yes like he just renames his lackey there
yeah to like like he has like all these different names for him you just they're all insulting yeah
and we're pretty sure that the lackey's in love with him but we're not entirely sure
yeah like there's there's a there's a lot of one-way homoeroticism coming from the lackey
towards robotnik yeah and robotic doesn't even care he like he doesn't like abuse him or anything
necessarily but he's like he doesn't even notice that it's happening yeah he doesn't even know
he's a giant fucking narcissist like yeah of course people love him i love me everyone loves me
yeah if you don't i'll just kill you
yeah so it it turns out that they're going to be doing for for the third movie they're going to do
shadow story shadow story from sonic adventure 2 which i think is not gonna work out unless they
somehow do sonic adventure 1 at the same time because this movie kind of did do sonic 2 and 3
and knuckles all at the same time yeah so maybe they could do like they could do like the first
act of the movie is them going to be explaining maybe sonic adventures and then they're going to
move on maybe i don't know because that's how we know that's how it's going to work because they
have like they didn't even explain tails that's how it's going to work yeah i guess they didn't
explain fucking anything if if there is a detriment to this movie it's how little things
are explained but that's because it's a kid's movie yeah and also because it's a movie and
they were going to run out of time yeah yeah they could have done like a tails movie then a knuckles
movie they didn't have them do knuckles in the third and then the second one they can do in the
third one you know they could have figured it out they could have spread out the material to be
honest maybe they were afraid that they like it wouldn't like get trashing because like prequels
generally don't do as well as i wonder how this one's doing sorry sequels don't generally do as
well as the first first movie so i wonder how well this one's gonna do well i guess we'll find out
yeah when all the internet because like it's kind of funny because because this is going out of
theaters this week is this final week yeah yeah that's why i suggested we go yeah yeah so there
is a wider conversation here where like do you recall the backlash against like star wars and
people because they're all terrible yeah including episode seven was okay episodes eight and nine
were both fucking awful yeah and people are like here's a misogynist here's because there's a girl
and it's like no no no no you can have a girl in star wars i don't fucking care
there's leia like who fucking cares no it's because they're bad yeah that's the problem
is that they're they were just bad movies yeah and that was it yep um these aren't bad
oh hold on though okay okay i'm waiting i'm like that what i'm getting to what i'm getting to
is that there has there has this there's this growing feeling of
partial disdain for your own audience in hollywood so so the situation is something like
oh i have this vision for for for star wars and so i'm gonna make the movies that i want to make
and then the audience feedback comes in and they fucking hate it and they're like well fuck you
you're just a misogynist and it's like well maybe or maybe your movie is bad and maybe you should
kind of figure it out yeah now there are a few movies that buck the trend because joker was
beloved and people fucking there was there was like weird progressives or beloved oh isn't it
the same thing i don't think it is okay well in any case you know what i mean there were like
weird progressives when joker came out saying like this is just a this is just a a movie that
lionizes white male rage and it's like shut the fuck up you're so jesus christ you're so stupid
you don't understand anything about anything just fucking eat a bullet okay um in minecraft okay um
in minecraft okay um and then there was sonic because i don't know if you did you see like the
the first leaks of the sonic movie and how fucking awful it looked yeah i did yeah yeah
yeah no i remember that everyone knows about that if you don't know about that you literally don't
have the internet like it was everywhere and people are like what the fuck like this looks
fucking terrible and then the company was like you know what okay we'll fix it yep well fair enough
and then they did right before the movie came out there were people who were saying
do not do not give in to the fans what do they they are entitled spoiled fucking misogynist
you know fucking reactionary brats do not give make the movie that you want to make don't give
them don't do what the fans want you to do and the song the the the uh the whoever made this
movie i don't know who they were they um they said how about we actually do what the fans want
and then the movie came out and it was a hit because it didn't look awful and i remember
that i sonic looked like a terrible stuffed like like what an off-brand stuffed animal
would look like if they had made that as a sonic doll and and and what's what's funny is like
this i think it's partially because the fans finally felt listened to the for the first time
in a while yeah this is like single-handedly revived sonic oh yeah 100 yeah like sonic was
a dead franchise there's no making games they all sucked like sonic forces sucked
um all sonic games are bad you've heard it here first that's not true that's not true
like recent sonic games have not been so good and sonic forces was absolutely fucking terrible
people had basically like sonic ever since like sonic heroes sonic has been known as this fucking
failed franchise and it's been like 20 games since sonic heroes there's been like two good ones
two or three um and then sonic forces come out and it was fucking trash and then people are just
like sonic is just fucking disgusting and then but this this this this movie was i don't know
how much money the first one made but it was so culturally successful that it basically revived
the sonic brand yeah and now we have a second movie and the second movie is it's still good
would you say is as good as the first i actually i would say this time it's about on par with the
first i'm i think i'm gonna say about on par um it like it sequels always tend to be it was a little
less you know some of the emotional moments didn't hit as hard you think so yeah because
because it was about um him tom it was about him and tom bonding and like sonic like
reaching adulthood you know but like coming like coming into his own after being on his own for so
long then in this movie he's still not on his own because he's uh he's like family but like tom just
wanted him to have like more people to hang out with other than just his parents yeah because he
can't go outside like he's a fucking alien yeah exactly yeah so then that that's more or less what
this movie was about but it didn't i feel like it didn't quite touch on that enough slash hard
enough slash hard enough slash hard enough slash hard yeah i couldn't make that into a proper
sentence there you go um so yeah yeah i think it's worth seeing if you like the first one oh
yeah definitely if you like the first one was good if you like the first one uh definitely watch this
one just remember that if you haven't seen the first one well obviously if you want like the
sonic lore to be exact you know it's not gonna be but it's fine it's still a good movie it's still
a good yeah just don't forget that it is specifically for like it's definitely catered to
children yeah yes like if you're a parent and you have like a nine-year-old that likes sonic they're
gonna love the shit out of it oh yeah they're gonna love it and watch it forever and that's
what you're gonna be watching for the next uh month two months about two months maybe three
maybe six maybe six happier maybe maybe until the next sonic movie comes out yeah you know
maybe yeah yeah so since jim carrey's retiring oh no i mean how what are you gonna do for sonic 3
they might get him back for sonic 3 yeah because here's the thing i heard that like
i kept i kept hearing that like jim carrey just wanted out of hollywood because it fucking sucked
yeah but he actually like he liked the robotnik role yeah and he was having fun with it he was
definitely having fun with it like i i didn't feel like he was a little slightly less funny
this time i said that in the theater i felt like it felt slightly less like the because in the
first movie jim carrey was definitely like jim carrying it up you know like he was being jim
care it was just funny this one it was just funny i but it definitely felt like he was kind of like
i want to say holding himself back a little bit for the character to come through a little more
you think so he's definitely still had his like jim carrie isms jim carrie isms jim carrie isms in
it you know it's still really good i'm not saying he wasn't funny it just like it felt like it felt
it felt slightly different from the first movie yeah and then to be honest i don't know if i agree
with you but i still like it i honestly probably have to watch them back to back because it's
actually let's go watch it again no it's been a while since i've seen the first one so i might
be totally wrong to be fair but you know yep so yeah yeah um is there anything else you want to
say about sonic 2 that's good are we gonna see the third one yeah when it comes out i want to
see emo sonic oh i'm ready i'm ready all right give me my lovable villain yeah so um i think the
first one of these trailer talks will come out on the main channel just to kind of kick start the
series again but the rest of them from now on if we keep doing more they're gonna go on finally
the dev kit channel is finally opening up i have that intro made by butters everything is good to
go so we're gonna probably do more of these over on that channel so make sure you sub to it okay
oh you you're just gonna like make that your your reviewing channel ish yeah the dev kit okay the
dev kit channel is going to be my non-political channel where i put whatever the fuck i want
boomers that was the gaming channel okay the dev kit is going to be like give me some tech stuff
there so guys you've heard it here games and politics are intrinsically linked stay tuned
interestingly linked i can't say that word intrinsically intrinsically listen listen i can't
say it dev kit is going to be just for is going to be for um non-political reviews is going to be
for stuff like this is going to be for unboxings new equipment is going to be for tech teardowns
is going to be for just that's gonna be like my personal channel basically i thought game boomers
was your personal channel that's the gaming channel fuck okay listen we're gonna get out
of here thanks go watch sonic it's pretty good um go actually watch it and not just pirate it
yeah i guess it's worth it it's worth it yeah it's it's it's a little bit worth your money
um i might just i might just wait till it till it comes out like not in theaters because man
theater's still fucking so even we had it to ourselves ourselves it was so loud though i
don't know how many of you have been to a theater it was so loud i haven't no i i i i don't miss the
theater going experience now that we've done this i slightly enjoyed just because we were
by ourselves i liked you know i like getting i like getting theater popcorn i just like it
there's literally nothing else like it you want to go into like a packed theater and be like
no be like elbow to elbow with some fucking fat greasy loser who's like eating a whole
fucking pizza just i was fuck you i didn't get pizza yeah like dude theaters are fucking
disgusting at this point fuck well that's why we have the theater to ourselves yeah it's quite
nice yeah right late night shows guys if you slightly i still don't know why despite you
having the whole you had the whole theater you still had to get like we had to still like rub
elbows in there oh my god my boyfriend is complaining that we had to sit beside each
other one seat in between to like put our stuff in you know yeah stuff just goes beside you fine
no hand holding for you fuck you i'm putting my seat belt on and drive it away listen if there
were like two arm rests nope then it'd be makes sense but no this is car talks we're done car
talks is that the name of the show now car talks all right guys we'll see you next time thanks for
watching fuck