I
Just finished watching one of these most recent videos and in it he said something very interesting. So let's watch together
I just finished watching short fat otaku's latest video and
In it, he played the clip of wash that I found to be very interesting. So let's watch it together
Call it selling out your principles. I call it winning and
And that's my principle to win as a socialist not to lose as a socialist
Hey funny how that all turns out
I wonder how many times I can layer the parasite Eve background music before it becomes unrecognizable
But the part of these video that got me thinking was when he described how if you're a known liar and suddenly need other people
To believe you you're pretty much screwed
He mentioned a few examples like how British and German pilots during the Second World War would refrain from shooting enemies who were parachuting down
From a damaged plane as an unwritten sign of respect while when Soviet pilots took no such mercy the Germans stopped doing it with them
He also mentioned the tranquil monk who is capable of fighting but would never be the one to throw the first punch
Well, I was watching this video. I started thinking about a conversation. I had a few months ago with a particularly recalcitrant
He's been banned oh wait, he's he's a punished variant now the tweets are gone though
It doesn't matter because if you hung around progressives for any amount of time
You'll understand the argument even without being able to see it the position
This guy held is that people's lives are obviously worth more than property
So when a burglar breaks into your house to steal your stuff
You don't have the right to use force on him in defense of your property
In fact, it's murder if you do because theft of property is not so horrible as killing somebody
I've noticed that when dealing with progressive ethics, the problem isn't that they're wrong
Obviously somebody's life is worth more than an animate object
The problem is that they reach a shallow conclusion that fits their politics and then they stop thinking they don't continue to dig for the
Real answer you can find progressives all over the internet exposing this position
What's more important is the reply given by me and others to his nonsense the general consensus is
Defending your family from an unknown intruder is more important than calling the police and huddling in a corner like a cuck waiting for them
to arrive or
Alternatively trying to do an accurate threat assessment and de-escalate the situation as he pulls out a gun and puts a bullet in your stupid
Ass when you don't know what he's there to do the worst-case scenario isn't that you're measuring your property against his life
It's that you're measuring the lives of everybody else in the house against his and in that case the choice becomes clear
But because commies like to lionize poor burglars as being victims of the system which to be fair
They sometimes are the burglars actions have to be inherently morally virtuous and therefore you must be in the wrong to protect your stuff
So let's give the progressive the benefit of the doubt
Let's say that the home intruder is absolutely only there to steal your stuff and let's say somehow
You know this are you still justified in using force to stop him even if that means he might end up dead
I remember when I was a child and I first learned about Gandhi and his nonviolent resistance
How he managed to expel the British from India and secure his country's freedom using nonviolent methods
I remember as a kid how heroic that sounded it sounded virtuous
High-minded that his people would allow themselves to be struck down by their occupiers until they couldn't stand to do it anymore
It still sounds miraculous even as an adult but obviously less
So do you think if India were occupied by Nazis or Soviets Gandhi's tactics would have worked?
Of course not those tactics relied on the basic human decency of the British the Nazis and Soviets would have literally just killed them all
Until there was not a single Indian left
I ended up losing a lot of respect for Gandhi as I got older because the only thing we can truly learn from his story
Is that violence is bad and sure but that doesn't tell us when it's appropriate or not to use it
That's a much harder question and Gandhi's answer was to ignore it
It's the difference between Chamberlain's appeasement of Germany and Churchill's willingness to fight them that plus when he started launching nukes and civilization
I figured Gandhi's day was over the answer to that question that our progressive friend here provides with his corn kernel brain
Is that you should never risk anybody's life except to save other lives
No violence unless in response to somebody else's violence and it sounds good when you say it like that
It provokes a righteous moral response on the surface of your personality
You can feel really good about and pat yourself in the back and say look how much more civilized I am than these plebs
But it's not deep enough. It's not right enough
There's more thinking to do than simply what feels good and gets you Twitter likes from your friends
Let's say a police officer sees somebody breaking into a house through a window
The officer should stop the thief with as much force as is required
Even if he might get killed even if the thief is only stealing jewelry and not actually hurting anybody because if nobody ever so much
As inconveniences the thieves there will simply be more thieves and the fabric of society breaks down
It becomes a far worse world to live in where you can't trust your fellow man or the institutions meant to protect you or the possibility
That you could work hard and save for the future
If bad people are willing to risk violence to get what they want and good people always stand down because violence is bad
Then bad people always win this can be explained reasonably enough by game theory true to its name game theory is the study of
Strategic interactions between rational decision-makers in areas with set rules and values aka games its application ranges from biology to sociology
To math to computer science as it applies to animals to humans to artificial intelligence and even just to regular
Non-intelligent computer programs if something has a goal a pathway to get it and other agents with goals and pathways to contend with you can
Apply game theory the home defense situation is best modeled by Hawks and doves
I'll leave a link to a video by primer explaining it in detail how it works. You really should watch it
It's probably better than anything I've made on YouTube, but here's the basic idea
You've got a limited amount of food and you've got two creatures Hawks and doves Hawks fight doves
Don't when two does both attempt to get the same piece of food
They split so each dove gets half of the food when a dove and a hawk both attempt to get a piece of food
The Hawk bullies the dove so that the Hawk gets all the food and the dove gets none of it when two Hawks both attempt
To get the same piece of food they fight over it fighting incurs a cost
So they each get half of the food minus the cost we can sort the interactions like this Hawk and Hawk
They each get food divided by two minus cost dove and dove
They each get food divided by two Hawk and dove the Hawk gets all the food the dove gets nothing
So if these are the rules of the game
What should you play as a hawk or a dove?
You might be tempted to choose dove because you're a pacifist cuck or Hawk because you're a Chad
But the most optimum strategy actually depends on what either players are playing
For example, if it's just you and I and I choose dove
You're better off choosing Hawk because then you can take everything from me every time we encounter each other
But if I'm playing a hawk then it depends if the cost of fighting is high enough that food divided by two
Minus cost is lower than zero
You're actually better off playing a dove because if I'm a hawk when we encounter each other you'll end up in a better position as
A dove instead of a hawk and we can keep tweaking these variables to see what kind of hypothetical
Society of Hawks and doves we get for example
If there's no cost of fighting at all Hawks will always drive doves to extinction
Inversely if there's an extremely high cost to Hawks fighting each other higher than having the food stolen from you as a dove then doves will
Drive the Hawks to extinction or rather the Hawks will destroy themselves and the doves will move into the space left behind
but what you'll find is no matter how you adjust the variables the population of Hawks and doves will always eventually reach an
Equilibrium where the population will sustain itself based on how advantageous it is to either fight or cooperate
The real world is obviously a lot more complicated than this
But the game of Hawks and doves can be applied to any social interaction where there is risk and reward
Associated with both fight and flight and the lesson we can take away is if a society is set up such that theft is more
Profitable than reaction to theft is detrimental then that society will be overrun by thieves and in case you think I'm just babbling a whole bunch
Of theory out my ass and that has no application in the real world
We are already seeing this play out in real time back in 2014
California reclassified shoplifting valued at
$950 or less from a felony to a misdemeanor and
Unsurprisingly shoplifting has increased videos routinely go viral of people stealing just under that amount knowing that security guards won't stop them
Cops won't be called and if the cops are called a misdemeanor isn't exactly high priority if a society makes the punishment for stealing this
Low if it's more profitable to steal than to work
Honestly people will steal and if enough people are stealing and not working then they're not producing
Meaning that there's nothing left to steal and eventually society collapses the counter-argument to this is that society can sometimes make theft too
Punishing or innocence can get swept up in the hysteria of crime fighting and that can happen
But firstly that's no reason to swing across to the other extreme to say theft is good
Actually, especially from the crowd that says that employment and profit are theft and secondly
It's been my experience that radicals of all types progressive and reactionary left and right doesn't matter
They completely forget about the existence of the golden mean yes a society that is too strict is bad
But so is a society that's too lax when a libertarian says government regulation makes everything worse in all possible
Situations and the socialist says that the free market leads to ruin in all possible situations. They're both making the same mistake
They're ignoring the golden mean government can ruin things the free market can ruin things, too
But it doesn't necessarily have to be that way and the same goes for theft and law enforcement
All of this being said if you wake up in the middle of the night and hear a burglar prowling around
You're probably not thinking any of this extended political stuff
You're probably thinking about how to defend your family, which means you're thinking about game theory
Even if you don't know it
You don't know if the burglar is a hawk or a dove so your response will be based on the cost of fighting if the burglar
Is a dove and regardless of the cost of fighting you should be a hawk because if you fight the burglar will give up or run
Away, if the burglar is a hawk then suddenly it becomes unknown what you should do if you're a dove
Will the burglar just take your stuff and leave or will he kill you?
Will he kill everybody else in the house? If you're a hawk, what will be the cost of fighting with another hawk?
It's all entirely unknown
But one thing becomes clear the possibility of losing everything not just your stuff
But your life your family's life if you choose to play as a dove is
On the table if the cost of playing as a dove versus a hawk is higher than the maximum possible
Cost of two hawks fighting then regardless of the damage you both might do being a hawk is always the better choice
In other words in a room full of doves hawks to stabilize things
But in a room full of hawks being a hawk is your only shot at survival and in a room full of unknowns in almost every
Situation it's better to be a hawk progressives. Just don't think this way
They say what sounds good and moral and will get their friends to accept them
But they don't really go beyond that and you know what I can make a good solid
Moral argument for home defense to people in the house depend on me and defending them is more important
My property represents the labor I perform to build or buy it making me a slave you steal it from me
But I don't even need to appeal to morality to refute the progressive position even in the most rational
Scientific materialist view of things which I'm sure the Prague will appreciate more than something like honor as long as you have others depending on
You whose lives mean more to you than your own
It will always be more worth it to defend them than to risk them the mindset of the person who thinks otherwise
Seems to be the mindset of the person who doesn't have anybody that they view as worth defending