Sup guys, this is just a short update video letting you all know what's going on.
Our channel is going on a short hiatus until June 1st.
The truth of it is, we've had a run of disasters that have made working on the channel next
to impossible.
The main reason we've been putting out as many Rogue Legacy videos as we have over the
past couple weeks is because we've been having computer problems and the Rogue Legacy stuff
was the only thing ready to go before our editing PC started acting up.
And I'm sure you've noticed the lack of anime reviews and gamergate videos, considering
we wanted more of both to come out at the beginning of May and they've yet to happen.
On top of the hardware problems, Kain went through a pretty bad breakup about 3 weeks
ago, she's pretending like it's not affecting her much but I know better, Dave was completely
unable to help until just a couple weeks ago due to his exam schedule, and we've had some
pretty major things happen to the house that we've had to take care of.
All really boring life stuff, but it's made keeping up with our stuff on YouTube pretty
much impossible.
So we're taking a 5 day uploading break until June 1st, to let us catch up.
On June 1st, No Talent Gaming returns with Mario Sunshine and Pokemon Soul Silver Ball
Lock, again on a twice a day upload schedule.
The next gamergate video will come out, come hell or high water, on Wednesday, June 3rd.
And the new anime review, Devil is a part timer, will be out the following Wednesday,
June 10th.
I'm sorry for the wait and for the disappointment, SF Bros.
I hope you understand, and look forward to us returning in a few days.