It's a pretty funny meme, but I feel that much of the humor comes from the source rather
than the meme itself.
I haven't seen too much variability beyond just changing location, but overall it's
a decent meme.
And it's pretty funny, but each version feels a little interchangeable, this time on the
editing end.
Each of these memes feels more or less the same.
This meme is sort of the converse of the Drake and Josh one, and it gets the same score.
I really like this meme.
It has many different iterations, and I really enjoy how it deconstructs the nature of argumentation
on the internet.
It's pretty much the most you can expect from an image meme.
Oh wow, a low-effort Twitter meme about aging.
Oh wow, a low-effort Twitter meme about stars falling on a character.
Oh wow, a low-effort relatable Twitter meme that's literally just another screenshot
from the same SpongeBob episode as Savage Patrick, literally the same scene.
Just stop, okay?
All this millennial humor or whatever the fuck you people call it is painfully unfunny.
Ooh, when you drop your iPhone X in the Starbucks room, it's so relatable.
Fuck this generation.
Enough is enough!
This meme is just annoying.
Not funny, not clever, just annoying.
Normies seem to love this meme, and they have forced it to Ellen show levels of popularity.
Shut up!
This meme has basically just changed my mind, but for Tumblr people, whatever.
This meme is alright.
It's a pretty clever way of portraying the idea of an ulterior killer through various
situations.
I wouldn't be surprised if Eric Andre memes continue to rise in the future.
This is an interesting little crypto meme that has stayed pretty underground so far.
It has a low risk of overexposure, and I'm interested to see whether this meme will continue
to develop or just fade away.
For now, it's a B-.
AHHH!
Oh!
Well, that's all the memes for April.
Some good, some not so good.
Were there any that I missed?
Probably.