Alright my friends, it's time to talk about the coronavirus again because this is a story and a virus that just won't die
official number of confirmed cases as of as a recording is 31,530 with
31,213 of those happening on mainland China because of travel bans and so forth
There's no way places like Japan or Thailand or Singapore are still taking in people who have coronavirus from China
So the disease is probably taking hold in those locations
Locally as in being transferred person to person there
Maybe not so much in in the West as you can see Italy has three
UK Russia Canada with seven France with six and the honest truth is regardless of how you feel about the the Canadian medical
Establishment or the American medical establishment the West is generally more able to handle this sort of thing than a place like China
Now the Japanese numbers have been weirdly fluctuating all day and that's because there's actually
60 people aboard a Japanese cruise ship and coronavirus is aboard the ship
So they've basically just anchored the ship out in the middle of the ocean and they're they're quarantining the whole thing
So for a while the Japanese numbers were slightly inflated, but they're actually just off the coast and they're not really in Japan technically
So fair enough, but the ship has 3,700 people
Because one guy from Hong Kong has the virus on the ship
But it's not just cruise ship shenanigans that are causing a weird fluctuations in numbers
Here's some data from a hospital in Wuhan and because the text is rather small and there's quite a bit here
I'll just sum it up for you nearly one in three patients at this Wuhan Hospital our healthcare workers themselves
So doctors and nurses, you know
you assume the people that are able to maybe wear face masks or or work with the sick with as little chance as possible of
Getting getting infected at least compared to a regular person who's working with the sick
They're still getting infected at a rate of twenty nine percent
That's almost one in three and since we're on the topic of the numbers
We have to talk about the elephant in the room and at the same time
This is a weird link with the the whole gaming blizzard a China story from a few months ago
Tencent may have accidentally leaked real data on the Wuhan virus deaths tencent briefly listed
154,000 and 23 infections and
Twenty four thousand five hundred and eighty nine deaths from the coronavirus as many experts
Question the veracity of China's statistics for the Wuhan coronavirus outbreak tencent over the weekend appeared to inadvertently release
What is potentially the actual number of infections and deaths which are far higher than the official figures?
But eerily in line with predictions from a respected scientific journal. They actually did this three times
I don't know if it's like a disgruntled employee or something or someone who wants to get the
Message out to the rest of the world of what's going on with the coronavirus or who knows it could be a hoax
They could always be a hoax, right?
but the fact that it happened three separate times and that it's in line with the outside estimates of the
Transmissibility of this thing it makes you think also to be honest as anyone is anyone seriously trusting China at this point
Come on, guys, come on
I mean
We already know that China spent the crucial first days of the Wuhan coronavirus outbreak arresting people who posted about it online and threatening
Journalists no one is surprised that China would lie regarding the official numbers and we are really seeing the power of the Chinese
Surveillance state at work here. If you have a Wuhan ID, even if you fled before the lockdown you're doomed
No hotels will allow you in no petrol station will sell gas to you
If you go to a Beijing hospital with a Wuhan ID, you will be pushed away. What can you do?
And do you remember when we all said that the Chinese social credit score system was a terrible idea and you know all the far
Leftist idiots in the West really really wanted one here
This is what you would fucking get if that's what happened
You would get this monstrous system where you can be tracked anywhere you are and should the government turn tyrannical enough
They will most certainly use it against you
Of course information is not the only thing being quarantined Guangzhou City
14 million population is now locked down all residential blocks are isolated from each other so far around
400 million people are locked down in China to contain the coronavirus
It's not a lockdown at this point then like you might as well lock down the entire country or the entire planet
However, despite the People's Republic of China's best efforts
Information is still getting out
There are still Chinese people who want freedom or at the very least want the world to know what's going on
I'm not gonna play these videos at length because I'm sure we've all seen them at this point
They've been floating around and going viral or repeatedly constantly
You've got videos of doctors talking about the actual grim situation
Testimonies of how people are just lying around hospital hallways or corpses are being burned in mass
You've got videos of people being stopped by the police then their ID checked
Then they're gathered up and forced into quarantine and despite China's tendency to
basically save face and not talk about the truth at all whenever something goes down an official told the New York Times that China is
Treating the situation as if it were wartime conditions
And if that's what the official party line is, you know, it has to be way worse than that
And if it's way worse than wartime conditions man, things have to be bad over there even the Global Times
China's official mouthpiece in the West is bracing Western industry and Western economy for a pretty big downturn in production
Due to the corona virus they have to know this is gonna seriously affect them even the WHO
Which to be honest is pretty much bought by China at this point has finally admitted that it made a massive mistake in downplaying
the corona virus
Everyone's finally coming together and saying no no, this is serious everyone but the social justice warriors
Of course, we live in Toronto where the SARS virus got world-scale attention
That's because the only people who died outside of Asia from that virus were in Canada and most of them were in Toronto with only
44 people dying in total in Canada. It had a huge impact on our city. We lost a lot of tourism
We lost millions of dollars, but most importantly we saw a lot of stigma and racism towards Chinese people
It's important that we do not repeat those racist notions that happened here in Toronto and we all need to be aware of this
When we talk about the current corona virus
We need to listen to and trust public health professionals and we need to not overreact and we need to not use this as an excuse
To be racist. Yeah, it's racism. That's it
I mean Chinese isn't a race and we're not talking about the race of people
We're talking about the cultural practice of eating animals that probably shouldn't be eaten by humans
Because they're going to transmit to us some pretty terrible rare diseases, but forget about that
It's all just racism and you better shut up
I bet if you told a social justice warrior about China's actual racism their heads would probably explode
I
There's a reason that Finn was kept off the Star Wars posters, you know, but you know what China Daily is reporting that
traditional Chinese medicine is
Actually effective at treating the corona virus snort the rhino horn powder you bigot
Okay, we've kind of been goofing around so far
But let's actually talk about some serious science here at least as far as a layman like me can understand it
There is still the theory floating around that the corona virus is
Somehow linked to the Chinese bioweapon program that actually had labs in Wuhan. It's possible
I don't think it's likely but it's possible
additionally people are starting to lose their minds over this paper that came out of India recently where they basically said that they were
studying the corona virus and they discovered that there are some protein sequences or something that are similar or
Identical to the ones found in HIV and in fact because of this some HIV
Medication might actually be effective at combating the corona virus
This doesn't necessarily mean that the virus itself is a modified form of HIV nor does it mean that it's just as potent or?
Deadly or scary or whatever because to be honest even from a layman's perspective like mine
I'm pretty sure that there's a lot of things in the natural world that that at least share some protein sequences
It could quite literally be random chance and this might mean nothing but hey it might not
Especially since it came out that an infant in Wuhan has tested positive for coronavirus just 30 hours after birth
It could be the case that they simply got an infection from being in the hospital where there might have been
Coronavirus patients there or it might actually be the case that the infection could be contracted in the womb at the same time
I'm actually curious to see what the racial makeup is of
People who have contracted the corona virus outside of China because there also seems to be some evidence that Asians are actually at a much
Higher risk of contracting it though
I'm sure just
Asking that question probably makes me a racist somehow even as the scientists do their thing the rest of us just seem to be spinning
off into crazy town for example
Horseback knight in armor guards the entrance to a Chinese village in bid to stop anyone with coronavirus
from bringing in the infection
Holy shit
Look at this guy
This is some Dark Souls shit here, dude
Don't drink bleach
Four myths about the corona virus and how to spot them was somebody even trying to drink
Did someone actually say hey, you know what I got the coronavirus
You'll just clean it out of me. I crossed off China and changed it to Hong Kong
Chinese student brags about sneaking into Australia
This is just as bad as that woman who went to Paris earlier
These people honestly need to be charged with like spreading a bioterrorist weapon or some shit
This is getting ridiculous woman frightens rapist by coughing and saying she was from Wuhan
The would-be rapist was deterred by the possible threat of corona
Take that rape culture eat the bat soup you bigot and here's one from my home of Canada infect me daddy
Queen's University student trustee resigns after attending coronavirus party
Students at the virus theme party drank corona beer and wore face masks
You know if this student did this back in the 2000s
He could have gone on to have a stunning political career like after Justin Trudeau's blackface
Chinese sex workers say they are being discriminated against because of corona virus and have forced to slash their rates by half
Listen, I've said it like three times this video already. You have to eat the bat soup, especially if it's if it's in her vagina
Okay
Okay, let's get serious for a bit the corona virus whistleblower
Doctor dies sparking an outpouring as well as censorship on Chinese social media
Li Wen Lang was the first leaker of knowledge of the corona virus and it turns out in his efforts to help people recover from
It he has since died
He was one of eight whistleblowers who were reprimanded by Chinese State Police for allegedly spreading illegal and false
Information about the virus on Weibo the Chinese government's official social media platform
The hashtag I want freedom of speech started trending and it was very quickly censored
However, this is the latest news on Li Wen Lang because this is a just updated four hours ago. It's from today
He actually died several days ago
However, again in order for the Chinese government to save face
He was put on life support and the media was forced to change its reporting including apparently
BBC Chinese
Isn't the BBC funded by the UK not the Chinese state nonetheless?
They changed their reporting from dead to critically ill. Holy fuck if there was ever a reason to defund the BBC
This would be it, isn't it?
You know on the one hand you have a lot of people who are saying
That this is gonna be the next black plague
This is gonna be the next Spanish flu that there's gonna be millions
There's gonna be millions dead
Humanity is gonna be cold like half of us are all gonna die or some crazy nonsense
And then there's the other half who are saying that it's just a cold, bro
You shouldn't worry about it that all this reporting doesn't matter
That all this BS is just people stirring up trouble scare mongering, etc
I actually am taking a middle approach to this, you know
And really hit at this point if you know me, you shouldn't be surprised by that
I'm not necessarily like a radical fence sitter like boogie or mundane mad or something
But I do think that there is a middle road here that is reasonable for example
Firstly, we cannot trust the Chinese government's reporting on any of this
For example, this article was from a year ago
But it's still relevant apparently as I understand it the unofficial numbers of January flu deaths in mainland
China was nearly the same as the official numbers of total flu deaths for all of 2018 all 12 months as well as
exceeding the combined flu deaths for 2016 and
2017 China is obviously downplaying this as much as humanly possible to put themselves in the best light they can at the same time it
People who are comparing this to like flu deaths or whatever, they're not quite getting the point
There's no native resistance to it in the human population at all
I mean
Maybe something will come out of it with that that HIV investigation or the the whole it only affects Asian people thing
Who knows but for now we have nothing we have to wait for basically the virus to either burn itself out and
Kill a lot of people in the process or we have to hope that in nature an asymptomatic variant
Like a mutation crops up and begins inoculating people without actually spreading the virus itself. That's what happened to Ebola
We didn't actually stop Ebola. We just got lucky with it
However, this thing seems to be significantly more transmissible as well as more deadly than SARS was there's possible evidence that it can be transferred
From mother to child there's possible evidence that the virus can exist on surfaces for a week at a time
so if somebody like
Sneezes on a door at the grocery store and they have coronavirus and you walk by a week later and like you touch the door
And then you like rub your mouth or something. You've got it
we have evidence that it takes up to two weeks for symptoms to even appear and
During those two weeks. You can also pass the virus on you've got evidence that the symptoms themselves
Take two to three weeks to actually work through and we've also had people die from this that weren't the very old the very young
Or the already sick or injured but people who were perfectly healthy and in their prime
This is not the same situation as previous high-profile viruses here consider this
What if this thing turns out to actually not be all that deadly, you know a death rate of around the same percent as flu
but it becomes endemic but that means by the way is it becomes a situation where it just stays in the human population and
It flares up every you know, once a year like the cold or the flu or something
It's just another virus that we have to deal with
Humanity had a long list of STDs to deal with before AIDS came in and it just added to the misery
It's almost like as we eradicate old diseases new ones start to come take their place at this point
I don't think you can avoid
Catching coronavirus like if it's gonna come to your city and it's gonna infect more than like say one person in the local hospital
Who's like under quarantine if it actually breaks out a bit in your city?
You're probably just gonna catch it and you know what? It probably won't kill you
You might just have to lie up in bed for a few weeks with ibuprofen and you know
Hope it passes on its own because especially if it's if it's taking over the entire city
There's no way to get in a hospital bed
However, hey after you've got it and it passed you're probably inoculated unless for some reason you can re-catch it
Which would be devastating and there's also a strict economic argument to discuss here if you have say
20% of your population infected and they're bedridden for a month
What do you think that does to your economy?
I mean obviously money is not not more important than lives
But at the same time it's something that you can't really look over because the manpower matters
Especially if part of that manpower it should be used to fighting the virus
You know if all of your doctors who are actually capable of treating coronavirus get sick with it
You're kind of screwed. It might sound like I'm going doom and gloom on you
I'm not I don't think this is the end of humanity or anything. Here's what I think you should do
At this point the the face mask even the gas mask is probably useless
What you should be doing is stocking up on some food
Stocking up on some basic supplies, you know in case the power goes out for a few days in case you you you run out
In case the local supermarkets have like bare shelves and there's just no food left in your city have a stocked pantry full of
staple foods that you can just kind of
Subsist off of for for a week or two if you have to you don't have to go all tinfoil hat
You don't have to build yourself a bunker in your backyard and sit in there with a machine gun or something while surviving off
Nothing, but Steve 1989's collection of MREs or something
But make sure that you have like a sack of rice a sack of beans
Have some stuff in deep freeze if possible get yourself a fair quantity of food that will basically
Last for long periods in a cool dry place so that if there ever is actually a shortage of anything
You'll be prepared and hey, you know what if it doesn't actually happen, you know, then just eat the food
It's not a big deal, right? There's one last thing worth talking about
YouTube has begun to put underneath every video that talks about the coronavirus a link to the
WHO's official coronavirus page
They're like they're like doing forced advertising basically on everyone's on everyone's videos on this topic at the same time though
There are reports of various insider videos like leaked videos or messages from doctors or whatever
Actually being scrubbed from YouTube because as always with current YouTube, you just can't trust them to ever tell the truth
So there's actually a bit shoot channel called Corona Chan
They are backing up every single coronavirus video that they can get their hands on they have leaked footage dumps here
They have reports from people on the street. They have reports from doctors
Basically, if something is at risk of being taken down off YouTube, it's being archived here
I highly suggest that you sub to this channel that you watch what they've got and that if you do have anything
That's a leak that might disappear in the future
Somehow contact these guys and send it over to them just because YouTube hasn't been good for the past five years
Doesn't mean that the truth should be left in their hands. In fact, it's quite the opposite
Alright my friends take care of yourself out there and good luck. It'll be okay. I love you