This post is from the twitter account of Comedy Unleashed, London's free-thinking comedy club.
No self-censorship. If it's funny, it's funny. Trying to make a joke that doesn't offend anyone
in 2018. Well, 2019 might be just getting underway, but I have a feeling that sentiment
hasn't really changed yet. I first came to know about Comedy Unleashed and its commitment to
free speech within comedy when this behavioral agreement contract began floating around the
internet. It's basically a form where comedians agree to not make fun of certain topics that
social justice holds as sacred cows. This comedy night aims to provide a safe space for everyone
to come together and share and listen to comedy, with all proceeds donated to UNICEF. This is a
chance for all to be entertained and overjoyed by the different performances here on this day,
the 23rd of January 2019, hence the importance of this contract. This contract has been written to
ensure an environment where joy, love, and acceptance is reciprocated by all. By signing
this contract, you are agreeing to our no tolerance policy with regards to racism, sexism,
classism, ageism, ableism, homophobia, biphobia, transphobia, xenophobia, islamophobia, anti-religion,
or anti-atheism. All topics must be presented in a way that is respectful and kind. It does not mean
that these topics cannot be discussed, but it must be done in a respectful and non-abusive way. I can
tell you right off the bat, just using the rules of comedy, why this is a disastrous line of thinking.
All comedy, without exception, requires somebody or something to be the butt of the joke. Even the
tamest, least offensive jokes require somebody to end up looking like they've got egg on their face.
Here, let me show you. Here's a list of jokes for kids from redtricycle.com. Why did the student
eat his homework? Because the teacher told him it was a piece of cake. The butt of the joke is the
student that ate his homework. Or I guess the butt of the joke could be you, since you're the one
probably groaning at that terrible pun. The point is though, in comedy, somebody's got to be left
holding the bag. Somebody's the person getting laughed at. When you boil it down, there is no joke
that isn't at the expense of somebody else. At least a little bit. Even when the joke is about an object,
something like, say, an ugly looking car, for example, it still connects back to the car's owner
and whatever tastes they may have. If the person that is the butt of the joke takes offense, and we
use that as an excuse to call that form of comedy over the line, then we will not have any comedy at
all. Especially with how easily triggered people seem to get nowadays. This contract is not, as it
claims, a way to ensure that all are entertained and overjoyed by comedy, but rather that these
topics are not made the butt of the joke. These are the sacred precepts that you must not violate.
And just like a hypothetical variant of this contract from a decade ago may have only contained
racism, sexism, and homophobia, next year's variant will probably tack on a few more isms and phobias,
ever expanding the list of things you cannot joke about because they're just too serious.
And any comedian worth their salt is taking notice of this encroachment into the comedic space.
Konstantin Kissen, when presented with one of these contracts, refused to sign it and turned
down being a part of the UNICEF event. He did post the contract to Comedy Unleashed on Twitter though,
which triggered a relatively predictable backlash from the social justice crowd.
If your jokes align with violence against marginalized folks, then they're not jokes.
They're propaganda. We don't live in a hypersensitive world. People are finally being
held accountable. Except that, when you really think about it, everybody's marginalized.
Everybody's oppressed. Everybody's got some hidden burden they're carrying that you're not privy to,
that maybe even their friends and family aren't privy to. And you're sitting here making these
judgments based solely on what people present to the world. Maybe you're black. So okay,
let's ban racism from comedy. We don't want you to feel uncomfortable. Maybe you're a woman.
Okay, let's ban sexism. Maybe you're a rape victim. So let's ban rape jokes. Maybe you're
a Muslim. So let's ban jokes about Islam. They're Islamophobic. Maybe you're trans. Let's ban jokes
about trans people. They're transphobic. Maybe you're gay. Let's ban gay jokes since they're
homophobic. But why not ban jokes about the family? Maybe somebody in the crowd was abused
by their parents as a child and would be massively triggered by a joke about how the comedian's dad
sucked sometimes. They would definitely be oppressed by it. So we have to ban family-based
humor. How about we ban jokes about cars? Because maybe you lost your sister in a crash. How about
we ban jokes about student loans? Because maybe you're poor and can't afford to send your kid to
a good school. How about we ban jokes about video games? Because maybe as a kid you were relentlessly
bullied and only took solace in retreating to your home and playing games after school.
This is why when you remove the ability to have somebody be the butt of the joke,
you destroy all of comedy. Because everybody is the butt of the joke, at least at some point in
their lives. And everybody also carries some burden with them through life. If offense is
enough to censor comedy, then comedy ceases to exist. I would hate to imagine one of these
nightmarish social justice comedy sets. It would probably be less entertaining than the actual
social justice classes held at the same university. But that is where we're going. And you can tell
exactly how morally bankrupt a censor is based on what they come to the defense of in their censorship
of comedy. Mumkey Jones, recently banned from YouTube permanently for his comedic videos where
the butt of the joke was Elliot Rodger, tweeted that in 2017 he was banned for mocking Sharia law
and in 2018 he was banned for mocking school shooters. Who will YouTube stand behind in 2019?
My money is on pedophiles. No, that's Twitter dude. But I'll have to make another video for
that. The point is, whenever some large tech company censors jokes about an edgy topic,
they are coming to defense of that topic. I'm sure YouTube does not actually support Elliot
Rodger, but in censoring jokes about him and his point of view, they are acting as if they do.
On this topic, recently Louis CK decided to make his big comeback. I was never really a
fan of him even before all of the Me Too shit happened. I just didn't find him funny. He seemed
like he was trying to play to the progressive crowd a bit too much, presumably not fully
understanding that eventually, once they were done with the free speech comedy extremists,
they were going to come for him next. But apparently his return set was filled with edgy
jokes, drawing the ire of the social justice crowd, who had hoped he would just vanish after
his Me Too accusations, which really, to me, just sounded like Louis awkwardly asking women
if they wanted to watch him jerk off. The woman declined, he didn't force the issue,
and I don't personally consider requests for sexual contact to be themselves
sexual assault, unless he persisted after being rejected, which I don't think he did.
Louis CK marks Parkland
Survivors an audio of stand up routine. Comedians said of teen activists,
you're not interesting because you went to a high school where kids got shot. Well, he's not wrong.
CK also mocked political correctness among young people and requests by gender non-binary people
to be addressed by certain pronouns. He also discussed his own bad year, which was set in
train after he admitted to allegations of sexual misconduct. He went on to say he was really
disappointed in the younger generation, calling them boring, for objecting to what they consider
offensive comments. The routine was panned on social media. It was panned on social media
because the only social media accounts The Guardian ever pays attention to is the progressive
social justice cucklord wing of social media. Here's the thing that I can't stop thinking
about regarding Louis CK. Given the broader context of his behavior towards women, delivering
a set about everyone being too sensitive these days feels like a sly way to say the same about
women. No, Jessica Valenti, he made a joke at your expense. And you're protesting too much.
The fact that Louis CK's anti-Asian jokes weren't originally reported speaks volumes
to how casually Americans still treat anti-Asian racism. Oh, so apparently not only was Louis CK's
set taken from the pages of the Satanic Bible itself, but the fact that the media didn't
talk about his Asians have tiny dicks section is the real problem? You know what's the worst,
most boring kind of comedy? The kind where old white men are angry that old white men
can't do or say whatever the fuck they want anymore. You know what's actually the worst
kind of comedy? The neutered, impotent, lacking a punch, social justice approved comedy. And you
know what's the worst kind of comedian? The kind who are too scared to make jokes about anyone,
so they cuck out to people like you and censor themselves and attempt to censor others. If your
jokes are bad, people won't laugh. If your jokes are consistently bad, you'll find that your comedy
career won't pay the bills. And that should be the only consequence of bad comedy, not fucking
witch hunts. Louis CK's new set apparently has a section attacking non-binary people. He thinks
it's wrong to use they as a singular pronoun. I, on the other hand, think it's wrong to sexually
assault people. Now see, that's actually a funny joke and is at the expense of Louis CK, and more
broadly the people who commit sexual assault. It's not necessarily an accurate joke because it's not
clear if Louis CK actually did that, but let's put it aside for a bit. This is a funny joke from an
SJW, at the expense of Louis CK. But because it trivializes sexual assault or whatever,
expect this person to be similarly excommunicated from social justice. This is why progressives
can't do comedy, and hell, why they can't meme. Because every time somebody's on the receiving
end of a joke, somebody else is going to yank a reason out of their ass to call foul. Louis CK
isn't being denied work because he tells stupid, unfunny jokes. He's being denied work because he's
a serial workplace sexual predator. The only problem is, if there were no accusations against
Louis CK, there would still be attempts to deplatform him based on this recent set.
You may have a convenient excuse with him, but that doesn't mean it's the reason.
Count Dankula has never had MeToo accusations hit him, and yet he's still one of the most
maligned comedians to ever exist due to the whole Nazi pug thing. It is always about censoring
speech. It just becomes a bit easier on the optics if the speaker has skeletons in his closet.
I'm happy to throw in with the free speech extremist lot, but to me free speech is even
more important when it comes to comedy. Think of it this way. Whenever a story wants to show
a king to truly be a tyrant, they don't show him killing rivals or starving peasants,
although they might also show him doing those things. They first show him executing his court
jester, because the court jester is always the person most willing to tell the king the truth,
and not pull any punches about it. And he can do this because he wraps it in comedy,
but the truth is always still there. The funniest, goofiest characters in any archetypal story are
also always the most wise. The one person that the hero turns to for wisdom just as much as for
laughs. A good king knows that the fool is just as much of a hero as he is, that the fool is willing
to look foolish if it means confronting the truth. They're willing to be seen as incompetent,
so that they may learn to be competent. They're willing to be seen as dumb, so that they may
acquire knowledge. They're willing to be seen as weak, so that they may grow strong. The heroic
fool is looked down upon, but is constantly growing, and is always oriented towards the good,
as best as they're able. The tyrannical king already believes that they know the good perfectly,
and so they judge, but never truly grow or comprehend. In the progressive war on comedy,
social justice is executing the court jesters of our culture.