Hey, y'all heard the ballad of bodega bro? Check it out.
Okay, so I just moved to New York and I'm trying to go grocery shopping and so I type
in like grocery stores on my Apple maps and like every fucking one I go to like I'm walking
to like they're like this shit or like fucking like this like bro that's not a grocery store
like I'm trying to get like eggs yogurt like cheese like shit like that right like look
at this place let me get a bacon egg and cheese the Aki way like you know those Tik
Toks like I'm fucking doing it like I've literally been to like five of those now like I don't
know what the fuck I'm about to do for dinner like where are the Kroger's and like the whole
foods at like I'm about to eat fucking like like cereal and ramen for dinner like what
the fuck this guy's real name is Griffin Green he's a former college football player from
Denison University in Ohio after graduating he got hired on to a tech startup called outreach
that had just expanded into New York City the job required him to move so this was his
first time in one of the biggest cities in the world and once he realized that New York
is basically a food desert he made that viral Tik Tok by the way a food desert is a neighborhood
in a city with no easy access to a nearby grocery store people living in that neighborhood
have to either order out go to restaurants or buy whatever they can at convenience stores
a bodega where the name bodega bro comes from is a specific type of convenience store unique
to New York City generally having a loud atmosphere and run by immigrants the word bodega is Spanish
for storage room bodegas are where a lot of people in New York get food because of that
food desert problem what really helped us all blow up though was this bug man's reply
to bodega bro there's so much to say he probably doesn't want to hear what I have to say and
that's fine this video isn't for him this video is for all the people who always say
Dutch why do you get mad about people moving to New York and it's because they often have
attitudes like that they come to the city in this case the Bronx and instead of integrating
themselves into their community they just make a mockery of it I mean what he's been
here like two days and he's found a way to make fun of the stores that many people in
the community relying on stores that people have to rely on because the supermarket he's
so desperately looking for doesn't exist because he's moved to a city which is historically
and still today systematically deprived certain neighborhoods neighborhoods that are predominantly
black and brown into a working class of basic resources I know you're gonna say it's not
that serious but it is how would you feel if somebody came in your house uninvited and
started making fun of all your furniture well I am not at all mad about somebody moving
to New York I'm mad about people moving to New York and having attitudes like that there's
comedy and then there's mockery and there's a very clear difference between the two boy
oh are you complaining that people are moving into your home and not adopting the local
culture instead they're holding on to their own views and complaining that those views
aren't being catered to if you were talking about a non-white person you would be immediately
called racist and xenophobic moreover a lot of poorer communities can't actually have
certain types of larger stores because of the crime in those communities remember during
the 2020 riots where people fucked up some neighborhoods so badly some stores just closed
and never returned it's not like these companies have infinite resources to keep dumping products
into communities only to have them all get stolen and then bring in no return a community with
rampant shoplifting is gonna see stores leave and not come back this is not some scheme by rich
people keeping your community down this is due to the behaviors of your own people anyway in
reply to both this and after seeing the general dilapidated state of New York City bodega bro
posted another video home then you're not welcome here and I think it's hilarious so I'm gonna
address a few things number one I got a job at a top 10 startup in the country in Manhattan so
I'm not fucking going anywhere number two my first day of work was today June 27th but my
lease on the Upper East Side this is until July 15th so I'm subletting in this shithole for three
weeks and yes it's a shithole you can't even argue with me on that there's like trash everywhere on
the sidewalks and streets there's like people sleeping on the sidewalk number three I just
thought it was funny that I typed in grocery store and a bunch of like corner stores showed
up I thought it was funny okay so fucking chill on me like it's a joke I think people are just
triggered by the use of the word shithole here since that was a Trump meme back during his
presidency the president tonight apparently uncorking another astonishing statement
complaining to lawmakers in the oval office about protections for immigrants why do we want these
people from quote all these shithole countries here according to a democratic aide familiar
with the conversation mr trump was referring to African nations and Haiti but people were triggered
so much they actually got him fired look at this absolute asshole I don't think it's very flattering
to have this type of person representing your company I would revile revalue I would revalue
his employment if I were you and yeah outreach fired him why for calling New York City a shithole
when it fucking is one they brought up the die shit the diversity inclusion equity but where was
he being racist he only said that the city was shit and that's because it is I did that video
a few months ago about why you should leave LA and it's not New York City but the same principle
applies here the progs have ruled over these cities for decades and have cultivated a culture
with no standards because the idea of holding somebody accountable for anything that they do
is considered oppressive by these softies when there's no standards why wouldn't your city be
covered in trash and heroin needles and junkies in the street it's obvious that bodega bro isn't
racist he's just a fish out of water his actual crime is that he questioned the leviathan he
noticed that the emperor has no clothes he looked at the state of apparently one of the best most
prosperous most progressive places to live on earth and asked the obvious question why is it
so shitty like watch this video of his bro like this place is so crazy like so many gay people
down here it's like I don't hate it like I'm not gay but like I'm all for it do what you want but
like like look at it I tried to do that trend on those people where it's like he's a 10 but
whatever and like they had no idea what I was talking about but they're in the talk so it's
hilarious like is being gay just like the new thing like I didn't know this many gay people
existed it's wild does this sound like a bigoted person to you I mean he sounds uneducated sure
he doesn't know what's going on this is all new to him but is that a crime is never having met a
gay person before now the same thing as an actual hatred of gay people most people who are freaking
out on social media right now over this dude are themselves either small town imports to the
nearest big city or they're still stuck in that small town and live vicariously online because
they hate their lives literally the progressive goal the dream is to take people from these
conservative towns entice them through economic factors to move into the city and then once
they're there convert them politically and culturally and now you're gonna shun this
dude or even have your hooks in him these people are exceptionally stupid bodega bro
ended up going on this whole apology tour thing okay so if you came here from twitter you may
know me as bodega bro I made a video that got taken way out of context so I went off private
to show you guys what bodega bro is really all about also if you know anybody that's hiring tech
sales or needs a workout partner in new york let me know doing a video giving food to the homeless
then all right I get it he's trying to soften the impact of a legit online hate mob coming after him
it's cringy but whatever and hey he's still doing good so fuck it I hope things work out for him
new york's expensive he needs a new job and he didn't deserve to get fired but I'm reminded
of that really god-awful woke game tell me why that we played on the gaming channel recently
the playable characters are these two twin girls except one of them grows up to be a trans man
there's this old backwater redneck type character who is friendly but very old school and extremely
uneducated on progressive topics at the beginning of the game you can tell that he means well but
he makes a few remarks about gender that the trans man is insulted by your brother oh shit
huh I guess I heard about that but I never
damn you look like a real man so do you sam you know what I mean I just didn't know they could
make a woman looks almost like a man I've seen a couple of lady transvestites on the TV before but
I've never seen a dude
sam that's not how you say that say what transvestites yes it's transgender transgender men
uh I'm sorry it's hard to keep track out here in Delos Crossing
world's just moving on without us during act two he comes back and the first thing he does is
apologize saying that he looked it up on the internet he doesn't quite understand all these
new ideas but he never meant to be mean anyway I also came by to say I fired up the google and I
I did some reading I didn't know the germs between all those words I mean I you know never
been much of a reader but I think I get why what I said was wrong and I'm real sorry
oh and before I forget or the lady of the house and from that point on he treats the trans man
character like any other guy that is exactly how it should be from both the liberal and progressive
point of view and yet the game is written like we should be viewing him as a bad person it's like
no he's actually the most likable guy in the game everybody else is insufferably woke meanwhile his
attitude is just like yeah I don't understand but hey you do you and that's how it should be have
you seen this clip of Natasha Devon no uh no relation talking about her bisexuality let's
listen in my sexuality is still part of my identity and I think probably the most hurtful
response that I get when I speak about this publicly and I get this both online and in real
life is when people say I don't care why are you telling me about this what you do in the bedroom
is none of my business and what those people are failing to understand is that this isn't just
about sex this is about life I think this attitude is at the heart of the matter the
liberal principle here is live and let live it doesn't matter what you do you do you even if
it's something new even if there's something about it that's new to me that's a little bit strange and
I might need to acclimate to if you're not bothering anybody else then fine but these
people don't want that liberal neutrality they want explicit validation neutrality to a progressive
is just as bad as rejection because remember you can't stand still on a moving train everything
needs to move leftward over time you've heard all this before bodega bro went through in a strange
tongue-in-cheek kind of way a hero's journey he went to a new place he got exposed to new things
he reveled in the novelty but ultimately accepted the non-damaging parts of it and grew a little bit
as a result remember what he said about gay people but that neutrality is an affront to the
progressive and the criticism even more so he was not a perfect leftist right out the womb and so
for that he needs to be eternally repentant the fact that he is not the fact that he gave clap
back meant that the prog canceling of him was inevitable