Hiya everyone! Nice to meet ya! My name's Nyunjoom in this short, flat otaku! Welcome
to my VTuber debut! I'm going to be posting lots of fun, cool content to this channel
in the near future! Here's a sneak peek of what you can expect coming soon!
What? What? What do you mean? I don't know how to play this game! I'm not a boomer!
Are... are... are you supposed to jump? Oh god! I'm so bad at platformers! I don't...
I don't understand you guys!
Oh no! No no no no! No no no no no no no! It's gonna get me guys! It's gonna get me!
AHHH!
God dammit junk, you stupid bitch! Why would you fucking pop him upward and kill me?
Even though I made a stupid decision, fuck you! Fucking use that you stupid cunt!
I love how both tanks just walked the fuck away from me, even though it was another mercy,
I'm a mercy! So, and I can't aim, cause I'm a girl, and they just abandoned me because
they're STUPID!
Wow! That's a lot of cool stuff! If you want to post artwork of me on social media, make
sure to use these hashtags, shortflatotaku and shortflatotakulude! And don't worry about
the last one, I'm actually like an ancient demigoddess who is over 900 years old, locked
into the body of a video game loving loli!
Okay, this has been New Joomz signing off! Like, comment, and subscribe to see what adventures
I get up to!