Hello ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to The Right Opinion, the home of a twat with
too much free time, and today we discuss a daddy that isn't Keemstar, what a shock.
No today we shall be talking about the infamous Daddy05, to those who are unaware of this
gent he is a family vlogger slash prankster, I use those terms very liberally, who found
himself on the rocks a few years back, he was both shaken and stirred. Why? Well if
you don't know you'll soon find out. Because my friends we are going back to a blast from
the past, but we shall begin with a little anecdote as always, because I have actually
made a video on Daddy05, although no one has ever seen it. You see as an artist, if that's
what you can call my work at least, I have started, scripted and worked on many videos
that will probably never see the light of day. That is the case for pretty much anyone
in the creative industry, it's about running with a lot of ideas, some of which do not
work, sometimes we realise these ideas don't work three lines into scripting them, sometimes
we realise they don't work three years after you uploaded them, that is the life of the
miserable creator. However the Daddy05 video was a classic case of changing circumstances,
I had a video, uploaded it to YouTube, was ready to drop some very stinging criticism,
had a big saucy thumbnail, and suddenly this video dropped.
And I felt these circumstances had changed. The thing about Daddy05 is that it was a situation
that greatly put his children in the spotlight, and regardless of whether they were sincere
about this apology or not, I was not going to continue to drag them to something which
they had shown a motivation to change philosophy in, there were children involved, and the
apology video changed the context to the point where I no longer felt confident in my upload.
Now that the dust is settled, hopefully firstly I can quell my allergic reaction, and secondly
I can look into the situation and the legacy with fresh eyes. What was he apologising for?
I'll explain the details very soon, but he was facing down a number of serious allegations
and evidence that the creation of his content was being elicited through the abuse of his
children, something not to be taken lightly at all.
He
was terminated by the YouTube gods for his transgressions, and likely because the media
were picking up on it, and YouTube's relationship with the media is quite rocky, and no compromises
can be taken when it comes to their reputation, to say the least, and we as human beings continued
with our daily lives. So why bring it back now? Well for a few reasons, first one being
some cheeky twats over on Twitter tagged me in a thread asking me to cover it, now I want
to make this clear, I do not often take requests, but if there's enough meat on the bone I'll
throw myself into the ring. The only reason I'm saying this is the last time I credited
someone's request, I was bombarded with requests of the newest naughty YouTuber, and I only
have so much time on this planet, I'm really sorry guys, I'm not saying don't send me
spicy news on people, I'm just saying don't get your hopes up. So I was mulling on this
for a while, and then I saw my Good Acquaintance Priminx video, which reignited my passion
for the whole debacle, because although the barebones information was something that I
was aware of, seeing someone expressing their opinion on it interested me further, and then
the fact that Daddy05 threw a tantrum in response made me think that maybe there is a bit more
to this story than we give it credit for, because the story in the headlines is that
Daddy05 is back, back in what way? Has he had his channel restored? Well, not really,
but you see Daddy05 never technically left, they were on YouTube until a few months back,
when YouTube clearly probably decided that they'd had enough of that platform as well,
and chucked them off, in which there was a very emotional video uploaded onto another channel,
alas their tears fell upon the frosty heart of the viewer, but a few months later they
are once again back, as Primink documents, but not exactly, you see their children now
have a channel in which they create their own content that is owned by the grandparents,
so Daddy05 claims to be not associated at all, the channel is known as the Martin Boys,
which is comprised of the three remaining siblings, after the biological mother of Cody
and Emma regained custody. There aren't too many indications of where this channel is going,
or what exactly it's going to be about, but one can assume it won't be too sinister,
given how I'm sure the Martin family are aware they're on thin ice.
Nonetheless, it seems there are some questions about the ethics of this whole debacle,
with Daddy05 positioning himself as a staunch defender of the lads rights to do what they want,
while also decrying any association with it. This has opened a whole new debate
about the morality of it, and frankly I find it all a bit messy.
Everyone's saying, oh Daddy05 is back, Family05 is back, no, no I'm not, I don't own a YouTube
channel, I have nothing to do with the Martin Boys YouTube channel, I do not own that channel,
my name is not on that channel anywhere, nothing on that channel links back to me
in any way shape or form, the Boys grandparents own that channel, they run that channel, and I
have nothing to do with it, stop giving me shit about a channel that I don't have nothing to do
with, I don't have access to it, I don't have anything to do with it, stop giving the Boys shit
about their YouTube channel, I have nothing to do with it, it's not even mine, you're being stupid,
I found that revisiting the whole topic has showed it to be incredibly appealing,
and my plan will be to open a discussion on a multitude of Martin's actions and behaviours,
particularly on how they rose to infamy, and how this rise can indicate a very simple longevity
that will be detestable to most people, but irresistible to a select few that will keep
their channel alive, equally I do not want this to be some simple analysis, because I do have a
lot to say that I held off on the day, and a lot of these sentiments still ring true now, so expect
a mix and match, today we're going to be discussing a lot, but you see to touch all bases you have to
hit a home run, and that's what I plan to do, because out of all the topics that I've covered,
I say this one has some of the most psychological discussions there are, so without further ado I
suggest we dive into DaddyOFive and explain the numerous phenomena that drive such a situation
that still has implications to this day, I cannot wait, and neither should you, let's get to it.
Now, DaddyOFive's channel was set up in 2015, however as noted it has been terminated,
so we rely on the remnants that history leaves us with to be able to make judgement of such content,
nonetheless we don't necessarily need specific details of DaddyOFive's channel to understand
everything that probably caused his channel to thrive, because 2015 was the year of the prank,
now I'm not going to make up any bullshit and say that pranks were only big in 2015,
they still exist to this day, many creators are still incredibly successful off the back of them,
and there is no doubt in my mind that it will continue to thrive for years to come at least,
however 2015 was the year that we had multiple controversies surrounding pranks, prank invasion,
Sam Pepper, and so on, it was a huge year for the pranksters, and this is where we discuss the
rise of the prank in the first place, the rise of the prank is a rather unsettling one, because
there will always be an audience for these pranks, needless to say I am not a fan of them at all,
but people love to see others in natural environments be fooled, while the audience
are completely aware of it, it's that dynamic, equally the notion of a prank can often make
creators conduct more extreme actions and excuse it under the notion of a prank, such as the
multiple social experiments, of course as a defence this is valid to an extent, but it's also
what creates the unique environment for pranks to thrive in, because you can't just stand around
expecting those situations to happen naturally, a social experiment is, although certainly not
conducted within the means of scientific reliability, an appropriate name for what many
of these YouTubers do, they manipulate an environment and then expose the reaction of
those in it, that is the trend that DaddyOFive appeared to jump on most enthusiastically,
the prank, now the prank typically involves deceiving the participant, and many immediately
would raise ethical claims, however sometimes deception is necessary to understand how humans
act in certain situations, for example the Milgram experiment, I'm not going to go into
details about it because it's fairly irrelevant, but it's a sobering study on the human condition,
and a perfect example of how sometimes we need to deceive participants to get to the truth,
and I'd recommend checking it out if you haven't, it wouldn't have been obtained otherwise.
However, with the notion of a prank, the deception is what makes it entertaining,
which once again in many situations is fine, particularly when considering that a majority
of pranks slash social experiments were fake, and although we can definitely be annoyed at the
people for faking them and misleading their audience, I'm glad that some of the direct
shock that many of the subjects of their videos appear to endure wasn't actually real,
because those situations, particularly ones where you have a bloody bomb thrown at your feet,
can be pretty intense and raises significant ethical questions. DaddyOFive appeared to start
off his channel in a fairly less extreme prank direction, with content that was stupid and
idiotic but still that you could see might pass under YouTube's radar, however probably seeing
the success in violence and seeing the audience response made them more motivated to become more
hands-on. But why on earth would more people want to see something which is, without debate,
much more aggressive and unpleasant? The thing is, revisiting DaddyOFive made
me realise that there is a significant audience that never really cared about ethics, what a
surprise. They didn't care about people's wellbeing, they're the sort of people who
see a crime and pull out their iPhones and say they were just recording for evidence.
The simple truth is, and there is no two ways about it, what made DaddyOFive so successful
was that it doesn't matter whether they were branded as pranks or a joke,
DaddyOFive provided the closest glimpse into the human reaction of a quote prank,
because it is an up-close first-person perspective of something that you feel.
And let me tell you, those emotions are very real, I was rewatching some of his Xbox pranks
on a reupload channel, and I had to stop because I was crying, I was angry, I was enraged at how
he treated Cody, and yet with a bit of emotional distance, that's what some people wanted,
because that demographic existed. The realism is furthered once you acknowledge the fact that
these people are children, and children are more likely to be emotionally volatile and react in
such a way. People like chaos, people like volatility, everyone likes a prank where
someone gets really angry, but whereas many pranksters were just plain actors,
Mike Martin's channel had exhibits of the most raw aggression possible, and people ate it up.
No one else did that, and no one else should do it, and most people couldn't do it. The emotional
intimacy of having a situation like that would be impossible, how can you expose yourself to that
level of suffering of your own children? But that's the thing, they weren't his own children,
and this matters more than you think.
Did you see this game when I sliced open his guts? I never felt so alive!
Yeah, well you've been alive for like two minutes.
While they do mess with the kids, a lot of the time it seems directed towards one specific kid,
and that is Cody. While in the family video where they defended themselves, they said, you know,
the kids get to decide if the video goes up, they also acknowledge that they have so much cool stuff
thanks to having a YouTube channel. So by getting stuff, they're incentivized to allow the parents
to upload these videos, even though the little kid Cody is very obviously not a fan of them.
The youngest and the weakest and the most sensitive kid, Cody,
is always nursing an injury, he's always covered in bruises. From video to video,
there are signs of abuse all over his arms, his legs, his face.
Generally there's a psychological phenomenon known as the Cinderella effect. Now I don't want to give
too much credit to this theory, as I do not find the research on it to be the most reliable under
closer scrutiny, but basically what it dictates is that step-parents are more likely to be abusive
to their children than their biological parents. Now although I believe the impacts are overstated
in certain circumstances, I do think there's a serious case to be made here of why certain
children were such targets. This is an evolutionary theory, and Mike and Heather
seem rather primitive to say the least. There seems to be this emotional distance. In the
Drama Alert interview, Heather has this very unsettling way of referring to Cody as quote
the boy. Interesting as she is the step-parent, once again, given the whole seedy nature of how
they gain custody over him, it genuinely would not surprise me if that emotional distance from
the adoption and subsequent alienation led to them being the greater targets of the abuse.
On top of this, what would then happen is you'd see these very weird ways of justifying the abuse,
which was probably both a technique for them and for their audience that somehow it wasn't
their fault. After all, in many households, punitive measures are seen as fairly straightforward,
even though this was clearly extreme, if you have someone who is punitively inclined, they see
Heather and Mike talking these children down, it will fall into their sphere of perceptibility.
I'll probably talk about this more in a future video than I have planned, but this is basically
the psychological techniques that led to these children being treated differently in my opinion,
and it seemed to yield from the fact that they didn't have that same connection, and the parents
actively tried to neglect it, particularly in the mother's instance. When people made exposed
videos on DaddyOFive, they rightfully highlighted the worst of his channel, but the thing is by
ignoring the best of his channel, it gave them a get-out-of-jail-free card, the oh well you don't
see the good side of DaddyOFive, there's a channel with a whole video dedicated to it, where they
just play the emotional music, over the riveting clips, but really this was just another
manipulation tactic to somehow once again create a moral delusion to justify the abuse, to try and
make people think, oh I guess he was alright after it all. Happy times do not negate abusive
or violent ones, that's like saying if Joe Blow punches his wife in the face, calls or slurs,
but that's only like 5-10% of the time, the other 90% of the time it's just good, he's sweet,
he cares, he apologizes, no the good times do not negate the abuse, that is a very important thing
to know. The truth is you can't orchestrate the child's emotions in many of the videos,
and then say, oh well he's happy in certain moments that somehow justifies it, I had many
happy moments in my childhood, it doesn't change the terrible things that happened to me and the
lasting effects they have to this day, and if the people who did those things were to come to my
house with a box of chocolates and an apology, I'd appreciate it, but it wouldn't justify their
actions. There is no prank, but people didn't care, and Mike clearly didn't care, he was
extracting money out of that kid like an ATM, and exploiting that emotional distance so he felt no
repercussions for his actions, and people watched it, after all, they're not responsible are they,
they're just a single view, watching cruel and crazy videos on the internet, isn't that what
people do? The thing is this isn't some third party testimony where you get to watch it on the
news, some found footage, this was literally a person making money out of direct abuse and
people let him reach 700,000 before others had to intervene. This is a situation like no other,
and the fact that many people didn't have to experience the consequences directly of their
actions meant they didn't feel responsible for whatever happened. On the other hand,
you probably had a smaller but more dedicated fanbase of actual sadists who used the first
person perspective that Mike often provided to live out violent fantasies that they themselves
were not prepared to commit.
uh all the kids need to gang up on jake at once
tie him down and torture him king broton you're right why the hell is cody such a damn liar thief
and evil nobody deserves his crap you did the right thing daddy five but this monster deserves
this
the internet is screwed everyone knows this and youtube is a target as much as anywhere else for
these people to congregate and create their cruel little circles where they pose whatever fulfills
their twisted desires i can't stop people from being inherently fucked up because some people
always will be but what you can do is put the well-being of others first and know that if you
were to enact your desires a lot of people would suffer and maybe reconsider your position on
supporting such content essentially daddy o5's rise to the near top of the youtube totem pole
was done through distorting a reality that made fans feel secure in their support of him whether
it was through the emotional distance or through the tonal shifts that created an illusion and yet
showed reality so raw that many people felt compelled to watch it's morally reprehensible
but no one wanted to take responsibility equally by taking the ever popular notion of a prank
and upping the realism to 11 he created something that without moral boundaries appeal to people
which they then justified in their own heads with daddy o5 doing something no one else would really
do and for good reason too the videos that mike made were absolutely appalling and there is no
doubt in my mind that they had to be removed but by letting them fester for so long martin had
created a fan base some of these fans left after mike was exposed whether it was for the moral
epiphany or just the fact that he'd no longer be uploading his brilliant content is probably down
to the individual but either way that was when the exodus occurred but as always there were
many stragglers who stuck around for various reasons and daddy o5 pulled out all the stock
to keep them on his side youtube had no option it doesn't matter if it was all taken out of context
which it wasn't there was no way that they could let that sort of reputation gather on a site that
was facing down tough times anymore i am for a free and open youtube but equally there was a
line and the only use those videos should have been for was custody evidence you see the issue
with daddy o5 is that he epitomizes the classic action consequence dynamic that helps drive many
of the exiled individuals from the internet this is always the situation with the platforming and
why it has been handled very sensitively when someone conducts themselves in a way in which
some people may feel affects them they may act on what they decide to be justice the problem is the
perception of justice is completely subject to the individual and when you take action against
someone you'll always give them some sort of power to use that narrative and make themselves
a victim does this mean you shouldn't take retributive action of course not you just have
to work out how to make sure people can understand that in the context of the situation your listed
justice was righteous and businesses often don't feel the need to do that after all people aren't
entitled to an explanation and one thing that we've found is that every time youtube opens its
mouth someone tends to get hurt equally however it does mean that those who you will remove have
all the platform to scream and holler about it and so on daddy o5 provided content that no one
else could which is why people firstly watched him and secondly tried to twist the content into
a morally justifiable mold which meant that when daddy o5 decided that he was ready to play victim
there was an army of fans ready to come to his aid so first came the original response video now
people hated this video many people did rightfully so but equally it created a sect of intense daddy
o5 loyalists through the narratives crafted titled false acquisitions another stunning
display of martin's intellect he decides to respond to some of these claims but equally
tries to keep the fans on board we're gonna make things right we're gonna make things right and i
want everyone to feel comfortable and know that these kids are safe that this is all an act
firstly it set up the precipice that his videos were fake normally this would be a compromise on
the appeal of your channel's content but martin knew that he was on borrowed time as it was and
couldn't continue his current brand anyway therefore in this instance claiming your videos
are fake immediately plays into that narrative the reason why i say claiming rather than admitting is
that it's such a tactical decision that i highly doubt they were fake and even if they were children
like cody have no way to discern that and it's clear it caused a lot of genuine trauma therefore
their defiance just really exposed how deceptive they were willing to be to maintain some semblance
of audience stating that these videos were fake played credence into some people's minds and
makes them feel better about supporting this madman uh cody is going to grow up to be an actor
um i'm pretty sure of that which page in the script involved a stepbrother punching cody in
the head he was being pinned on the ground and he got kicked in the crotch was that just kind of an
ad lib thing are they method actors then they claim they put disclaimer that it was all just
for entertainment purposes which just makes it all right i put in the video description for
entertainment purposes early i categorize the videos as entertainment or comedy something that
i know i've even used keywords a few times i use the word fake in the keywords and stuff a few times
this is embarrassing but still it was a confirmation bias to people who wanted to
hear that then they do the classic greg paul technique of reaffirming loyalty by branding
them as real fans and praising the ones who stick with them after this i i we just wanted to make
videos for you guys and we truly appreciate the love and support that you guys our real fans have
given us over the last few days with everything that's going on and we're really sorry that we
have to disappoint you and say that this immediately detaches them from the horrible
mainstream moral normies and creates a reaffirmation of bond and pulls the dedicated
viewer in it creates a moral burden remaining with these people and they look tired and forlorn
they're the victims here guys can't you see all these false acquisitions have been weighing down
with them brings a tear to my eye another really important narrative you'll see is him talking
about the news once again the mainstream media is an easy target i mean i sure as hell don't like
them a bunch of sensationalist cowards but it doesn't mean they're wrong all the time however
the general distaste of the media allowed mike to move in and take advantage of it attacking the
news and lumping any of his critics in with it as well it's also a power play attacking the
mainstream media 99 percent of the time is going to come across as punching up and punching up
makes you look more justified in your position because of some perceived institutional power
they hold while name-dropping philip defranco for merely reporting it and setting his delightful
fans on him it's clear that they didn't really know how to respond this is a peak victim narrative
and once again it plays off that collateral dynamic that it's philip's fault for documenting
this abuse rather than their fault for the abuse now they claim that the abuse is taken out of
context they claim that the threats they've been receiving somehow makes defranco responsible as
well it would have never got this out of hand if it wasn't for that defranco guy starting all of
this doing all of this to my family he's responsible for this their voices are emotional they've been
attacked someone get me a tissue i'm gonna gonna cry listen because defranco is a huge creator he
has that clout to lead to such instance because you made provocative videos when working out how
someone has contributed to your hatred you have to look at their presentation sometimes i've
criticized people for making individuals out to be worse than they actually are however defranco
just delivers a message on a situation that has been transpiring anyway the only difference was
his size and many people were left to make their own judgment which they did when you behave in a
way that instigates hatred upon yourself you have to be prepared to take it unless it comes from an
exaggerated or false narrative defranco wasn't even the initial incident that caused this it
was your ink prank he was merely publicizing it which he had every right to there was a range of
anger some people saying this is outright abuse of your children others saying this is not abuse
but these are asshole parents that are exploiting their children for money and hurting them
emotionally and then it also appears that they have a dedicated audience that are completely
fine with it crimey river bitches anyhow there's a lot of back and forth and anger and eventually
the backlash from this video was felt people were angry and riled up and the walls were closing in
on them
oh
this is where it becomes interesting because the family then puts out a more regretful video
with the mum talking because although i'd say she's just as manipulative she's a bit more
subtle chances are this was probably motivated by the threat of losing custody to cody which
they subsequently did and there was a whole story behind this that had martin and his wife deceiving
the authorities into having custody over the children mike martin daddy of five left back
in 2008 when cody was one and emma was almost three my sister took care of those kids by herself
with no money or help from him for almost seven years she gave him another chance and hunted him
down to be a dad rose was a little overwhelmed and asked mike if he could visit while cody was
visiting mike's wife forged paper saying my sister gave him custody of cody two years later after
emma visited for thanksgiving they removed emma saying there was abuse that was unfounded we went
to court and got a judge that was prejudiced against women with bipolar and wouldn't even
look at our evidence that mike was unstable and abusive and gave him the kids in august
a friend of ours came across their videos and told us about them we contacted the police
immediately they did a report here and sent it to maryland which she included the document showing
the redacted version because i don't want to share addresses and personal information and maryland
told us it was corporal punishment they refused to do anything even though we talked to doctors
and other professionals who say it is clearly abuse of all kinds we are just so worried who
knows what kind of damage this is doing i can't confirm if every single detail of this is true or
not but i consider it very plausible given the circumstances and with that publicly looming over
them they no longer have their fans just to preach to this is the video that stopped me from putting
out my video on them because i respected their children now i think for many the custody of cody
and emma to their biological mother was a very satisfying ending to an emotional saga but it was
just the start for the daddio five family to victimize themselves further look at what they've
lost all for a few light-hearted pranks that got out of hand oh no the tragedy on top of this they
were actually prosecuted for their treatment of their children and placed on probation a decision
that i will probably respond to in a bit i mean let's be clear youtube made absolutely no mistake
by booting them off the platform and every single one of the following repercussions were completely
justified as well even if it was just pranks you can't expect social services to be happy with that
especially following public uproar which once again good job on people for taking a stance
and making the shitty legal system actually respond but at the same time with all the
punishment mike positioned himself as a foolish man who didn't know better but now he has learned
and doesn't deserve to be deprived any further and this was convincing enough for some people
i just wanted to take care of everybody i just wanted you guys we wanted them to be happy we just
wanted our kids to be happy and we went about it the wrong way the thing is youtube's biggest
mistake was actually allowing daddy o5 to continue on the platform at all after losing custody of two
of their children and once again giving them nothing much else to lose they rebranded to
family o5 in which they continued many of their antics now of course the content was now watered
down with some moments that are done with the conviction of tommy wiseau
however there was still content that was angry and edgy enough to bring that audience back
i'm trying to stop you from coming from the script
with the new channel with the spotlight firmly off the family from the moment with it off daddy
o3 he takes multiple breaks to talk about how hard done by he is in an excellent video by creator
amanda the jedi she observes these exact techniques ones that would have been taken
apart by larger creators if they were still on the other channel but now had a free place for
their fans to feel sympathetic towards them they lost so much with nothing too much else to lose
they knew they could milk what they had lost for the expense of very little else you'd think that
maybe they'd apologize for the things that happened and that they were going to change
and and make make things different make things more fun make it a genuine family fun friendly
channel but no when mike comes back he complains what's up team do5
oh man my wife has been driving me crazy has been driving me crazy about starting back up this
gaming channel and even my therapist has been on me about starting this gaming channel they both
think that it'll be really good for me to do this they think that it will help bounce me out
of my depression and stuff like that i remember i used to be so happy that we were out of our
bad neighborhood we were so happy everybody was happy as hell
the camera this was a channel with approximately 300 000 subscribers videos that pulled views and
it clearly wasn't as extreme but equally having that smudge on their reputation i really don't
know why youtube would have tolerated it that long and it was still fairly intense and eventually
they did respond to the fact that they were still uploading and the fact that policy wise
they shouldn't really be able to and they kicked the family o5 channel too but by doing this they
prolonged daddy o3's constant struggle against those horrible evil mainstream elites so in
their tragedy they once again milked the situation by starting a passion i think they mean petition
to bring back the poor persecuted daddy o5 there was also a video uploaded where the martin's
sons basically power at the same talking points their father made times before they really are
troopers and of course the sad piano music adds another delicious dimension just pulls on your
heartstrings so we got shut down for nothing at the end of the day youtube terminated your channel
once which gave you no right to have another channel and the fact that you were still allowed
to operate on youtube for so long should have been considered a privilege oh and of course
don't forget about those real fans and you all know you the real fans know how good of parents
mom and dad are but this is the thing through this they had successfully emotionally appealed
to a lot of audiences who were trying to confirm a biased conception of daddy o5 as the victim
people who valued their own motivation for entertainment over the basic facts of the
situation were more than happy to take this explanation the daddy o5 had been unfairly
persecuted because it fit their world view and by having these kids deliver it in their quivering
confused voice it was more than enough for many people to be satisfied the thing is that mike
martin and to an extent his wife is the guy who punches the tiger and then complains when he has
his arm bitten off but for every time he loses a limb he continued to irritate the situation
just being more subtle every time oh guys i merely slapped the tiger uh uh guys i merely
poked the tiger guys come on i merely tickled the tiger considering this is the same tiger the
tiger isn't going to take chances and that first impression will rightfully stick with many people
you don't get a blank slate when you do something as outwardly horrific as that and then try to hold
onto the remnants as a brand and use it to play a victim card there will always be people who
feel bad for the guy and call out the tiger to be put down how could such a savage animal bite off
the arms of a poor helpless man daddy o5 positions himself as the underdog when really he received
the repercussions that he asked for he is someone who baits these situations that can be seen with
his behavior on youtube but eventually the bait will blur the lines of morality which is where
we come to today's situation
you see what i've shown here is how daddy o5 made the most of everything that happened against him
even though many of us would agree that it is justified there will always be an audience who
discard that narrative in favor of what they enjoy and every time he's continued to irritate the
system and it has responded because they know his brand and they know what he likes he continues to
cry about it and yes i believe people can completely change and that is reflected in a lot of my
philosophy but what daddy o5 has done on this platform is so beyond redemption that he has to
accept any consequences that come his way you can't bounce back from something like that from
both a business and even morally oriented standpoint i'm gonna be honest i think mike got
off lightly i think they were far too nice with him with the probation in my opinion he should
have been sent to jail for what he did along with his wife especially to cody and he should be
grateful that it's extremely difficult to fully evaluate and legislate against psychological
trauma because if you go back and watch videos like nerd cities it's unbelievable levels of
emotional torture that children like cody cannot process and then blaming it on him when he acts
out is just unbelievable publicly creating this image that promoted a sick twisted mentality to
punish him further i wish he would behave himself and act like normal child normal kids have bad
behaviors cody has something else so up until now i have argued that most of the repercussions
that occurred on the platform were completely warranted it must be noted that i never support
threatening individuals and by doing so you give them an extra way to play victim as well
though that is assuming all the events claimed by daddy o3 did actually happen but hey benefit of
the doubt even for someone like him it's not necessary to the argument however with the latest
move documented by some the lines become increasingly blurred basically the new youtube
channel is dedicated to mike and heather martin's sons the martin boys and many people were claiming
that daddy is heavily involved they've uploaded a few videos one in which they eat food good for
them and many people are questioning whether they should be on the site and are criticizing them
for having a platform and so on this has led daddy o3 to respond what you'll see is a classic
situation but one where the lines are more blurred this time the sons have a channel and
now daddy o5 is picking up that victim car and talking about all these people attacking him for
having his sons on youtube he's private his account he's spoken about it on his twitch stream kids
doing their youtube thing people are attacking them thinking it's my channel how stupid are they
care about your kids so much let me attack them and have their channel shut down
let me make a video talking shit about them and send hate over to them so i can get my views on
my channel because i have no creative process and and the only way i could be creative is if i
bully and you know just make someone else's life miserable fuck out of here man my heart breaks
let the kids be kids and you know what i agree i don't think that the children although morally
dubious in many of their actions complicit with their father should necessarily be prevented from
ever operating a channel but what's been done here is that it struck the sweet spot between just
and unjust they're still operating under the martin brand and they're still using the martin
fan base however in my opinion they should be able to have a channel nonetheless people criticizing
it is not a case to play victim because once again daddy o3 is tempting the tiger and that victim
card is going to be used again and again to retain those fans who have convinced themselves
that he is the one who has suffered undeservedly the martin boys themselves have promoted a brand
and the brand website which we'll discuss in a moment if mike wants to detach himself from the
channel he's doing it in the worst way possible but we all know he doesn't a lot of people think
him responding is out of insecurity it's not just that it's a case of cultivating a fan base through
their perceived notion of victimhood and trying to leave reality in the back of their mind daddy
o5 is not a vick he has a twitch channel which does all right and he gives out stellar advice
on curing depression as well best way to handle depression is to stop being depression
the more you know
because if you just stop being depressed you won't even be depressed no more
and he has an instagram where he can post hell he has his own website the real antics are on
his family of five domain which really is the only way to keep himself going now because as
this title implies you can never get rid of daddy o5 as much as we detest who he is this is what
has happened he has grown that fan base out of persecution and then taken them to a corner of
the internet where he can cover them and provide them with videos for the very affordable cost of
five dollars a month using that exact same persona to string them along about how he is the victim
he has community posts where he's the victim he has tweets where he's the victim he has instagram
videos where he is the victim this man the abuser he's the victim guys and if we paid five dollars
to see that sweet daddy content we probably have videos where he's the victim too alongside him
screaming at his kids and having the paywall immediately places a moral dilemma onto anyone
who wants to continue criticizing their content do you pay five dollars and help support them and
risk finding content that is nothing particularly to write home about or do you go leave it behind
and risk possibly some very questionable stuff going on behind the scenes family o5 has it
locked down for now and there's nothing anyone can really do about it he has taken advantage
at every turn however i don't want it to seem like daddy o5 is some kind of mastermind because he
isn't and i'm sure masterminds would be doing something much more with their lives he merely
filled a gap in the market that is extremely morally questionable and they've worked out how
to make people feel better about it and then using that entertainment to string along a load of sadists
to engage in his content and support him through those tribulations i do not know how many fans he
has right now but hopefully as time passes and the kids grow up the world will run dry
just like with his first ever pranks he'll likely continue to push the boundary until someone hits
back and then he can claim to be the victim again and start some fresh fresh drama which is why it's
not worth attacking the martin boys personally let youtube decide what they want to do with it
and try not to give mike any ammunition to cry about it i'm not saying you shouldn't criticize
them go ahead be my guest you know i'm making a video criticizing them what i'm saying is if you
are criticizing them make sure you're taking the high road however if the martin boys's channel
does become integrated with the family of five brand more tightly people should then speak up
a bit more mike martin is a persistent bastard and he has created something through that persistence
he doesn't have much else going for him he knows that given his public reputation this might be all
he has left and he is resting on the shoulders of fans who he has convinced that he is the one who
has all the wrongdoing against him but those shoulders will not carry him forever and although
i would argue he has never had to fully face down the consequences of his actions i like to leave
you with a quote from native american author vine deloria jr from his book custard died for your
sins which by the way is an excellent read if you enjoy cultural discussion with a great dose of
sarcasm anyhow the quote that always stuck out to me since reading is the one at the end of chapter
four you see the wheel of karma grinds slowly but it does grind finally and it makes a complete
mike i'm sure the circle will be complete in the end
so yes that was the video probably one of my longer ones but there you go i would love to
hear your thoughts on the daddy 05 situation always open to a bit of discussion down below
really appreciate the support of recent pretty sure by the time this will be out probably be over
100 000 but you never know you never know we live and hope my friends oh my god wow
i'd love to give a big shout out to the editors who have once again done a stellar job i will
leave their channel links in the pinned comment go and check them out give them a subscribe they
really do deserve it videos would not be possible without them i'd also like to give a big shout out
to my patreon names up on screen right now and a special shout out to ryan who once again has
donated a hundred dollars generosity exceeds his beauty i'm sure i don't think i have too much
else to say i hope everyone's having a lovely day and i hope this has made their day a little
lovely even though the dark nature of the topic i hope i've managed to engage you until then
however i'm the right opinion and i will see you in the next one
so
you