Good evening my friends. Well it's evening for me, it's gonna be morning for you when you see this.
I'm gonna be gone this weekend so I'm trying to record something quick just so there's something
for Sunday. I know Sunday is usually the weekly sip which is my weekly streaming show every Sunday
morning but this week I can't do it. I'm hoping that I can get this recorded and then it can be
edited and put out in time for at least some kind of content to come out on Sunday because I know
that it's been a little bit sparse recently but nonetheless I'm gonna be gone this weekend so no
weekly sip instead you get this video that I am basically recording last minute before I leave
for the weekend. In fact I might not even be back in time for the Warhammer tabletop campaign
happening over on Archer's channel. Hopefully I am but hey don't tell him okay? But because I am
a little bit time strapped I want to go over something that's kind of funny and goofy and I
think we can have a good laugh at. This was put up on the website of the University of Virginia live
and leftist twitch political live streaming and Hassan Piker. So what's happening here is
somebody's I think master's thesis is literally an analysis of the online left and how it relates
to how it relates to twitch. This has to be the most parasocial fucking thing I've seen in a while
I ain't making this up you can go and find this and here it is live and leftist Department of
Media Studies University of Virginia May 2022. You know hey good for him I never finished my
thesis so acknowledgments my parents advisor all the normal stuff that you see in a thesis my
classmates who have hopefully ignored me speaking at length about weird shit oh my god imagine like
you're in class and you're just trying to get through your get through school get through your
degrees you can get on with your life and this guy is just like ranting beside you in the lecture
hall about Hassan's latest antics my god University must be more insufferable than it was when I was
there to Hassan and chat for inspiring this paper has L I hope he sees this dude thanks to anyone
else who reads this hope you get something out of it I'm gonna get a lot out of it but I don't know
about anybody else leftist political live streaming has become an increasingly visible subset of
twitch.tv content and internet live streaming content generally with Hassan Hassan Abby
piker the most prominent among content creators in this new genre this thesis aims to understand
how leftist political live streaming fits into a historical lineage of partisan political
broadcasting from talk radio to present-day structures labor and generates income and how
its programming engages its audience through its use of technological affordances collective
effect and an integrated materialist analysis in the first chapter I traced the lineage of
twitches political streams I synthesized previous literature beginning with right-wing talk radio
stars like Russia Limbaugh on through television political media liberal infotainment online
gaming and online radicalism with this context I situate piker and other leftist political live
streamers in historical context outlining the cultural and technical affordances they draw
from legacy media in the second chapter I take a political economic approach of political live
streaming drawing on the statements of streamers public facing company policy and trade blogs I
first break down the way that both streamer and audience labor our audience labor are configured
on the platform building from that I analyze how twitch operates as a payment processor handling
and incentivizing transactions between audiences and content creators and finally I discuss how
twitch is able to exert political power over its users by gatekeeping their income producing a
chilling effect which affects political streamers coverage in the third chapter I described the
experience of a twitch streamer combining auto ethnography the walkthrough method and
computational text analysis I described the programming of the streams content itself in
its phenomenological and effective dimensions I use this description to show how political
discourse is shaped and received by sides of the streams communicative circuit if you ever needed
a fucking reason to think that academia has become entirely superfluous at least insofar as the arts
is concerned here you go here it is all right Jesus Christ oh my god there's so much garbage
here maybe we shouldn't go through all 61 pages of it but that's okay I have a few choice snippets
we can talk about what's interesting to me is that this thesis drops in the context of a son
recently doing a a pretty high-profile internet about his life in his career and how he got a job
at TYT because of his uncle chenk Uygur and how he ended up you know going on his own and becoming
a streamer and Hassan gives his his story but Hassan leaves out what actually made it all work
and that was destiny years ago Hassan was a destiny orbiter destiny platformed Hassan which
is what basically gave him the boost in an audience to get him going at the start Hassan
used to pile around with with destiny's friends and destiny's community and now that Hassan's made
he basically abandoned destiny and now he kind of hates destiny vosh did the same thing other
streamers have apparently done the same thing as well the the destiny bump seems to be a real thing
in the online streaming space at least for politics and the number of people who have
turned around after they've basically got big bigger than destiny and then backstabbed him
that list also seems to be growing and in that interview that Hassan gave to the mainstream
media he completely leaves out destiny's influence in fact he says that he was the first person to
merge politics and gaming and streams when it was in fact destiny the entire thing is basically this
weird rewriting of history and that's the thing about the process of legitimization as soon as one
organization whether that be a school or a government or a media organization or whatever
says something that is false is true and other legitimate organizations can point at that citation
and say look it's obviously the case right and so that lie can propagate and become legitimized
which is basically what happens in this thesis for example destiny is only mentioned twice in
this thesis once in passing and the second time in the conclusion where it reads while
piker may have frequently used his bullhorn thus far to advocate for anti-imperialism
anti-capitalism and marginalized voices others are already pivoting to other targets vosh who
has shown up throughout this thesis has regularly used his position to demonize decolonial advocates
on his live stream and the self-proclaimed neoliberal streamer destiny has made it a goal
to harass anyone to his left these sort of reactionary tendencies are supported through
the constant push for engagement and the drama that ensues is itself a lucrative market so this
seems to be an incorrect statement as far as I can tell because I do watch some destiny I do check in
on vosh every once in a while I don't really watch us on piker but basically I like to keep my thumb
on the pulse of a lot of these people even though I'm not in their communities and from what I can
tell I don't think destiny has made it a golden harass anyone to his left I think people on the
left are taking it that way mainly because destiny is very good at de-radicalizing people from far
left positions and in fact this thesis does outright ignore that destiny was the first
person to come in and mix politics and gaming on Twitch and then also start doing debates from the
left and then also start bumping up other streamers and helping platform them and helping them become
streamers in their own right like like vosh and asan this thesis ignores all of that while the
cause for leftist twitches rise in popularity can only be speculated on no we know what it is you're
just not saying it the growth of political audiences on the platform has continued along
with the growth of the platform beyond eSports and the growth of the popularity of live streaming
more broadly as with the coincidence of rush limbaugh's ascendance to talk radio stardom in
which the wider American political context in this formal novelty aligned perfectly for popular
success twitches lefties and asan piker especially seemed to have stumbled into success more than
initially seeking it out this this is actually describing destiny and then these other people
were bumped by him that's the actual truth here oh hey look at the bottom here at least this paper
still points out that YouTube doesn't actually have an alt-right pipeline the way that Xander
Hall thought it did you know that pipeline video of mine that I made that got Xander Hall's panties
in a bunch he did a reaction to it and then I went on Adam and Sitch on their weekly Sunday
show to to basically react to the reaction and Xander Hall was supposed to pop in but he he never
did that was some ridiculous drama that happened surrounding me too it was it was fucking stupid
what's really interesting though are some of these citations used in this thesis and no I don't mean
Karl Marx's 1978 work a contribution to the critique of political economy you might have
gotten the century wrong on that one dude I'm talking more about how this thesis just seems
to be a description of twitch drama like like check this out several other streamers were then
banned for discussing the controversy this is the the cracker thing where twitch banned use of the
word cracker as a slur including the white libertarian socialist vosh who had send the
who had said the n-word on stream previously piker had attributed the event's origin to a brigade of
white right-wing naysayers who put themselves into a frenzy and also fellow streamer vosh for example
takes neoliberal stances which uphold colonialist global capitalist and or reactionary paradigms
and he's able to persuade his audience by exerting his power as the arbiter of the stream a lot of
these comments specifically about vosh but also many other streamers in this thesis rely on this
quotation Samson 2022 and what he's referring to is this YouTube video Noah Sampson 2022 solving
the debate bro problem and here is that video by Noah Sampson this video is intended to document
the many problems that debate streamers are creating for the online left and the built-in
white supremacy which allows this to happen Noah Sampson's a fucking idiot whoa whoa whoa the cow
gee Jesus Howard Noah Sampson who said that he liked me in a video and then later posted like a
minute-long retraction in the following video I have no problem black craters getting really big
however FD signifier is a dump okay okay so this video is kind of a meme video on the left right
now and something that kraut actually predicted years ago would be that there would be a complete
and total collapse of lefty tube of the online leftist space after Trump left office and that
has happened you've got the more video sas lefty tubers like contra points like h bomber guy like
Lindsay Ellis and these people you know as bad as they can be sometimes they absolutely hate the
the lefty twitch politics crowd at the bread tubers and the reason seems to be as far as I
can tell is because the twitch politics crowd there are a bunch of dunning kruger dumbfucks
who rely on charisma and debates to make arguments rather than any kind of actual foundation in in
fact meanwhile the video essayists even though they are you know often wrong as well they can
at least pull out a book and read it and give you a theory and like outline something they're not
simply shooting from the hip all the time and right now in the far left internet space there
is a huge civil war happening between react bro streamers and the video essayists and then there's
also the ongoing civil war which I talked about and in previous videos I think a year or two ago
at this point between the socialists and the progressives where the progressives view socialists
as being racist and class reductionist for not taking into account other intersectional issues
the socialists view the progressives and the intersectionals as basically just being rad
libs who aren't really part of the left and that these localist issues regarding race or sex or
or culture are distracting from the socialist revolution and so there's this tension on the
left between these two groups that just they just don't fit together and they're constantly bashing
against each other and they're basically ripping the left apart at this point the whole vosh
contra points drama recently or the vosh cat black drama recently and now the Noah Sampson
video these are all just individual data points along this larger trend of the left basically
fracturing and on some level you know I don't care I'm not part of the left and whatever it
is kind of funny to watch but that's the extent of of my attachment to it but some people are
taking this very very very seriously because the same thing happened to the right on YouTube back
in like 2017 2018 where internet blood sports destroyed the whole fucking thing and now it's
happening to the left and I guess this fucking guy thought it was so goddamn important that he
had to write his master's thesis on it I'm here mostly just to laugh at it because it is kind of
ridiculous but let's just check out the conclusion real quick here despite its challenges live
streaming uniquely benefits the socialist position the leftist materialist analysis
it requires its practitioners to navigate liveness and all its sincerity and intimacy
Jesus how can you say so much without saying anything at all necessarily the arrangement
and dominant culture of live streaming hold streamers accountable to their audiences on
some level with direct methods of recourse or critique available when suspicion arises via
the chat this kind of pushback is common in political live streams with users asking questions
in both good and bad faith and getting responded to appropriately here's how I know that you're a
son simp because this is not what he uses his chat for if you criticize him he just bans you
right-wing and more esoteric ideologies are not equipped for liveness because they simply cannot
respond to the collective bullshit calling of a live co-constitutive audience capitalism and
rightism cannot explain away the contradictions of their own relations sufficiently because the
contradictions of material life there's that marks 1978 again under capitalism say otherwise
this to me explains why right-wing content flourished on YouTube and in other static
edited forms but is yet to really make its way to live stream beyond the fringes it cannot explain
itself without debate speak and editing meanwhile live streaming rewards the sincere those who can
take critique and either adapt or view or explain in sufficient terms it's failing I think it's
actually much more simple than that I think it's because these platforms ban right-wing people head
over to cozy TV you see the 5,000 viewers that Nick Fuentes has I don't like Nick Fuentes but
he's clearly on the far right and he clearly has a big audience and he streams all the fucking time
this person is literally seeing that all of the right-wing debate bros who can actually debate
because this fucking analysis that right-wing and more esoteric ideologies are not equipped
for liveness that's just like immense stupidity because all the actual right-wing debaters they've
been banned and every time a socialist actually has to debate a liberal who is knowledgeable about
socialism on socialism the socialist constantly fucking loses because socialism itself is this
incoherent mess of an ideology that can't ever actually happen it can't ever actually be held
together like I've watched destiny debate people I've watched Sargon debate people I've watched
econoboi debate people all like debate socialist I mean I've watched like a bunch of people who
are who are liberals and who are conservatives debate socialists and as long as the liberal or
conservative is knowledgeable about socialism the socialist loses every time because socialism is a
losing ideology this thesis unironically reads like a super Hassan simp who has never actually
noticed that when you ban non leftists they don't simply disappear from the internet they go to
other platforms and their audience continues to grow there anyway it's time for me to take off
hopefully this gets edited and put up on Sunday as I intend and I will see you guys next time
have a good one I love you