hey there my community of chadley free thinking giga chads if you're watching this on release
i would like to let you know that this afternoon and this evening because it always goes on for a
very long time i'm going to be on efap again for the third time efap is over on mauler's channel
mauler is a friend of mine and i'm happy to be there again this will be the third efap in a row
that i'm featured on so maybe in about six hours or so you can head over to his channel and come
say hi because i'll be there with the gang and because i'm doing efap tonight i can't do my
usual nightly gaming stream so instead you know what i'm doing the gaming stream right now if
you're watching this video on youtube on release head over to the game boomers twitch channel or
the game boomers youtube channel and i'm going to be streaming kirby and the forgotten land right
now so please come say hi i would really appreciate it and enjoy the video thanks guys i
love you about two years ago i made a video called we're getting old and it may be worth going back
and watching it before checking this one out and though it goes without saying we're still getting
old i haven't gotten any younger since then the general point i was trying to get across back
then pretty poorly by today's standards because i think i've gotten a lot better at this sort
of thing is that millennial leftists have a shared childhood experience they all grew up
during an era where the religious right was still a powerful force and youth culture was under attack
from that force dungeons and dragons was satanic violence in video games was turning kids into
school shooters sexual content in hollywood was creating dysfunctional people skateboarding and
graffiti were a gateway to gang violence weed was a gateway to heroin and it was the left that stood
in defense of individual liberties and not punishing people for things they can't control
people should be left alone to do what they like as long as they aren't hurting others that
includes video games and drugs and sex being gay or trans should be protected because they're
immutable characteristics in the same way that races and speech should not be censored simply
because it's blasphemous to some people this is just old man dev talking about the good old days
of the left those days are over nowadays the left talks about dungeons and dragons being problematic
because orcs are black people i guess video games turn people into misogynists sexual content in
hollywood is objectifying and degrading the left still likes skateboarding graffiti i guess but
only if the tag says black lives matter and the drug conversation is a double-edged sword in the
left right now as they simultaneously oppose the effects of drugs while still wanting to get high
in the most blatant case of wanting to have your cake and eat it too the left now thinks that you
cannot be left alone to do what you like because everything is political being gay or trans is a
choice not an immutable characteristic and choosing to be those things is okay for the
most extreme radicals you have a moral obligation to choose to be gay or trans and that speech
should be censored because it is offensive the reason this complete 180 on these principles
happened is due to an effect that i described in my g4 frost cure in video when a generation
consists of teenagers in their efforts to find themselves they will rebel against the status quo
they live in for millennials that's rejecting the hyper civil relatively apolitical yet still
conservative boomer order and embracing quasi anarchic politics with a punk aesthetic but when
that generation reaches the age in which they start settling down those old rebellious parts
of them are deliberately defanged so that they may integrate with society and suddenly these
people who were so edgy in their youth begin to view that old edginess as being deeply wrong and
so the next generation of youth still in their own rebellious phase are not simply going through the
process that everybody else goes through but now they are a fundamental problem with society that's
why you see so many videos and articles about how there's large swaths of zoomer fascists right now
because those zoomers are teenagers currently in the process of rebelling against the leftist
culture that millennials have crafted for millennials it was legitimate for them to
rebel because they were rebelling against the right but it's not legitimate for the zoomers
to rebel because they're rebelling against the left in essence the millennials have forgotten
what it's like to be young they are so incredibly self-centered that they think just because they've
figured it out because they've gone through the maturation process that other generations coming
up don't need to do the same thing for themselves as well in that way the millennials are almost
identical to the boomers they just have the misfortune of lacking any of their material wealth
but they're equal in levels of entitlement and delusion i'm talking about this because
this clip went viral a couple of days ago
to play this game i'm not a noob all right god damn
what what a bitch bitch is a bitch talking to me is a female talking to me
am i don't know am i tripping am i tripping or how do i tell it's a female talking to me right
now it's a fucking female talking to me get off the fucking game and do your wobbly dishes bitch
shut up fuck you fuck is wrong with y'all stop talking like that nigga fuck is wrong with y'all
dog i'm not one of these little lame ass valor nerd nigga fuck
ass ass y'all are pure ass y'all are ass
y'all are y'all are ass y'all are ass this guy is i show speed a big time valorant streamer on
youtube he's 17 years old and just in case you can't tell he's black this clip blew up because
some leftoid esports dude named jake lucky posted it to twitter with the following caption i now
understand why valorant cues are so unbelievably toxic you got one of the most popular streamers
on youtube i show speed saying crap like this and getting nothing but praise and laughs crap is whack
actually unbelievable kids be looking up to this and finding it all right he is 17 my dude
he is going to be a mouthy little shit when he's online and his parents aren't around have you
forgotten what it's like oh wait you've already gone over this yes you have forgotten but you know
what i haven't i remember dropping slurs and gamer words like it was nobody's business as a kid
because i was a kid it was hilarious to watch people like jake lucky clutch his pearls in
response and you know what it still fucking is and like every other stupid moral outrage we can
do the usual things in analyzing it for example this idiot says this guy needs help the idiot's
twitter feed is full of him using slurs and making suicide jokes and all the rest of it and then this
idiot embarrassingly deletes his complaint because every single woke scold online right now used to
do this stuff and now that it's 2022 they all think their shit doesn't stink the actual correct
response is to understand that this is fucking banter there's tons of clips floating around
where speed is getting slapped with racist shit in chat too
you gotta back up man you're a female you got a period
ah
just heal like only the white characters can heal
yeah only only the the white characters can heal i'm sorry
hey yo it's all clearly trash talk it's not like speed is walking up to random women on the street
and saying get back in the kitchen bitch out of nowhere it's clearly in the context of playing
valorant and talking shit now maybe you think that all trash talk all banter is just bad and
okay fine you're wrong banter is a fundamental part of the game and it's been a fundamental part
of games since long before video games it was part of sports before gaming was a thing you might be
wrong but at least you're consistent in thinking that all trash talk is bad most people currently
losing their shit at speed aren't consistent they're being pointed at him by a viral tweet
and ignoring the hate that he also gets in return because there's a lot of retweets and likes on it
and it's a great way to show your followers how fucking morally correct you are by joining in on
the dog pile even though get this speed did nothing wrong yes he was being an asshole you
can even say he was being sexist if you want to believe that he actually holds these opinions
and wasn't just nerd raging out but fundamentally banter is a part of the game it's a part of every
game and engaging in it isn't deontologically bad these people just think it is because they've
grown up in the most sanitized version of the internet to ever exist such that they believe
it's on the level of being brutally stabbed to death if they even so much as see a drop of
negativity in their notifications tab look at this look at this fucking comment this is from like 20
years ago everybody who saw this back in the day knew it was specifically designed to be inflammatory
it played off schoolyard console war shit and it made people laugh over how over the top it was if
some 19 year old soy leftoid saw this on social media today he would probably spontaneously combust
there's still enough sane people out there that there has been a sustained objection to speed's
treatment by the mainstream the leftist reply to this objection can be summed up here y'all
wouldn't have survived cod lobbies in 2009 my brother in christ you are 36 years old it's time
to move on the whole modern warfare 2 lobbies thing has quickly become the video game equivalent
of dudes holding on to being cool in high school but losers now not evolving as a person is not a
flex not growing with society is not a flex you are stuck look at how disingenuously they frame
this conversation they think that it's progress to become more censorious they think that it's
good to expand the list of the things that you can't say they think that reversing the trend
of society moving towards irreverence towards individualism towards expression is what
constitutes growing up they think that having thinner and thinner skin over time is a sign of
strength rather than obviously it being a sign of extreme weakness in other words they've gotten
soft in their old age and they're flabbergasted that young people aren't as old as they are
these people are fucking retards they're acting like things have never been worse when things have
never been better they're acting like the early days of xbox live didn't have the single most
concentration of slurs at any one time on the planet it's like with feminists becoming more
radical as they win more rights or black activists or lgbt activists as they win they need to keep
justifying their outrage and their existence so smaller problems are treated like they're way
worse than they actually are but it's like i said in those previous videos there's something about
the competitive nature of gaming that makes it anti-socialist inherently and i think that's why
a lot of people look at zoomer gamers and scream fascists and then extrapolate that to this crazy
conspiracy theory that there's a new era of fascists on the rise in the west and that kids
are going to be groomed into right-wing thought when the reality is the kids are just resisting
only partially i might add the left-wing grooming that is currently all over the place in any case
speed got completely fucking destroyed the head of youtube gaming is saying they're looking into
him and somebody at riot games posted this this is a huge yikes and we do not want players like
this in our community at all i went ahead and permabanned this player from valorant as well as
all other riot games thanks for raising this please keep raising stuff like this and reporting
so we can make valorant safer bitch it's an online shooter people get frustrated people banter it's a
fucking violent game welcome to the internet this is why your games have mute and block functions
isn't it so great another black kid's career is destroyed over literally nothing except some older
white guy didn't like the language he used and it offended his middle class bougie sensibilities
no matter how morally righteous the progs claim to be some things just never fucking change