Well, I'll start off by saying this.
Hey, what's my feed in the mail?
I mailed it on you, saying this, yep.
What does that mean?
I don't care who you play, whether it's a high school team, a junior college, a junior college team, a high college team, much less a game college team.
When you turn the ball over, nine thousand times, four interceptions, one per interception, one per game college team, one per Bill O'Reilly, one per five dick.
In my opinion, that sucked.
Fucking thing sucks!
Well, I'll start off by saying this. Do not blame that game on the game defense. Blame that game on Bill O'Reilly.
Fuck you.
What's that?
Cocksucker.
What does that mean?
Playoffs.
Playoffs? Don't talk about it.
Playoffs? You kidding me?
Playoffs?
Playoffs.
Playoffs? Don't talk about it.
Playoffs? You kidding me?
Playoffs?
Do it live!
What what what?
What does that mean?
Do it live!
Playoffs.
Don't talk about it.
expandable
You kidding me?
What what what?
Playoffs?
I just hope we can win a game.
What does that mean?
I don't know what that is.
Step.
What does that mean?
I don't know what that means.
Fuck you?
I've just killed O'Reilly.
DIE!