Hello ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the right opinion of the home of a twat with
too much free time and I am fucking exploiting that free time right now because by my calculations
this video is going to be a 20 minute point so I hope you bellends have some patience
I would assure everyone that this is a special and if it does do well I may do specials once
a month or so if I can though I cannot guarantee or promise anything my free time has its boundaries
Back it up, pack it in, let me begin, I came to win, battle me that's a sin, I won't ever
slack up, hunk it better back up, try and play the role and you're the whole crew, well
act up, get up, stand up, come on throw your hands up, if you got the feeling, jump across
the ceiling, mugs let's all bump up, someone's talking junk, yeah we'll bust them in the
eye and then I'll take the punks home
Given that this is such a big event I need to introduce what this video is going to be
about I'm going to be looking at social experiments
and the recent chronology preceding this video, their creators and the implications
that they actually hold I'm on the warpath today and you're going
to be along for the ride with me, also I'm going to be focusing on racially divisive
videos and the effect that they have on the society around them
Now I know some of you will be saying but you said you want to cover YouTube drama,
well you twat this isn't just YouTube drama this is social experiments and they are greater
than YouTube they extend this to society and the impressionable idiots that believe the
propaganda they peddle This is not just a petulant personal gripe
nor is it just shit content which by the way it is
This is me saying that there is a genuine danger to the crap that these channels pathetically
pump out and profit from My intention in this video is to prevent one
of these disgustingly divisive and derivative videos from ever surfacing on the internet
ever again Which is a completely ridiculous far-fetched
ambition but I feel if I shoot for the stars I'll have more impact on these extremely egregious
vacuums of meaningful content I'm fucking going in and these cunts are going
to bear the brunt of it But first a little background
My first experience with social experiments was with the show What Would You Do an ABC
series that began in 2008 and created stage scenarios to see how the general public would
respond I was intrigued at the time and I watched
a fair few episodes which human psychology does genuinely interest me
Given the often controversial nature of the situations I was surprised by how passable
it seemed to most people It's never really had much of an accusation
of being fake though and to be honest when I watch it it does seem pretty representative
which is probably why I avoided any allegations or prosecutions
It had standards to maintain and although American TV isn't always the most real
There was something believable about it Sometime a few years ago YouTubers discovered
that there was a social media platform for these sorts of experiments and began enacting
them to the oblivious public In my opinion the first videos of these social
experiments were likely real with these said YouTubers finding their feet and working out
the limits of their social experiments However upon learning their limits they realised
in fact that there were no limits Not on YouTube at least
As long as you were making them a fuck tonne of money then who the fuck cares
And more importantly they couldn't prove your pranks to be fake
But thank god some people have
I have a lot to get through so let's start off with the most recent of controversies
and the silliest of YouTubers Joey Salads
All time looks like there's an Ebola outbreak in New York
Joey Salads has been around long enough for me to be aware of his antics
I have always had the niggling suspicion that his videos are completely faked
And now the simplest of snapchats has proved it
For anyone who has emerged from a 30 year coma and you're not aware of what's gone
down recently Joey Salads set up a fake social experiment in which he dressed a car in Trump
apparel and left it in a predominantly black area to see what would happen
In barely any time at all a load of youths turned up and completely trashed the car
In fact one of them had found a very well suited lead pipe in which I'm presuming he
had lying around in his humble abode in case any Trump supporting vehicles entered the
vicinity He concluded that because of this that black
people must hate Trump And that in elaboration of this fantastical
scenario he had people approach him and say they were scared to vote Trump because of
community hostility Now with the emergence of this new evidence
that proves this was all completely contrived and staged
I would normally just dismiss him as another money grabbing idiot who just wanted to make
a quick buck off racial tensions And he probably is
However that's already been spoken about You see this goes deeper than a normal smash
and grab If you were to glide onto his twitter and
have a scroll through his tweets it wouldn't take very long to realise that he was a fervent
Trump supporter In fact he was a very very very aggressive
Trump supporter At first I thought okay this is clearly a
parody account So I was just creating meaningless banter
to fulfil the controversy But scrolling down far enough I found this
absolute peach of a twitter video
He's a multi-billionaire And Ronald Reagan matter of fact he was a
TV actor who became president and is one of the best presidents we ever had in history
So even if Trump was just a reality TV star Reagan proved that you can come from entertainment
and media and become an awesome president regardless
So those two points totally debunk that whole stupid stupid liberal argument where how Trump's
a reality TV star he can't be president he's not qualified
After watching this the true scum of Joey Salads and his latest prank really emerged
Here is a man driven by his own political agenda of turning people against a community
in favour of Trump And yeah he can apologise profusely and make
up bullshit excuses about why this is the case but there's no excuse for this
His conscience could not have been clearer when he published that video and he knew the
exact implications Despite the transparency of this video I
mean look he has a fucking lead piping The foolish idiots just ate it up
Unfortunately the comments section has been swamped by H3H3 fans but initially there were
people who genuinely bought into this repulsive repugnant reptilian's rhetoric
I'm really glad this video has called out for what it is because if it hadn't and people
had believed this given the current racial climate the implications could have been terrible
It only takes one straw to break the camel's back and judging by the comments it could
have very easily escalated You don't know whose lingering prejudices
you could have fed and based on false information it's hardly justifiable in any case
The one hilariously stupid argument that ignoramus has always come up with is
Well it reflects all that's genuinely happening in America
Well mate if it's genuinely happening then why'd you have to fake it you asinine half wits
He masqueraded and invested Trump's supporting agenda in this facade of public interest which
is as inexcusable as far as I'm concerned and a simple apology video with a made up
story about how he was approached is just as phony as any other prank video
He's removed that particular video because of all the negative press however if you need
any other provocative content to fulfil your prejudices do not fear because all the previous
videos like the legendary bake car are still available for public consumption
Joey Salads is a cunt who does not belong on YouTube
Okay so Joey Salads is a bad person who knows what he's doing is incredibly odious
Well I'm pretty sure he does at least What's worse than that?
Well I found the cherry on the cake
I should know better now that I've met ya I hope I can alter my ways
But I've been a bad, bad man I've been a bad, bad man
I've been a bad, bad man I've been a bad, bad man
Ladies and gentlemen this is Fouseytube a special type of twat
This is a rarest specimen a person who believes he is a missionary
Here to be your inspiration on YouTube Well I can assure you that you have inspired
me to make a whole section dedicated to your highness Fouseytube
This one is for you I could go on about his fake drama or how
he's evolved into another generic vlogger with the personality of a fucking grapefruit
But as we're doing racially focused videos I'll stick to the subject and cover any extra
points afterwards We've seen the forced prejudice against black
people social experiment But let's mix it up with a forced prejudice
against white people social experiment Firstly remember that this one is also completely
fake as well In this one he has the hashtag blacklivesmatter
which is a great way to start off a fake politically charged social experiment
This video entails how people will react if a black person stole an item from a white
person and vice versa Now Fouseytube not only engineered the experiment
to suit his agenda and to feed the tension rather than actually fight it
He also plugged in an in-memory section at the end of his video to manipulate the emotions
of all the people watching and create this slimy veneer of unity to what is actually
a very divisive video The truth is simple however
When you make a video like that you don't do anything to stop the prejudices
People don't associate negativity with the realisation that there are race divides
In fact this sort of video will just make white people defensive and feed the prejudice
of others When the truth is really really much simpler
there are cunts in every race and religion and the best way to deal with this is to bridge
the gaps not to make them In the words of Martin Luther King hate cannot
drive out hate and hating in the name of love is one of the most contradictory bullshit
messages but it's one that Fouseytube has adapted very well
It's just as divisive as the Joey salad situation and probably even more deceptive
Fouseytube is a wolf in sheep's clothing There was a video on the internet a couple
years back where they paired homophobic people with homosexual people and made them maturely
talk out the differences and at the end the final goal was to make them hug each other
It was a very successful video and that shows the real power of positive association
Once again they didn't need to plug in a forced message to try and justify what they
were doing because they did it naturally There is nothing natural about this video
and that's only emphasised by the fact that it's fucking fake
How do we know that it's fake? Because Fouseytube admitted it himself but claimed all his videos
were done in good spirit I'd say he doesn't know better but he clearly
does he's just full of shit Now this is the point where I would thank
and reference ColossalersCrazy's video to Fouseytube and endorse you all to watch it
However unfortunately it has been taken down and Colossal given a copyright strike by the
Fouseytube himself In Colossal's video he systematically took
apart Fouseytube's videos and explained why Fouseytube is an absolute cunt
And Fouseytube being the crazed egotistical megalomaniac he is, striked his video and
took all the revenue from it All the fucking revenue
So on the 30th day that I had that video still under my CMS I got a tweet saying it's the
30th day and what did I do? I told my team to remove the video thinking
that would be that Colossal took months to make a video
He put time and effort to script, create and edit 45 minutes worth of content
More than any manufactured product that Fouseytube ever wanked over
And he has the audacity to monetise a video that's not even his and then get it taken
down It's a fucking disgrace and exactly why people
like Fouseytube should not be given the power they currently have on YouTube
The reason that Fouseytube has done this is because he doesn't want anyone to challenge
his YouTube golden boy image that he so desperately wants to preserve
He wants to inspire people, be this role model, he's a good person you see
Let me tell you this Fouseytube, you are a bad person
You have profited off prejudice, you've coasted off a career made by exploiting stereotypes
and you honestly want to stand and be this role model who's gonna tour the world and
give inspirational speeches and write a fucking book?
You want to shut down anyone, anyone who dares speak against your own self-centred image
You try to justify your good deeds by buying shit
You're an idiot, you know that
Buying stuff for people does not make you a good person
People like Al Capone and Pablo Escobar did a lot of community work
Unfortunately it didn't stop them from being absolute scumbags
And unfortunately for you Fouseytube, you're too thick in the skull to realise that it's
not how you spend your money that defines you as a person, it's how you fucking earn it
You're the American equivalent of syndicate and you'll grab the money even if it's not
yours It doesn't even matter how you fucking do with
it afterwards
And people are gonna shut the fuck up about charity work
Some of the worst human beings have done charity work to try and justify a false positive
image to manipulate the public
Not this time Fousey, not this time
Charity work does not right your wrongs
Bad people can do good things
Especially when those good things are done in a half-assed attempt to try and project
a false image
And this brings me to my closing statement
No one should be making money off dangerous hate-inciting content
It's only going to be demonetised when talking about sensitive issues like I have in the
past and I understand why
This must also fall under that
I really want to go in on more YouTubers in this video
Unfortunately most social experiments have not been completely proven fake even though
I have a hunch most of them are
Social experiments are dangerous when you fake them because you're feeding an image
to the public that will cause prejudice and tension which in America right now is the
last thing we need
Joey Salad and Fouseytubes are not affected by any of these prejudices because they have
a fuck tonne of money
If they were actually related to any of the victims of race-related crime, the unarmed
black civilians or the police officers, they would think twice, I'm sure of it
But they're not
They live in their own YouTube bubble driven by self-interest and taking advantage of the
emotions of viewers who don't have to experience the implications that this sort of content
might hold
That's the real threat and that outdo's any good indeed
If you're considering doing any social experiment with regards to race relations, I have a message
for you
You can do it, but if you do it, then the blood is on your hands
Don't be Joey Salads, don't be inspired by Fouseytube, both of whom are driven by the
incentive of a hidden selfish agenda
Make content that will actually ease the situation and work to stop this bullshit that is a danger
to society as far as I'm concerned
In conclusion, social experiments with a propagandist undertone should not be mis-sold to the public
as it endangers race relations for those who are actually exposed to living in more deprived
impoverished areas, the ones affected by the insidious message that these videos hold
In my opinion, they shouldn't be airing, but there's nothing I can do about it
Fuck you, YouTube
We can just hope that one day we'll see an end to these disgraceful, disgraceful, supposedly
social experiments
Do you think there's anything remotely defensible about the recent escapades?
Do you think Joey Salads and or Fouseytube are good people?
I hope not, but it's a free world
Leave your thoughts and comments in the section below
I'm the right opinion and I hope this doesn't get taken down
Fuck you, Fouseytube