Justin Trudeau called an election and you know what that means it's another SFO
Trudeau video. I've done a few of these now over the course of the history of my
channel and we vote in the 20th so now is as good a time as any. First of all I
want to make it clear that absolutely nobody wanted this election and it's
almost insane that Justin Trudeau would call it because the ball was in his
court. For those of you who don't know Canada works on the British
parliamentary system. The idea is if you have a majority of the seats in the
House of Commons your party is locked in for five years and so when Justin Trudeau
won a majority in 2015 he was locked in for five years. The next election saw him
win a minority. A minority government is when you don't have enough seats to form
the majority but other parties decide to prop you up in the coalition and
generally a minority government topples because those other parties have
withdrawn support triggering an election. Didn't happen this time though
this time Trudeau just triggered one out of the blue and even now nobody seems to
know why it just seems like he thinks he's really popular and he can try and
get another majority. It really feels like a power grab and so far it's kind
of been backfiring in his face. So a few months ago this motion went through
Parliament. Now a motion is not a a legally binding document it's not a law
it's just Parliament's declaration of intent and the motion reads that the
House remind the government that a general election was held in October
2019 and sadly note that more than 1.3 million Canadians including almost 360
thousand Quebecers have been infected with COVID-19 and that nearly 25,000
people have died as a result and in the opinion of the House holding an election
during a pandemic would be irresponsible and that it is the responsibility of the
government to make every effort to ensure that voters are not called to
the polls as long as this pandemic continues. And nearly everybody agreed to
this motion 320 yeses one no including all the liberals including Trudeau
himself and yet just a few months later on August 19th Trudeau called his
election. I can't emphasize enough how how dumb this seems to be like there was
no reason to do it Trudeau's popularity was already down his opponents are
actually stronger than they were in 2019 regardless of how you feel about
coronavirus the population here in Canada certainly does not want to be
voting during the pandemic this has been a deeply unpopular move and it has
exposed Trudeau's baldness in trying to consolidate power Trudeau's public
events have been marred by protesters.
To stand up for people here and you know what we did it we won you guys are
still able to export to the United States on privileged terms thanks to our
collective success then.
At one point his campaign bus was blocked in by angry people
Oh
At another event people threw rocks at him and by the way that's assault guys
don't don't go throwing rocks at anybody all right. He has had to cancel events
due to how deeply unpopular he is. Hey Trudeau remember how liberal leaders
used to deal with protesters in their way? I sure do. Over the course of the
campaign the Canadian polls have looked something like this the Liberals down
the Conservatives up the NDP sitting in a comfortable third place as they always
do a complete destruction of the Green Party and the PPC is slowly rising up
however now that we're closer to the polling day the Liberals and
Conservative are both neck and neck but not because the Liberals went up but the
Conservatives went down instead the PPC is rising now I'm not somebody who's
breathing in a shit ton of copium there is no chance the PPC forms a government
they might get a seat or two here or there but at this point the race is
basically neck-to-neck during a campaign stop Trudeau is asked about his own
campaign violating COVID restrictions by jamming so many supporters and
journalists into the same room at once and in the usual Trudeau fashion he
completely dodges the question yes the videos from Rebel News and I don't like
those guys either but they pulled it from CPAC this is not some kind of a
trick this is the real deal check it out
I'm not sure that was an answer to my question so did you get special clearance to hold an
event that exceeds current crowd capacity in Ontario indoors we're going
to continue to do everything we can to keep people safe we will always follow
public health guidance we will follow the best recommendations of the public
health experts advising our campaign and the first and most fundamental thing we
do is to be able to look at Canadians and say every single one of our
candidates is doing the right thing and speaking of chrono bars Trudeau was
basically on the same train as Nancy Pelosi back before it hit you were a
racist for worrying about it and lockdowns or other measures were just
conspiracy theories how dare you even say that we do them in fact Canada was
so sure of that position that Ottawa sent 16 tons of personal protective
equipment to China in February of 2020 of course like everyone else a year
later he had changed his tune rolling lockdowns restrictions mask mandates
and now vaccines and keep in mind I'm not an anti-vaxxer I've said this many
times all across the internet and I'll say it again at this point I'm pretty
sure the vaccines are safe yes there are side effects there are complications the
chances of you having a complication from the vaccine are lower than the
chances of you having a complication from naturally catching the corona
virus so generally for most people you should get the vaccine but it is 100%
government overreach for them to demand that you get the vaccine for them to
force you to for them to insist that you show your papers just to go outside of
your house that is not a scientific conversation it's a political one and
the people who are endorsing it are tyrants and just like with every other
tyrant the rules don't apply to them here's January 26th 2021 Trudeau is
warning about new travel restrictions coming to Canada and Canada's exposure
notification app and while his official Twitter account was tweeting this he was
vacationing in the Caribbean Trudeau has repeatedly lied about the status of
Canadian readiness when it comes to stuff like personal protective
equipment masks and hospitals and other most famously though he lied about local
vaccine production he announced that it would be ready in 2021 but the company
that his government enlisted soon after clarified they won't be producing
doses until 2022 nonetheless Trudeau's government is demanding that all
government workers get the vaccine this page dropped August 13th 2021 and
actually was quickly taken down when Trudeau decided that he wanted to call
an election and he realized this would be a very unpopular move so it went up
and then down and it's been scrubbed from the internet and just in case I
couldn't be more clear about my contempt for Justin Trudeau this explicit threat
by sitting Prime Minister is disgusting and is completely 100% unacceptable in a
free open and democratic society but the bottom line is if anyone who doesn't
have a legitimate medical reason for not getting fully vaccinated chooses to not
get vaccinated there will be consequences as I've said I'm no
anti-vaxxer and the vaccines work but if this is how the government is going to
behave I will play chicken with you right up until the end of course it's
not just Trudeau in the Liberal Party all of Canada's left-leaning politicians
want to force-vax people at some point I will need to do a video on Jagmeet Singh
because at the end of the day he's a terrorist sympathizer a communist
mass-murder sympathizer and a Sikh supremacist as well as the leader of
Canada's NDP but for the purposes of this video he is 100% on board with
fucking people who don't comply with the government we know that the vast
majority Canadians want to do their part to keep people safe and want to get
vaccinated and we also know that the vast majority Canadians believe in in
having some way to prove that that vaccination having a vaccine passport
and we know that people on the front line that are providing care or
providing services directly to Canadians can pose the higher risk and should be
vaccinated so we would work with unions and work with the workers on the ground
to make sure we establish a way to move forward but we absolutely believe that
there needs to be mandatory vaccines and there would be consequences for those
who are not able to or not willing to do that thankfully the most poll he
actually has is streaming jackbox on twitch where he draws Justin Trudeau
losing an election to him keep dreaming buddy the coronavirus has hit everyone
economically quite badly including Canada Trudeau's plans for a carbon tax
increase have basically been destroyed due to the pandemic and pandemic spending
just like every other Western nation has destroyed our economy Canada's current
deficit level will be unsustainable within one to two years and it's been a
year since this was published so we are on the verge of being fucked right now
and despite the call for more taxes more taxes more taxes taxes remain the
largest expense for Canadian families with the average Canadian household
earning ninety six thousand three hundred and thirty three dollars and
paying thirty five thousand and forty seven dollars in taxes that's thirty
six point four percent of their income going to taxes compared to thirty five
point four percent going to housing food and clothing combined and although I'm
not necessarily a believer in grand conspiracy theories I do at the very
least like to keep a pulse on them and Trudeau is absolutely 100% on board with
the great reset building back better means getting support to the most
vulnerable while maintaining our momentum on reaching the 2030 agenda for
sustainable development and the SDGs Canada is here to listen and to help
this pandemic has provided an opportunity for a reset this is our
chance to accelerate our pre-pandemic efforts to reimagine economic systems
that actually address global challenges like extreme poverty inequality and
climate change but considering Justin Trudeau's dim-witted nature I don't
actually think this is part of some kind of grand Bilderberg lizard men
conspiracy theory of trying to create a one-world government I think Trudeau
thinks it sounds good and appeals to his base and so he's virtue signaling
because almost the entirety of Trudeau's government has been about virtue
signaling this is a man who will appeal to every single issue in the book
anti-semitism Islamophobia women's rights LGBTQ rights French language
rights classism even fat phobia it doesn't matter he is a pure
intersectionalist and so when sometimes these intersections come into conflict
Trudeau is often left holding his dick this was a scandal over a year ago when
Trudeau defended not publicly supporting LGBTQ rights in Senegal and taking a
photo of him bowing towards an Iranian minister who is known for being quite
anti LGBTQ it turns out you cannot be on the right side of every single issue
because they come into conflict all the time
Trudeau has given taxpayer money to support black Canadian entrepreneurs
again leaning into intersectional race based bullshit surely we should just be
supporting Canadian entrepreneurs regardless of their skin color a member
of Trudeau's cabinet attended an arranged marriage ceremony where a young
woman was auctioned to the highest bidder I guess despite the feminist
leanings of Justin Trudeau selling women is okay as long as it's a beautiful
native culture that's doing it meanwhile at the same time another member of
Trudeau's cabinet when talking about the current Afghanistan crisis referred to
the Taliban as our brothers Trudeau's government put forward bill c6 back in
2017 making it so that people who immigrated to Canada became terrorists
and committed terrorist attacks cannot be stripped of their citizenship and
sent back by the Canadian government and just like in the United States the
Canadian government has authorized the tearing down of statues related to our
history but unlike the United States these aren't Confederate statues or
something this is Sir John A Macdonald Canada's first prime minister this is an
erasure of our history our identity our culture as Canadians by our own
government I know in one of those previous Trudeau videos I don't remember
which I made fun of Trudeau saying people kind not mankind well here's some
more recent cringe for you enjoy it is exactly the example of the kinds of
things you need to do to counter the she said the she session and turn it into a
she-covery just like with every other woke oid Justin Trudeau's virtue
signaling is an act designed to hide exactly how he does not live up to his
own principles for example despite Trudeau's lip service on environmental
issues his party has designated environmental protesters as federal
security threats additionally during this election cycle the Liberals have
promised to build 1.4 million new homes and ban foreign home ownership both
ideas that are popular but also both that they had six years implement so far
meanwhile the Liberals of Vancouver candidate a city where the housing
squeeze has hit people the hardest is known for flipping dozens of homes a
topic which Justin Trudeau has absolutely nothing to say about his
candidate sure does though how much have you profited on those 25 in the past
decade I mean I'm not you know I think it's important to talk about I'm gonna
answer that question again so I don't be sure yeah how much have you profited on
those sales
I when you ask I'm gonna give me a second to just make sure I have the
right okay so sorry ask me the question yes sir yeah yeah how much have you
profited personally or business-wise on the sales of those 25 properties in the
last decade while I can't give you an exact number what I can tell you is that
it is by no means the number that has been bit forward but what I can also
tell you is that I am absolutely committed to any and all measures that
we have put forward that would that would apply I am still waiting for a
number outside here if he has one a bottom line he doesn't seem to think or
won't say that his past business dealings are part of this unafford
unaffordability problem another of his candidates I think it's pronounced Raj
Saini has been accused for six years now of multiple instances of sexual
misconduct and despite those accusations despite Trudeau's feminist credentials
and his glowing support of the me2 movement his party has still allowed him
to run at least until another set of more recent allegations dropped and
Trudeau finally asked Saini to step down not without the Liberal Party giving him
$93,000 though of course there are actually more legitimate scandals
surrounding Trudeau's government not just virtue signaling and hypocrisy but
actually violating the law the most recent high-profile scandal revolves
around the we organization which paid hundreds of thousands of dollars in
speaking fees to Trudeau's wife mother and brother and completely coincidentally
I'm sure later received a 900 million dollar contract with the Canadian
federal government during a remote only session of Parliament because this was
early in the pandemic Trudeau had to give testimony about his involvement
with the we charity and it did not look good for him yes or no question mr. chair
prime minister you twice were found guilty of breaking the ethics act after
those two convictions did you decide to read the act you got 14 seconds prime
minister yes I have read the act a number of times are you aware of section
21 yes since I've read the act I'm aware of section what does it say I can pull
it up for you but if you have it in front of you well it says a public
office holder of which you are one shall recuse himself or herself from any
discussion to decision debate or vote in any matter in which in respect of
which he or she would be in a conflict of interest now what you've admitted
today is not just that you were in a conflict of interest but that you
consciously recognized in your May cabinet meeting that such a conflict
might exist that it didn't just slide by your desk that you were consciously
aware that there was a an inappropriate link to your family that would put
you in a conflict why did you at that moment not call the ethics commissioner
and recuse yourself that is simply not true mr. Paul yeah the issue of
advancing issues for one's own and by the way the ethics commissioner is
looking into this right now and I fully trust his judgment on on determining it
but at the same time my concern around accusing myself was a question around
perceptions because I know well that this Canada summer students grant for
16 to directly benefit my mother or my brother your 16 seconds are obvious
your 16 seconds are up I'm gonna ask you again because you know nobody nobody
believes you when you say you don't know how much money your family has got from
the wheat group you've had a month to look into that you knew you were going
to testify here again how much money total have your brother mother and
spouse received from this organization how much that information has been
publicly shared but I will tell you what it is how much has just the dollar
figure throughout her life the dollar figure prime minister this ways and is
how much of the work that she's done and I'm proud of how much I'm looking for a
dollar figure we can get that number for you if you like it's been in out in
the media it's been in the media but you don't know it you don't know how much
your family has received from this organization which you tried to give a
half billion dollars really I'm waiting you haven't done an answer so far let's
make this the first one my mother has worked as an advocate the dollar figure
speaker good organizations across the country I do not feel that into the
work my mother is doing and eventually he had to come out and
apologize for not recusing himself in the we charity contract decision but
this sort of government corruption where money's changing hands all the time is
not something that Justin Trudeau is a stranger to everyone at this point
remembers the SNC lava Lynn scandal and if you don't to be honest it's an
extremely complicated topic that I've already done a deep dive into so if you
want to know what's going on please go watch that video but Trudeau has been
blocking the investigation into him and his party every way he can
she said that she then committed to revisit and look into the decision once
again mr. speaker all these are elements in the testimony examined exhaustively
now the Prime Minister has caught himself in a trap of his own making he
came out on February 15th and compliant said that no one had come forward to
raise any concerns about his conduct and now he admits on the floor of the House
of Commons that way before in September his own Attorney General asked him to
his face
prime minister having so much difficulty remembering his story is it because it's
simply not true and Jody Wilson Raybould the person who ultimately blew the
whistle on Trudeau's wrongdoing has finally been allowed to publish a book
on what she knows now that the investigation is wrapping up let me read
a short excerpt from the book for you I know the Prime Minister had always
considered me a challenge not political enough too independent-minded and
ultimately not part of the inner liberal crowd I think I was foreign and
incomprehensible to him after all I was from the other side of the tracks I was
an indigenous girl from a small fishing village Cape Mudge on the southern tip
of Quadra Island just off Vancouver Island I am Jesus this word dude
kawaka wacko okay quack wacka wacko quack wack wack all right the Prime
Minister did not grow up in my neighborhoods with the kids I grew up
with none of his family went to residential schools my childhood
memories are closer to commox and Cape Mudge than rock cliff my political point
of reference was the big house not the House of Commons to be fair he did not
choose how and where he grew up or who his parents were but liberals political
parties not my world there is no question in my mind that the Prime
Minister knew there were attempts to pressure me to avoid a criminal
prosecution of SNC lavalin and while those attempts failed thankfully they
were wrong and he knew it instead of simply addressing the issue publicly and
accurately the government was sending out talking heads to make comments that
evidence has now shown were not accurate or right I told him that he should be
telling Canadians the truth the Prime Minister seemed to be listening intently
I never directed he said referring to interfering in my role as the Attorney
General in relation to the SNC lavalin prosecution his public lines started
coming which were designed to deny responsibility and culpability there
are differences between pressure and direction he emphasized we talked about
our soon-to-be infamous meeting with the clerk of the Privy Council on September
17th 2018 riot asked him directly when SNC lavalin was raised are you
politically interfering with my role my decision as the Attorney General I would
strongly advise against it he repeated in that Airport room that I was not
shuffled from being Minister of Justice and Attorney General because of SNC
lavalin as he went on I suddenly blurred it out I don't want you to say anything
further about what happened after September 17th to this day I'm still
surprised I said it I know why I did it and why I wanted him to stop talking I
was trying to leave space open for a constructive solution to the mess the PM
in his office had created and that in my overly optimistic opinion could still be
found either the Prime Minister knew everything that had happened and did not
care and was clearly lying to me in the country or he didn't know what had been
happening during the months after September 17th to try to exert pressure
on me and was not in control of his office as I had in the past I gave the
Prime Minister the benefit of the doubt for what would be the last time I made
it very clear I did not trust the people around him and that he was being badly
advised in this situation he made it equally clear to me that he would never
fire some of them so I laid out the only other options that existed the
Prime Minister's office stuck with its current approach of changing its story
over and over again which would only make things worse in which case I would
resign or he came out and came clean and we placed our trust in the truth and in
Canadians I pushed the second option he said he would think about it and that we
would talk again we met again on February 11th and proceeded to cover the
same ground as the day before I recounted again the incidents where
pressure was attempted and he again had excuses or answers for everything he
repeated that he would not clean house or fire anyone and then he offered up if
we did we would not be in government in October I replied I would be surprised
if we were in government if you did not clean at least some of the house in some
way and call some type of investigation I added after all if you're confident
you did nothing wrong then why would you not want to do this this was about the
maintenance of the rule of law and the fundamental tenets of our democracy
surely this was worthy of our attention he again insisted no one would be fired
I could see the agitation visibly building in the Prime Minister his mood
was shifting I remember seeing it I remember feeling it I had seen and felt
this before in a few occasions when he would get frustrated and angry but this
was different he had become strident and disputed everything I had said he made
it clear that everyone in his office was telling the truth and that I and by
extension at Jessica Prince my chief of staff and others were not he told me I
had not experienced what I said I did he used the line that would later become
public that I had experienced things differently I knew what he was really
asking what he was saying in that moment I knew he wanted me to lie to attest
that what had occurred had not occurred for me this was just more evidence that
he did not know me did not know who I was or where I was from me lie to
protect a crown government acting badly a political party a leader who was not
taking responsibility he must be delusional Jody Wilson-Raybould in her
capacity as Attorney General attempted to see justice done in retaliation
Trudeau protecting himself and others removed her from her office and the
Liberal Party and in my opinion it is quite notable that despite being
expelled from the party in 2019 she ran and won her seat as an independent and
even though I personally do have some differences of opinion with her over
other political topics I can certainly respect her for her conviction jumping
off of that topic I think it's now probably important to talk about the
aspects of Justin Trudeau's government that are this point just openly
tyrannical we'll start with the easy one free speech has limits Canada's Trudeau
says if it did then it would not be free Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau
defended free speech on Friday but added that it was not without limits and
should not arbitrarily and needlessly hurt certain communities we owe it to
ourselves to act with respect for others and to seek not to arbitrarily or
unnecessarily injure those with whom we are sharing a society and a planet we do
not have the right for example to shout fire in a movie theater crowded with
people there are always limits sure but what certain communities are affected by
this in a pluralist diverse and respectful society like ours we owe it
to ourselves to be aware of the impact of our words of our actions and others
particularly these communities and populations who still experience a great
deal of discrimination kind of like how in my book burning video the Germans
would ban speech that denigrated Germany or the German Volk no this is tyrannical
freedom of speech means the freedom to insult people period the Canadian
military wants to establish a new organization to use propaganda and other
techniques to influence Canadians we are more specifically talking about here the
weaponization of the military's public affairs branch the initiative involves
the creation of new research capabilities established to analyze and
collect information from the social media accounts of Canadians non
governmental organizations industry and the news media the Canadian Radio
Television and Telecommunications Commission is now seeking to regulate
all content online including online videos what we're talking about is bill
c10 and it applies to any online account that has a large enough following and is
based in Canada despite bill c10 being deeply unpopular parliament moved to
limit debate and push the bill through thankfully the bill died in committee in
the Canadian Senate but the Trudeau government wants to control guide and
direct the content that you watch in your free time the government believes
you're not watching the right things and so they will try to force you to do so
thankfully at least this time they're not going to get the chance another bill
bill c36 also currently seems to be in limbo but it would see Canada make
online hate speech a crime punishable by a $16,000 fine and just in case you want
to know how draconian and terrible this bit of legislation is the wording of the
bill would allow for example Catherine McKenna to seek damages against the
person online who called her a climate Barbie here is part of the rationale that
the Canadian government published for this new hate speech legislation
Canadians expect to be safe and free from hate speech and hate crimes online
and offline well the truth is no we don't because hate speech is still free
speech and if there's something that we don't like we can always choose not to
listen to it too many people in communities in Canada are harmed and
victimized by hate speech which is often amplified and spread online online hate
can turn into offline hate with devastating impacts on communities and
families sending a tweet I can't believe I have to say this sending a tweet is
not the same classification of thing as assaulting somebody offline and
assaulting somebody offline is already illegal hate speech is free speech
people should be allowed to say the most objectionable things they want
that's the point a medical journal in Canada has claimed that the Trudeau
government has muzzled scientists this is rich because Stephen Harper the
previous Prime Minister and the leader of the Conservatives back then did the
same thing he also muzzled scientists and Trudeau lambasted him for it and
frankly so did everyone else nobody in Canada liked that and yet Trudeau is
doing the same thing to the point that Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party has the
gall to take a speaker of the house to court to block the release of
unredacted records about those same scientists the liberal the liberal
government is taking the House of Commons a speaker to court in an
unprecedented move to prevent the release of uncensored documents to
members of Parliament that offer insight into the firing of two scientists from
Canada's top infectious disease laboratory I can't believe this has to
be said but a sitting Prime Minister does not take the speaker of the house
to court for a political reason like this and to me most telling of all is
Justin Trudeau's outright admission that what his government has learned from the
coronavirus crisis meaning the ability to centralize all power control the
lives of the citizens lock down segments of the economy at will basically how to
be an authoritarian those aren't powers he intends to give up once coronavirus
is over but his government intends to use those powers on future problems they
face what we learnt from this climate this COVID crisis we will be applying to
the climate crisis to the housing crisis to reconciliation to making sure that
everyone has good jobs and careers that carry them through and create
opportunities for their kids I mentioned early in the video I am pro
vax but anti lockdown and anti vaccine passport what really bothers me are the
number of people that proclaim to be liberal and yet they support these
illiberal authoritarian measures coming out of the Canadian government right now
and it's not it's not just with vaccine passports those are bad enough on their
own in 2015 Trudeau ran on electoral reform it was the thing that got him
elected and as soon as he realized that it would hurt his own chances at future
elections he abandoned it actually while I was editing the video yeah literally
at the 11th hour here it's the evening of the 18th Trudeau has actually come
out and said if he's reelected he will revisit electoral reform it is the most
popular thing he's ever run on but I have no idea why two days before people
go to vote you would remind the electorate of your most embarrassing
failure I don't get it Trudeau wants to have the power to regulate not only what
you say online but what content you consume online Trudeau wants to
confiscate by force legally owned guns from firearm owners Trudeau supports
using heavy-handed government tactics to force people to be vaccinated even if
they don't consent Trudeau refuses to end Canada's war on drugs the list goes
on all of this in addition to his use of the powers of his office to bully his
own Attorney General to bully the Speaker of the House and invade the
jurisdiction of how the House of Commons is run to blatantly lie about almost
every single thing he's ever said and yet Justin Trudeau still has the nerve
to call himself a liberal this man is not a liberal the Liberal Party under
his leadership is not liberal Trudeau is a tyrant he's always been one but he
just really needed an excuse to really come out of the closet and kovat 19 has
given him one and I expect now that his grasp on power grows more unsteady by
the day he will become more and more tyrannical in order to keep it that is
your personal business nobody needs to know but you the only thing I'll say is
I will never ever vote for Justin Trudeau they are putting at risk their
own kids and they're putting at risk our kids as well are putting us all at risk
trying to bring people together is not always compatible with science with
respect for human rights with the best way to move things forward I mean when
Aaron O'Toole talks about oh yes we need to unite people we need to bring people
together he's talking about defending the rights of people who are anti-vax if
anyone who doesn't have a legitimate medical reason for not getting fully
vaccinated chooses to not get vaccinated there will be consequences