At first, I didn't think this meme would go anywhere, but lo and behold, the meme community
put so much effort into innovating this thing that it exceeded everyone's expectations.
Interchangeable Infinity War meme number one.
This is technically an April meme, but I wanted to cover it anyway just to document how much
of a pathetic mistake it was.
This was a meme so painfully bland, derivative, and unfunny that even the most basic normies
eventually disowned it.
Just a complete failure in every sense of the word.
What are you possibly doing?
Finally, a meme making fun of oblivious idiots instead of pandering to them.
Simpson's shitposting delivers again with this very solid meme.
Could it be?
A meme based on a trendy song that's actually funny?
Bonus points for making the faux journalists actually reject a meme for once.
Interchangeable Infinity War meme number two.
The Dress 2.
I don't really care about this dull meme, so instead I'm gonna rant about the term
millennial.
I cannot stand this word, and this is coming from a guy who uses the word normie unironically.
This fucking word needs to be deleted from the lexicon entirely.
Nobody actually knows what it means, and it seems like the only people who use it are
washed up 35-year-olds who want to passive-aggressively disparage young people.
So fuck the word millennial and fuck 35-year-olds.
And uh, this meme is meh.
The Dab 2.
Let's face it, this trend will be on the Ellen show in a few months.
It's just hoost of two.
But I actually enjoy these memes that tinker with the basic concept of language.
After all, aren't memes just the universal language of internet culture?
This meme is gay.
Well, that's all the memes for me.
Some good, some not so good.
Do you think that angry, self-righteous journalists are gonna write a hit piece calling me a homophobic
bigot for using the word gay as an insult?
Probably.