So it's been three months since that is the plan died and YouTube is in dire need of a
meme review series. That doesn't suck! So I'm here today to debut a series that I call Minute Memes,
where instead of narrating off the Know Your Meme page in between a bunch of filler while
desperately trying to reach the 10-minute ad break threshold, I'm gonna straight-up tell you
if a meme is good in 60 seconds or less. I am the mouthpiece for your new opinion on memes and let
me just tell you all that my reviews aren't just opinions. They're 100% bona fide facts backed by
volumes of peer-reviewed scientific research conducted by me to determine which memes are
bold and brash and which memes belong in the trash. So make sure you take my words as seriously as
possible. I'm not making meme reviews. I'm making biblical commandments. I have a 420 IQ with a
PhD in Applied Memetics from the Meme Institute of Technology. I am the smartest meme man on the
internet and don't you question it!