Hello, Skullgirls discord, I know that you obsessively watch every video about this drama that comes out
There's always someone who posts it in there. So I know that some of you are gonna be watching this one right now
I hope you guys specifically stick around to the end of this one. I
Remember skullgirls very well it launched back in 2012 over 10 years ago now and I played a fair bit of it on release
But like all things you eventually move on
I haven't touched skullgirls in years and to be honest and I've really intended to go back to it
Even as I heard about the game receiving new updates on the periphery of my attention
It was one of those things where I enjoyed my time with the game
I don't regret the hours I put into it, but I didn't really see a need to go back and play it again
It's been a decade. I'm doing other stuff now as simple as that all of that changed when the skullgirls censorship controversy hit
The first thing I thought of when I heard the news was censorship for skullgirls a game that is specifically about fan service
Okay. Yeah, I know it wasn't all about fan service
But fan service was certainly one of its primary focuses and now they're censoring it
Well to dive into this conversation fully let's rewind back to the beginning part one lab zero games
The primary artist for skullgirls Alex a had or a hot I'm not sure gave an interview about the game during e3 of 2011
He had been doodling rough versions of the main skullgirls characters as far back as the early 2000s while he was still in high school
But the idea of turning them into a fighting game roster emerged while he was attending college
Mike Zimont on the programming side of skullgirls was a few years older during a 2012 panel
He described his own entry into the games industry
His parents bribed him with an Amiga to stop him from trying dangerous stunts on his dirt bike
This got him interested in computers and eventually led to him taking up a tester job the lowest of the possible
Entry points into game development, but it paid off
He worked on Star Wars Battlefront 2 as a programmer the original one
Not that god-awful modern version as well as assisting with Lord of the Rings conquest
He was also a professional fighting game player and evo champion and these two
Intersecting skill sets allowed him to land gigs balancing blaze blue continuum shift and Marvel vs. Capcom 2 by
2009 Zimont was programming his own fighting engine on the side and a mutual friend introduced some day had the two quickly realized that they
Had artwork and character roster fit well with the engine that Zimont was creating and they decided to work together to make a fighting game
They were both fans of Western and Eastern art giving skullgirls its unique half anime half rubber hose animation feel
They also wanted to make a Western take on the Japanese all-girl fan service fighter a la arcana heart
But they also realized they couldn't do it with just the two of them
Hey had and Zimont shot the idea around to multiple indie developers eventually signing with Reverge labs in 2010
Reverge labs signed a deal with autumn games to publish skullgirls with Konami handling distribution
Skullgirls launched a critical and commercial success in April of 2012. However autumn games had other problems
Allegations of fraud were levied at both autumn games and Konami by City National Bank
The two companies secured a 14 million dollar line of credit from the bank to publish and distribute the 2010 game Def Jam
Rapstar and the bank was alleging that the two companies misrepresented their financial status at the time of their deal as a result autumn games went
into belt tightening mode
They couldn't afford to renew the contract with Reverge labs and after time was up
Reverge labs ran out of funding all of their employees were subsequently laid off including the Zimont and a had
Wasn't the end for skullgirls though the Reverge labs employees who had worked on skullgirls formed a new company lab zero games with Zimont
As the new owner autumn games retained the skullgirls IP and hired lab zero games to continue work on skullgirls updates
But still funding was tight
So the team turned to indiegogo now remember this was in February of 2013 while there's still a lot of crowdfunding scams nowadays
People have more or less acclimated to the crowdfunding model back then though
There was a lot more skepticism among the average internet user regarding the validity of crowdfunding a game
but the skullgirls crew managed to pull it off raking in a total of
$830,000 covering the funding for four additional characters and a whole bunch of other goodies including an art book a
soundtrack release and a bunch of alternate voice packs and other small bonuses by November of 2013 autumn games
Severed ties with Konami claiming that Konami's lack of response was a major hurdle in the distribution of new content for the game
Konami replied by demanding that the Konami published versions of skullgirls on the Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 storefronts be pulled
lab zero games announced that the game would be re-released as skullgirls encore by spring of 2014 with all the current
DLC included as baseline and without any Konami involvement the Xbox 360 and steam versions of skullgirls were updated to the skullgirls
Encore version but due to technical limitations the ps3 version was pulled from the store and had to be redown loaded as a new game
Sony made the game freely available on ps3 to all previous owners of skullgirls
But unfortunately gamers save data didn't carry over to the new version
The game was eventually updated again this time with a skullgirls second encore branding with a new round of characters and updates
Second encore was the baseline version of skullgirls for the ps4 which was released in July of 2015 by April of 2016
The steam version of skullgirls was updated to second encore as well
Meanwhile autumn games had tapped a phone developer hidden variable studios to create the game skullgirls mobile
This wasn't just a phone version of the main skullgirls game
This was a new title set as a prequel to the main story and made only for phones skullgirls mobile released in May of 2017
After a long silence skullgirls a second encore received a Nintendo switch port in October of 2019 the Wii U
Nintendo 3ds and Xbox one were all considered for skullgirls ports
But were ultimately skipped at this point in the story skullgirls is a pretty old game and yet
Updating it and refining it is what lab zero games had to focus the majority of its efforts on
Skullgirls just didn't receive enough
Consistent support or continued cash flow to be a game with a life cycle this long and it wasn't just because of Konami's roadblocks
Autumn games was also out of money and couldn't afford to keep funding lab zero games for continued development
Skullgirls development only started to make a comeback after autumn games pushed the mobile game out and by then lab zero games
Was already deep into production on their next title
Indivisible a hat and zymont had shifted their focus to early indivisible development as far back as 2015
But according to a lab zero games employee on Twitter a had left the company in the middle of indivisible development because he had become
Increasingly hostile difficult to work with and was not able to meet company standards
He later tried to sue the company and walked away with a sizable settlement
So with a head of the pitcher zymont was the remaining member of the original
Skullgirls duo and he seemed to want to move on to indivisible development while autumn games was trying to keep the skullgirls raft afloat
Yeah, I know guys
It was a popular game in 2012
But we're at 2020 at this point focusing on new projects is the right choice for the company going forward
The truth is by 2020 nobody's talking about skullgirls anymore
But people would start talking about skullgirls again very soon though not for the reasons
Anybody wanted part two the downfall of Mike Z in June of 2020
Mike zymont was commentating an official skullgirls tournament when he made an I can't breathe joke
This was two weeks after George Floyd's death. Just just listen to this
She's gonna die, yeah
Would it be fair to say that uh
You can't breathe
All right gelato
You got a chance now
Yeah, that might be one of the most awkward things I've ever heard captured on audio
Zymont apologized in the same day saying that the joke was too soon
He blamed his social awkwardness for not being able to read the room, but the damage was done
He was canceled and we all know how canceling events work
so of course this would be the precise moment that other people jump out of the woodwork to accuse Zymont of of
Whatever really professional twitch streamer and cosplayer bunny a you known for thirst trapping everywhere
She goes in the internet leaked her DMS with Zymont where she thanked him for including
Lesbian BDSM in skullgirls and claims his response to her was creepy bunny
I you has her own deep lore most notably being in a high-profile relationship with another thirst trapper that ended very publicly and
Spectacularly with her being slapped with her own set of allegations. That's a different rabbit hole for another day
What's important right now is that at least in my view bunny I you is a snake
She masks her behavior behind a progressive inclusive public persona, which is why I'm not surprised
She was the one to jump on the Mike Z canceled bandwagon first just to be clear
She publicly thanked a had for including lesbian BDSM in the game who responded with the ever so slightly flirtatious glad you liked it
Oh, ho ho. This is like a 0.1 on the first scale
But she had privately messaged Zymont with the sentiment and characterized his responses as uncomfortable and demeaning. Let's go over their DMS
Thank you for making a video game. Where is there is BDSM Yuri. I'm glad you enjoy it
Yeah question mark seems appropriate
There's a lot less of that type of thing than it was originally because even fewer people would have taken it seriously
Otherwise witness filly is unused typo pose, which you can look up online. That's not good middle enough. Let's see who this person is
Oh, I think it's the lady was streaming the game recently. They mistook button Jupiter for visits the Twitter page
Whoa, you actually have a catch light slash. I like that's some serious production values. I have so many questions
I want to ask that. I'm definitely not going to ask. I'm happy SG is fun for you
I joked about sending the thanks for Yuri fan service message on twitch while playing Eliza story
I also tweeted to an artist who was completely respectful and normal about it. Here's the link this one. I think it's awesome
I understand though. I like DOA a lot, but it gets a lot of negative feedback for being too sexy
I love Philly yellow. Yep. I have played skull goes three times on stream
I really love the style and played Eliza's story today. So that's why I thank you for the your a BDSM
Ask away. I'm a fan of the game so far. It's like really cool and fun for sure
Oh, yes
We had to add all the mommy raps to Eliza's getting throne frames and we wouldn't have gotten the right rating
Also some foam in her bath strangely said nothing about her other storyboat art ask the questions. Well
Okay
Are you putting on the high voice like lots of Japanese ladies do what brought you SG?
Anyway, I guess I've embraced the thirst culture. But like isn't this weird. It's definitely not anyone's fancy
I don't know how I feel at your place. Did you start out with that as a name?
I'm genuinely curious. My voice is real. It gets higher pitch when I'm excited though. I'm cursed with it
I get that question a lot. I like fighting games
I've had an interest since I was a kid and I wanted to revisit some for nostalgia
I found skull girls through recommendations from my fans. It doesn't bother me thirst is human nature
I started as a grab your style model online and did sexy modeling for maybe three years or so before retiring
I retired a year ago to pursue twitch streaming
I'm used to thirst stuff from my job and I'm a huge fan of each artist and the culture so it doesn't really bother me
Well, sorry for ask the dumb comic questions, I know some other ladies like that
I bet it's annoying to get asked to put your parent on the phone
I suppose there's definitely helps sub count and probably validation if external validation is necessary. I'm embarrassed enough streaming at all and I dislike
People so I feel like quantified speaking here. Hey, I'm sort of curious what your family thinks of it
But that's a dangerously close to the coin. What is your boyfriend think promo of you single?
It's just the world up so unfamiliar with gravia the printing process Oh
Google helped you're aware of like the prevalent problems with sexism in the FGC assume. Sorry about that advance
I love the skull girls community in particular is better about it. Anyway, I don't mean to bother you
You're just kind of fascinating and unfamiliar. Well, that's a good weird ending
The validation comment was like very uncomfortable and demeaning. Can you imagine this conversation with a man in the FCG?
Hmm I'm sure you get messages from humans with penises asking that kind of stuff pretty regularly
So if you prefer, how about I acknowledge the brain inside the lady?
It takes a lot of skill and kind of get a certain amount of both
Integrity and ruthlessness to succeed at pretty much anything. So calculating successful person who owns herself. What's your end goal is streaming sustainable
Do you want to own a tech company or manufacture solar cells or grow cute flowers or what?
I'd like to know what to prepare to invest in his responses are creepy
Demeaning and I really don't think you would talk to a man this way in the initial messages
I want comes off as an awkward starstruck nerd bunny replies by blowing up his ego a bit over how much she liked skull girls
Considering that bunny started this conversation with sexual content, you know
The lesbian BDSM thing it makes sense that the conversation might go this way
One of the questions I'm on asks her is what it's like to embrace thirst culture and be the object of people's affections
Bunny replies honestly saying that this is human nature. She's been a model for years. She's used to thirst stuff from her job
She's a big fan of hentai in the surrounding culture
So this type of conversation doesn't bother her after this as I months questions do become more creepy and more personal
But they also kind of read like an awkward nervous nerd who thinks he's having a sexual
Conversation with a girl way out of his league and you know considering how bunny started the conversation with sex
That is one of the possible directions a reasonable person could believe this is gonna go at this point bunny cuts contact with him
And then blasts him online as a creep
But frankly I can see it from both points of view
Bunny seems like somebody who's had to deal with creeps a lot sexual content is likely pretty normalized to her
So to her this was an innocent conversation not a sexual one
Meanwhile as I'm on seems like an otaku who gets exactly zero play and suddenly this hot chick is sliding into his DMS talking about
How grateful she is for his lesbian bondage content?
I can absolutely see a guy like that spilling his spaghetti
But of course bunny only saw fit to release this during Zaymon being canceled over the George Floyd joke
She dropped the logs along with the following public statement
I will no longer be playing skull girls the creator Mike with incredibly
Disrespectful in DMS and made me very uncomfortable
I have shared screenshots of the conversation to others in the FCG and to combo Queens
Combo Queens is a group that tries to get women into the fighting game community
affiliated with combo breaker a professional fighting game event that Mike Z used to commentate for as a result of bunny going public with the
DMS Richard Thire the general manager of Evo and the event director with combo breaker put out this statement in
In addition to the listed reprimands are relayed in the statement released by multiple skullgirls organizers and community members
Mike Z will not be welcome at CB 2021 in addition to well
Uh this account called da purple sharpie who seems to be just a random
Individual speaking for the skullgirls community presented a list of demands that the fans want implemented upon Mike Zaymon in
Retaliation for the whole bunny thing. Yeah, I don't know what the fuck this is all about
These people aren't employees of anything they're not from an organization. They're just fans
Alright, let's read it
Our goal is to create a gaming space that is welcome for all participants regardless of their race gender blah blah blah
We believe Mike Zaymon should no longer be welcome on commentary or participating in events in the skullgirls community as there is no singular
Entity responsible for the skullgirls community for who determines who is allowed on commentary or who determines per event eligibility
We are asking the community to respect and uphold the following actions one
indefinite ban from all commentary to a two-year ban from offline and online
competition until July 30th
2022 our decision to enact and recommend these reprimands was based on Mike's history of problematic behavior in public and
Private including the callous. I can't breathe reference while commentating a match and the reveal of additional inappropriate
Interactions with members of the skullgirls community in private we believe these okay, okay, who's who signed this?
There's a couple of tournament organizers couple of pro fighters and the skullgirls discord administrators
The discord admins guys the jannies do it for free after this a second cosplayer named carbon gray who has annoyingly changed
Her name to also be bunny since this drop back in 2020 came out with a video making it vague but similar allegations against Zaymon
This is like my 20 billionth take I have not yet read bunnies DMS, I don't know what Mike said to her
I'm sure it was shitty and I know that because Mike's been making weird sexual comments at me in and out of cosplay
Fighting game events for actual years and I've been writing a lot of it off because when I tell people they're just like oh
He's kind of like that. I'm sorry and like yeah
He is kind of like that and he's kind of not changing for the past five years y'all and like neither is anyone else in
The fighting game community and I think a lot of it is because when I tell like my male friends or other TOS what's happening
They just kind of don't do anything with that information
If you find out that one of your friends is being absolutely weird or creepy to females in the community
You need to call them on it and actually hold them accountable
This is par for the course when someone's canceled it happened with super mega as well
There's generally one person with detailed allegations logs or text or whatever and then a few hanger-ons show up later to literally go me
To me too and most of the time they have far less evidence
She expanded on her allegations in a series of tweets that basically amounted to Mike said weird sexual shit to me
IRL and we're supposed to just take her at her word for the most part what carbon is describing is actually pretty bad if it
happened
This is all he said she said stuff that she's clearly been holding on to and only dropping right now because Mike's going viral
For most of these examples, there's nobody to corroborate carbon story
But in one there actually was another witness who told their version of events
Mr. Banana god 7 who said on June 29th 2020 during the bunny a you think that Mike tried to laugh it off and apologized
Carbon agreed at least enough to like the tweets
However, when carbon retells this story two months later in August of 2020
She says he could have just apologized two separate people have told me they asked him to apologize to me the apology that banana god 7
Confirmed Mike gave and that carbon agreed with has been completely erased from the narrative now
Maybe you could say that Mike's apology being of the laughing off of variety was not good enough
It wasn't serious or something
Maybe that's the case but carbon saying he apologized and I didn't accept it sounds way worse than he didn't apologize
Which is in my opinion why the story quietly morphed over time another allegation came from a guy named. Mr
Beezle a former employee at lab zero games. I had to dig this shit up on the wayback machine because he's since nuked all
of his allegations
Mr. Beezle claims that Mike Z scapegoated him gaslit him made verbal threats of violence against him
But he saves the worst for last he made a racist remark three times the majority of mr
Beezle's thread is focused on the racism and we never actually get any explanation on the threats. They're just forgotten about mr
Beezle complained about getting racially profiled as a Latino thug despite describing himself as the stereotypical image of a Latino thug and he called
Mike a white man in power who refused to see my reality. This is a really strange allegation, man
Mike looks more like a Middle Easterner than a white guy and zymont is a Jewish last name. Oh, he's a colonizer
I get it now in actuality. This is another he said she said story and even in mr
Beezle's retelling of events Mike doesn't sound like a harasser
He sounds like an idiot who is entirely clueless about the intricacies of politics and systemic racism
And the only thing I can really say to that is boy
I wish that were me all of these other people coming forward with their own Mike Z story
Prompted bunny to publicly declare that she felt like she was doing the right thing
I was extremely anxious even mentioning anything because it could have been way worse
But hearing all the women come forward after my post and bms makes it worth it
We need to make the fcg better for women. I am taking the rest of the day to process everything
Thank you
It wasn't all sunshine and rainbows for her though enough people saw through her bullshit that she began to take flack for this obvious
Spin job so much so that she eventually backed down Mike has reached out to me with an apology
I really hope this makes him aware of others who have come out in hindsight
I feel like I should have handled this differently and I apologize for that. I will be deleting my tweets moving forward
It was too little too late for Mike's I'm on though in the eyes of the public
He went from being an awkward
Flirter to a sex pest to a sexual harasser to a sexual assaulter pretty quick as a result of all of this the board of directors
At lab zero games formally requested that he resigned from his position
However, you have to remember that Simon wasn't just the lead developer at lab zero games
He was also the owner of the company in exchange for his resignation
Simon made demands of the board that one member Brian June described as
Unrealistically high and potentially illegal the board rejected the demands and in response
Simon simply executed his power as owner of the company and dissolved the board
He gave all employees an ultimatum if you got a problem with it leave the company by August 31st
2020 and so they did a bunch of people left lab zero games publishing statements on social media denouncing
Simon shortly after all of us autumn games and the skullgirls mobile developer hidden variable studios announced they were severing ties with
Simon and lab zero games
They also announced that since autumn games still owns the skullgirls IP they intended to simply continue work on
Skullgirls with the employees that had left lab zero games and without Simon the employees made a new studio called future club and began working
With autumn games to create additional content for skullgirls second encore
Simon dissolved lab zero games shortly afterward which put an early end to updates for indivisible which had just been released
The Simon continued to be active in professional fighting game scene
But he exited the game development industry for a couple of years
He resurfaced in the summer of 2023 as an employee of modus games working on diesel legacy the brazen age
It's a hand-drawn 2d fighting game like skullgirls
But the animations a completely different style from a heads work the CEO of modus games Christina seal stated directly that she chose to hire
Simon for the game not solely because of his extensive experience in the industry
But because she believes that he's accepted his guilt and is capable of being reformed
I am one of the few women that are CEO's and making games in its entire
Industry in a couple years since I made that decision to hire Mike
I'm one of the two women CEO's that are running publicly listed companies in the whole industry in the world
I did not take this decision lightly when I was talking to Mike and went through the process of figuring out where he was
At if you want to have an inclusive environment in the world and you want to have diverse viewpoints all of the things we want
diversity equity
Inclusion you have to have a path for people to learn and improve you have to create a better
Way for them to show the world that they've changed and decided to do better
and I really got that from Mike I got that he was committed to it and
That he didn't want everything that went down to be the end of his story
He wanted the opportunity to have the redemptive arc that's in so many stories that we all love man
Maybe I've just become too cynical reading communist theory
But this really sounds like Ximont's gone through a struggle session and has come out of it re-educated and de-fanged
You know what? I mean? He made an edgy joke at the wrong time in a just society
That's something that you apologize for and move on from but that's not what happened
one George Floyd joke turned into internet outrage which turned into sexual assault allegations because he was a nerd who thought a hot girl was
Flirting with him and his DMS were clipped and shipped at the perfect moment during the cancelling
He's not innocent but he's also not guilty of the high crimes
Everyone thinks that he is and seal here coming out and saying oh, he's reformed now
I've got him on my leash just seems very strange part 3 the censorship with both Ximont and a hat out of the picture and
Now considered to be problematic elements by the community
It was time for the past of skull girls to be scrubbed clean of any impure elements
You know despite being a fan service focus game in June of 2023 skull girls second encore was updated to remove any risque elements
This includes removing all panty shots or otherwise sexual shots of the various female characters like torn clothing the BDSM inspired stuff
That bunny I you complimented is gone, too
Removing the Nazi inspired red armbands of the red egrets one of the game's villainous factions
Removing artwork from the game's art book that references either the game's sexuality or the red egrets armbands keep in mind
This is a digital art book for the Indiegogo backer version of the game
If you crowdfunded this game back in the day your art book has been changed
Removing the hair comb in Philia's afro animation presumably because it's some sort of black afro stereotype or something
Removing the police brutality scene in big bands story mode
Removing sexual jokes like barely legal for reaching an 18 hit combo or peacocks opening reference to hentai
Removing the Soviet announcer voice pack. I don't think this is because it made fun of communism
It's way more likely that it's because Mike Ximont voiced it
Oh and just in case you thought you could download old versions of the game to get around this
Yeah
Those don't exist anymore on
Steam and modern consoles second encore over wrote the originals years ago remember and on older consoles where the original skull girls is still
The latest version Konami made them impossible to download years ago
But if you had them downloaded you could still play them until recently
They were quietly finally disabled off your system in this update
I even logged into my old Xbox 360 to see for myself and nope
Even though the game has been paid for it's gone on my Xbox series X skull girl second encore is available to purchase
No problem. However, I still have the original skull girls registered to the account
And if I go to that page in my game library
It simply says not available right now or ever again Microsoft as expected
There was a huge fan backlash
Fan service is a core part of skull girls as identity and removing it basically rips out what made skull girls fun
Plus a lot of the stuff that was removed were indie go-go goals
Like if they reached X amount of dollars in crowdfunding
They would add a perk to the game
People had met those goals with their own money and now a decade later the content they funded was being axed for political correctness
Fans responded by leaving negative reviews on Steam
Causing the 10 year old game to dip into the mostly negative rating for the first time in its history
Of course the new developers at Future Club sensor the negative reviews and the score has mostly recovered by now and to be fair
There were a lot of people who didn't actually play skull girls leaving negative reviews as well
And these guys are clearly jumping on a bandwagon
However, the general consensus among the public is that while censoring a fan service game is kind of lame
Specifically censoring the art book to remove guest art and concept art that is no longer in line with the current vision of the game
Is what reveals this whole thing to have an ideological motive?
Anybody who's seen an art book for a game before knows that oftentimes the art in the book doesn't make it into the final game
It's meant to show off a work in progress to show how the game evolved from the earliest spitballing of ideas to the current release
Censoring the art book is quite literally removing the past and pretending it never happened
Another tiny tidbit that shows their intent is how after all the censorship went through they began calling their current round of updates
Season one like everything done before this moment just didn't happen
It's a very creepy year zero type of stuff and then the legendary discord DMS leaked only adding fuel to the fire
Let's read them at rocks chobatsu a lot of the original team went on to do their own thing like richer
Alex a had left but not before making a big stink about it. Mike's I'm aunt needs no explanation
I'm sure but Mariel Earl Brady Brian Chris. They're all still here Miyazaki the red shinobi. Yeah
It's still a majority of the OGs and I knew you guys are never comfortable with certain stuff in the game
Aatrox lol. I mean I liken it to just housekeeping
Miyazaki and to see so many people say no
This is what drew me in specifically just makes me pity them so much
Aatrox like there's a dirty sock in the corner
That's just been there for years and we only just had time to get it out of the way now
2011 was such a different time too. Oh boy a current year reference. Here's the context Miyazaki
The red shinobi is the person who took this screenshot and released it to the public since the discord DM window is labeled as sending
Messages to a trucks unless somebody stole Miyazaki's phone and released it or something
We can assume it was him who sent it a quick check online shows that Miyazaki has been a longtime
Skullgirls fan having been part of the skullgirls fan website skull heart calm ever since the game launched and posting on the skullgirls
Discord as far back as 2015 his pics of account also has a bunch of skullgirls lewd fan art favorited either
He genuinely agrees with the current skullgirl censorship as he originally wrote in the DM making him kind of hypocritical or he struck up
This conversation with one of the developers with the express purpose of making them put their foot in their mouths
I tend to believe it's the latter because this conversation does not make the developers look good and he chose to release it plus
I'm currently in the skullgirls discord myself and checking out his profile on old messages
It seems like he's been kicked from the server. It sounds like he was our guy getting us some info
Also, just real quick during my perusal of the skullgirls discord public channels
It seems like they purged not only trolls and shit stirrers, but genuine fans who expressed discontentment at the changes
Atrox Chobatsu is one of the current artists working for Future Club on skullgirls
And as far as I can tell he was not a part of the original team back during the Reverge lab days
He's very lefty hailing from Portland. We all know what that place already
He's also the guy who hosts the skullgirls animation streams on Twitch. I watched a bit of them
There's nothing really going on there. In fact, he generally doesn't talk
He actually just types in the chat in between drawing or whatever
He hasn't publicly said anything directly with the controversy but two days after it broke
He posted this on Twitter
Is it considered censorship if I wanted to remove my tattoo of Yuji Naka's face from my left armpit?
I don't know. I'm just not feeling the same reverence I had for the man 20 years ago. It was a different time
I was younger and stupider, but not by much in my opinion
This is a tongue-in-cheek jab at people who were crying censorship over skullgirls
His positions clear the current legal owners of the skullgirls property who are not the original duo who conceived of it anymore
Don't like some parts of the game and they want to update it which yes
They have the legal right to do but that also means pissing off everyone who doesn't agree with their new vision and those people
They're not likely to keep supporting you the DMS show that at least
Atrox believes rewriting the past and updating it to fit modern progressive sensibilities is a good thing as he seems like the type to
Develop some variant of trolls remorse
He used to make kind of edgy stuff back on Newgrounds and in one of his old
Animations from 2012 it cuts away to some real-life pictures of somebody that I assumed to be him since he does talk about himself as being
the artist of the animation
He looks like a pretty normal internet nerd from that era and most Millennials cut from this cloth suffer from trolls remorse today
For example, despite his current very progressive sensibilities
His personal YouTube channel has a video from 2009 where he's goofing around with his friends and one of them says faggot
You're not the father
The worst words are ones that are not spoken, okay
I'm not pointing this out to cancel him even though an edgy joke is literally what got the cancel ball rolling on Mike Simon
I'm only pointing out that just like the tattoo allegory implies. This is clearly not something that he'd do nowadays
Oh, also, he's out here talking about how problematic skullgirls is while drawing lewd furry artwork
Good job, dude
with all of this being understood the current public narrative regarding skullgirls is that the two original creators a hat and
Zymont were slowly weaseled out of their successful
profitable IP their life's work their dream and the current owners being
Progressives with no respect for the property its history the original creators vision or frankly what the fans want are now
Repurposing skullgirls to suit their needs updating it for modern standards by removing what people love from the game
I understand why that's the public narrative considering how often this sort of thing happens nowadays and how it looks from the outside
But it's also not completely accurate. There is more going on here
But in order to understand it
We're gonna have to dive into a topic that has until very recently largely flown under the radar
Part four the lawsuit while the initial idea for the skullgirls universe might have come from Alex a hat and the game engine from Mike
Zymont they aren't the only people who have been attached to the project since the very beginning
Marielle Cartwright one of the original animators who was on the skullgirls project from day one of it hitting reverb labs is just as
Crucial to the development of the game as the two boys are and she is the central focus of the skullgirls lawsuit
After lab zero games collapsed and Mike Z laid off all remaining staff
Marielle Cartwright got together with the company's financial officer and producer for indivisible
Francesca Esquenazi and in early 2021
They fired off a lawsuit against lab zero games and Mike Z for wrongful termination on April 1st, 2021
I bet they thought it was an April Fool's joke
Mike filed a countersuit with Superior Court of the state of California against Marielle and
Francesca and against the company that all the lab zero games former employees had founded to continue the skullgirls work
Future Club the court document is
207 pages long and linked in the description if you want to read it for yourself
The claims Mike makes within the documents are backed up with dozens upon dozens of pages filled with internal chat logs at lab zero games
Private messages between Mike Marielle and Francesca and public communications that provide additional context
So let's dive in the court docs begin with describing skullgirls and lab zero games
Which we already know about as well as what a slack channel is
Presumably because the American court system is full of boomers and then we get to the third section titled my history of autism spectrum disorder
Mike described what he had known all of his life as Mike being Mike an inability to understand social boundaries
Maintain friendships and just generally deal with people properly
He confided in Marielle and Francesca whom he described as his close friends and with their encouragement
He eventually went to a therapist and got an autism diagnosis in the next section
He describes his friendship with Marielle Cartwright in 2010 Marielle was brought on to Reverge labs
Specifically to work as an animator for skullgirls under Alex a had who was I think the creative director
She would become the lead animator in 2012
Mike and Marielle became close friends talking and going on walks frequently in Marielle's public statement when she left lab zero games
She claimed that Mike harassed her at work. There was years of sexual comments uncomfortable jokes unwanted hugs
He apparently suggested she helped him masturbate she claimed to talk to him about how uncomfortable she felt in 2017 and in return
He called her a hypocrite
Marielle says that this hypocrisy stemmed from how she dressed in public implying that Mike believed her way of dressing allowed him to sexually
Harass her. However, this isn't the whole story in the court documents
Mike provides tons of slack logs showing on-the-job
Conversations as well as Marielle's private messages to him directly where she regularly engaged in conversations with him about sex sexual orientation
urination pornography
prostitution threesomes plastic surgery body image issues and on and on she began these
Conversations herself and expected him to participate her behavior led Mike to believe that this type of talk was welcome and ordinary in the course
Of their friendship. She also regularly engaged in this type of talk with other co-workers and drew pornographic artwork while on the clock
Which she displayed in the office at least that's how Mike characterized these chat logs in the court documents
And you know being somebody who's around their age. I'm a millennial. They're Millennials. We're all in our 30s
This is how people of my age group talk when they're friends and not just you know casual work
Acquaintances all of these logs read to me like they were actually genuine friends and that whatever banter they have going on is
Clearly welcome and also a two-way street. Also. I'm not getting Naomi to do the voice for this one
I don't think she wants to do a stereotypical Asian accent
I
Francesca Esquenazi had a similar friendship with Mike. He met her while she was working at a GameStop in
2005 before either of them had begun their professional careers in
2007 while Mike was working as a programmer at pandemic studios
He was able to get her a job as a receptionist this began
Francesca's career working in the paper-pushing side of the games industry in
2016 he brought her into the skullgirls project as a producer
Mike and Francesca's friendship was similar to Mike and Mariel's with lewd or inappropriate topics of conversation being a part of the normal course
Of their interactions and again, it wasn't one-sided. They both began these conversations and expected the other to participate
They had been friends for 15 years and Mike describes several personal events that he helped her through weddings
Tragedies Mike helped Francesca come to terms with the death of her child the subsequent gender transition of her husband
How her marriage and sex life were affected how menstruation made her feel inadequate?
Mike took up a role of stability in Francesca's personal life
Next up in the court documents is Mike describing in detail the bunny a you canceling event
You know, it makes sense that they be in the court docs because it is one of the big events that led to the destruction of
lab zero games
But it's still kind of surreal to see internet shit in a court filing Mike confirms that his conversation with bunny a you happened on May
13th 2020 when bunny released her version of these DMS after the George Floyd joke in late June of 2020
They showed that she took the screen caps when the DMS were one day old
This means that bunny deliberately sat on these DMS until she could release that the most opportune moment for maximum damage to Mike
He also revealed that bunny privately apologized to him something that was left out of the original version of events on June 29th
Mike expressed his frustrations to Mariel over the situation
Highlighting the obvious double standard when bunny a you makes the conversation about sexuality and skull girls and her own sexually charged career
But when Mike engages with the conversation on that level bunny frames it as if he would never talk to a man in the fighting
Game community like this in response Mariel said directly to Mike that all men have to deal with the result of what shitty men have
Done but also that she didn't want him to quit lab zero games and that if she had the power to fire him
She wouldn't over this the conversations tone seems to imply that Mariel knows Mike is innocent
But also that her progressive politics apply a collective male guilt to him that she isn't directly pushing but that he is
Rejecting and she is uncomfortable with that rejection
Meanwhile in a conversation between Francesca and Mariel where Mike isn't present
Francesca directly says that she thinks a bunny a you baited Mike that bunny started the conversation weird that she didn't believe that Mike meant
To demean bunny and that bunny deliberately cut out Mike's apology in order to paint him a certain way
Mariel agreed with Francesca's assessment in the public lab zero slack channel
They reiterated this position saying that Mike was innocent at the same time in a previous slack channel for women only Mariel
Francesca and several female employees outline that they've all had experiences with Mike where he's been inappropriate
But also that they all know he doesn't do it purposefully. He's been apologetic every time it's happened
He's worked to make up for it and he genuinely tries to be better
But also that his autism makes it hard for him one employee asks
How many fires are we going to have to put out and that if it wasn't for his autism?
This would be a lot more cut and dry
This is where the scheme to take control of lab zero games began with Mariel and Francesca
Understanding full well that Mike was doing his best with them openly admitting that they truly believed he was but nonetheless
Reluctantly deciding that it was time to take control from him. Well, it was reluctant initially by the end of June 29th
They were privately messaging each other discussing removing Mike from his leadership position on June 30th
Francesca and Mariel scheduled two team meetings one with Mike present and one without they were scheduled in the company's Google Calendar
We only have Mike's word as to what happened at the one meeting
He claims that the two women encouraged all of the employees to bash him to his face
He admits to crying during the meeting and being forced to explain his autism to the entire company
The woman then ended the meeting by claiming it was a waste of time
It was at this point that Mike believes Francesca and Mariel had a change of heart
They were no longer
Understanding about his autism or his good faith efforts to fix things they no longer care that he was innocent with regards to bunny
Are you and they were beginning to retroactively redefine all of their past interactions as harassment an hour after the meeting Mariel
Formed a new slack channel called Z Z Z where everyone but Mike was present with the express purpose of planning to undermine
Mike's ownership of lab zero games one of their plans involved removing Mike from a leadership and
Ownership position and allowing him to stay on as a contractor
Francesca pitched the idea of the entire team up and leaving seeing as they still had connections and options
Mariel says that she still considers Mike a friend but that he's destroying the team and he has to go they discussed the peril of
Having to explain to the publisher of the next game focus all of this internal turmoil and how it will affect
Focuses support and funding of lab zero games and then Mariel says this I oh no, this is manipulative
I wonder if it would go over better if Mike stepped down on his own
It will look bad to focus if Franny and I asked Mike to leave but if Mike steps down it would be better
This was the beginning of Mariel's plot to manipulate Mike to voluntarily step down from his own company by intentionally
Misrepresenting the situation to focus as she was afraid of them pulling funding for lab zeros next game
Part of this plot involved absolutely nothing of this going public as Mariel directly stated. Yes. It looks bad
But if we make a public statement that makes us look slightly better
But then lose all of our jobs and close the company
What good will that have done by the end of the day?
Francesca had drafted an email to focus as the launching of their plan and Mariel approved of it
They intended to manipulate Mike into stepping down by misrepresenting their upcoming meeting with focus
Specifically the two told Mike that unless he was gone focus was pulling out in a future meeting
Representatives from focus directly denied this to Mike's face
In fact, Francesca later admitted that what they had said regarding focus and Mike was not true while she characterized it as a misunderstanding
This statement reads like she got caught and she knows it
Mariel had concocted the whole story that focus was pulling out if Mike wasn't gone under the belief that focus would continue to work with
Them if they managed to get rid of Mike themselves the next day July 1st
2020 the group was discussing forming a new company without Mike still using lab zeros official slack
They explicitly stated they intended to take over all of lab zeros contracts with Mariel and Francesca at the helm of a new company
Without any of the baggage of lab zero games and none of its debt
They were aware that this meant leaving Mike with the responsibility of paying focus back all of the money
They provided to fund the next game along with other business debts totaling around one and a half million dollars
They initially didn't seem thrilled at the idea of leaving Mike with all the lab zero debt
But as the summer dragged on they warmed up to the idea with Mariel at one point threatening to use the debt as a weapon
Against him. It's at this point that as their plans began to develop Mariel and Francesca began to harden against Mike's autism reasoning
Which they had accepted just a few days prior on July 4th 2020
Mariel said I don't buy as excuse of a checklist and never trying to hurt anyone to do anything bad anymore
And I don't accept autism as an excuse anymore while Francesca said that though she doesn't think Mike is a monster
She also doesn't feel like she can believe anything
he says anymore as an explanation even though Mariel and Francesca had previously stated that they knew Mike didn't harass anybody and
Falsely accusing him of harassment would ruin his life
They had decided to maliciously characterize his conduct as harassment in order to drum up public support for their new company
But specifically in a way that protects them Mariel said we can't acknowledge any lack of knowledge
Enabling or wrongdoing because that validates Max's claims and allows him to come after us
The other ones also open us up to Mike coming after us for defamation. The defamation thing is obvious
But who is this max guy?
The only person named max who once worked at lab zero games is apparently a person named max gone
At least that's his profile over at art station calm under the screen named B's all aka our friend. Mr
Beezwell from earlier the Latino who accused Mike of violent threats
But never actually provide any proof of them in his long thread full of bullshit nonsense
He actually blames Mariel and Francesca for enabling and supporting Mike's mistreatment
This meant that Mariel and Francesca had a tight line to walk
They needed to make the claim that Mike was actually the harasser
They previously said that he wasn't while at the same time at not giving any ammo to mr. Beezwell that frames them as harassers themselves
Bitches be calculating by July 16th
Mariel began characterizing Mike as the aggressor and reframing all of their past actions within an abuser victim dynamic
By August 6th Mariel seemed to simply view Mike as an enemy saying I don't even want to like get him back or ruin of
Her anything just leave please just leave forever the plan for everybody to abandon lab zero games was underway
Employees were waiting for a specific time that time came and on August 24th 2020 the implosion of lab zero games was underway
Employees announced the resignation in unison including Mariel
Francesca due to her access to the company's financial information knew that quitting at this specific time would maximize damage to the company
It was just before payroll was going out for the next month and the conspirators had managed to convince focus not to pay them their
Next reimbursement with no money coming in and no staff to perform any work lab zero games was forced to shutter its doors and lay
Off any remaining employees including Francesca by September 6th 2020 Kim McCaskill a woman who works in the games
Industry and who is well known for her strong public stance against the sexual harassment of women in game development
Privately spoke to all parties involved and discovered that none of them even mentioned harassment at Simon's hands at all
In fact the whole thing appeared like they were using the sexual
Harassment claim to drag Simon through the mud in retaliation for him not following through on making lab zero games a worker cooperative
Apparently due to the negative experience
everybody had working at Reverge labs the long term plan for lab zero games after Mike Z took over was that he would turn it
Into a worker cooperative a business model where all workers have an equal share of company ownership
However, there were two reasons as to why this wasn't possible
Firstly it turns out that lab zeros corporate lawyer went over the options with Mike Mariel and Francesca and told them that giving the employees
A bunch of stock in the company in order to make it into a worker co-op would massively raise those employees taxes
Which does make sense?
They now have a lot more net worth being part owners of a successful company the employees didn't want to pay more taxes
Obviously, but Mariel and Francesca interpreted this event as proof that Mike was refusing to fulfill his promise to the team
However back on June 29th Mariel admitted outright she understood the reason the company was in a co-op wasn't Mike's fault
He was more than willing. It was a legal problem on June 30th
She said that the team should only buy up shares of lab zero games and turn it into a worker co-op that way if Mike
Were gone on July 2nd at Mariel no longer trust him with the shares on July 27th
Mariel says that no one's paying Mike anything for his shares of the company the implication being that they just want it for free
Something that was legally difficult
Secondly all of the new co-owners would be on the hook for lab zeros debt
Mariel broke down the details of the 1.5 million dollar business debt in one of the chat logs focus is owed
$775,000 that is their publishers investment into their next game
Which they expect game sales to recoup if the game doesn't come out they're on the hook for the money
Arsenal is owed $100,000. That's the company's agent Brandon is owed $40,000
That's the company's lawyer seems like they had some bills that needed paying Alex is owed
$50,000 that's Alex a had settlement that was mentioned earlier and Peter is owed
$450,000 who's Peter a PlayStation blog post about skullgirls was credited to Peter Bartholow the CEO of lab zero games a
quick internet search reveals that Peter Bartholow began his career as a games journalist writing about video games in newspapers back in
1994 through industry connections he made in journalism
He landed a job with origin systems working on Ultima games
This began his game development career, and he worked at multiple studios before ending up with Reverge labs in 2010
He was one of the people who made the move from Reverge labs to lab zero games
Peter being the only member of Reverge labs with any business experience and having any capital became the company's sole owner
According to Mike's court documents an unnamed CEO and sole shareholder of lab zero games left the company in
2018 upon which Mike became the new owner this had to have been Peter the timeline matches up
So why was Peter Bartholow owed?
$450,000 was it compensation for his initial seed capital was it a settlement like Alex a had well at one point
Francesca mentions offhandedly when I was getting really sick of all the Peter crap
I mentioned I might want to leave and start my own thing the company lawyer
Meanwhile in an email mentions what he calls the Peter buyout. This is just speculation on my part
We don't have the whole story
But it sounds like the team ended up disliking Peter and at some point in 2018
Bought his share of the company in order to be rid of him which the company still owed debt on
Also, it's possible that Alex left around the same time as Peter. Yeah, I'm jumping ahead in the story
There's circumstantial evidence that kind of proves this later in the video
Which is interesting because it implies a pattern of people at the bottom of lab zero games purposely pushing out the people at the top
Marielle even admits as much on July 1st. I don't think I feel comfortable staying at lab zero if Mike is gone
That's not in defense of Mike
But rather what it means for what the studio has become and how that impacts us who remain lab zero has so much baggage
We've rightfully hosted all the people we need to but what remains is not the company that was founded initially and we're left with all
the stories the hurt the literal lawsuits and settlements and hundreds of thousands of dollars owed to people and on a personal note Tyson
Expressed he was nervous for how all this makes me and Franny look as people who weren't at the top that kicked all key members
Out and now lead the company. It's entirely possible that Peter left due to workplace disputes
Alex left due to workplace disputes Mike was being pushed out due to workplace disputes while Marielle and
Francesca both served to benefit from all the original core players moving on while also being at least part of the reason why they
Moved on but that's just my personal conjecture
Finally on September 23rd one of the employees that left
DM to Mike directly on discord and said that it was actually all about
Ownership of company in the end that everyone else was tired of waiting for equity distribution
During the public collapse of lab zero games one of the former employees Brian June had been answering questions on Twitter
That's where we got the information about Alex's settlement. For example
He also said however that Mike was never intended to be the owner of lab zero games after Peter had been bought out
Ownership was transferred to him temporarily for legal safety
But everyone had agreed to eventually turn the business into a worker co-op and Mike seemed to be trying to do just that
The roadblocks appear to be legal not personal but everybody blamed him and retaliated against him
Anyway, when he finally wielded the legal power of ownership that he held against the employees trying to dethrone him
They took it as a sign that Mike was never going to play ball and was just stringing them along
but Mike wielded that power because he believed he was being set up as a fall guy for all the problems a
Belief that the slack messages seemed to corroborate. So since we're pretty deep into the weeds here
Let me give you a quick recap of what we discovered from the court documents
Reverge labs collapses like a decade ago the core team reforms as lab zero games with Peter as CEO
Alex Mike Mariel and anyone else important to skullgirls comes along for the ride over the years a Peter and Alex both leave under weird
circumstances what we do know is that the company owes them money and Mariel states that her and
Francesca removing them and moving into more of a management role themselves was good and necessary
Skullgirls development winds down and the focus shifts to indivisible
After Peter and Alex are gone Mike owns the company and everyone agrees to turn it into a worker co-op
Mike has significant legal troubles trying to do so in June of 2020 several public
Controversies go viral all stemming from Mike's autism and social awkwardness each of which he apologizes profusely for on
August 24th 2020 a huge swath of lab zero games is staff all resign at the same time having coordinated their responses with
Francesca's financial data in order to cause maximum damage to the company
Despite the former staffs public statements claiming that they've spent the summer of 2020 engaged in an internal investigation
Their private chat logs show that they were already creating plans to either remove Mike from his own company or quit and form a new
Company one day after the bunny au thing went viral before anyone even knew the truth of it if they managed to wrestle control
Of lab zero games their long-term plan was to keep Mike on as a contractor to wrap up any remaining work on the current projects
Before eventually quietly firing him if not they would all quit in unison
Which is what they did and use their knowledge of lab zero games as inner workings to saddle Mike with the business debt
Steal and use the skullgirls contract as a quick moneymaker to get on their feet and then move on to different projects
They explicitly schemed to use Mike's various viral controversies as a public justification for these actions
The man they were friends with for 10 years in a matter of weeks
They went from being understanding to hating him even as they learned more about his neurodivergency in that same time frame
Oh also
Maryland Francesca knew they were doing some fucky shit because despite Mike's lawyer telling them they should not delete messages on lab zero games
Slack they tried to delete messages on lab zero games as slack
With all this shit stacked against them what Mike filed ultimately was a countersuit
Remember Maryland Francesca filed against him first for wrongful termination
I guess they saw the fat
Paychecks that Alex and Peter were getting and decided to get some of that for themselves on the way out the door
Also the chat logs show them shifting from empathetic towards Mike and reluctant to take action against their friend in June 2020 to outright
Hating him by August of 2020
It's certainly possible that by January of 2021 when they filed the suit all feelings of friendship were gone
And they simply viewed Mike as a resource to exploit
But I think they overextended their hand on this one
Francesca was laid off because the company could no longer do any work
That's not wrongful termination and Mariel didn't quit she resigned but maybe she means the disbanding of the board who knows
But what we do know is that Mike only slapped them with all of this shit after they came for him legally
Mike countersued Mariel Francesca and Future Club for interfering with lab zero games as contracts and relationships
Which had fallen apart due to the two women's plans who are now CEO and creative director of Future Club
respectively the damages stem from losing the skullgirls contract the shutdown of the indivisible game including the loss of a contract for an
unannounced but in production
Indivisible animated series with NBC as well as an unannounced contract with Arc System Works the creator of guilty gear that Bridget game
Lab zero games was going to be collaborating on probably the biggest anime fighting IP in the world
Mariel and Francesca tried to get the countersuit dismissed using anti slap laws
slap stands for strategic lawsuit against public participation and it refers to people using the courts and the threat of
Lawsuit to intimidate those who are exercising their First Amendment rights
most of the time anti slap laws come into play when somebody with influence threatens those who are speaking out against them with a
Lawsuit in order to stifle their speech and this is what Mariel and Francesca alleged that Mike's detailed countersuit was intended to do
In fact their lawyer compared the situation to Donald Trump and Stormy Daniels
But in March of 2022 the judge disagreed ruling that the countersuit can proceed that this wasn't a free speech issue
But a labor relations issue, but by April of 2023
It seems like the anti slap denial had been overturned and the case was remanded to the trial court for further proceedings
I'm actually not really sure since this case isn't being talked about anywhere online right now and all the official documents are heavy in legalese
but it sounds like where the case is at right now is that the court agrees that Mariel and Francesca's case arises in part from
Their public statements relevant to a public issue and therefore Mike's countersuit may be a malicious use of the court against them
But only if Mike's own case against them is baseless and the court outlined four of Mike's complaints that he might actually
Legally win on on their merits independent of the woman's public speech and so they sent the whole thing back to trial
So who knows where this goes the best I can tell is that their day in court has been set for February 6 2024
Man, now this video feels kind of incomplete, doesn't it?
I considered waiting to do this until the court date, you know to have a nice little bow to tie in the whole story
But who knows how long the trial might take it might be postponed
It might get appealed the Mike's I'm on versus future Club legal battle has already been quietly going on for two years
And it could go on for another two
Unfortunately, though that means we're all just sitting here with blue balls
But maybe I can offer you something else to tide you over until then part 5
Mariel Cartwright of the main woman in this lawsuit Francesca Esquenazi is clearly the more elusive of the two
She spoke significantly less in the slack channels than her counterpart and there's not much in the way of public appearances of her out there
I'm personally not surprised
Remember she was a GameStop clerk that Mike basically turned into a receptionist and she worked primarily in the
Financial and administrative side of the business but Mariel Cartwright
She's an animator by trade and the internet is littered with her various public appearances
A lot of these are simply animation workshops or doing press tours for games
But others are personal interviews and in those interviews, she said some very interesting things
So let's take a look at who Mariel Cartwright is at least who she appears to be from my point of view
There's a handful of primary sources. I'm going to be jumping between in order to make my point
They're all publicly available on YouTube
So if you think I'm somehow misrepresenting Mariel or I've got something wrong
They are all available for you to watch yourself. The major interviews
I'm going to be talking about are in chronological order one
Mariel's first ever on-camera appearance in an interview with Destructoid on December 23rd 2012
Two an interview of multiple lab zero games artists for the black torch anthology, which seems to be an art book
They all worked on on May 9th 2013
Three a panel on how to animate for video games that Mariel gave at a digital dragons convention on July 1st 2014
Four an interview that Mariel gave to the fighting game YouTube channel Pat the flip on February 2nd 2016
Five a GDC presentation of indivisible hosted by Mariel and Mike on October 11th 2019
Six an interview Mariel and her husband Tyson gave for mega 64 on July 25th 2020
And finally seven an interview Mariel gave with the horror game Awards on October 30th 2023, which is just a week ago
There's also a few other clips that I couldn't get an exact date on but they're short ones
I'll make sure to display on screen exactly which source I'm pulling the statements from let's get into it
Mariel's dad is an animator for Disney and her mother is a Japanese citizen. My dad was a Disney animator for most of my childhood
and my mom is Japanese
So it was just like this this blend of
You know Japanese culture Japanese films just you know, everything Japanese
combined with
My dad is a gigantic nerd
So it's Disney animation
He you know, he had the Atari
He was doing like a little bit of programming and he would get me into video games and stuff a quick Google search of Disney
Animators with the family named Cartwright revealed a Randy Cartwright who had a very prolific career at Disney
He was offered a job at a Japanese studio in the 80s where he trained Japanese animators on the general Disney style
Mariel grew up as a Sega kid and was in love with Sonic back in the 90s
Sonic
When I was like
maybe nine or so, my dad gave me a oh my goddess and
Rama
Look that he didn't need anymore. And then from there I started getting into all that kind of stuff
She ended up spending a lot of time drawing influenced by both of her parents preferred art styles
Was your father being an animator a burden or a help?
No, it was it was definitely a good thing
I remember
You know being very young and being able to go to my dad and ask questions about how you know
how do I draw this or that or
And you know, he would he would sometimes help out and be like, you know, ask me questions
like how do I think I would draw this and then he would show me the right way to do it and
No, he was he was great Mariel met the mega 64 guys at their first ever panel in 2006
She got to know them personally during this event and ended up helping them make a lot of their content mostly behind the scenes
How did me and Mariel meet?
She was at
Our first panel. It's so weird
Because that we the first panel we ever did
was at anime Los Angeles in 2006, that was the first panel we ever did and
In that room that audience was maybe 50 to 80 people that was I mean that was it and
In yet in that group was more
People that would affect my life than any other
Like like I met Mariel and all her friends people other people that I grew to know
other famous artists
That work with her and
Worked in the game industry stuff like that. They were in there
There there were other girls in there that I that I would later like years later like I dated
Like a couple different people who didn't even know each other in that same room
Who just happened to live in you know, Southern California?
I guess she would have been 18 at this time way before her professional animation career ever got started
You you're I mean, honestly, I think out of all the artists that we work with
I think we've been doing that stuff with you the longest I think of anybody I think
I was just saying I think it's like 14 or 15 years. I think I started this when I was
818 that's crazy
And I'm 33
Mariel attended the California Institute of the Arts otherwise known as Cal Arts. Well that explains a lot of the story we had like a
portfolio
Show thing at Cal Arts and I had all my stuff out and
normally the companies that come by are like Disney and DreamWorks and
You know big film companies like that
But who also was there was Matt Bozon at WayForward
Because WayForward is in the same city as Cal Arts
And he saw my stuff and I think he he got things going he was you know
He was a fan of my stuff and he got things going for me at WayForward
She met Jonathan Kim another Skullgirls artist while at Cal Arts and brought him into the project
The two of them as well as other creatives in their friend group ran what they characterized as an art
Collective called mecha fetus where they collaborated on various art pieces. Well, I met John
persona in
college I
Went to Cal Arts for character animation and he was in my year and we became friends super quick
And he had the idea with another friend of his to start like an art collaborative
group mecha fetus ran from their early college days in
2006 up until basically their professional careers took off and they no longer had time to work on it
I think people who have followed my work, I guess from the beginning
Know my stuff from the mecha fetus visual blog
Which was me John Kim persona
Paul Robertson
Eu03 and Brad Raffi and it was just a place where we
posted
Whatever really just it was just a place for us to post our earth that like wasn't deviant art or you know, whatever
And I think I don't know how I think it's because Paul already had a bit of a following
But people discovered that pretty quick. Yeah
And so we had like what what what time period were you doing the mecha fetus stuff mostly it was like
2006 or 7 to
Like it's sex because I don't want to say that
It's gone. Sure, or we're not gonna come back to it, but we haven't posted on it
But I mean, yeah, all of y'all are doing other things, right? Right. Yeah
The style of mecha fetus was described by Marielle as revolving around blood guts and naked girls your styles
are definitely different but there's reoccurring themes amongst all of you that being like
nudity
exposed brains and like intestines that are fun you like mix
Disgusting and sexy and cute all together. Am I right in thinking that that's kind of a unifying theme between um, I
Think that's that's most of a thing between Paul and I
We just like gross and cute things
I've always been like a fan of like horror scary stuff
and
Yeah, I mean that's that's kind of it
I just want to draw stuff that I think is cool
Mariel tells the story of how her career got started several times across these various interviews and though the story changes each time
It's mostly the same then I had my stuff at the job fair
I did not get noticed by anyone except
Family guy family guy sent me or requested like a storyboard test for me. All right
And then Matt bows on a way forward noticed my stuff
And that's actually kind of how my relationship with way forward started
She had done a bit of freelance work in video games here and there making the UI for some Barbie game and most notably making
A couple of drawings for the joke ending for Silent Hill shattered memories. My first thing was actually
Silent Hill shattered memories
Wow, which completely yeah, it came out of nowhere. Like we were you know, we had done the busy vlog for a couple years
And then I got an email from Tom hill at Konami
Asking if I could
You know do the the joke ending the UFO ending for shattered memories and I said, yeah
I'd love to but through way forward. She got her first big job in the games industry the Scott Pilgrim game. He
Asks what artwork did you work on for the Scott Pilgrim game?
Oh, I know I was forgetting something Scott Pilgrim game that you worked on what a what a beautiful piece of work that game is
He says the game is awesome in the art style rocks. So what did you do on that game? Um, I was one of the animators
I was actually only freelance on it. I worked off-site
But I did all the background and PC characters
and
I also did the title screen illustration which eventually was
Changed a bit in the final version, but I did the original of that
I
mentioned earlier in the video that the current fan narrative surrounding skullgirls is that the original creators Alex and Mike the ones who were truly
Passionate about skullgirls got screwed out of their own creation by progressives who don't give a shit about the property never worked on it
Never cared about it and now they're just ruining it
But this isn't true
Alex was another of Marielle's art friends and he brought her onto the skullgirls project before they pitched the concept to Reverge labs
I was a friend of Alex's and
In 2010, I think at the start of 2010 I started
Animating on the skullgirls just you know as one of my spare things
They started pitching it to different companies to see if anyone wanted to
Publish like pick up and fully develop skullgirls and I think we pitched it to like Ubisoft and maybe stag or something
and in the end it was
autumn autumn games who picked it up and
You know said we want to publish this game and we can fund a team develop it fully full-time
In fact Alex and Marielle were working on skullgirls before they even brought Mike on with his engine
Skullgirls started as an indie project originally as a pixel animated game in like
2004 ish
Alex was just working on it by himself at the time
And over the course of a few years and after several iterations it made the transition from being a 2d pixel game
To a 2d HD game then we had who is now our lead game designer Mike Z join the project and with him came
His own fighting game engine that he made himself
He was working on that for a long time before
Mike has been very particular about this point saying consistently that he or the rest of the team aren't the creators of skullgirls
Alex's at one point when Mike and Marielle were discussing indivisible in 2019 Marielle said this
The designer
artist on skullgirls Alex Ahad
You know was was a big part of it. He was the one that also designed all the monsters
Yeah creator of skullgirls
Yeah, so I think I think
Now this might just be me reading into it
But I feel like the tone of this exchange is Marielle downplaying Alex's involvement
Mike correcting the record and defending his friend who had left the company at this point by the way and Mariel quickly agreeing but
Rushing past the point but I could just be reading into it a little bit too much
Mariel confirmed that only the core skullgirls people from Reverge labs moved over to lab zero games
The skullgirls team has made a new studio called lab zero games
and we as a
Smaller more of like the score the core skullgirls team
We want to continue working on the game. She would later describe this as eight people in total
We have eight people in house we have four artists a programmer a designer
An art production guy and our CEO. Okay, we've got Alex Mike Marielle John Peter the unnamed CEO
In fact the way that Marielle describes him here as not a part of the creative process just the CEO
It really does sound like he just provided the initial startup capital
Like I theorized earlier Marielle describes this arrangement as not really being professional
They were just a big group of creative friends who wanted to make games together
The skullgirls team is made up of
Primarily 2d artists and animators and we worked with what we had as just a small indie team
We're just a big group of friends pretty much and in fact all throughout these videos
Marielle Alex all the artists that are interviewed they all seem to be part of some larger Southern California art scene
I actually forgot to mention in my introduction that I'm also part of a lava punch one and two and the spaceman anthology
Which are the previous books that that this group has done before and I've known them since
since my days in bow, which is basically
artist group gathering in the Bay Area Bay Area artists unite and
I was I had met them through there back in high school
So I guess I've known them for many years now speaking of that 2019 indivisible stream
There's some very interesting things going on there
Mike and Marielle are very clearly comfortable with each other acting like old friends Marielle is in the PR role in this conversation
Being diplomatic hitting talking points while Mike is this zany all-over-the-place hyper creative type with no public speaking skills
Probably the most blatant example of this dynamic is when Mike talks about why they didn't go with the epic game store for indivisible's release
What motivated your decision to sell the game where you do?
I mean we're we talk to designers now and developers so often
A major point of contention is which store front to put the game on and which service to put it out on and that seems
only likely to grow more
Contentious in the years ahead. So tell me how did you think about how to sell this game?
And sort of why did you put it out the way you did?
I mean, I guess you're referring to like steam versus epic now is kind of the discussion that we're having right?
I mean, I guess I guess for us epic came so late in the game that it just didn't really impact our decision at all
I mean it just
Some part of it was that we already had a steam version that worked right? Yeah
Yeah, so it you know
Consoles in
PC Mac Linux. Yeah was just basically it at the time, you know that we made the decision
Steam was the thing and so that's just kind of what we followed through
so we haven't been to
Know what's watching
About the epic store like that they give you information to
Their Chinese owner
Because that was a weird thing for a minute I recall sorry it was a weird thing for a minute
I have no idea whether it was actually confirmed because we didn't come out on the epic store. So yeah
I don't I don't want to I'm not trying to defend the epic store here
I'm just trying to make sure our claims do you know we're on a live stream here
So we don't we don't have the luxury of an editor. Yeah, so some have said
I think the bigger point is just that you know steam was our option when we were deciding and so that's what we just stuck
Yeah, but more interesting to me is how Mike and Mariel describe their workplace
How much do you let your staff provide creative input?
How do you organize staff input and how do you keep that input from clashing during production?
I think I think everyone has say
Yeah, that was that was exactly what I was gonna say and I'm I do not mean to speak over you sure sure
Well, I was just gonna say everyone
We encourage everyone to speak up just because I think a lot of the issues we ran into development
we were able to
Kind of like avoid or circumvent because someone spoke up and just just gave us an opinion that we weren't expecting
So we do try to encourage everyone to speak up as much as possible
But I think like Mike you and I we're both kind of like the vision holders
so we know that what we want out of the game and
And so, you know, we're always listening to feedback
But ultimately once a decision needs to be made it's gonna be made by you or I essentially we are as far as feedback goes
Completely flat and I don't want us to change that I've worked at places where it was like
You say you would say something about art and the artist would be like, well, you're not an artist
Like the artist would come to a designer and be like this parts been really frustrating like in me
Just playing it because I'm art in this part and the designer be like, yeah, well, you're not a designer. So shut up get out like
That sucks because the feedback that you get that's usually the most useful is from the people that aren't in your discipline
Right because they notice things that you are not trained or are trained to not notice anymore and like I
try to listen to absolutely everybody from everywhere at all times and then
Like the way that I put it on skull girls was I'll listen to everybody but the decision is mine
They both genuinely seem to want a flat hierarchy where everyone has an equal say as team leads
They do have to make the final choice that's inevitable
But Mike seems genuinely committed to the idea of everyone being equal
Elsewhere Mario characterized Mike as essential a talented genius that could do things by memory in a way. She'd never seen before the way
making moves for skull girls works is
That the artists kind of like all come together and brainstorm just a bunch of moves that they think would look awesome for the character
to do
Just no limits. Just anything just kind of trying to keep in mind like well she needs to punch
She needs to kick she needs some supers and you know all that stuff
and then we pass that on to Mike Mike see who's the designer of skull girls who is just
Like the brain behind everything game play related at our company
How literate is Mike in terms of animation?
Like was he able to speak to you in your language or you know what?
Yeah, that's something that I'm so grateful for in Mike is that he might not understand
Like animation terminology or
Just like all like the twelve principles and all this stuff
But he is such a good and thorough understanding of how fighting games work
That a lot of times he would help us fix our animations to make them work more like other fighting games. Yeah
Just send you like animated guests from like fighter generation. Oh my god constantly
He says, you know
I want it to work like this and it works like this because of this and this it has this many frames in it
You know, this is why it does what it does
And so much of what I learned just came from him telling me
You know, like this is X number of frames and it works because of this reason
And do that in your animation and a lot of times he's fixing the timing on my animations. Like I don't think I
Could have done any of what I did like without his input. Oh, yeah crazy
Yeah, I swear to God like the sentence that I hear most often in fighting games is alright
So here's how they do it in guilty here
It's funny because I don't know anyone else that could just rattle off exact frame counts of certain moves from some random game
And just you know, it's not even fighting games like he could do that about
You know Metroid
Any game he's passionate about he will just dissect and
Know in and out. It's really fascinating to me
This all lends weight to the claim that even though Mike was the foundation of the whole operation
Especially after the absence of Alex
He still intended to make lab zero games a worker co-op
Probably because he viewed these people as his friends and he wanted to do right by them
It just wasn't legally possible Mario's attitude towards her own art has changed over the years in 2012
She said she didn't really think about what she drew or why she simply knew that she liked girls with big boobs and gory horror
Stuff and mecha fetus was her connection to other Southern California creatives with those same tastes
Is there any reason why the mecha fetus blog is a little slow with updates?
Where can we get more regular updates on your work? I thought you had your own tumblr as well. Is that right?
Uh, yeah, I do know well
I think we were almost active on the busy blog while we were in college and since then we've had
You know jobs and we come home from our work and we're just too tired to try extra stuff
You know, it's still updated sometimes but definitely not as much as it used to and although Alex wasn't a part of mecha fetus
He shared these interests
Which is why Marielle was drawn into the skull girls project as skull girls also includes a lot of those things though toned down
Did you come up with any of the more disgusting ideas? No, I didn't actually it's it's all Alex and what's great about him is
That
Also Alex and I like the same stuff
his stuff isn't quite as is
Like brain exposed gory as I like but he just loves weird monstery
You know gross out stuff. So yeah, no, it's super cool Alex and I think pretty alike
That's great that you yeah
So many people who who get you in that way and that you have so many fans who get you as well
But when you first signed on to work on the skull girls project full-time
Did you feel like you were taking a professional risk in any way or did it just feel natural and like them?
Um, it pretty much felt like a dream come true. Like what better job could I ask for than to animate cute girls?
Marielle also mentioned that skull girls received a lot of flack back during its release that nowadays sounds very familiar
You know as soon as like our first trailer came out, you know, everyone was like, oh
Pedophile disgusting all-girls game. It's like well one. I don't know where the pedophile comment comes from because they're all girls with big
I guess Miss Fortune's boobs are medium. Yeah that pedophile in the art world
Yeah, I know it's it's stupid because in the end
Not every girl is like a sexy bombshell. I think we're actually pretty varied
But those are the characters that people remember
Um, but
You know, we we all we got a lot of negative press and stuff in the sexism and all that nonsense
but I
Feel like everyone on the team felt that we were really making something good and we were pouring our hearts into it
And we were working your asses off and we just wanted to make the best product we could boy
nothing's really changed has it calling drawings of cute women pedophilic is just as dumb today as it was back then and
Developers fear of being labeled as a sexist has only increased since 2012 but back then Mariel gave the correct answer
I'm finding more and more talking to publishers and developers that it's not that they don't want to add
More women or add more minorities and it's not that they think that minorities and women can't sell
It's that they're oftentimes afraid that they're going to be called
Sexist or racist right if they depict a woman in the wrong way
Then everyone's gonna call them sexist or if they you know, make a male character
I mean a black character with big lips and an afro then it's gonna be oh, you're you're you're racist when
We'll have big lips and afro. It's uh, it's it's limiting people's fear of racism and sexism
I feel can limit them a lot and you guys didn't have that at all. You just went for it
yeah, I I mean I
Think the way Alex thinks in creating his characters is he just wants to think you're he just wants to make what he thinks is
Super cool. He's not there's no quota to meet or you know, anything like that. He just wants to make awesome stuff
But did you ever?
When people call me racist which happens sometimes I think maybe I'm racist and I just don't know it
Who knows I have to like really scan my brain for racism that might be like planted in there
Did you ever think that maybe you were a sexist pedophile?
um
I've
Don't want to say I've thought about it
But I mean, you know it all the discussion has has made me question like well is my stuff problematic
Um, and I I think what it comes down to especially with school girls is that I
don't think that anything we've made is
Purely eye candy. I feel like every character is substantial
Like the characters that are super sexy like Sarah Bella and Valentine. It's part of their character like
Valentine in particular
She knows she's sexy. She flaunts it. It's it's part of her to be that and that's okay
That's I think that's totally fine. It's not wrong for a woman to be sexy
This is the liberal reply the sex-positive anti-piritan reply
I I feel like there's an attitude of like that every woman
Like every female character has to be like a strong independent woman and I think that's great
We do need more characters that are like that, but we also need all types of characters. We need different women
One a woman who is strong a woman who is insecure and weak
As long as I think we get variation like that's what we should be going for. Not every woman should be eye candy
Not every woman necessarily needs to be a super badass either
You know people are different and I think that's what we should be going for in our games
If only progressive creators knew this nowadays Ray Skywalker or Captain Marvel don't work because they're not real people
They're just avatars of female empowerment 2012. Mariel understood this but by 2016 Mariel's position on this topic had shifted quite a bit
When I was six, my parents got me a Genesis. Okay, and on the Genesis
I had Street Fighter 2 and then super came out and that had Kami
And I was always really bummed that Chinle was the only girl in the original and then so they introduced Kami
But my parents didn't want to buy it from me because I already had the game
So I would rent it from blockbuster over and over and over just to play as Kami
I thought she was super cool. This was when I was you know, like seven
She just seemed super cool. She seemed super strong. I
Liked her hair. I liked her moves. Just everything about her was like appealing to me for some reason Tifa was a big one
Just for some reason I was always
Attracted to like cool female characters
Which is interesting because I actually started off drawing Sonic, okay
Sonic was my life from six to twelve, but even then
You know, I always liked drawing
Sally and bunny and just like the females of the Sonic universe
I started just like getting into manga more and then that kind of like dominated most of my teens
But yeah still like throughout I was always just like attracted to
girls, yeah, and
I've only actually dated men like been in relationships with men
But I'm still like attracted to girls
it's I
Have like a weird
Relationship with my own sexuality where I've only dated men, but I don't particularly find men attractive
Yeah, it's it's kind of weird to say she is clearly hinting at the same sexual awakening and interest that she mentioned back in 2012
But the tone of her story has changed in 2012. She was more. I don't know. I just think hot chicks are cool
Look at my artwork. It's got girls at big tits while in 2016
She's more about identifying with her sexuality in what we would call nowadays a quasi political manner
She also makes the claim that she still likes all the same edgy stuff
But that she purposely tones it down because she knows she has eyes on her now
She knows that she can influence others and that the political environment in 2016 is different than what she grew up with
I like pretty girls
May or may not know that I'm also into like horror and I like gory stuff and you know all that
So
Like from the very start just being an artist like drawing was the outlet for all those things that I liked sure
and
It was like if someone told me not to draw something
Which you know has happened?
It's like well, what why wouldn't I this is how I get that stuff out of my head, right?
Like that's not to say that I don't have
Fears about putting certain works online
Like I've kind of toned down the amount of like gore kind of stuff that I post
Like I don't post that stuff as much
Like I think that's just in part like I'm aware that I have a lot more eyes on my work now, right
You know, my art is the way I want to like express certain things, but I do still have a fear of like
Oh, is this too much?
Especially now, I think
Like kind of like the culture and environment that we're in
We're very hyper aware of like the meaning like the implications of the work we put out which is good
but my personal struggle is like
When do I stop putting myself into something and start thinking about you know, what other people are seeing about me
And that's that's something I still have a hard time with in
2012 Marielle was asked about the future of her career and the answer she gave was interesting Tim Schafer
For instance, he's been in the business for so long
He's built up a huge following you can just go on Kickstarter and be like million dollars, please
I want to make a game. Do you see yourself maybe in 15 years being like million dollars?
I want to make brain naked boobs
Testons zombie
Rainbow party game and people giving you I know I'd I'd donate as much as you want for it right now
Do you would you ever see yourself being able to make the kind of games that are as weird as you can possibly get? I?
Don't know I think it's kind of tricky with I
feel like with games you have to really be conscious of the player and what the player wants which which
Isn't necessarily how it should be like I wish it could be as open as making like an independent film is
I don't think I don't know if I'd be a good game
Yeah, what makes you say that?
hmm, I don't know because I feel like it's a lot of
Like thinking about systems and and you know, where's where's the game in the game?
And I'm like, well, I want to make something that's pretty and that doesn't make for a good game
But I kind of look I am interested in it, but I feel like
There's a lot I still have to learn before I even try tackling it in 2020
Marielle states that she has no time for any of her old projects anymore and that she is getting old
Over the past couple years. I've been working on my personal stuff less and less. I don't have the time anymore
I think I'm getting old is what's happening. But yeah
You're in charge of things
Yeah, it's different like when you
You have to do that take up your entire day. Yeah
It's different when you're done with your work for the day that it used to be
This is on some level the natural progression of a successful career
You begin as the plucky energetic creative and as you move up in life
You lose that energy and end up in a more managerial role and in 2023 when she has to face that question a second time
Where do you see yourself in ten years? Her answer is very different
Where do you see yourself in ten years in the games industry?
Hmm that's a good question. Um, I
Mean, I would I would love to work on more projects like this
I do enjoy being kind of like in a leadership position, but what I really want to do is
help
bring up others
And and get them to leadership positions to be able to create their own games
Like if I do kind of go more to a management kind of position
But but if that gives me an opportunity to kind of help others bring their own ideas to life
Like that's something that I would love to see
So I definitely don't see myself like always doing all the art myself and stuff like that
I really believe in making room for for others to share their art
So
Wherever that takes me
Um, I think that's something that I would I would be excited to see passing the torch to the next generation is fine and necessary
Of course, but there's also at least from how I'm reading this the sense that she's lost what made her her
Yeah, part of that is just aging. I'm old too. I've probably lost some stuff over the years actually with me
It's more like I've gained but here's what I mean. My core interests and values remain uncompromised even after all these years
I've explored different ideas different hobbies and interests different politics, but my values have always remained the same
I'm still the same edgy 2000s era dev
This isn't stagnation because what I was back then was good and it's still good
This is the rejection of change for changes sake I feel no need to answer for anything
I've done in the past because even if it doesn't line up with modern sensibilities, it's still overwhelmingly good in short
I don't have trolls remorse
We've just spent like a half-hour watching clips of Mariel describing her career and her art and maybe it was a little bit too much
But I wanted to paint a complete picture
What's happened here isn't just that Mariel's matured and her ideas have changed over time though. That's part of it
It's also that like Atrox from earlier Mariel seems to have not trolls remorse, but sexy remorse in 2012
She was unapologetically sexual open about her attraction to other women proud and direct in
2016 she claims to still feel that way but was afraid of the current political paradigm canceling her for being misogynistic in
2023 all traces of that former Mariel is gone and she has become the Puritan the
Canceller that she once feared and if you want proof of that
All you have to do is go back and see how she shit on Mike her friend for over a decade for the crime of
Engaging with her on the terms. She established or hell how about this, you know Philia the skullgirls character
That was the most censored in that 2023 update
Mariel was the one who did those initial animations in 2010. I think at the start of 2010 I started
Animating on the skullgirls just you know as one of my spare things
and
We we were focusing on Philia who was the first character and we we pretty much almost finished her
Yes
That character was her baby
Mariel drew the panty shots that became iconic of the game and his future club creative director
Mariel greenlit the censoring of her own work
There is this narrative among hardcore skullgirls fans and terminally online culture warriors that the skullgirls
censorship story is one of new progressive corpora types coming in kicking out the original creators who were based and waifu pilled
Updating it for modern sensibilities regardless of the desires those original creators and all the fans who don't like the changes are just racist
Alt-right fascist gamer Gators
It's an appealing story because that actually has happened before but it doesn't quite fit this time
The majority of the original team that worked on skullgirls back in the day are still there at future club
And this is a case of them ruining their own legacy in order to appeal to the new progressive standard that they either feel
Browbeat into adhering to or that they genuinely believe in themselves and I personally think it's the latter
What's going on with Mariel Cartwright specifically is what I would like to dub Lindsay Ellis syndrome where you fear the puritanical nature
Of the audience you've cultivated even as you yourself become more and more like them when Mariel stated that she fears her old
Artwork being used one day to cancel her those words sound like they could have come directly from the nostalgia chicks mouth
Yeah
Like I haven't been posting like the weird stuff the weird and gory stuff recently because I've honestly been scared of the backlash
You know, I've now seen how people will try to dig up stuff about you and post it
Like, you know, here's something you did in
2006 let's see it
Destroy you because you know the same person you're the same person you were in 2006 and it's like it's not the case people are
changing constantly
but
You know because I'm now scared of those kind of people coming up from the fucking depths of hell to destroy me
I
Haven't been posting that kind of work in 2012
She simply wanted to create artwork that was authentically her and to hell with those who didn't approve for political reasons by
2016 she was afraid of that 2012 attitude coming back to bite her in the ass
Even as she still ultimately believed in it and by 2023
She has absolutely morphed into the type of person who would have canceled her past self for saying the word retarded
But other than that I hadn't really done like a full comic by myself other than
Like retarded
While researching all of this I went to go check out whatever remnants of that mecha fetus thing might still exist online
And I quickly found this page a lost relic in
2009 our art collective mecha fetus put together a little art book that we sold at anime Expo the mecha fetus site is unfortunately down
But some of the artwork now lives on in a PDF you can download for free 18 plus only please features nudity
Gore and some jokes that have not aged. Well, you've been warned. All right
Well, even though it says it's free the button doesn't work unless I put something in so I guess I'll put in one cent
There's no PayPal. I got I got to use a credit card
Do I really want to give Mariel my real-life information? Oh god. Well if something weird happens to my credit card
I guess I know who did it. All right things I do for a video
Wait a minute. The amount must be 99 cents. You said it was free
Okay, one dollar Jesus when you guys toss me a $1 super chat at some point
I hate the idea of actually giving her some of my money
But I guess that means I'm giving her yours instead and here we go. I've got the PDF mecha fetus
2009 nice girls nice cats. It is a lot of overly sexualized ridiculous drawings
Honestly the kind of stuff that she's still post nowadays on her private accounts
But I want to see what she's referring to when she says jokes that haven't aged. Well. Oh, yeah
I definitely got a sense for this
This is a picture of a naked zombie girl getting seppuku and her blood fountaining out onto a mecha fetus a robot fetus
Well on the other side, there's an angel woman who's squeezing her tits together and spraying milk onto the same fetus
I mean, it's ridiculous and goofy and stupid but definitely not you too safe. Oh, I think I found it
This is a giant
bloodied
futanari woman with like a four-foot cock and a whole bunch of women are like climbing on it and dancing around it while it
Ejaculates a huge rainbow, but also she has a swastika carved into her tits
This is so stupid and ridiculous. It really is funny artwork, but man
This is not the kind of thing that a 2023 progressive would do
I'm not bringing this up to cancel Mariel just like I didn't with Atrux earlier
It's to point out that all of these people have followed a similar path
Despite all of their claims to be artists who are creating what is authentically them
They nonetheless move and bend with the wind when being edgy and sexual was popular and progressive
They were edgy and sexual when the political paradigm moved on they also moved on but only kinda
These people will still make and like sexual art on their personal accounts while at the same time
Chastising you for your own sexual expression because they're progressive and sex-positive while you're a fetishizer and an exploiter
Once again, we come face to face with safe horny. There's a hard truth here that I've personally had to learn the hard way
I think Mike might be learning it the hard way, too
when you look at Mariel and Alex and all these other people in their Southern California art clique when you look at other similar cliques in
Twitch streaming or youtubing speedrunning indie game development any sort of creative field that is relatively new
You can see the beginnings of class divide in those cliques
I'm not gonna sit here and say that Mariel is the haves and the artist whose stuff never takes off as the have-nots
Mariel's not a capitalist bourgeois oppressor or any nonsense like that
But these are all people who know each other they live in one of the most affluent areas of the world
They have connections. They wear their politics on their sleeve. Their groups are called collectives or cooperatives for a reason
They want a bit of that commune aesthetic. We are feature club and we are
cooperatively owned and run game company everyone on the team has equal ownership and
Voting power and to determine sort of how the studios run and that was really something that was really really important to us and
Frankly people like you or I were just not part of the club even if we became successful
I remember talking to I think it was it's a Gundam about this in private
He's got a really successful channel, but he's still on the outside of the YouTube game
He's still somebody that the equivalent of Mariel in a lefty youtuber clique would look down on it's true that Mariel got to where she
Was based off of her own talent and hard work
She is truly a successful artist, but she's also physically attractive. She has the right politics. She lives in the right place
She knows the right people if I were an equally skilled artist as her
I still wouldn't have her career because I'm not her the socialist analysis of the state of affairs would be to consider the system
Oppressive and work towards its destruction, but I'm not a fucking retard and also I don't want to destroy what they've built for themselves
I don't want to be a part of it. The actual solution is to build your own
institutions outside of their control in
Locations that they ignore and with people they've cast out and of course you gate keep it from them
A lot of the youtubers that I know personally we've all learned this lesson the hard way and I hope Mike is learning it too
part 6
Future Club in the court documents Mariel and Francesca exclaim that their company doesn't need to be about fighting games anymore
They can do whatever they want and there are other stories that they want to tell that are slower and more thoughtful
You know walking simulators, I guess they reiterated the sentiment during a segment in the progressive gaming expo future of play
Mariel mentioned back in 2012 much of a fan of clock tower that she is, you know that SNES horror game
I would really love to work on a survival horror game
I think it'd be kind of hard because right now my skills are 2d oriented
and I think
It's kind of easier to get like a survival horror thing across in a 3d environment though. My favorite
Survival horror game is the first clock tower. Oh, yeah, which which is a 2d, you know point-and-click
So
I don't know
But I guess you know that that would be my dream project and I guess it would star a girl
Well in 2023, she's the lead on the clock tower remake. Give us the lowdown
Why clock tower?
Yeah, so I think something that way forward and limited run have been really interested in doing
over the past few years is
kind of
Finding these hidden gem games that haven't seen Western release
So I think clock tower fits exactly that criteria where clock tower is a game that has a really
Great, like dedicated fan base the original Super Nintendo game, which is my favorite
Never got a Western release or an official translation
So it seemed like the perfect game to kind of reintroduce to people kind of bring back
This brand and
You know just just share with the world like how great this game is
So it seems like she's successfully managed to make that shift those slower more intimate stories while still doing something her younger self truly
Desired which is to her credit
But my analysis of the court documents seems to be correct
Marielle and Francesca and the rest of the future clubbers just seemed to be over and done with skull girls
But it's probably the only lifeline they have right now. It's making them some money though
I'd guess less now since the censorship controversy has tanked their public image, but I think they no longer care about the property
Here's what I think happened on the business side of things when Marielle and Mike gave that indivisible GDC talk
They both described skull girls like it was over. It was a finished project indivisible was their next big thing
We were kind of coming off of finishing all the skull girls DLC that we did which we also crowdfunded on Indiegogo
So we would how many characters did we release for skull girls?
Okay, so so we put out six DLC characters for skull girls
And and once we finished that, you know
We started looking ahead and thinking about our next project
This explains why skull girls was getting little to no updates during this time, by the way
The team was just done with it
But after the implosion of lab zero games and the creation of future club
I think Marielle and Francesca realized just how fucked they were
The only contract they could secure was with autumn games for more skull girl stuff
Which is why even as Marielle and Francesca talk a big game about new projects
The only thing they did for like three years was try to revive skull girls
The only property of note they can get their hands on if they were going to be able to move on and do those future
Games they need to milk that old skull girls legacy as much as possible to me
It seems like this is probably what drove the censorship in the first place
They thought it would boost popularity and hopefully sales enough in the short term just to get a few more dollars out of it
While their real priorities lie elsewhere
Additionally, I'd be remiss if I didn't mention this plus I spent like 12 hours researching it and I got to get something out of
That time even if it's only one final paragraph at the end of the video
But it seems like future club is actually a real worker co-op
Marielle and Francesca founded it in Colorado as a B corporation
Which is a corporate status that only some states have a public benefit corporation
Which allows them to pursue profit but not have a strict fiduciary duty to shareholders
They can instead also pursue a declared public good separate from profit
This basically gave them the legal leeway to be worker owned right from the beginning instead of trying to turn a normal for-profit
Corporation into a worker co-op future club, Colorado a b-corp shell company owns a separate company future club, California
Which is a normal corporation, which they all work for however due to the nature of American business law
The worker co-op status is if I'm reading this gobbledygook right and I might not be at the whim of Marielle and Francesca
Future Club's founding documents outline that all company shares are pegged at a value of one cent
one share is given to each employee upon the completion of their probationary period and that the company itself has
1,000 shares the vast majority of which are held by the company and handed out by executives to the employees
Even though everyone has one share Marielle and Francesca control the remaining shares
So it might be possible for them to pull some legal fuckery if they wanted to and just take over the company
I don't know though. I'm no expert in law from my layman's perspective
It does look like future club is at least a real attempt at a worker co-op and that American law might be unsuited for it
I'm not sure. So that is everything to me. It seems like Marielle Cartwright is a snake
She's not a fake gamer girl or some new progressive face coming into skull girls to fuck it up
That part of the fan narrative is incorrect, but that doesn't mean that she's innocent
For all of Mike's I'm onts faults and there are many of them don't get me wrong
Marielle seems like a person who corrupted this friend group from the inside out
She blamed others for actions that she committed herself
Including workplace sexual harassment and expressed fears that she would eventually be discovered for it
She genuinely contributed to a wonderful game in skull girls using her own incredible talents
But she then used that leverage to force everybody else out of the project and kept it for herself
Only to exploit it to springboard her career in a different direction
She betrayed her friends people she knew for years in
Mike's case being extremely close to him for a decade and then in just a matter of weeks
Pulled a 180 and viewed him as her worst enemy that decade of friendship meant nothing. She had no compassion
She knew the claims against him were false and she pushed them anyway because she knew it would help her career
She didn't even really care if he got saddled with all that debt and in the progressive point of view
At least everything is forgiven because she is a minority woman in game development who is harassed by a white male
Because he did the same shit to her that she did to him only she is attractive and popular while he is autistic and awkward
I personally believe that despite Mike's own faults a lot of the flak he receives nowadays is basically just out of spite
Remember modus games the company run by the woman CEO who decided to give Mike another chance
She said that his work has been truly genius level stuff
He is an inspired master of his craft, but also that his personal behavior at her company has been perfect
She was not willing to trade genius level work for bad behavior and she hasn't had to Mike's direct supervisor
Deagle legacy's art director has said the same thing but in that PC gamer article about the game
They also reached out to future club employees and printed the opinion of an anonymous former co-worker of Mike's
When I heard that modus was going to work with him. I was like that's disgusting. They're disgusting. It's disgusting
They'd work with him because they clearly don't care about female game developers
The public record was there of his continued harassment of two ex co-workers. We don't know who this is
It's anonymous
but they seem to believe that despite Mike's good behavior at modus games his ongoing lawsuit proves that he hasn't truly changed and that if
Mike were actually remorseful. He wouldn't be fighting back in court
He would just be accepting whatever legal punishment
Mariel and Francesca wish to inflict on him having read all the court documents and watched all the interviews
I personally believe that this anonymous source from future club is probably Mariel herself
She is the only one of the former staff who exhibited such visceral hatred of Mike and if I were to do some armchair
Psychologizing I think that by 2023
She still holds this visceral hatred because she knows she backstabbed a close friend of hers and she needs to justify it to herself
On the extreme off chance that you're watching this Mariel
I just want you to know that tiny voice that you can never seem to get rid of completely
lingering in the back of your mind in the middle of the night telling you that what you did was wrong and you keep
Bearing it with more and more hatred more justifications new projects new public statements, whatever but it never seems to go away. It's correct
The skull girls team
Predicted that the narrative surrounding future club would be that they bullied Mike out of his company that they destroyed an innocent man for simply
Being kind of weird and that is exactly what the narrative surrounding future club should be. I hope Mike wins in court
That's it. That's the end of the video guys. Thanks very much for watching if you couldn't tell this was a lot of work
I hope you enjoyed it Naomi my girlfriend and Dave my editor doing a few
Jokey voices for some of the characters in this story if you want me to keep using their incredible talents like this
Let me know in the comments. I guess I just decided to try it on a whim additionally
Yes, I do know about technicals video. He got it out first and it was a very good video
It's certainly worth watching
I went over a few things that he didn't but also he got that exclusive word from Kim McCaskill
He emailed her and got her comment on the story
I could have put that in my video, but I didn't want to steal his work
It just didn't seem right. So you should go and watch his stuff too. Why not? Anyway, I know this took forever
Thanks for sticking by me. I will see you guys next time. I love you