Let me take you all back to the year 2009, back when YouTube looked like this and memes looked
like this. This was a time before dank memes, before MLG memes. This was a time when YouTube
poops reigned supreme. So many legendary poops came out around this time. Who could forget
classics like Toys Gone Wild, Freddy Ruins Sam's Life, and Hank of the Hill? YouTube poop was at
the peak of its cultural relevance and it would go on to inspire the editing styles of some of
the biggest YouTubers of today. There's an old legend in the YTP community that not many others
know about. It's a tale of the most glorious day in YTP history, about how one man literally broke
YouTube in the name of shitposting. Nowadays we would have called it cancer, but in 2009,
antics like this went by a different name, AIDS. This is the story of May AIDS.
Scientists at the National Centers for Disease Control released the results of a
study which shows that the lifestyle of some male homosexuals has triggered an epidemic.
A-I-D-S. AIDS. The most frightening initials in America today.
Not much is known about the YouTube pooper May AIDS. I never knew the guy. I missed him by a
couple of years. I only heard about him from the stories from way back in the day. May AIDS was
someone that casual YouTube viewers never knew about. Searching for him on Google today yields
only a couple thousand results. There just isn't that much information out there about May.
But using what little I could find, I was able to piece together this much about him.
In order to know about May AIDS, you had to be in the loop of the YTP community. He was a fairly
enigmatic user in the early days of YouTube, the YouTube Poop Forums. He was most active on
YouTube from 2007 to 2008, but his videos never really got that much attention, mostly because
he never really stayed in one place for long. I say that because he had about a dozen accounts
banned from YouTube, and those are just the ones we know about. The only May videos you can find
today are re-uploads, some from as far back as 2007. From what I can tell, May AIDS's style was
very chaotic and unpredictable, much like the individual himself. He was one of the first
poopers to employ the technique of sentence mixing. I need that cock he's wearing so I don't suck
tits. How come Robotnik's badniks wanted to catch you more than they wanted to catch herpes?
He also made a lot of sex jokes, which would explain his reportedly degenerate taste for anime,
furries, anime furries, and anime furry porn. The name May can actually be traced back to May the
Goat from the film Arashi no Yoru ni, which is an anime about furries that he used as a source in
his early YTPs. And despite making pretty decent and well-respected YouTube Poops for the time,
May AIDS was not simply satisfied with resting on his laurels. May AIDS never got attention for
his videos. No, no, no. Quite the opposite actually. May never went into making YouTube
videos for the fame. He was in it for the flames. May quickly established himself as the most
notorious troll in YTP history. There was this one time when May fabricated an entire account
and persona called Toby Said It just to troll the YTP community. You see, back in 2009 there would
be all these anti-YTP people who would pop up and make terrible rant videos on their 240p webcams,
and YouTube Poopers would always troll them in response. So May AIDS basically took this concept
and decided to troll the trolls. He intentionally made a bunch of stupid controversial rants,
got attention, baited a bunch of angry comments, and in the end he revealed that he was actually
May AIDS the whole time. And then he closed the account. That's just the kind of guy May was.
He was sort of this renegade meta troll. He didn't care about loyalty or community or taking sides.
He just kind of did whatever he felt like to see if he could. And wherever May went, he seemed to
leave a trail of chaos and confusion. His accounts on YouTube and YouTube got banned so frequently
that it was really tough to pin down exactly who May was at any given time. Couple that with a
boatload of impersonators and alt accounts and you have the veil for one of the most mysterious
figures in the YTP community. He was kind of ethereal in that way. He was both everywhere and
nowhere at the same time. May's antics pretty much only remained within the realm of YTP,
an obscure hidden micro community in a vast sea of content. But what if I told you that one day,
for one glorious moment, May AIDS reached a level of trolling that shouldn't have been possible.
While everybody was relaxing at home and enjoying their winter vacations,
something very strange was happening on YouTube.
So what in the world was going on here? Well the truth is that YouTube got hacked.
And May AIDS was responsible. But how do we know that? YouTube was the fourth biggest site on the
web at the time and a pretty big target. YouTube could have been hacked by anyone. So how do we
know it was May and not someone like the mysterious 4chan? Well first of all, many of the videos
involved in the hack were popular YouTube poops, a disproportionate amount. Additionally, one of the
hacked thumbnails was changed to an image of Conrad Slater, the founder of the YouTube forums.
Clearly, whoever was responsible was someone within the YouTube poop community.
The final and most compelling clue came from the images used in the hacked YouTube poops.
The thumbnails were changed to an image of a pink anime goat called Piano Chan,
which just so happened to be May's profile picture at the time. Some people still dispute whether or
not May actually executed the hack himself. Some have suggested that the hack was actually carried
out by a guy called ADHD Yoshi, May's partner in crime. Regardless of what actually happened,
May was certainly complicit in the hack at the very least. As far as I know, YouTube has never
experienced a hack of this spectacle ever since. Just imagine if something like this happened today.
Imagine if channels like Logan Paul, RiceGum, Jimmy Kimmel, and Taylor Swift had their thumbnails
changed to pink anime goats. It would have been a legendary and unforgettable event. But that's the
weird part though. An event of this magnitude did happen, but not many people seem to remember it.
Now why is that? Well, I think the lack of hype around this event truly demonstrates how drastically
YouTube has changed since 2009. When May hacked the thumbnails, YouTube did not have the tremendous
cultural impact that it possesses today. YouTube just wasn't that big because the internet wasn't
that big. And at the time, it was still a new frontier from which nobody really knew what to
expect. YouTube was much less strictly regulated back then and weird stuff just kind of happened
all the time. I guess one little thumbnail hack didn't seem too out of the ordinary back when
YouTube didn't really have an established norm. Nowadays, YouTube is a huge dominant platform that
every person, brand, and celebrity uses to try and snag their own little piece of fame.
YouTube has never had a more important role in society than it does now. Back in 2009, people
didn't really take YouTubers seriously. YouTubers were still viewed as amateur webcam geeks and
nobody thought they were particularly important individuals. Today, a YouTuber like Logan Paul
can make one mistake and receive global mainstream news attention. In 2009, big YouTubers weren't
hated nearly to the extent that they were today. YouTube drama is a relatively new concept and it
only existed as a small niche back in the day. I feel like the rising competitive culture of
modern YouTube has bred the drama which has elevated YouTubers to a much higher level of
relevance and modern YouTubers now face so much more scrutiny than their predecessors.
YouTube is no longer a wild west type free-for-all. It has become a legitimate,
strictly regulated business and brand reputation has never been more of a salient issue.
And with that being said, you can imagine the potential impact that a May AIDS thumbnail hack
could have today. Perhaps May would have been more nefarious in his thumbnail imagery. Imagine if May
had posted offensive or pornographic imagery on family-friendly YouTube brands. This had
the potential to be a huge controversy that could have cost YouTube millions of dollars,
but luckily for them, this oversight happened during an unimportant time
by a person who was just shitposting.
Personally, I can vaguely recall the pink anime goat in the thumbnails of a bunch of YouTube poops,
but I never really thought anything of it at the time. I figured it was just a weird YTP meme and
only later did I learn the true convoluted story behind it all. There used to be a video of May
AIDS allegedly performing the hack, but it has since been lost. While making this video, I tried
to use the internet wayback machine to find screenshots of the event taking place, but oddly
enough I couldn't find any archive of YouTube or the hacked channels during the dates on which the
hack took place. There just isn't that much documentation of this event out there on the web.
It almost feels like a dream in a way, like something that was all made up, just a tall
tale. But the Christmas thumbnail hack of 2009 really did happen, and there are still a few
surviving videos out there on YouTube right now with a hacked pink anime goat thumbnail.
You just have to know where to look. I think what puzzles me most about this incident is that May
just sort of got away with it. I mean he did get his account suspended, but for May that was a
weekly occurrence. So what's the big deal? After hacking the thumbnails of some of the biggest
channels on YouTube, May AIDS just went back to his typical YouTube Poop related shenanigans.
He stuck around for a few more years, and then around 2012, he vanished. Nobody really knows
what happened to him. Maybe he left YouTube for good. Maybe the FBI finally got him for all that
underage goat porn. But most likely, May probably just did what he did best. He opened an obscure
alt account that no one knew about and left everything behind. Perhaps he continues to lurk
among us to this day. An anonymous observer, forever a mystery, abandoning his only legacy
to fade away and, in time, be forgotten. There is one last thing May AIDS did under his name.
Some YouTuber wanted to make sure May AIDS was not forgotten, so they tried compiling all this May
footage scattered across YouTube onto one account known simply as the May AIDS Memorial. Then the
real May came back and submitted three fake copyright claims and terminated the account.
But what can I say? That's just the kind of guy May was.