🎵
Savage Patrick is the reincarnation of the Chicken SpongeBob meme,
which I thought was far and away the worst meme of 2017.
I will admit that the Savage Patrick source image is at least funnier and less annoying than Chicken SpongeBob.
But other than that, this meme pretty much falls flat on its face.
This type of meme is nothing new.
It's the latest installment of relatable emotions portrayed by SpongeBob.
All these memes suffer from the same issue.
They're more shallow than a tub of Burger King foot lettuce.
Savage Patrick is a meme so basic that you could replace it with a single emoji and it won't make a bit of difference.
This is a meme that only works as a one-off joke applied to a specific situation.
It's simply not built to be spammed into oblivion.
It's the same punchline every time, and just changing the wind-up doesn't make it funny.
As a matter of fact, it makes it less funny each time you see it.
It has no substance, no room for iteration, and it's not even the best picture of Patrick for the joke.
To me, that makes this meme dead in the water.