Only in Russia
Hello ladies and gentlemen welcome to the right opinion the home of a twat with too much free time and today we talk about Russia
The delightful place in which all men are free unless you're a gay or a Pokemon player in a church
Then you're fucked
But the point still stands Russia is a country where you can do some pretty crazy shit
And what better way to exploit that spirit than by starting up your own real hunger games
I know it sounds too good to be true
But I can tell you that in Siberia they will be indulging themselves in just that before having it broadcast on Russian television
Now so you may thinking what are the hunger games?
Well for those who've been living under a rock and because I don't have the patience to spell it out
I'm passing it over to my good friend and editor youtuber to explain it all in 60 seconds. Take it away
The Hunger Games is a poorly put together knockoff of a Japanese movie called Battle Royale and a novella called the lottery and it takes place
In a world in which our universe has collided with that of the spy kids 3d universe now long story short the people of white
North Korea are starving and poor that is except of course for some people who live in a place called the capital who for some
Reason like to watch poor children butcher each other in some kind of Truman show style
gladiatorial event known as the Hunger Games because why the fuck not
So anyway once a year some sort of circus clown comes to town and draws the name of children out of a fishbowl or something
Those children then have to go and fight for survival in the Hunger Games for some reason
But not before a poorly green-screen ceremony announced by some sort of creepy human cartoon hybrid monster
The type of which is born out of my nightmares to sum it all up
It's a terrible movie about kids killing each other for sport as old men watch it on the telly
The plot is fucking ridiculous in all honesty
The series is so directionless and ex machina that even though I've read all the fucking books and watched all the fucking movies
I had to Google the fucking point. It's a Frankenstein monster of plagiarism and the characters are cliche. Don't watch this movie
Don't read the books. I give the Hunger Games three inches out of eight
Thank you very much youtuber and his link will be in the description below very talented guy got the gist good
If not, watch it again. I'm not virtue enough to sit down here and have a lesson on the history onyx of such fiction
I'm sure many of you are thinking to yourself
But how will they get away with committing such crimes?
The truth is they won't in fact all laws of the Russian Federation applied during the Hunger Games
It's just you can go to jail and know that once you get out on parole in 70 years
You'll be able to live the last few in tranquility
Also, if something goes wrong, you can hit the panic button to be rescued. So they've changed that bit slightly
I'm sure to everyone's disappointment. So for example rape it's completely allowed, but it's also illegal
So basically it's just a way to absolve the organizers of any responsibility
Also, I have a few questions. So for example, if they're being raped and they hit the panic button what happens?
I mean any threat at all like fucking fighting a buddy Siberian bear
I mean, I know Russians aren't really ones for cowardice, but still it's not very logical
Basically they wanted to be as edgy as possible
But they had social norms to adhere to which led to this very icky premise of something
That's either going to be terribly disappointing or terribly immoral
So people are saying this and they'll probably enjoy it especially Russians
I feel like I should be angry at this and I actually am it's inherently immoral almost insane and things that are a lot less
Important have pissed me off in the past and probably will in the future
But my thoughts are if people are actually willing to sign up to do it
Then it's their funeral
literally natural selection in
Perfect function if Russia are gonna be mad enough to host something like this and people are gonna be mad enough to
Participate in something like this with the risk of dying or going to jail anyway with the very distant prospect of winning money
Then they can fucking do it
But knowing everything it will be reserved Lee quiet because I'm a miserable cynical cunt and everything's disappointing these days
Whether that's a good thing though in this context or a bad thing can be left for you to decide for all I know
Maybe mr. Putin will pardon them. Maybe he has some sympathies for the Hunger Games
We'll have to see I'm the right opinion and only in Russia