Hey guys a few things of note before we start this video one is that I apologize
but I was quite sick yesterday and it kind of comes off in the recording
two is that Arsh is sick which is why he didn't show up hey at least I did
and three is that there's a whole bunch of outtakes that can be found on the side channel
Devonatized and also linked at the end of the video so make sure to check those out
enjoy the garbage fest that is Lord of the Rings the rings of power
I know you had covid how's that doing Lilith?
I still feel a little bit sick my throat's a little bit out but
imagine catching covid at this stage embarrassing this would be like my my like fourth time having it
that's brutal you go outside just like a lot I'm kind of jeez I gotta I gotta mute kids here
what the fuck is it is playing audio for you guys yes what the fuck how
it should even be started I think it's just hold on I'm just gonna yeah yeah
Kibs you never understand you never do the audio correctly it always fucks up it's them like this
is the menu right it's them look at that little mute symbol right there muted I feel like they
autoplay the episode to try to make you an interested like they're that desperate also
it's dropped a 3.0 now yeah you know what I think's going on with it man I think like there's
some kind of weird player issue where the where the video is like behind the page still playing
did you get that in some in bed sites where like maybe that's how they get uh our view count
really I mean how else exactly come as a view well one thing I have been noticing is that even
the normies are starting to figure this out those low reviews they just aren't going away
you know they're growing a little bit I have a message for you on behalf of one of our mutual
subscribers he works as a packaging company he told me that um in his packaging place the
amazon stickers and stuff actually arrived a couple months before the launch and most of
the warehouse stuff and they were basically just sort of sitting there and then they finally got
around to using it so they were already pre-planning the uh putting the stickers on
everything yeah and actually speaking of that as well so I have a viewer who's in Montreal
and who sent me basically a giant advertisement that's taking over one of the main
subway stations in Montreal for this show they just like plastered it on the ground they
plastered it on the walls and it's just like please watch so this is like apparently fucking
everywhere right now oh my god there's a there's a payphone still in this station Jesus I feel like
I'm in the 90s again the advertisements get even wackier because for example if you own a
legal copy of photoshop and you were to open it up right now you're gonna get artwork as
a splash screen of lord of the rings as your loading page an adobe deal huh too yep so now
I haven't seen this because I don't have my copy of photoshop legally but if you happen to have
fuck adobe what's going on is adobe has made this big deal with lord of the rings they're
just putting a bunch of lord of the rings shit into the app that you paid for because fuck you
and in fact people have been complaining about it because this guy's like this is revolting I pay
monthly for photoshop and now I'm forced to see an ad for the amazon rings of power series every
time I open it this is a disservice to the to the consumer what is the next step having to see a 30
second ad to save a file it's like fair enough you know I don't want this to be the way that apps
go in the future it's one thing to run ads cyberpunk future oh god you know it's one thing
to run ads on a youtube video it's another thing on an application that you just have on your
computer right and it has been slowly coming out that amazon is offering youtubers big stacks of
money to just blanket praise the show now I haven't gotten my stack yet
suddenly it's a great show yeah so for example this came out with um hello future me
he was given an email from amazon to promote rings of power on his channel he asked amazon
hey can I review it honestly and not just simply praise you and they ghosted him so they are
looking for people who will just say the show is good and will give you a bunch of bezos bucks
this story with hello future me that was reported on bounding into comics so that's something that
everything knows but I have for you a dev exclusive I'm in contact with a youtuber a
friend of mine who is way bigger than all of us way bigger than sargon this friend of mine came
to me in private and showed me an email there is a lord of the rings phone game for this show
that I haven't heard of at all but as part of the promo deal he was offered to do some kind
of promotional tie-in for the phone game as part of the show's advertising project
and he was offered for one change of his profile picture on all of his social media
and two retweets oh that is a lot of money that's wild yeah apparently everyone who has like
millions of subs on youtube they're just getting scattershotted these emails hoping that someone's
gonna bite um well they're probably like from an advertising agency that amazon's contracted you
know gave him a budget said just go pay off these guys to do this like that's pretty common you know
i've i've received from a dozen different companies all offers to do a promo for raid
shadow legends you know it's just big enough yeah i am but i never answer them actually actually
a funny thing my editor keeps saying dev can you please look at the promo folder
just look at some of these we need some money i'm just like i will not compromise my ideals
here's a man of principles are you trying to flex on arch stop that
well here's the thing like i'm not against the idea of doing an ad if it's something i was
already gonna say it's like say the show is good it's like well if i think it is sure
yeah i'm not gonna get bought i'm not gonna be bought though you know it's pretty problematic
too for you because people rely on you to like express yourself honestly and if you compromise
that then people have less reason to listen to you in the future yep yeah for your irreversibly
damaging your uh portfolio yeah you know reputation i would basically only do something if i believed
in it so for example i actually do like hello fresh as a product so i wouldn't mind doing a
hello fresh ad but like i'm not gonna do something unless i unless i don't already believe in it
that's the dev way i guess so wait so in regards to raid shadow legends wouldn't you try it
to find out if you like it what if you like it what if you love it oh god don't make me play
raid shadow legends listen dev come on i hear from arcs all the time it's not get bad cubes
but he always says that on youtube when we're live he always says it when he has a big check
dangling in front of him he's like you know this raid shadow is pretty good actually probably does
feel good when you get a few thousand bucks doesn't it but all right there's lots of advertising
money flying around for this show and absolutely none of it is going to us so let's get it on the
road kibs that's let's watch episode six what's it called uh hold on it is called the phantom
penis the phantom well it was a good guess but it's called undoon which might mean phantom
penis in uh orcish or whatever listen lillith we spent 30 minutes talking about trans stuff before
the call started we can't keep going we can't do it udun let's roll now watch this ah crap
skip the intro basically nice thank you okay it came pre-skipped amazon really does know what we
want it wait hold on it's it was this far along because this is when i stopped it by closing and
opening the window again so it was playing in the background holy shit my theory was correct
they're all fake views that's what it is if you open the page you get it you give them a view
just by opening it even if you don't watch it oh my fucking god i can't believe it yeah
i don't know if that's been proven but we just proved it now listen if you're a conspiracy
theorist that means that you're a fascist according to some kids so you can't promote
these ideas you're gonna get fact checked you get debunked well well it happens sometimes
there's dirty fingies those are his cocaine fingernails probably nice nails oh god have you
seen that picture of princess leia's actress with the cocaine fingernail in the movies look she
likes to play hard i'd like that's why it's liked oh my god the orcs are revolting oh my god wait
pause the video kibs okay i just realized we didn't actually address why ark isn't here
ark sorry yes arch we we didn't we didn't even we forgot
whoops oh my god we talked about it literally before the stream or the recording so
oops yeah oh god i'm sorry guys yeah so i have the coof and lillith has the coof and arch has
the coof but the two of us we have the metal to actually show up and arch is sleeping it off
he's weak to be fair i'm so fucking brain fogged i'm so brain fogged right now that like i didn't
even think to fucking oh my god i didn't even think to tell you guys that arch isn't here i'm
sorry arch isn't here i'm sure he'll be back next week with apologies and chocolates he'll
never apologize but you can you can hope i guess god damn it well we watched the entire episode
with him just to torture yeah no we didn't record it all right let's go let's see let's
see the trial that awaits us they got a fat one this is what liberals look like
dude they ruined it with more wokeness dude that guy was like oh shit i probably chose
the wrong team and the bad guy are we the baddies
they looked like it i don't know they look pretty trustworthy to me
they're brave beautiful stunning immigrants okay they've come here looking for a new life
you ever look at those like portland and teeth and look shots it's just these guys oh god it is yeah
taftas are you gonna start like skull measuring soon is the skull measuring arc
yeah exactly and they're gone are they gonna sneak attack first strike bonus
wait is this plan just to like okay solo them oh the tower's gonna collapse
okay wait whoa whoa whoa that seems like a bit okay
i don't get this
and trap them in there yep wait what happened to the horde of orcs coming up
they all went in i guess
i guess so
oh
jesus now how'd they get over there and they have oh i have a problem with that
those lights could be seen for miles yep
we have to make ready the village
wait the the far less defensible village the castle was yeah i was gonna say that narrow
pass they would never be able to breach if they barricaded it not in a reasonable time span
that's what i was gonna say they seem a bit close to the army yeah just a pinch
all right so we just saw the the anti-helms deep all right
god jesus
where's his liver that's a waste at least give it to the horde all right
you know i don't like the whole wearing plate armor in the deck of a ship thing
like that that's something you put on once you're getting ready to to leave the ship
because you're not you can't swim in that shit uh yeah you're right you just sink instantly yeah
i just noticed her hair when braided is the same length as her hair when not braided
you think she uses extensions in the show i mean from what i understand of women's hair that's not
really that possible i've seen the only braided hair a whole bunch of times it always gets
shorter it doesn't get that much shorter though yes it depends on how big your braids are yomi
has a lot of hair and it does get noticeably shorter it's like down to her butt at this point
oh but the kid's gonna know he's gonna follow him
i think that's good protection okay just that'll stop him
all who cannot fight will be barricaded inside this is to be our peace our fallback point
okay take off all of you the wooden thatch building that's flammable is
the final step i don't know i don't know about this one
isn't this a quote from the main movies uh kind of sounds like it in fact it's trying to imitate
it i'm pretty sure but i don't think they've ever said that movies there was even something similar
in the previous episode when elrond was was getting his own pep talk they are trying to
imitate the uh the original peter jackson movies though and this whole sequence does feel like that
mandalorian episode now which one the one where um mando and kara dune are basically teaching the
villagers how to fight because they're going to get invaded and they're setting up traps and
they're like learning it's a trope that's used in a lot of movies where the villagers have to defend
home and there's the one warrior that knows what he's doing yep they're like a bit short notice
like they were just right there next to like the orcs that kind of work and they escaped with
enough time to do this best part is this little village is like right below the castle so you
think the orcs would be like looking like hey wait a minute he wants to plant some
oh they finally kissed that actress is really pretty i don't blame him
look at how tiny that village looks but holy smokes it's like three buildings
there's like 40 people that live in them it's like if you're playing an old rpg in the super
nintendo it's like this is a big town and there's like five buildings oh god
i ate a bunch of spicy ramen before we started just to try and keep my sinuses open and now
they're starting to close again definitely a good move like you guys had a full day you could have
just ran and with the sick of the elderly like i'll give them that they probably wouldn't have
gotten far yeah but they can only travel at night their enemies that's true that doesn't give them a
advantage yeah 16 hours versus eight and you open move to an open field and cross the planes
like what are they gonna do is that their battering ram
oh jesus rip
the hammering sickle always wins
well if you had the same idea
boom oh did they just like
oh it's like oops laugh track
hahaha
jesus look at that grandma shield maiden going
oh yeah if archer here he's tearing that apart listen old lady's still got some spirit
just eats him
wait when did the elves learn kung fu uh when they need them to
get started in the hobbit just got worse
jesus that's a bit much
gooey's gonna get his mouth let's not kiss this time that's uh
it all happened off screen they've actually won yes
that's how you save on budget
okay i picked the wrong side i mean they're still bad guys like they betrayed them yeah
why are all the betrayers black or brown what what is this show trying to say
okay here we go gingers are also a minority oh shit
knew that victory was too easy yeah it's time to go inside guys
oh there goes the girlfriend
key to the key to the tavern tavern yes let's all huddle up inside a wooden building that the
enemy could just burn down very easily i have a feeling the uh newman orange will show up just
in the nick of time very nice of the orcs to just let them do this give them the breathing room
um-hmm that blood's coming up fast by the way yeah yeah
the wake up mother
oh my god so is she just holding her breath i guess
i just wanted to see how long i could hold my breath it works up in mighty quiet
while they were doing the entire thing no they're it's a turn-based game they're waiting their turn
hey we're here so that they came to save this village i guess
apparently they knew this specific village is under attack too yeah
you can only just stand there and wait for it yeah yeah at this point
so
so i guess archer's theory that there's a time skip was wrong
yep which makes the story a lot dumber let me guess they gave they did that just so the bad
guy could get the weapon so i can get away with the weapon to be a problem later oh god
you know
the action's actually not bad yeah we're actually there yeah it's actually a lot more entertaining
than the horror footage i'll give them that i don't think we're seeing them this episode
i think the focus he has on the this storyline yeah which i kind of prefer to be honest with you
so where an entire squad of elves fell to this guy gladiel's just gonna do it
yeah she's she's got girl power
oh shit she used the speed buff she popped it you know i will say this for this show
they're clearly like going out into the woods and shooting this there
it's not just cg nonsense it's like all right good
they're putting on the afro problem is it's just only did the same thing for the writing
wait how do you get ahead that's an excellent question
we still have to find out his lore
i need him yeah end his neck
straight down it is
unsatisfies it by drinking semen
preferred pronouns so wait is the implication here is that he's
with the what the urakai came from that's what they're trying to say yeah probably
you know i don't think that's how that works because the orcs are elves those are the ones
that were taken by yeah they're like corrupted elves they were dragged down to the earth that's
why they pulled them out of the mud creations of the one master of the secret fire the same as you
is worthy of the breath of life and just as worthy of a home oh my god the orcs aren't bad guys now
the framing is so reactionary
it's clearly they're not worthy of the same like dignity
so the story implication is that like some people are just unequal
and it's wrong to believe this yeah because like the villain here is saying we're all equal
everyone's the same he's a socialist show gonna be like no actually people aren't equal
well here's the thing teftash if you're a maggot shud for example then you're not equal
oh the orcs the orcs the orcs are trump supporters
they deserve to be banned from twitter immediately
oh my god so true and the good and the beautiful are people like galadriel who vote with her
perhaps they really have no reason to keep them alive no if i could just hold on to that feeling
keep it with me don't stop believing
what they're gonna bang alpha c kibs what what the heck
they really are just adding whatever they want i guess romance of galadriel okay
bit strange but all right look that's the power of himbo okay halbrand played by hasan piker
you know most of the town is dead half of them joined the enemy and a bunch of them died like
party party dev this town is uh gonna be a bit scarred you might say
get over really quickly okay
actually most of them are dead girl bosses girl bosses look at underneath her armpit
she's wearing the t-shirt wait they're not just gonna keep it here are they
yeah wouldn't it want to return it to like a more secure place the front line i'll be fine
you must not accept the dark side yes that that was what sam that was what sam said to frodo
oh is it like literally the same words yeah i i just watched it like a little bit ago
was it resist the ring of sword power yeah they're doing the same thing like they're
gonna use the sword like the ring the same trope just say precious do it oh wait hold on
oh my oh wait you got away with it anyways
yeah i'm not sure that the the various sauron artifacts had the same pull as the one ring did
yeah they're leaning in on trying to copy it too much
uh wait a minute it's just the key to the dam
the message of the story is that infrastructure is evil
it's cursed dams this is what hydropower does
this is what happens if you raise taxes and build a dam guys
they want to move away from coal saron's work he's all about green energy
so
oh it's coming through all the tunnels first
it's all part of their plan they dug this thing
so wait what where's okay
oh they're making obsidian
no minecraft reference no yeah no they're trying to get another i have many questions
and how they knew how to do this and how that works
and so now that wait what the orcs are free now
oh jesus okay that doesn't happen in minecraft
poor villagers take catch a break wait take shelter they're all on fire take take shelter
and all the buildings that are on fire yes and all the buildings that are all made out of straw
oh wait is this how it becomes the black lands
probably but it feels a bit weird that this is the reason why
no you know what they're doing they're making mount doom that's what they did
it's the origin story
mount doom didn't exist it had like we had to show it being created yep
she's dead
oh so the other guy escaped how did he escape how does everyone just escape all the time
oh my fucking god all right another episode of the greatest television series okay
the world's beginning to disagree with that sentiment they're a bunch of
liars
they're all gonna die from like the the just the ash alone like they're waiting for the volcano
okay or just that that is a big enough eruption that it's going to cause like a nuclear winter
on the planet the next few years no crops yeah it's gonna be pretty bad so um i'm curious as
to how they're gonna roll this off and like the next episode we'll have like some ash land and
then they'll be like oh it's all better now okay so i just wanna i just wanna see if we can parse
this so somehow the old man who he must be dead that guy like he's fucked he gets a hold of the
key and he opens the dam not knowing what it does but he opens the dam and they just they they built
not bad yeah he's like oh he's like oh shit what did i do he's like an idiot okay so he opens the
dam and the water floods down and but then they built these canals and they just knew to do this
i guess they had it all this is all part of their plan this is a big plan to use the water to ignite
the magma because that would guaranteeably cause mount doom to explode that seems a bit contrived
i'm not gonna lie yeah okay so i i know it's a thing in warhammer for example there's a
bunch of tunnels underground that go deep and deep and deep and there's a bunch of things
that happen down in the tunnels but i don't think that if you were to dig deep enough
you would find a giant hole that's like huge several kilometers just a big cave
down to the center of the earth where all the lava hangs out like i don't think that's how that works
um you generally you should take geology class dub because i think it's perfectly accurate
because uh there's always gonna be a lava a giant lava cape yeah yeah a lava but not necessarily
okay and it funnels it up perfectly so it explodes outwards and basically creates a bomb
you see the water yeah the water was basically a chain reaction don't ask me how but it basically
caused it to boom boom yeah let me okay so that part i could actually see because like i've seen
um you know how lava reacts by having water poured on it really quickly or like the inverse
it gets violent yeah it erupts so i've seen stuff like that yeah like if you if you because
the the heat wants to rise and so it goes through the cold and like pressurizes upwards so
i get that i just don't buy there's a giant fucking cave down there well i feel like the
more realistic thing to happen would be like the cave collapsing in on itself yeah if it's not like
yeah but like i get why they wouldn't show that because it would it wouldn't look good
if it was just like a tube it's a lot more impressive to show like a giant cave
mm-hmm and also like i think there was lightning in in the eruption like where did the lightning
come from from the evil from the feels wrong but i feel like there's gonna be some geology
nerd who's like um actually that makes perfect sense yes so this episode went from like kind
of ridiculous start with some of the fighting but then like the main bulk of the action was actually
like half decent and then it was like what it just spun off into ridiculousness right in the
last five minutes where it's just like oh a lot cooler things could have happened rather than like
the explosions in the water like what if it unleashed like some like ancient evil beast
and that's terrorizing them maybe that would be that would be cool that'd be quite this
spectacle and i feel like it would make more sense because you could just like lock it behind doors
and then it would like awaken with the ancient magics also i don't like this trend where we have
to show where like fucking everything comes from we don't need to know where mount dune comes from
oh fuck solo don't remind me it's like we have to have origin stories for everything like this
is why it's ashen like dude sometimes maybe the land is just that way because of the positioning
well especially with lord of the rings right one of the amazing things that toki did was like he
knew when to have mystery in the stories i went to let your imagination fill in the gaps so i
hope we don't go down the path of explaining every little thing the note we gotta it's gotta all be
rationalistically explained nothing can just be for flair anymore well i think it works for some
stories but i think that other times it can just be like a cheap way of sort of drawing connections
between yourself and the previous source material in a way that ends up like cheapening outwards
the source material i mean like midichlorians is like the perfect old school example of this
because there is so much like mysticism and interest and intrigue in the forest and that
was kind of stripped away and that sucks because that mysticism was like a very
i think it was a core part of what made the force so cool and to kind of remove that sucked
yeah yeah i agree and the same thing with mordor here like we're seeing how mordor was formed but
i don't i i think it might even make it less interesting to know that oh it turns out that
it was foreign because an idiot opened the gate to a dam and then the water rushed in and caused
a volcanic eruption that that is a lot less interesting than you know it's it's the land
of the dark lord what like what is what does he even have the motivation to do that at the end
like you know your bosses are like defeated bro like why are you still working for him
i guess in for penny in for buck i guess i mean maybe killed a teenager so but he also seemed
stupid like he was kind of not necessarily possessed in the same way as the ring by the
sword but he it seems like he had some kind of compulsion maybe because there was that earlier
scene where he's talking to the kid and he's like no sauron is kid he's kind of acting like a crack
dealer so maybe maybe it's like a yeah he's like schizophrenic for sauron when he talked about
orcs he talked about the fact that uh yeah i remember he was lamenting about the sun how he
was gonna have to blot it out so this is this is him doing that because yeah oh yeah yeah yeah
that was a couple episodes ago but i do remember that i mean that's kind of a cool connection then
i kind of want to see like i want to see a prequel to this prequel literally called
schizo for sauron and it's like a romance between sauron and like him when he was younger
yeah i was just totally in his head
jesus oh my god and it's framed like a romantic comedy
oh sauron oh you i wonder what arch is going to say about this when he sees it
oh he's gonna be he's gonna be fucking enraged i think
oh god the the spicy is the spicy noodles have fully worn off i think i i think i need to get
to bed before before i like fully descend into madness you i'm sure you've all seen a game of
thrones and how there was that usually there's like that one big episode where they they cut
all the side stories and they focus on one arc so they did like battle of the black water where
it was just that fight or they did the battle at um at the wall where it was just the wildlings
attacking castle black and i think they really wanted this to feel like that like they were just
doing one thing today and it's going to be this fight and that's it and they were kind of really
trying to do it to do that kind of thing but it just felt sort of cheap yeah i'm not exactly sure
why i think it's because we just don't have the same one location but well the same connection
to the characters yeah that's what it is yeah there's no connection to the characters and i
don't care about any of them with the exception of maybe the villain who seems he's kind of
interesting even if it breaks lore conventions still with with the urakai but fine he's at least
he has at least has a character the urakai urakai are the thing saruman made he's an uruk
yeah he's at the precursor right if you they're claiming that he's like the first or part of the
first urics that they were that close but which is weird because from my understanding of the lore
is that the urics all came out like the orcs we know because they were but they're all that
corrupted and warped and twisted they weren't really elven looking anymore well maybe he's
a work in progress you know they didn't finish him you know at least there was no harfoots
that's true the next episode will be 100 harfoots that's also just as a horror
just to make up for it how many how many episodes left so there's eight right so there's two more
to go in this season and there's five seasons god help us all this this seems to be like too
early an episode for a giant climax like this yeah i agree i think this is like the fake-out
episode because there's gonna be like another episode because now now the war is gonna have
to escalate because now the orcs have the power of darkness on their side so like the good guys
are gonna be on the back foot next episode is what i had to guess yeah these guys because then
they're gonna have to retreat and they're going to go back and get like a bigger army and then form
the uh recall because this is gonna lead to the last alliance of men and elves which is that big
battle at the beginning of fellowship of the ring the elves and men uh basically are fighting you
know saron mordor this is all leading up to that point so i don't know where we are on the timeline
before that but isildur is here so i don't know yeah maybe that's the plan but isildur is middle
aged still has to like have his balls drop a bit more yeah he's gotta he's gotta become more of a
leader and he hasn't really gone through a leadership arc well to be fair he does end up
like not destroying the ring so maybe he could just be a be not a leader right up to the end
i guess that's the thing about an episode like this is there's actually not much to talk about
you know it wasn't they weren't jumping around between different scenes and we couldn't like oh
well here's what happened with elrond and like it really was just one scene and the battle happened
and then the ridiculous eruption happened and it's like okay then so sorry to disappoint everyone
but i guess i guess that's the end of the episode i mean don't worry we're just as disappointed as
you that's what it is but hey there's always next week there's always hopefully arch will be here
that time