Hello my friends, this is another one of those thinking videos where
I just kind of mull over an idea with minimal sources because this is mostly
my own thoughts in the subject, my own musings
and what we're talking about. And today we're talking about the birth control
pill and my theory that birth control probably
caused third wave feminism and social justice and all of the
modern radical left BS we seem to be seeing today.
Now this is an idea that I might have spoken about on one of Sargon's streams
like a year ago and as soon as I brought it up he
laughed and thought it was kind of a funny idea but then he asked me to
unpack it to explain myself so I just didn't sound like some kind of
some kind of lunatic and I did and I think I did an okay job of doing it.
I don't remember the stream it's probably going to be hard to find
honestly at this point but I have been thinking about the theory on and off and
I think I have it a bit more refined. We figured out that from a biological
perspective the type of man that a woman finds
attractive does change somewhat depending on her fertility cycle.
So when a woman is more fertile she finds more masculine men attractive and
when a woman is less fertile she finds less masculine men
attractive. There was even a study done I hope I can
find it and splice it into the video where women judged their attractiveness
to various men based only on the width of the jaw so it
was like a picture where only you only saw how wide the man's jaw was
and the jaw width they preferred actually changed depending on what time
of the month it was. Now there's going to be a lot of red
pill types out there who talk about how this is
an obvious example of why all women are cheaters and it is in their biological
nature to be inherently unfaithful and how they're
always going to look for the alpha male to have sex with while
she's fertile and then try to find a beta male to
actually raise the kids. And maybe there's some biological truth
to that but I'm more inclined to believe that
shitty women who cheat will use that as a justification
and shitty men who cheat will use a very similar justification
you know the whole sowing your wild oats stuff.
Regardless of the biology we're still intelligent rational creatures
we're still in control of what we choose to do and we still have a
responsibility to those choices that we make
but from what I understand the birth control pill basically
freezes a woman's fertility cycle in that period where she's
not fertile so therefore she always finds the beta male attractive
and in fact there's been multiple cases where a woman who was consistently on
birth control for many years starts dating a guy and after she
decides to go off birth control so they can have children or whatever
she no longer finds him attractive she says he's not manly enough he's not
virile enough is it pronounced virile I don't know but this sort of thing
happens often I'm not saying it happens to all women I'm not even saying that it
happens reliably but it happens reliably enough that
statisticians and and sociologists and stuff have have taken notice.
So on the one hand you could take a purely biological deterministic approach
to this and believe that more beta males are
reproducing therefore the children that they're creating are also more beta than
they would have been maybe that's the case
but there's also the fact that the pill has given women control of when
and how many kids they have rather than having eight or ten throughout their
20s they're having one or two when they're
30 or 35 or 38 and yeah there's obvious problems with
that you know the the rates of deformity and various diseases and disorders you
know they all go up when you have a pregnancy in your 30s
instead of your 20s I think we all know that at this point
but even if the children are healthy you've also kind of put all your eggs in
one basket you know if you have eight kids throughout your 20s
you're not really raising them anymore they're they're raising each other
you don't have enough energy to to raise all them all the time
you do what you can then you rely on the older kids to help out the younger kids
I'm not saying it's necessarily fair to those older kids in fact it's probably
quite unfair but that is what necessity requires
but genetically you haven't put all your eggs in one basket
and the cold hard truth of it is some of those kids could die and the family
unit would still be intact I'm not saying it wouldn't it wouldn't
ruin you it obviously would no one wants to see their kids dead but
it's not the same as having one child and having that child die at
that point the family's gone the the future lineage no longer exists
but if you have eight kids and one of them dies that's a terrible tragedy
but the other seven will you know more or less grow up and
have their own kids and in a few generations things will be roughly back
to normal it sounds harsh and maybe it is harsh
the world's a harsh place I'm not saying that I don't have
feelings for these mothers who have lost children
but when you when you only have a few kids at the end of your
reliably fertile period you have really put all your eggs in one basket
there are some advantages to that you know you can devote more resources to
them maybe maybe with your eight kids some
kids are going hungry more than they should
something like that maybe you can afford to send them to a better school maybe
the family christmas is a bit more of a cheerier time because there's more gifts
to be to be passed around but at the same time you have every
incentive to helicopter parent if you only have one or two kids you
have every incentive to to really I don't know overbear on them and
really try to ensure that everything goes perfectly for them
and that's why you see the rise of things like parents who get really
gung-ho about their kids baseball or football careers you know
whatever career it is when they're nine years old playing with other kids or
like playing in a local league or something you know they get they get
really into it well because they can kind of afford to do that they
have the resources to do that and they have the
the mindset to do that it's why you see parents complaining to the teacher
rather than their kids when their kids start failing at school
because of this helicoptering overprotective
this is my one chance so I better make this kid count kind of mentality
and you know over the course of 20 years or 25 years or 30 years
this this movement has been like a wave through demographics it's gone through
preschool it's gone through primary school it's gone through high school
and now it's in the universities and the universities um to their discredit they
should have put their foot down they should have said no no your kids are 18
when they're coming here they're adults now
you no longer get to helicopter parent them you no longer get to baby them
you no longer get to email professors and harass them because your kid failed
their class you no longer get to have safe spaces
when you come on campus because hey this is a place of learning this is a
place of discussing at difficult topics but when enough people complain and
those people are paying money well that's the way things go so you end
up with a generation basically of simps there's no other way to put it they're
they're like a softened generation they're snowflakes that have have
tantrums and meltdowns and they're constantly triggered whenever something
that they don't personally like happens to
them or is said around them and now the workplace is having to adapt
to this stuff I bet HR departments are making a killing right now
but it really seems like this all kind of spawned from birth control in a sense
since it created a culture of parents who really only had
one shot to be a parent and they invested everything they had in making
that right and so now you have a generation of
people who have been who have been coddled
and catered to and who can't really grasp why things don't go their way
they view their own failings as society's personal attack on them
and oftentimes they'll turn to various totalitarian ideologies as adults
to try and fill in the gaps rather than simply taking responsibility for their
own failures and the generation I'm talking about
is my generation and I have to be honest um there was once a point where I was
like this too I had to really grow out of it in my
20s because it was holding me back in life
it would seem to me that women having control of their reproduction
was as big of a change at least demographically as the invention of the
computer was for technology or communication or as
the invention of the atom bomb was for war
birth control was that for human biology we have to ask some serious questions
that I'm sure feminists don't really want me to ask
what are women now to men from a strictly biological sense
I don't mean socially I mean we're still going to treat each other as if we are
the genders that we are but I mean biologically before men
had at least a basic understanding of what women were and that
basic understanding as terrible as it might sound to our modern sensibilities
was the person that you have sex with and create children with
but if they are not that anymore biologically
what what are they do we even know it's almost like humanity has become a
different species in a sense so many species are identified by their
reproductive patterns and we have radically changed ours using
our own technology we've changed what women are attracted to using our own
technology and in the human species women have
always been the sexual selector so what does that mean for us the helicopter
parenting culture was the impetus that caused every major
structure from school to the universities to the workplace to
value safety over personal freedom and if safety is the name of the game
well then you have all of these various oppressed minorities and groups all
jockeying for their own safe space all talking about how the heteronormative
capitalist patriarchy is oppressing them and needs to be done away with and
demanding other people's freedoms be curtailed in order to get the job done
in the name of safety and and you have to ask where has that left us
if the radical left's view of all hierarchies being corrupt
is just taken as a given fact at this point
what is the natural end result of that well that would mean that hierarchies
that are just don't exist and it's all just
power politics and that would mean that those people who have
traditional aspirations are also corrupt women like the tried wives we've talked
about before are simply gender traitors and men are
simply abusive patriarchs looking to take their place within that corrupt
hierarchy if you spend an entire generation
telling boys and girls this message and then you start to tailor both the
workplace and the school in this direction as well
you end up with a generation of dissatisfied women who can't seem to
find men that meet their standards and depressed men who don't know what
to do with their lives and judging by the former's complaints
and the latter's suicide rate it would seem like this is the case
but at the same time the whole idea doesn't really make any sense does it
because no feminist will ever complain when a woman takes on one of those
corrupt patriarchal roles you know you see a woman's ceo or you
see a woman superhero like captain marvel or something acting the way that
superman would it seems to be completely fine for a
woman to take on this corrupt role and become a patriarch herself
it's good for her to do it but but men can't do it it's an inherently
contradictory philosophy and i would say that it's because the
philosophy itself is not really meant to be understood
it's only meant to destroy things at the same time the left is correct on
some level about hierarchies in in ways that the
right wing generally can't accept conservatives like hierarchies and they
don't really seem to understand just how corrupt hierarchies can get if
you're not keeping a proper eye out sometimes the corruption the sjws
complain about actually does exist but their solution of destroying the
hierarchy itself doesn't help anyone it in fact makes the situation worse
people are on some level built to take their place
in a non-corrupt hierarchy because it ultimately isn't about being
in a hierarchy of stacked up people like a corporate hierarchy or something
it's more about the hierarchy of the individual what you value for your life
what you aim at what you aspire to be and if you take away that hierarchy you
can no longer rank order what you prefer and what you
don't prefer when you destroy the hierarchy you destroy
aspiration itself and without that there's no possibility of self-improvement
if there's no way to judge what possible future you is the better one
how could you possibly move into the future these same people radical
feminists social justice warriors they often overlap with the marxists who
talk about the dreaded one percent let's be honest here the one percent is
somebody who makes more than thirty two thousand u.s dollars a year i think
that's the number because most people in the world live in abject poverty and if
you make more than thirty two thousand u.s dollars a year
um you are making more money than 99 of people in the world
that seems to be the proper cutoff line for the dreaded one percent
so why is it that all of these people these people who can afford to go to
these universities these these sociology professors these these
gender studies professors and whatever else
all people who are making way more money than that usually unless you're going to
school on a loan and if you're going to school on a loan
for gender studies maybe you should rethink your life
but all of these people are already in the one percent all of these bougie
socialists and communists they actually just hate people who are
rich they don't care about poor people at all they just want to take out their
jealousy on those who have been more successful than they are
there's a joke that actually floats around academic circles at least it did
back when i was in school maybe maybe the HR department has snuffed it out
if you quadruple the pay of a university teacher all of this multicultural
indoctrination will disappear because what you have
right now are a bunch of people in academia
who are just hyper intelligent but really have nothing going for them
with the exception of their intelligence and so they are just pissed that people
who are working out in like the more capitalist spaces of society
make more money than them you might say that i've gone off topic from the whole
birth control thing maybe i have a little bit but i definitely think they're
connected i think what's happened is that we
haven't properly adapted to the invention of the birth control we
haven't changed our our viewpoints and even in some
senses our culture to properly deal with what birth control
means basically we've been using old rules for a fundamentally new game
and the end result of that has filtered down through everything
into academia into the media into the workplace
and this drive towards equality and safety
and away from personal freedom and liberty has come about
basically because we have become so successful
that we can afford to be soft in that manner at least in the short term
i think if this stuff doesn't stop it will destroy our society eventually
but in the short term we can afford to be
a little bit of a softened generation because we're no longer dealing with the
same problems that we were dealing with 100 years ago
coronavirus seems to be a pretty big deal but i highly doubt it's going to
turn into like the next black death it's very unlikely we're going to
actually see a world war 3 despite whatever has been going on with the
climate the possibility of a serious famine
seems to be rather low right now it almost seems
like our own ingenuity has solved so many problems
that now the stuff that we're collectively complaining about is
not being comfortable enough or being too offended on the internet
or somebody coming to university and saying something that you don't like
human beings are in a sense pack animals we need a load to lift if we're going to
feel any kind of meaning in our lives and since a lot of the larger problems
have been solved maybe maybe all we have left to do is
complain about small problems problems that frankly shouldn't even be
complained about due to the whole freedom and liberty thing
and i really do think that that part of that
cultural shift came about because of the impact of the birth control pill
what it did to reproduction and then what our reproduction did to the society
in which we live