Hey, I'm back. Yes, I was banned for a week. Yes, it was because of the dog pill video.
So all those plans to do the tubcast with Lilith on Kyle Rittenhouse, that pretty much went out
the window. I will still be making that content, but now it's a week late, unfortunately.
That is just how things go. But the one week ban is up, and I'm back.
There will be a weekly SIP tomorrow, there will be a Game Boomer stream tonight,
and I'll be back on the SFO content train next week. While I was gone, I did do a few things.
I got the Dev and Lilith channel set up. That will be the future home for the tubcast. It's
going to become like a weekly show. So make sure you're subbed to that channel.
I'm also probably going to be splitting off the daily 10 minute takes, the stuff that I do on
this channel, and the longer, more serious videos like the hour long essays. Those will probably be
going off onto their own channel called Devtrospective. And of course, somebody who
is not me has made the Devonatized channel, which is where you can find unmonetized re-uploads of
some of my content that just will not work out on the main channels. I do have to formally disavow
that channel. It is, after all, not mine. But if you're wondering where some of my backlog went,
it is probably up there for everyone to see. All of these channels will be listed in the
description of this video. Please consider subbing to them. And I'm back. I'll see you guys next time.
I love you.