Hello, my friends welcome to SJ weekly today, I'm only drinking ice water
Because it's actually quite warm out let's start with
tor.com's
problematic classics
For questions to ask when beloved books haven't aged well
Now we all know about the whole the whole huckleberry Finn situation, right?
Where because the the word might have some some racialized terms that are no longer considered polite to say
People want the book banned or or censored or rewritten
which is obviously ridiculous because it was written in the time that it was written and
That is what this article is all about
I recently decided to reread th whites legendary classic the once and future King at first
I was delighted by the exact book. I remembered but from my youth
Wart young King Arthur being taught by Merlin goofy King Pelennor sullen Kay a lot of ridiculous adventures with some
anti-war
anti-totalitarian commentary mixed in for good measure as
I continued I found some bits. I didn't remember I hadn't noticed the occasional asides about the base Indians
White says archery was a serious business once before it was turned over to Indians and boys
He talks about the destructive Indians who chased the settlers across the plains. I
Did not feel good about this
Well, I'm sure you didn't you know
Running into a word that may be considered racist today
But in the time the book was written was considered fine
Maybe maybe the changing nature of language is something that you will have to
You know come to grips with as an adult then I found the n-word. Oh, no
Granted it was used by a bird and an unhinged one at that in a rant where the hawk blames the administration the politicians
The Bolsheviks and so on for the state of the world
Another character rebukes him for his comments though not for using the word specifically
Later in the book Lancelot uses the same word to describe the Saracen Knight
Palomides I
Couldn't believe it not so much that the word was used but the fact that I didn't remember it. I
mean
You were a kid. You probably just brushed it off
You probably thought you had stumbled on something that was cool and adult or something, right?
And so you just kind of kept it to yourself
I was equally shocked that I didn't remember the denigrating comments about Native Americans
It left me feeling distressed about the book
I had been trying to convince my teenage daughters to read it had that been a mistake
Probably not, you know because
consider this consider this
you were presumably a teenager probably around the same age as your daughters when you read it and
You obviously grew up fine or at the very least you grew into the type of
Good obedient progressive that you want your daughters to be your exposure to the word Indian or the n-word
Clearly didn't change what you later became. So if your goal is to raise your teenage daughters into good obedient progressives
It's probably still gonna happen if they read this book most of us who love speculative fiction run into this problem at some point
There are classics of the genre that are uncomfortable for various reasons
Some of them are straight-out racist or unrepentantly misogynistic or homophobic or all of the above
How and why and when we come to these realizations can change depending on who we are
I'm guessing none of my african-american friends have come across the n-word in a novel and not noticed even as kids
so this is the biggest problem that I have with this article is that
It completely discounts the possibility
that these works of fiction are racist or
misogynistic or
Homophobic for a point maybe they are those things in order to show why they're wrong
maybe they are those things in order to be in support of
Progressive or or social justice politics and I'm gonna read between the lines here a little bit. This is why I think
Sjw's want to censor
Everything for example
We have this article here on PC gamer Nazi tattoos removed from survival game scum
Developer apologizes the developer and studios to the tattoos inclusion was a mistake
after an initial abrasive statement from a community manager now the point of the game is that
You I think you play as a convict or someone who is who is in jail somehow and if you don't know what the prison system
There are a lot of white supremacists in there
There are a lot of legit Nazis who are going to get tattoos of like the the swastika or 1488
Somewhere on their bodies. So to have a character that has Nazi tattoos on their bodies. It actually makes sense
This doesn't mean that the developer is in support of Nazi ideology
it means that the developer has created a character within the world that is in support of Nazi ideology and in this
Case, it would make sense that this character would exist, but they're even censoring that now if you have
say somebody who is
you know politically
unengaged or or uneducated or something and
They're confronted with
Two different points of view they they have like a Nazi on one side talking about the purity of the white race
And then they have an SJW on the other side and the SJW is like no we have to have
Complete equality for everyone no matter what and then let's say this uninformed idiot asked something like how come neo-nazis are bad
How come the white supremacists are a bad group? You could show them a game like scum with a
Shitty neo-nazi character in it show him what he acts like show him what he does and say
This is a neo-nazi. That is the point of art
Art does in some way reflect reality. It does have something to teach us about the real world
But when SJW's censor art that are even in their position
Art that would show their political opponents to be as bad as they are in real life
That means that SJW's are simply saying
You don't need to be taught why Nazis are bad
You simply need to believe me when I tell you that they are bad
And that's the problem with the Nazi tattoo being removed from the scum game
And if we go back here that is the problem with this
This four questions to ask when beloved books have an aged well article because the four questions in this article are is
This a work I can continue to recommend to others
well, just because it has
Slurs in it that you didn't notice before it doesn't degrade the quality of the work. In fact, that may be the point of it
But if you're an ideologue that is looking to indoctrinate people rather than teach them
You might not want them to read it question two. Is this a work I can continue to enjoy privately
The answer is honestly why not? This is where you get those people who?
have
kinks and and either engage in a certain type of sex or watch a certain type of porn and
Yet they feel like they shouldn't because it's problematic. Their kink is problematic. You know, you might have like a
Feminist woman who is extremely submissive in bed and she says I really like this but you know what?
I I feel like I can't do it because I have to be a strong independent woman who don't need no man
And that's that that's what this is
you can obviously enjoy something privately that you would not recommend to everyone else and
You don't even need to bring politics into that discussion to make that determination
Question three. Is there another work that doesn't have these problems but occupies the same space
this is where we get into the SJW tendency of
replacing and co-opting
pieces of art and and cannons
and whole industries frankly
You know, we saw this with Magic the Gathering we saw this with Vampire the Masquerade
We saw this with all sorts of tabletop
We saw this with Warhammer 40k. We see it with video games soon enough. You're probably gonna hear something like
Why would you play Doom eternal or cuphead when there are these?
SJW friendly alternatives in the same genre as those games and
Question four. Can I create a work that is a corrective to the problematic work? I love this is where you get
like the the Star Wars
Situation where SJW's come into Star Wars and just completely overwrite everything and destroy it
This is where you get the comics gate situation where SJW's roll into comics completely co-opt everything and destroy it
These questions are basically how can I prevent the spread of work?
that is problematic and
How can I?
Whitewash things to be in line with social justice and speaking of whitewashing the past
Here's an archived tweet from Vox. You can draw a straight line from John McCain to Donald Trump through Sarah Palin
This tweet was later deleted because it came just after John McCain had died, but it links to this article, which is still up
John McCain Sarah Palin and the rise of reality TV politics
McCain empowered a demagogue who put the Republican Party on them on the path to Donald Trump
The party of Donald Trump began almost ten years ago to the day when John McCain tapped Sarah Palin to join his ticket
It's one of the most important moments of McCain's career
He proved willing to empower a demagogue when he thought doing so would improve his political fortunes
Exactly the sin so many of his colleagues in the Republican Party have committed since Trump won their party's nomination and a lot of this
Is just a general recap of the stupidity of Sarah Palin in the 2008 elections
And I think we all know that at this point. However, what's interesting is that the article claims McCain
Sacrificed his values to win
McCain's campaign was in freefall at the end of August 2008
He needed a Hail Mary the author of this article flew to Alaska the day after Palin was tapped
He headed to the city's clerk office to pick up copies of meeting minutes from when she was mayor
I assumed the McCain campaign had done the same but no as I wrote at the time
I just got off the phone with a very helpful city clerk at the West Silla City Clerk's Office
Christie Smithers who was pulling some documents for me from when governor Sarah Palin was mayor
I told her I appreciated her help since I'm sure she's been bombarded with requests in the last few weeks
The clerk's office keeps all city council meeting agendas minutes legislation ordinances, etc
She chuckled then she told me that I'm the first person who has asked her office for anything
McCain was prepared to put Palin a heartbeat away from the presidency without even checking if she could do the job
Instead he picked her because she seemed like a good play to the base
Now this is a very interesting line of thought and let's remember it for later
Palin unleashed reality politics
McCain and Palin lost but after the election Palin stayed in the limelight for a time
She got a deal with Fox News and traveled the country
endorsing and stumping for Tea Party candidates
Schmidt who had pushed McCain to select Palin was depicted in the HBO version of the reported story of the 2008 campaign
Game change as racked with guilt for his role in the decision
This wasn't a campaign. It was a bad reality show he says
Palin herself went on to sign an actual deal for a reality TV show and here's where we get back to Vox's tweet
you can draw a straight line from John McCain to Donald Trump through Sarah Palin and
Vox is right
but not for the reason that they outline in this article in this article Vox makes the claim that
John McCain legitimized Sarah Palin and Sarah Palin was basically just a doofy
Made-up version of a reality TV star and
Then her popularity allowed for an actual reality TV star Donald Trump to take the presidency
That's not necessarily how it happened though because I am old enough to remember the 2008 elections with
with a lot of clarity I remember
very clearly I
Remember John McCain that that whole very famous exchange where he was with a?
Woman at a rally and she she's exclaimed
I believe Obama's an Arab and what she meant by that was was a Muslim and and potentially a supporter of
Radical Islam and McCain stole the microphone away and said no ma'am
He's an honest family man that I have
significant disagreements with on the issues
But John McCain outright said that if Obama were to win
he would not believe that Obama would take the country down the path of of
Radical Islamist treason or something he just said that he disagreed with his politics
But that he was ultimately a good guy and really that seemed to be the turning point of the election because Obama's
Popularity had had had become so huge so great and the Republican base had seemed to go off the rails
So much that when McCain had to step in and defend Obama from his own base
It was it was done the election was over at that point, and that was the turning point however
it was still the right thing to do it was still the honorable thing to do and
Despite that the media still absolutely destroyed John McCain
I remember this very clearly he was he was tired and feathered. He was slandered the far-left called him a
Nazi and a tyrant and you know all the things that they called Donald Trump today
Basically even as John McCain was acting reasonably and honorably
The left took a giant shit on him, and then the same thing happened with Romney
Romney acted very civilly even though he had obvious disagreements with Obama and
The left still tired and feathered him like he was some kind of Satan spawn
And he lost so when the third time comes around and Donald Trump is is now the Republican candidate
He just said fuck it. I'm gonna get tired and feathered anyway
So how about I do something that is worth being tired and feathered for and that's why we have Donald Trump as president because I
Think everyone clued in over the course of the early 2000s everyone clued in to what the media does
To right-wing candidates whether or not they deserve it
They'll just completely shit on them act like that the Democrats have some kind of
Inherent moral high ground which they don't and no matter how reasonable the person on the right acts
They still just get a smear job ran against them. It just seems to be how it is and that's why we have Trump
That's the line that you can draw between John McCain and Trump Vox. It doesn't go through Sarah Palin
It it goes through the the left-wing bias of the media that has existed
Since the Bush years frankly and if you want an example of that left-wing media bias
Let's read this article
immigrants don't need to integrate you do oh
There's no such thing as integration for immigrants and their descendants
Growing up in rural Britain Wales to be precise. I was the poster child for immigration. My teachers liked me
I was a prefect I captained my team. I won ribbons on sports day attended high grades and did after-school activities
I did everything they tell young brown kids to do
It never occurred to me that I was the only one who considered myself just like everyone else. I'm sure that's not the case
Once I was far enough away several years later somewhere between Cairo and Gaza after a Facebook exchange with an old classmate
Who told me that he knows I'm a good person
So I don't need to apologize for whatever it was that some Muslim had done a file opened in the back of my mind
For months it began to fill with memories I'd shrugged off poo-pooed or not given a second thought to at the time
like when I was 19 lying on a trolley in a hotel conference room in central Durham a needle in my arm and a
Bag of my o-plus switching or somewhere around might near my hip. I
Knew that donating blood made me act oddly that the gore of it made me giggle uncontrollably
I tried to redirect my need to make a noise by babbling rolling my tongue ridiculously and popping my cheeks it helped
The nurse walked up to me to check on my sack of blood. I
Stole a look at it and it only made me babble more
You're speaking in your language, aren't you?
Because a nervous brown teenager prattling at the grossness of giving blood must of course be speaking her native language
My language is English. Damn it. I'm sure this was traumatizing
I'm absolutely sure this was just a harrowing experience for you, and I'm sorry that you had to deal with it
Also, I just realized there's this comment some somehow up here and it says
Integration an already problematic concept that should be abandoned in favor of acceptance. What?
Okay
There's a reason that
Societies want integration. It's not because of racism. It's not because of any kind of
racial or ethnic or religious hatred
it's because
societies have a
Duty to promote social cohesion at least to a point certainly not over the rights of the individual
but at least to a point and they have a duty to to continue the existence of
the native culture of that society
You know
There is a native British culture. That is not
British Islamic or
British Chinese or British anything else, but just straight-up British and
Britain has a responsibility to maintain that culture
Canada has a responsibility to maintain its native culture
And by the way that includes Canada's native non-white population the people that were here before Europeans came over
Absolutely, their culture should be preserved the same with the United States the same with any country
It's very obvious that that Muslim immigrants to Britain are not part of
Native British culture and that in Britain native British culture does have to at least be given
some type of precedent
Some type of consideration
So this idea that no you're not going to integrate that the
Natives of the area have to integrate into you. It's a ridiculous notion
There's no question that my hijab my skin color and my innate foreignness despite being born and raised in the UK
Is what got me put in lower sets?
Okay
No
This is this is another big problem with social justice is that they view
differences as one always being an
Instance of the greater versus the lesser and to always being a power struggle. You can definitely have
Separate but equal you can definitely have things that are different but still considered with the same amount of at least
cultural respect
instead of telling the foreigners to assimilate Britain you should take a long hard look at yourself because
Participation does not bring minorities acceptance in order to achieve harmony in Britain's multicultural landscape
It's not immigrants who need to integrate. It's the white majority
Majority
Until the majority stops treating people of color like a curiosity for their entertainment
The country will be stuck in an existential crisis in which British children grow up as outsiders
This is this is really interesting. Okay, because in this article
Almost everything that she brings up has to do with not everything but almost everything
She brings up has to do with her being a Muslim wearing a hijab
Talking about her hair, which is obviously covered up in public view
None of these things are racial
You know if you were to take you know
She says she's Iraqi Iraqi by heart British by upbringing if you were to take an an Iraqi girl
who wasn't a Muslim or at least didn't wear a hijab and
Raised her in Britain. She would likely just be straight-up accepted
When you wear something like a hijab, it's it's almost like a social handshake
It's you making a direct statement about who you are and the value system that you live your life by
Because only a certain type of woman wears a hijab a Muslim woman
it's very similar to a Christian wearing a very visible rosary that's also a statement and
If you don't like what that statement says to other people
Maybe you should not make that statement