So let's talk about jokes. Ideally, a joke is supposed to be funny. A knock-knock joke may be
the worst kind of joke in existence because knock-knock jokes aren't funny. Listening to
a knock-knock joke is like watching a high school dance through a telescope. You can see the punch
line from a mile away. What you just heard was a pun, which is essentially a knock-knock joke
without the foreplay. Alfred Hitchcock once called the pun the highest form of literature.
Hitchcock was certainly a genius at filmmaking, but he was really being an idiot when he said
that. Puns aren't funny and neither are knock-knock jokes. What is funny, however, is this new
underground meme called Grabahan, mostly because it is so unexpected and unpredictable. Who knew
that a random city in Indonesia could make such a dynamic and long-lasting meme? Now this meme
stayed pretty obscure so far, so there's a good chance that many of you watching this are asking
yourselves the same question, what's so funny about Grabahan? And the answer to that is,
grab a handful of my nuts!