extra extra read all about it lindsey ellis is leaving the internet well she's leaving youtube
anyway yesterday she posted this on her patreon it cost two dollars to get in but uh i ain't paying
for it it's on archive.today walking away from omeleus omeleus well i don't know what this is
this is going to be a youtube video but i just don't have it in me to invite that kind of
scrutiny to be the last in the sex sad line of youtubers to get all weepy on camera and
crap about the how just can't do this anymore boo hoo hoo i wonder if she's expecting empathy for
herself even though she doesn't give it to other people i had planned to move video content to
nebulae but i realize now that doing that is just keeping wounds wide open my life ended nine months
ago what has been taking up bandwidth ever since then has been a ghost are you serious i know you
got cancelled nine months ago i did a video on it but this is histrionic lindsey chill out man
ain't that bad just just walk away from the screen turn the pc off go outside it'll be okay
it's almost funny how many people will insist that i have lost nothing you know because subscriber
count is the only metric for success and cancel culture doesn't exist one youtube channel checking
along on algorithmic inertia is not success it's just an engine driving on fumes you know i uh
wouldn't mind those subs i wouldn't mind that algorithmic inertia hey how about this just give
me your channel lindsey it'll be okay right you don't want it anymore many will say this is being
melodramatic that my life isn't over that there was absolutely nothing stopping me from brushing
myself off building back up goodwill and shutting up and playing the game and i tried that in a way
i suppose it's good that i did because i needed to learn the hard way this is never going to work
there's no unfucking this you can't find the energy if there's nothing left to convert to it
you can't be a better person if you're nothing but the hollow shell of one well lindsey you brought
this on yourself you weren't a good person progressive leftist politics do not create
good people you cultivated an audience of bitter failures who took it out on you because you were
not a bitter failure i'm not an idiot for being canceled by my audience even if i disagree with
my audience even if i even if i put out a video that no one likes and i just say you know what no
every single one of you is wrong even if i get into a knockdown drag out fight with my audience
i never fear being canceled because you attracted the terrible people with your own terribleness
i didn't do that sargon didn't do that even people like destiny didn't do that we all have audiences
who value free speech which means inherently valuing disagreement you rejected that and now
you are here 2021 has been the worst year of my life i'm traumatized by it to this day i still
have people scolding me about how i handled it i should have handled it differently i should
have controlled my stance if i had the capability to know what any of these people are even saying
to strangers on twitter while i was shitting blood for weeks on it what the fuck shitting blood are
you sure there's not something else happening here the worst thing about this whole year is
that i can't even admit this trauma because all the rhetorical devices people have already come
up with to dismiss it that centering my own pain is evidence of me not listening does it occur to
these people that you can listen and disagree with people's conclusions no it doesn't and you wanted
it that way you wanted to be able to shut down everybody who went against you everybody who
disagreed with your politics and now it's being used on you that i'm weaponizing my fragile white
womanhood or whatever to point out that having thousands upon thousands of people who you have
never met hate you and say whatever will get them the most up-dutes about it is in fact traumatizing
you wanted it this way you discarded real equality for equity and now that has been turned around on
you that people i used to know would fragrantly lie about me on twitter.com to the tune of
thousands of retweets and tens of thousands of likes i just had to sit there and take it again
you did the exact same thing to a lot of people you used to know my favorite are the people who
dismiss any potential harm i might have incurred as justified because i'm a wealthy white woman
i'm not wealthy um you're wealthier than most people let's be honest these people don't see how
similar these talking points are to the same boomer bootstrap parenting style that i thought
most of us agree was abusive you need to toughen up accept your punishment except that even if the
reaction was outsized you did something wrong because where there's smoke there's fire you
cultivated that attitude even the most repressive religions have a pathway to salvation your ethical
system is more immoral than like islams because at least with them if you repent you're welcomed
back into the brotherhood you spent years among a group of people who did not care one lick for
the virtue of forgiveness and now you are surprised that when you have to ask for forgiveness they're
not going to give it to you these same people always crow about believing victims telling
victims of public dogpiles that they do not deserve to claim their trauma let alone to process
it because they deserved it there is no such thing as cancer culture there is no incentive reward
structure in places like twitter to call people out there are no updoets faves follows retweets
for hotting a take on whomever is trending remember you didn't say this lindsey but you
absolutely love the person that did everything is sexist everything is racist everything is
homophobic and you have to point it all out and now you are being called out i don't even agree
with what anita said here but these are the rules that you live by and they are the rules that you
are now dying by one of the most common tools of exclusion is through mobbing which is rarely
talked about because unlike rape or murder it's not easy to pin it on a single person or scapegoat
mobbing is emotional abuse practiced by a group of people usually peers over a period of time
through methods such as gaslighting rumor mongering and ostracism it's most documented
in workplace or academic environments key points of capitalist tension it's capitalism it's done
this to you lindsey isn't it your own capitalist success has made the rabble who watch you decide
to overthrow the system but is thoroughly institutionalized into feminist queer and
radical spaces as well almost like it's not fucking capitalist one it has an unusually
strong power to damage the victim's relationship to society because it can't be written off as an
outlier as some singular monster it reveals a fundamental truth about people that makes
it difficult to trust ever again people become like aliens like a pack of animals that can turn
on you as soon as some mysterious pheromone shift marks you for death you wanted collectivism and
now you have the justice of the mob to the insidious nature of emotional abuse how do you
fight ostracism and rumors they leave no bruises they just starve you every youtuber has had some
level of rumor spread about them all the time there's so much false shit about me online it's
beggar's belief but you know what i just keep making videos i don't look at it i don't care
i go offline we need to go offline i hang out with people irl when i need to like it's the internet
dude chill three mobbing typically occurs in places where the victim is trapped by some need
or obligation work school circles and friends twitter twitter is not a place of need or
obligation turn it off the isabel fall case is almost a textbook example of how online mobbing
harms people how the people who participate in these mobs never engage in any self-reflection
when some people read falls helicopter story and questioned the trans botafides of the author in
early 2020 twitter did what twitter does and ruined falls life death by a million cuts no
one single person even beginning to question whether they did anything wrong by jumping to
the worst possible faith and interpretation of both the text and the author one of isabel
falls detractors neon yang became the new scapegoat using some of the same tactics used
the prior year to attack fall i'm not going to touch on yang's original comments about fall or
the pushback to them but what was downright charming and its lack of self-awareness about
the whole thing was the way people used falls trauma to attack yang the way that they invoked
fall being checked into the hospital while yang said whatever about fall all the while having no
idea what was going on in yang's private life what's particularly galling is how many people
accused yang of sending a trans person to the hospital of ptsd while apparently being completely
oblivious to the fact they could very well be doing the same thing to yang a non-binary trans
person there was no lesson learned on the nature of mindless dogpiling just twitter doing what
twitter does and this is actually a very interesting part because it is describing how
the left eats its own you have isabel fall who wrote a story called helicopter story people
thought that was a reference to the attack helicopter meme so a bunch of trans people
dogpiled her and she ended up institutionalized for a short while one of the prominent dogpilers
was neon yang and later on for another event neon yang got dogpiled by the same people and one of
the things they attacked neon yang with was saying how audacious it was that neon yang
attacked isabelle fall during that previous event even though they also all attacked isabelle fall
in the same way and you get people like this on twitter who kind of prove lindsey ellis right
lindsey ellis a new york times best-selling author comparing herself to isabelle fall a
trans woman who was harassed to the point of near suicide for a short story she wrote and then going
on to defend the person who did the harassing is a truly an apt send-off there are so many other
examples she could have used for comparison maybe don't use a trans woman who didn't even get to
fully begin her career while ellis enjoys a career as a successful and well-loved author and video
essayist listen i thought the defense of neon yang in an essay about leaving youtube was weird
and even weirder when she implied that it was mostly cis straight men criticizing them when
in reality it was mostly other trans people so excuse me if i call that out point it all out this
person is doing the exact thing that lindsey ellis is criticizing the entire left for like
this passage doesn't even come to yang's defense it just draws parallels between the two but this
is the nature of the online left both the socialists and the progs and lindsey the
reason that you are so inundated with this is because these are the people you courted as your
audience i court edge lords i court people who are interested in humor i court people who can
laugh at everyone in a non-partisan way people who aren't strictly leftist or strictly rightist that's
why i'm not afraid of it but you chose this something else that was also inevitable i was
going to quit youtube i knew i couldn't do it forever that i was running out of steam that i
was sick of the increasing dehumanization inherent that i just didn't have anything to say about
movies anymore what happened to me in march and april hastened it this was always inevitable now
if you fall out of love with a platform or a project that's fine happens everybody i mean the
main reason i'm still going is because i love doing what i do i've reinvented this channel
several times but i've never seriously ever thought of quitting my initial plan was to leave
youtube for nebula but i realize now that this is only entrenching myself in a more intimate form of
harm rather than the broad buckshot kind that youtube invites i won't go into detail but i
can't do video content for them either i can't make content period i just can't do this anymore
there is no healing as long as there's attachment to the thing that makes you suffer and the thing
in this case is being in the public eye at all you go back and you watch really old lindsey ellis
videos we're talking like that guy with the glasses ear stuff when she was the nostalgia check
she is bright she is happy to be there she has interesting things to say even in old vlogs she's
very clearly like quite leftist but she seems like she would be a genuinely fun person to be
around and now she isn't she's exactly as she said she's been hollowed out but it wasn't by age
despite all of the jokes about her current looks i'm married wow me too um i'm flattered you know
and i and i get that you've been trying really really hard to get my attention you know for
obvious reasons but again i'm married uh i don't think it would really work out between us honestly
you're a little old for me but i find it really interesting how you wish to personalize this
because lindsey if we have to do this let's have a conversation about attractiveness shall we
because i don't know whether you recall but we've seen you from the side and i don't want
to be brutal about it but i'm not terribly impressed i happen to notice you've also had
an abortion and then made a movie about an abortion now i as a father of three and with
a very healthy and happy fat bouncing baby i'm not very attracted to the kind of woman who would
have bought her own child before she was born i think that's really gross but then i looked at
your wikipedia page it says you're 37 37 i'm 41 lindsey my wife is five years younger than you
and it wasn't even by her audience even though her audience is a big part of it
it was by her own politics broad spectrum leftist politics it's like heroin it feels really good
it's really pleasurable it's addictive but its corrupting influence does eventually destroy you
and you either drive away the good people who are around you or those people turn it just as
bad as you what i wanted was to quietly disappear but since this is a platform where people are
paying me to make content i feel like i have to make a statement if it were just me by myself
i would just sign off and say goodbye and that would be it but i have a team who depends on my
company for health insurance and including dependents i supply full benefits for eight
people and here in the us employer-based insurance is often the only feasible option
saying to everyone sorry about your children but they can't have insurance anymore because twitter
makes me sad just doesn't seem like a fair deal none of them incidentally know i'm posting this
hold on you're you're quitting you're running a company you got employees and this is how they
know this is how they learn that they're losing their jobs what the fuck the only thing i can do
for now is keep this page active with the loose promise that someday i'll figure out something to
in the future to make up for this while asking you please stop messaging me for apologizing for not
being able to subscribe anymore you don't owe me anything this patreon is like my own life and
career just running on fumes okay let me translate these past two these past two paragraphs for you
i have a business i have financial obligations to people who work for me i will be legally and
morally fucked if i renege on those obligations so even though i'm not producing anything i'm just
going to leave my patreon up knowing that a lot of people who currently monthly subscribe to me
they have probably forgotten that they're doing it and they're not entirely paying
attention anymore and i just want to keep that passive income rolling in this is exploitative
as fuck dude but all i know now is that being in the public eye at all is a losing game and
i regret all of it i regret every time i've ever stood up for anyone it always backfires
i regret every time i've pushed back and something unjust it was always just used to hurt me i regret
every time i've ever stood up for myself i never did it correctly i regret every time i ever showed
any vulnerability just my ammunition to be used against me later i regret every time i ever tried
to play the game with peers and colleagues they will drop you the second you aren't popular on
twitter anymore it's all hollow and brittle if there's one thing i've learned this year it is
how eminently expendable i am it's amazing because it's the complete opposite for me
i don't regret any time i've stood up for anybody i have said unpopular things and i have had people
get mad at me but it was the right thing to do because i believed in it i don't regret any time
i've pushed back against something unjust even if i lose and everything falls apart i can at least
sleep at night i don't regret any time i stood up for myself in fact i should have done it more
i don't regret any time i showed any vulnerability there were some people who poked fun at me for it
and that's fine that's what banter is all about and i don't regret any of the friends that i've
made in this space even the ones who have backstabbed me i'm happy to have at this point
several friend groups full of people who genuinely like me and i genuinely like them it might suck
that friendship wasn't real where you were lindsey but it's definitely real over here the good
progressive cis straight wealthy white men keep on trucking and coming out on top because deep down
they know that the systems they profess to stand against ultimately exist to benefit them
well i'm not a good progressive cis straight wealthy white man it turns out it's almost like
it's your side of politics that has the misogyny problem that has the sexism problem that has the
racism problem now don't get me wrong the uh the right definitely has problems that are akin to
those but the left is not immune it's the people who are unaligned it's the people who are in the
center it's the people who do not subscribe to the left-right dichotomy it's the individualists
we're the ones who don't have these problems and so there it is lindsey ellis has taken off guys
and to be honest people on the left right now are overwhelmingly proving her right in some respects
has lindsey ellis considered the possibility she's kind of a whack bitch defending a rich white woman
with a victim complex while calling pocs incredibly sensitive and making up some bullshit scenario
to explain the way the criticism is just beyond parody lindsey ellis being harassed sucks but
lindsey ellis was racist in her portrayal of indigenous people with the portrayal of the
kulat tribe in the twilight series it is not poc's responsibility to protect white people
when we call them out point it all out my empathy for lindsey ellis is severely limited because what
is happening to her not only did her audience do to other people and not only did she cultivate
that audience with that attitude but she has done it to people herself she did it to rose of dawn
she did it to tom scott she certainly helped do it to doug walker and everyone over at that guy
with the glasses and trust me those guys weren't perfect either but lindsey acted ridiculously in
that scenario and possibly most famously of all she helped do it to movie bob now movie bob
he he really fucking asked for it but still even in her apology video she doesn't really apologize
like one other person i owe an apology to is movie bob i told him on twitter to leave me alone because
he was acting like a creep by being over familiar and continually signaling to the world that were
friends and he he was acting like a creep and we're not friends but i would have never done
that if i had known that the diet nazis were going to turn that into a meme like i don't like a lot
of what he says on twitter either but please stop using my face to torture this man leave him alone
like listen to the arrogance coming out of this woman yes i know that the sun god king rays of
lindsey ellis will not shine down upon the lambs of movie bob but do not torment him in his darkness
just leave him to rot peasants jesus christ i don't know if lindsey ellis is actually going
anywhere or not who knows she pulls this stunt every six months she's deleted her twitter before
and like i'm done i'm done with all this shit and she comes back a couple days later she has
repeatedly self-destructed in a spectacular public fashion phil fish style so this could be her
trying to get more relevance but it also could be her legitimately leaving doesn't really matter
though because aside from her self-destructions lindsey ellis at this point seems to be kind of
irrelevant oh well the end of another old guard youtube channel happens all the time nowadays
goodbye and good luck nostalgic here's some advice for your next adventure watch who you get in bed
with and over the last few years i have had so many of my colleagues all of them women people
of color trans people queer people or some combination of the above voice to me the constant
anxiety that they live with about maybe saying something wrong that will get them on the bad
side of their own communities i didn't start getting noticeable harassment from the purity
tester brigade until i stood up for a trans woman on twitter and that backlash did not
come from the alt-right or even the diet nazis but our own community our side