Okay welcome, welcome, welcome one and all to yet another episode of WIC-TV Across Ideological
Platform where we can come together to talk about issues both political and cultural from the silly
to the serious and gang we have a show for you today. Many moons ago, years ago, mortal enemies
a battlefield littered with rhetorical corpses and champions on either side standing strong
eyeing each other across a moonlit field swords at the ready blood staining everything they did
today however both sit before you right in a much more peaceful setting a calm setting
and we're going to discuss well all sorts of things today we have the wonderful Brianna Wu here
welcome welcome and is joined by also the equally wonderful short fat otaku or dev
as he is known welcome to you both of you how you guys doing today
uh i'm feeling it's been a crazy day uh but i do agree wick when i think of your show i think of
peace i think of calm discussions so i'm sure that will also happen today wait wick are you
sure you're live is it i'm looking at i'm looking at your youtube and you're not up
uh people are chatting in my uh chatting with my space uh i see yeah i see faces on my live stream
uh youtubers am i live am i here can you hear me well yeah let's make sure this is important wick
has been censored by big tech i might have youtube is up there you go you just popped in okay okay
just took a minute that's a that sounds like a maybe a canadian slowness they're always a little
bit behind so yeah i'll real quickly i'll tweet out that this is happening beautiful thank you
thank you um but yeah i wanted to just kind of get um get the temperature check just in general
i know that there's been a lot of really heavy discourse of late online um and in spaces so i
just wanted to make sure like how how are we feeling uh brianne you privated a bunch of your
stuff today what what happened i i'm just tired of getting yelled at by my own sidewalk and it's
not more complicated than that though i never privated my twitter even during gamer gate and
that's just how bad it's been lately um yeah there's nothing to it it's just um yeah i think
it's and dev i i don't know how you feel but i think it's really clear that a portion of my own
movement has uh certainly been engaged in apologia for uh you know october 7th and uh i've tried to
push back on that even though i stand with you know the palestinian people and uh it's just
really been uh really unpleasant lately um so i've just i've had enough that's it
here to be alive be with us i'm posting the final message okay okay let's let him get his tweet out
i i've just annoyingly added everyone in my discord that'll work well thank you i appreciate it
yeah no problem no problem um but um to that right um you've been watching this from afar
i've seen you tweet on it i've seen you reply to posts and things dev what what is your take on
this whole situation on ocuber 7th like the israel no on the uh the discourse surrounding it to be
clear right um it's cancerous yeah i expect that from the internet at this point to be honest
i've i've seen so many so many news cycles where people will take the most extreme
version of events push it just outside the realm of truth so that people who agree with them still
still hold on to it because it's still somewhat truthful and then they just roll with they just
run with the narrative right like i've seen right wingers do this with a whole bunch of things
concerning trump i've seen left wingers do this with the whole like for for the past 10 years
discourse has been a nightmare online in my opinion i'm old enough to remember what it was
like before i think it was it was still bad 10 years ago i think it was bad 15 years ago
i think it is definitely getting worse um but i think part of that is you know when you and i
were growing up deaf and i assume we're roughly the same age because the music from your videos
is like parasite eve and final fantasy 8 so i just assume you love those for the same reasons i do
i grew up in the 90s yeah yeah yeah i mean the the the normies just were not online it was only
people like us so i think that the addition to the uh to the cool kids has uh really made the
internet a much worse place to be it used to just be uh yeah um sexism and now it's terrorist
apology so that's not good ah there was i know there were definitely some real sexist back in
the day but there was also a lot of joking around too yeah sometimes sometimes it was hard to tell
the difference between the two but uh yeah things have gotten worse for sure yeah definitely i guess
on that note right like of back in the day um i guess i'll just ask this to you first brianna
and i'm curious what dev would have to say uh i'm again as i alluded to before there were a lot of
well we've we've had a lot on online presence for a long time um how do you feel you've grown since
then and in what ways right oh boy that's a long question well we got a long time i set aside two
hours for y'all we gotta talk about something right well i think you one of the thing the
things is the older you get um i i think that if you do it correctly you're you're constantly
changing and growing and you you take in new information i don't think that's true for everyone
i think that some people uh get really static the older that they get but for me you know i i think
you keep i think you keep adding new information and hopefully like ending up at better answers um
i think for me personally one way i've grown is just getting more and more and more over the
trauma of my childhood which makes me less reactive uh though i can certainly be reactive
but um not being in that fight or flight mode all the time um is certainly helpful um i i think that
one of the really big changes in me personally today versus the gamergate era is i've seen
like jessabelle just closed yesterday who was a huge force in the gamergate years i love jessabelle
i love most of the writers at jessabelle and i think like the the financial collapse of that
particular business model you know part of it is due to mismanagement by uh the private equity
firm that bought them out but i also think part of it is we have the tactics of feminism that
we've employed for the last 10 15 years are clearly not resulting in a vibrant movement
it's not resulting in more real world rights um it's not resulting in a conversation about what
women are facing and i think for me personally the biggest lesson i've taken is that internet
screaming does not really equate to real world policies if that makes sense oh that makes sense
to me right like do we have to ask ourselves like is what we're doing moving us towards what we want
or is it moving us away or is it just like making us shred water um i i've seen a lot of posts and
this is kind of not a non-soc whatever a little bit of an aside of people who are swearing they're
never going to vote for joe biden right they're like oh i will never vote for genocide joe is that
what the term they use like and then the question you ask is like well considering that you want
policies that genocide joe will support and the other options will not what what do you think
you're accomplishing here is this moving you closer to your political objectives or is it
moving you further away and i think we all kind of have to ask that but i want to isn't just well
hold on because this will piggyback into dev you know dev one of the reasons i enjoy your videos is
i think um and before people online scream at me i do think you come up with a lot of things are
structurally are wrong with the directions that progressives are going that's not to say i agree
with the conclusion she reached but i think you've really put your finger on some of the things that
are wrong with our movement today and one of those are the purity spiral that you have an excellent
video about and the utopianism that we kind of fall into so i would love to hear like from your
point of view how you feel about that well i mean i'm not a progressive right i don't view myself
aggressive so you're not no no like i'm glad we got that settled i was curious right i
i view myself as like an adam and sitch style enlightened centrist you know i definitely do
not like the right wing there are some serious problems on on the right i grew up with the right
wing trying to censor video games and and wanting to repress gay people and i didn't like any of
that when i was when i was younger um and i think because the right wing was so ascendant in the 90s
at least culturally um it was easy to be a leftist it was easy to be like a cent like maybe not
not like a communist or anything but it was easy to be like you know why shouldn't we have health
care i mean we have health care in canada but why shouldn't america have health care right why
shouldn't we have gay marriage these were kind of easy they're like slam dunks for people who are
left-leaning right um but the slam dunks are kind of drying up and now you have tougher questions
on the left and the answers to those questions aren't exclusively leftist because because now
you're getting into like more esoteric things like you know should trans women compete in
women's sports that's not a slam dunk it's a complicated question there's a lot in there
you know so i think i think the reason that there has been a slow shift away from broader leftism
is because it accomplished a lot it accomplished a lot of good but we're kind of running out of the
good we're not we haven't completely run out of it but we've but it's definitely starting to run out
of good stuff out of the on on that note like what would you say currently in 2023 today is the
what should progresses in your opinion be putting out there what do you think is their strongest
argument that they have today right what should they be focusing on right now yes uh health care
yeah american needs health care yeah that is that is the big one um oh and you talked about
utopianism and purity spiraling brianna i'll give you a concrete example okay so
you see a lot um a lot of rhetoric on the left they see that they say they're very far left is
you know health care is a human right everything should be free everything should be available to
everyone otherwise you are oppressing people and you're letting people die you're killing people
in fact um in practical terms what we've discovered looking at like the uk's health
care system and france's and canada's health care system what we've discovered is that if you make
everything free you have a shit ton of waste there's and you don't you only have so much
resources to go around there's so many doctors only so much time so if you make everything free
you end up bankrupting your system you can't like it's it's fucked however if you add like a 20
copay to go to the doctors you cut out like 90 of the waste because most people who are just showing
up to like get a day off work and get a doctor's note they're not going to do that because it's
not free anymore right so the the i these numbers are i got them from econoboi like a year ago i
can't pull them up right away but i do remember them as being mostly accurate is that basically
if you add a 20 copay you cut out 90 of your health care waste um in terms of like people
actually like health care waste from from patients so that's that's not ideologically pure
if you're talking about health care as a human right like if that's your value well now it's not
a human right now it costs twenty dollars which means that if somebody doesn't have twenty dollars
if they're too poor and they no one can lend them twenty dollars and they can't get a job
well that person is fucked they're not going to get health care but it also means that you get to
have a health care service for everyone else right so there's certain instances where if you're
ideologically pure you actually end up with worse results than if you compromise and i think health
care is one of those yeah i i certainly agree with that i think that there's that trend across
the board right like we're seeing it right now i think uh really hyperbolically with with with the
israel hamas war and the rhetoric around that you know if you have a stance that is yeah i did to
our wic panel the other night and i said multiple times like i stand with the people of palestine
the human rights abuses towards uh civilians is unconscionable i don't support it our top like
foreign policy in this region should be to you know stop the violence uh but if you don't
leap to the most extreme conclusion there like a one-state solution and like implementing a
democratic utopia there and taking away the borders uh you are just uh you don't have a voice
in the conversation so i agree with you on that yeah dev i do want to say in like tonight i hope
we can just have a respectful back and forth about some of your content i was studying a lot
of your videos which again largely i enjoy they're well produced they're well thought out i think that
this is stuff the left needs an answer for i've noticed though that there's a really big difference
in how you define progressives and is i define progressives depending what the argument is
you're trying to make there's one i was watching and yeah you define progressives in this nice
people that want health care but as like antifa antifa and self-id like trans people you know
they're non-binary and just want to make it up on the fly right so i think like one of the the
things i find sometimes difficult about your content is it it sometimes feels like you have
a conclusion that you want to reach that both sides are equally bad and you kind of reach for
facts that fit that and i don't always think it's an accurate way to to view a situation
well how do you define progressives then what's your view of it i have a much more charitable
point of view on this right uh which is it is i think the highest level progressivism is about
wanting structural um change for solutions like health care is a really good example
um you know i grew up in mississippi so when i think about structural racism in the united states
um i realize there's no policy around the edges that's gonna you know make that society heal from
the the wounds still open today from the civil war so i think at the highest levels like
progressivism is about thinking about big structural policy changes what i you and i
i think agree on is that there's a real tendency especially online to reformat to mean this
extremely online kind of argument that tends towards a purity spiral which is not helpful
that's true but it is um it's not just online but i think it it comes out online because it's it's
so easy right i think you know twitter is no longer 240 characters or whatever it was but
it was for a very long time and i think that promoted a certain type of very uh very short
thinking where you could you have to fit it into a very small box and people did that for a decade
and now we have a bunch of short thinkers if that makes sense especially if you're like like a
twitter addict or you're a journalist or something i think i think twitter ruined a lot of people's
brains i think that's part of it yeah um but but the bigger the bigger problem i think i'm gonna
have to i'm gonna have to do a bit of philosophizing unfortunately go ahead which i i did i did with
the carl max debate as well just to explain a few things so there's um there's a a leftist
philosopher named herbert marcus and he came up with this idea and he it's called it's not called
the march of progress but we'll just use march of progress as a shorthand and the idea basically
is that if you have and he thought this is a good thing he was promoting this i don't think it's a
good thing if you have a movement that is based on change and then you kind of universalize that
so so that it's it simply pursues change it inevitably radicalizes and drives off a cliff
it has to because it's not it's not aiming at a goal it's aiming at change itself so it's like
if you say i want to change to do xyz that's one thing but if you're saying i want to change for
changes sake then that's where the utopianism comes from and the purity spiraling and he
outlined this all in a book called repressive tolerance where the idea is that tolerance in
his view had to repress um people who weren't tolerant right well this is where i think i would
like one of the reasons the way like my views on what women are facing in america have not
changed since gamergate what has changed radically is the way i go about trying to
like affect that change right because i agree with you like at some point um you know we turned
a corner in how we are talking about what women face in american society and we stopped talking
about policies and we started talking more about an aesthetic where if you had the right
like points of view and the expanded feminism to mean you know body shaming and you know this this
this very wide gamut of related struggles where you had to kind of identify with all of these
values and then eventually hopefully you could talk about the policy um i think this is where
feminism really fucked up frankly in the gamergate era if i could do anything and go relive those
years over again i would have gotten off of twitter and i would have used the political
capital i had in that moment to push microsoft push activision to like change their internal
hiring processes right um and and i think that we've really gotten to a point where
feminism as a force is not going to be effective until we take a step back and go hold on what are
the issues we need to be thinking about uh child care is completely unaffordable women have been
run out of the workforce post-covid we're not really seeing an investment in that until we
look at these kind of bigger structural issues i don't see us like becoming relevant force in
politics again one thing that i noticed in your answers here from both of you right
um when uh dev asked you what is progressivism what who is progressive etc uh and then also
from dev's uh philosophizing there i think i've kind of had a a bit of a eureka moment and bear
with me right um in my mind woo right progressivism from your uh definition what you gave to me
is progress towards a goal right but it should be it is not but what but what a lot of progressives
and what i've seen this argument online before right is that we are going to progress for
progress's sake like we are going to move forward right regardless of where that is we are going to
move forward we have to move past capitalism we have to move past these things we have to move
forward right and i think that um sometimes at least in the sfo videos i've seen that is the
that is the uh what progressives are painted as and i don't think those that's that's a fair
characterization dev right i think that like yes there's some of that um and i think that's mostly
online stuff but i do think that plenty of progressives plenty of people who who do identify
as progressives are towards specific goals um does that make sense how am i off my rocker here
that does make sense but i'm not sure it's entirely accurate i mean there's there's some
accuracy there i think but considering how much blowback you've been receiving recently brianne
you have to know that there's definitely not just a small radical online fringe but a significant
number of people who now believe this way yeah i i completely agree uh and i've you know we've
talked about this privately in dms i don't mind sharing it here but you know i i personally
believe that the left is just 10 years behind the right as far as being radicalized on the internet
right i think a lot of the same tendencies we see in the tea party uh have now come to our own
doorstep um i think this version of the democratic party unfortunately would be very susceptible to
uh you know a left-wing donald trump if a figure like that came along so i i agree with you i think
there's time to stop it and you know wick one of the reasons i consider you a good friend at this
point is i think i think we have i have a different i think the degree to which i think women are not
getting a fair shake in society is a little different than yours i think we have a different
appraisal there but directionally i think we both see this torrent of crazy on both sides and we're
taking a step and saying this needs to be about policy we've got to calm this down and we've got
to learn to talk to each other so we can have a functioning democracy you know i very much agree
with you about that so does that make sense to you dev i think so yeah yeah um to go back to what you
were saying earlier you mentioned that um basically progressives have been making less progress as the
radicalizations happened right yeah um you probably don't agree with my characterization of this but
i'm going to give it anyway please um i think that there was a lot of um of things that needed to be
fixed and the feminists fixed a lot of them not all of them but they fixed a lot of them over
let's say the past 100 years or so there's been a lot of improvement um and then as the the number
of things to fix began to dry up you started to see them focus on on small things right micro
aggressions body shaming like you mentioned you know think things that weren't nearly as important
as should women be allowed to hold jobs and vote you know much smaller things and then as they
focused on the smaller things um they radicalized they became a lot more crazy looking to the normies
and then while they were in that that echo chamber they started taking big l's like with roe v wade
yeah and and like the rollback of lgbt acceptance so i think i think there's been this um this ebb
and flow where as the left the broader left has been accomplishing goals they've run out of goals
to accomplish and which has radicalized them then they became crazy then they started rolling back
they started losing all those goals they had accomplished so i understand that these things
happened at the same time dad but my question to you would be like are and i want you to be
clear here are you blaming that um that niche kind of focus that the left has had on the micro
aggressions and the small things as to why they lost roe v wade and as to why they've taken big
l's when it comes to lgbtq processes of protections and stuff is that are you are you
implying that there is a causation factor there i think there partially is yes i mean obviously
another part of it is that they have political opponents who want to roll those things back and
they took that opportunity right but they they made themselves weak they gave them the opening
you know i i hear what you're saying and i'm not going to deny there's a lot of that that's going
on i i definitely think so i i think and you talked about this in your video about the purity
spiral right uh which is excellent i hope we can leave that in the show notes and people will check
it out i think if you're on the left thank you very much dev has a very good analysis of a real
problem that we have um but even in your own video you talk about how this is advantageous for us to
build a coalition but in the end is kind of a cancer that eats us apart right so i think i
think that's exactly what happened right this started with us kind of all getting together
and going hey you know we've all noticed that our sexual assault claims are being kind of
systematically not being taken seriously i think women across a wide variety of fields look around
at the workplace and go you know what i have a lot of trouble being taken seriously and being
heard on my own teams right or as soon as i have a child i've noticed that my my my job is very
eager to show me a door right this is a set of problems that we've certainly not solved and we're
nowhere near solving what i think has happened is i think online is a trap particularly for people
you know i want to be really clear i fell into this trap i i look back at my own congressional
run and i think if i understood the things i do today i think i would have had a much better shot
of winning because what i can look back and see really clearly was online was pushing me to take
this this leftmost view on literally everything you know sex work not accepting you know money
from xyz and really focusing on the superficial when what i needed to be doing was spending a lot
more time in my district and talking about the policies like directly affecting their lives and
that's something i would do very differently today online i think is a trap because i think it it
gives people this feeling that they're they're making a change and i think it's with the best
of intention you know um yeah i'm not uh i'm not like a fat person but i can really imagine that
like feeling degraded all the time or feeling the ways that like society doesn't respect you i would
imagine there's some anger and some trauma there and i think it probably feels good to talk about
that online the problem is somewhere along the line like the problem is with online culture
there's no point where we pause and say okay we need to make it so um you know people that are
larger can access trains and planes with a little bit more dignity right there's not a public policy
component that we're pushing for as much as the fringe left loves to shit on liberals i do think
this is something structurally liberals are better at than progressives kind of forming coalitions
and trying to get specific policies passed well insofar as the fat thing is concerned as a fat guy
i'm quite how dare you speak over one of the oppressed classes
briano we have a fat man i apologize okay i i will say that like being fat's just unhealthy
and i think rather than like it it is better to promote public health than it is to promote
you know accommodating people being fat i think we want people to lose weight not feel comfortable
being being fat if that if that makes sense yeah i agree with that um but i also yeah this is
something i saw like when i was running for office i do think that there are situations where i don't
think it would kill airlines to have a few larger seats that are given for priority for people that
physically can't fit in those seats that doesn't seem crazy to me right um maybe maybe the main the
fat thing is a bad example there are any number of like reasonable public policy things we could
be focused on and we just don't because the conversation is so much about uh like online
purity here's a really good example uh the trans debate you know if you put me in charge tomorrow
of like talking about the the trans public policy um you know issue i would try to find something
very similar to gay marriage where like you're focused on a single public policy position with
a broad possible range of support and i would make that like the rights of trans children to
attend public school um but instead it gets into like this more esoteric thing and this more
esoteric thing which often i agree with but i also understand how it's not ever going to be a
popular public policy position and i think all of this is a trap i think if we're serious about
things like health care and trans dignity and women's rights we've got to come up with a new
strategy because any honest look at where the progressive movement is today you have to admit
we have less cultural power today than we did a decade ago to you brianna right yeah you say this
but the implications are are weird at that if the online is a trap does that not at least
imply or infer that we should simply seed the field leave online to be do online things right
and just leave it alone i think you and i could both agree and i think sfo might back us up that
the online and how that uh plays out does have real world implications it does impact not only
policy right but people's individuals lives as well like there are countless examples that we
can point to of people being harassed stalked etc and also of policies that have been either
implemented because of discourse that has started online or prevented from going through and or uh
swift voted because of uh that's an old term uh because of online discourse right um
like if online's a trap it's not a trap we can avoid is it i i've talked so much def go ahead
i hmm i don't know how to how to answer that actually because i had a brainwave about a
previous thing you were saying brianna and that was occupying my head i'm sorry wick no it's okay
do your brainwave thing we can ignore wick we can we can just play as video games and make money off
i will say wick i will say that like um i don't think you can ignore the online space
because you have uh people who are more left-leaning complaining about harassment
all the time and there's there's some faked harassment but there's a lot of real harassment
but then you also have people on the right who complain about getting cancelled and that
definitely happens too people have lost their jobs they've been de-banked they've had their
social media shut down i'm gonna make a prediction for you there's going to be a left-wing
resurgence in believing in cancel culture after uh after a month or two right like i think in the
next couple months we're gonna we're gonna hear a you and cry of people decrying people losing
their jobs for their political opinions i am guaranteeing that but go ahead yeah yeah yeah
absolutely i know um for example kraut if you know kraut and t he recently said that in germany
a whole bunch of migrants who had showed up from the middle east and now there's things
stuff about israel they're getting they're getting deported because germany is very strict with its
its jewish laws for obvious reasons right so there's a whole bunch of people who are just
getting kicked out of germany now and so i do think there's going to be some sort of a backlash
with people who are going very mask off on these on the israel-palestine situation and losing their
jobs and suddenly it'll be like you can't cancel people over over your political beliefs and it's
like well listen that's been happening for for years now to people who are right-leaning so
i like i don't want anyone canceled either like either side right but if these are the rules of
the game this is how it has to be you know i mean i i i don't have an issue with someone
losing i i i don't think i have the same position over what y'all do i mean dev you have a video
where you talk about uh the woman uh with the wig pulling right and how you didn't support uh
i think the name of the video is uh what is it cancel culture is totalitarian or something like
that and you're talking about this woman that basically uh this drunk white guy uh sees her
on the street tries to pull her wig off uh in a really violent way clearly hurts her and uh she
happens to film it and the guy ends up fired you're talking how you you don't support that
um i actually don't really have a problem with that necessarily what i do have a problem with is
and this is where i expect to get yelled at after this show is i have been against a certain set of
tactics from the gamer gate era right i think it is wrong to dox people i think it's wrong to go
through everything they've ever said publicly or privately and then try to use that to destroy
their reputation i think death threats rape threats all that stuff should just be off the table
right um and i want to be really honest and say that a decade ago i think gamer gate was doing
that and i would imagine all three of us would probably agree today the people i personally see
doing this the most are my own side and it just seems so crazy hypocritical of me that we decried
all these tactics and now we've just embraced them as our core strategy does does that kind of make
sense yep yep that's um uh fuck what was his name was it saw linsky i don't know the guy who wrote
rules for radicals you wrote this book basically outlining what radical movements should do to take
power and one of them one of the rules is just be as hypocritical as possible yeah do do the
underhanded stuff and also accuse your opponents of doing it you know right so it's this is kind
of how radical movements go as they radicalize but i mean you can't this is where i'm really torn a
lot of the time because i do agree with the political the stated political goals of the
progressive movement right uh you know i do want more acceptance for trans people i do want things
to be better for women i do you know i've been on a wick panel before talking about my belief in
like structural reparations for you know black people i think it's the only way we can move
forward from the pain of the civil war so when it comes to a lot of these policies i'm right there
on board where i'm feeling increasingly homeless is there is a standard i try to hold myself to
professionally and how i behave and i just see a lot of my own side engaged in tactics it just
i i don't know how to say it other than they feel evil to me to both of you and this is a very good
question because i think we've both acknowledged or all of us have acknowledged that it's worse
now right than it was 10 years ago it's worse value was 10 15 years ago um again i'm i'm a
little older myself right and i was i was active online in the early 2000s and things like that
very different very different environment for better or worse right there there's some things
i don't want back from those days um however you don't want the xbox live chats back look
we had some uh we had some fun times but those times are behind us um yeah uh we have grown up
and grown out of those things um but i will ask well should we and how do we do so and that's my
question is because it's it's very easy to get black pilled on this like these doxing
tactics these um these just doubling down taxes this constant harassment it's been shown to work
right it's been shown to be effective in getting the people you don't want to to be around not be
around anymore it hasn't worked when it came to combating our ideas getting policies passed any
of that but it's worked for what i think people really like and that's hurting others um so how
do we how do we get passes can't we get passes is it is there a way to stop this spiral as i
guess you'd call it or this uh this constant wave of tit for tat of reciprocal radicalization of
if you use those tactics we're going to use those tactics 10 times as hard etc etc
uh what what do we think i want dev to go first on this one and then i'll let you go
oh man how do you how do you fix the problem that's uh that's a very if we're going to talk
about the problem we gotta talk about how to fix it right yeah yeah um you have to
it's it's a tall order not everyone's gonna be able to do it you have to be able to understand
your your opponent's arguments all right you have to understand that like when a conservative
you know expresses some sort of anti-trans opinion he doesn't actually want to kill all
trans people and how you know how have the streets run red with the blood of trans people and
outlaw no he's generally scared for his kids right and now you can think that it's wrong
for him to be scared for his kids in that way and there's some good evidence that he probably
is wrong but it's not it's not coming from a place of of evil right and there's also there's
obviously inverted situations as well where like right wingers do not understand leftist point of
views leftists don't understand right wing point of views um basically if you can't steal man your
opponent's arguments you're you're not going to be able to sympathize with them when they
have an emotional reaction to something that they think is bad
so being able to steal men or wanting to steal but the problem is dev no one wants to do that
i well i can't make them i mean so so there's this idea um like pre-internet you watch what was on
tv maybe you could like rent a movie but like you watch what was on tv i would have never grown to
love um to love martial arts films if i didn't watch them at 3 a.m by like sneaking downstairs
as a kid right it was the only thing on um and i i had i think from 16 to 18 i had an
insomnia so i couldn't sleep and i was just staying up all night watching these martial arts films
because that's all i could do right um it's one of those things where as technological
advancement has increased and we have more access to netflix for example we never have
to be exposed to anything we don't like ever again which is nice because we don't want to
interact with things that we hate but also it means that we never actually discover anything new
so if you take that principle you apply it to political echo chambers people don't watch videos
or read books or entertain ideas from other political camps because they don't have to anymore
you know if you're a leftist you can go on youtube and watch an infinite amount of leftist content
and never be exposed to a right-wing idea and same same the other way around right there's
there's it's it sounds very strange but there's like there's too much access
and you know the the um the white pillar in me wants to say that well no people can be trusted
to diversify their their their media intake and understand what other people think and there are
some people who have for sure but it seems like most people just aren't doing it it's uh i think
that's oh i think that's go ahead no no i was just gonna say yeah like i know that you know
i've told you this in dms i am better at my job because i watch your videos and i do think because
you have such a salient uh brutal fair critique of the left i think it makes me stronger to watch
that critique and figure out what the answer is right so i agree with you that uh this tendency
for all of us to never listen to something on the other side it makes us weak it makes us unable to
function um and one of the reasons i really respect uh destiny a lot is i think more than
anyone else out there yeah look let's be clear he makes a lot of sweaty gamer comments he can
certainly tend towards being hyperbolic uh but i also think one of the good things he does is he
teaches people how to think i think when people make claims uh he really encourages his audience
to look through that to think through it uh before responding and to really really do your research
before having really strong opinions um i think that's a really good example um one of the things
i think has really really changed over my lifetime is this democratization of information i'm just
barely old enough to remember when you could get uh your news and it had to be on either cable or
the printed newspaper that came to your house every single day and that had a lot of downsides
you know you didn't hear about a lot of stories about gay people in uh that time period you know
the the the makeup of the newsrooms had huge implications for how things were covered which
is why i think we can look at public policy and the conversations we are not having about issues
like structural racism back in the 90s and see how simple they were compared to today that is a
bad thing but something was really good about that that i think is really really um under acknowledged
today is in the newspaper and cable news era of public information that did go through someone
at the top that was mature that was thoughtful that generally took some time to make sure the
stuff there was mostly accurate and did represent both sides um today we have no incentives for
any of that and i think we're much weaker as a society i think a direct reason we're seeing such
a stupid analysis on um on foreign policy issues today is we have now two generation of americans
they've never heard any position other than america is bad and our foreign policy is always
wrong and the world is a little bit more complicated than that even though we've made
plenty of foreign policy mistakes so i think that a really important thing is for america to take
more of a role in thinking about how this information landscape is influencing us right
we've got to protect free speech we've got to protect open expression but i also think we've
lost control the way people get their information to a mob and i don't think it's serving our
country well yeah so you're getting at like the post-truth era yeah if you know the post-modern
post-truth era yeah so it's it's like well can you trust cnn well i mean maybe you know they're
a decently big institution there's a lot of moving parts lots of people there but like
what if they're all compromised right well can you trust fox well maybe not like these are big
corporations and if you don't trust corporations because they're corporate you know maybe you want
to go somewhere else you know do you trust tim pool or do you trust like some some smaller site
do you trust some really fringe one like zero hedge or something because there's there's
utility and looking at the small guys too because they don't have corporate interests but they but
now they have like personal interests and they're and they're probably more radical than the
mainstream guys like anything can be tainted with some form of bias you know any company
any individual any institution so who do you trust and then you get to a point where it's
like well do you trust anything at all like i've i i've never been to antarctica so how do i know
that it actually exists right like it could be an entire like a huge psyop the entire world's
playing on me you can you can go down a rabbit hole joke about this but there are some people
there's a growing well it's not growing that fast but there is a portion of people who do just
don't trust anything any institution is suspect any fact is suspect look at the denialism that
has come out after october 7th of the things that everyone saw on video and suddenly there's
there's people with millions of followers with hundreds of thousands of likes on their shot shit
just making shit up and saying it and uh it gets more likes than the truth right and
yeah how do you how do you fix that because brianna woo like uh respectfully like there were
a lot of problems back when we had so much gatekeeping right like there's it held us back
so much and i don't know if we want or can go back to that style of having some kind of um
person on the top a uh uh some elite deciding what we can and can't like what i don't want
that right and that's not why i'm advocating i'm saying that i'm saying that every system has
upsides and downsides right a really big upside that system is there was an editor involved and
i think the fact that editor is no longer involved today is a real downside for how we are getting
information so you know like i think i think the fact that all of these algorithms exist to
addict you like they literally keep psychologists on staff to figure out how to addict you
i i don't have an immediate answer for this but i wonder if there's a role for us to take a more
active um in a regulatory position in asking how is so much social media affecting people's brains
right uh when the facebook whistleblower came out you know she was giving all kinds of instances
from facebook's own internal studies about what instagram is doing to an entire generation of
young women's brains and it's it's terrible it's upping their suicidality it's destroying their
body image it's leading to mental health issues i mean it's just across the board it's really really
bad and i just i'm not gonna tell you i have easy answers for this right now because all of these
problems are multi-factorial but i do think the fact that we've just basically seeded all of this
we've said we're not gonna take any role in this whatsoever i do think that's adding to the the
the instability that is really putting democracy at risk yeah you see there's like a there's another
i i mostly agree with you but there's a different way to kind of phrase it right
the downside of democratization is that people are generally retarded right and that's that's
just that's just how it is right you know man i okay i remember during the height of let's say
covid paranoia not to imply that covid wasn't real or anything i'm not going down that rabbit hole
okay i was about to say come on man i'm trying to keep my content monetized like
no no no but like there were people i remember some one person specifically said you need to
respect democracy and trust the experts and i'm like hold on those are two completely opposing
values because an expert opinion is specifically non-democratic it's the opinion of a learned
minority that is informing the unlearned majority right so when you have democratization you do
hear from more voices and that can be a good thing but also like special specialization is like is
like i don't know what the word is there there's something that is anti-democratic but also
necessary in society in order to actually try to ascertain what the truth is the the only issue is
like how can you trust that right it's we are in a quagmire like i have no solutions to this problem
i just know that at least on a local scale like within your own personal life if you do your best
to tell the truth you can make things at least somewhat better better for you and better for
people around you you know if you have a platform better for those who listen in on your platform if
you're allowed to be honest yes but i think one of the major problems with these platforms are
people are not allowed to be honest can we look can we talk about for a moment right i know this
is maybe off topic but this is bothering me ethan klein and hamas pipe oh i guess not uh give me a
second hopefully she ran away soon um i didn't kick her out gang wonder if she uh i hope her
internet's okay um we'll give it a second um in the meantime uh gang if you're enjoying this
content uh hit that like button hit that subscribe button uh feel free to follow me on twitch or
kick if you're watching me through those things hit those uh hit uh hit the sub button um throw
bits at me uh give me subs throw super chats i'll read one super chat now from testicle johnson for
five dollars i think all the chicks i think all chicks in video games should have thin
wastes and massive tits and all the dude should have five percent body fat everyone should feel
bad ten dollars from zephyr hash to say at dev i get what you're saying but how long are we
supposed to wait and how much energy are we supposed to put into making sure everyone
understands our point of view specific specifically when time is of the essence
and also welcome back brianne hi uh my computer is restarting uh so i'm on my phone so sorry
no it's okay do your thing uh let's get a scheduled windows update that got you i have no
ideas well i'm just glad you're back and we were wondering if uh if finally the leftist mob had
come for you right like that this was your time and we were going to be like hearing news reports
or something of suddenly sunday uh found your location and his mob descended upon you i don't
know right uh yeah wick i've heard that you've you've had a beef with president sunday recently
what's that all about um he made some uh he keeps making shit up and going after people um he told
aristocracy that she needed to calm down after october 7th and made some very very um untoward
comments i called him out on that and here we are um there there are some people like i will
talk with pretty much anyone you know i'll talk with very far left people i'll talk with very
far right people um the people i won't talk with are the people who actually take it offline
right so i'll never speak uh okay i'll never speak to president sunday i'll never speak to
uh ethan ralph i'll never speak nick fuentes people who actually try to like get get your
get your stuff fucked up i will never talk to those people because that's that's too far for
me well i had a i had a gentleman um i this wasn't sunday to be clear it was someone else i know who
it was um recently um basically told me he's going to try to get my channel taken away uh he got me a
warning um uh on twitch the other day because i unfortunately forgot that uh one of my guests was
banned from twitch and uh but they they remembered and so i took a ding from that but yeah there are
people who will just sit on my shit wait for me to break toss and it is what it is yep same here
i mean this is really i think this is really a very serious problem where um one of the things
i have really found recently is i've i've really really enjoyed spending more time uh reaching out
and talking to people in the right wing right like i debated uh john doyle at the the university
of south carolina just a couple of days ago i did tim pool show uh you know dev i know i speak for
myself but i'm really enjoying speaking with you tonight you know uh despite you know our history
of gamergate and i i just i don't know we're talking about gamergate eventually the chat
we will get to that but before we do we'll finish we'll finish my point yeah go ahead what i was
going to say is i don't know when we got so afraid to actually talk about ideas right um it really
feels like the left our top answer for stuff nowadays is to um just refuse to engage with
anything that's unpleasant right and it's not i understand that often there's some ideas that
just are not worth responding to um like i think we would want to take the the like a policy
proposal of a holocaust in the united states uh seriously or give that air time but for a lot of
the stuff we talk about um i i think it's so counterproductive the way we won't engage it on
its merits just before the show uh i was watching ethan and hasan debate and ethan really having
some very salient points about why one state solution would not work for israel right and uh
just hasan would not engage with that in any honest way that's a that that that sticks on the
point that i wanted to bring up before you had your computer issues uh first of all your camera
isn't up so if uh i don't know oh apologize yeah i just didn't know you know um
let's talk about ethan and asan right because dev made the point that we need to be improve our uh
improve our areas of the internet by being honest ourselves so that and so my my question on this
my uh tack on this is i don't know if we are going to be allowed to do that right and i think the way
that ethan klein has been treated uh over his what is this the third fourth discussion he's
had with us on over all this right to see the vitriol my timeline has put on ethan for simply
being upset that a bunch of people like for having pretty normie takes right you can say they're
wrong or whatever but he's just being honest like you can't say that this guy's lying about this he's
being honest and to see the way that he is just being excoriated that he is losing respect
viewership etc to be being raked over the coals he was forced to apologize right to someone who
had offended him like uh it's it's it's wild to me and i don't see it getting better i think this is
kind of at least for the the foreseeable future the new norm you are not allowed to be honest
because if you are that platform or that space you have will be taken from you um what do you
think well kind of like like sargon's still around right he's certainly not on the left
he's something further to write than me he thinks i'm a communist for example which i'm not obviously
but he's he's he's but like we're still good friends though even though if you have political
differences we're still we're still pals um but he still has he's like he exists outside of the
leftist internet bubble and he still exists you know he he opened his uh his think tank and he
has like a dozen employees and he's doing his thing so there's definitely ways for you to
exist outside of like internet leftism i think i think you can still you can still you know speak
the truth if you're not in that bubble it's hard for people who are though because you know i've
seen a lot of people who are you know they're like center left you know like someone like stardust
right get into lots of trouble with some people for for speaking out against the far left
um hmm i i have a very black-pilled opinion on this oh no i hope maybe i can be white-pilled
on it one day but i think i think there's this view i think there's this view on the left
that because so much of of academia is leftist that the right just has no worthwhile ideas to
consider which isn't true there there's there's there's some decent right-wing literature out
there for sure that's worth reading i'm going to put a pin in that because i want to ask who
who what's the best right-wing opinion out there right now well so one of the things i you know i
was very very young uh i had to get over my you know religious right mississippi indoctrination
and i look back on that actually and see it as my superpower there are a lot of things uh that i
took from that that i think are very advantageous in my professional career um i think that the
right has some ideas about personal responsibility that are just just true they they are like um a
responsibility to solve your own problems i'll give you a really concrete example when it comes
to drug addiction one of the things like i just celebrated 20 years this is bryony right you have
noticed when you talk to left-wing friends their top um thing they suggest on this is not judging
let's get aa out of the mix because they are uh you know they're a non-secular organization all
of this and i can tell you the the thing that is most helpful for getting over a drug addiction
is accountability structure standards and frankly really harsh consequences when you fail
you know this is the reason drug courts are so effective right so i think that the right does
have some really common sense ideas that make less sense about how to get to where you want
to go in life sorry for the interruption dev i just i wanted to see what we would have to say
on that but carry on please right wing ideas the part okay you know where you're at um you you just
mentioned something about um getting away from aa right okay right and earlier you mentioned
refusing to engage with unpleasantness yeah something yeah okay so there's something i've
been i've been thinking about and and i had a conversation with sitch like six months ago that
kind of sparked this idea in me and i've really been going over um wick i know that you know about
height moral foundations yes um rihanna do you know about i don't i apologize okay it's a
psychology thing um jonathan hight did did research into the psychology of morality
and he basically pointed out that there's there's six dimensions across which humans
judge things to be moral or immoral and i just pull up i'll just pull up here real quick
okay that's uh care and harm fairness and cheating loyalty and betrayal authority and
subversion sanctity and degradation liberty and oppression and what he found with his research
is that you have certain political views map onto certain um certain moral foundations which
are more more or less important to the individual and also certain personality types so when you
have what what you found is that when you talk to someone who's very very progressive they tend to
basically only to care about care and harm right so maximizing care avoiding harm can you name the
other four really quickly so i can contrast that in my mind um it's care harm fairness cheating
loyalty betrayal authority subversion sanctity degradation liberty oppression and those are the
six would uh i mean i mean we can see the liberty oppression right the oppressor what's the
difference between liberty impression and oppressor oppressed dynamic because the left is famous for
oppressor oppressed dynamics internal well in his research he found that socialists do tend to
value liberty and oppression progressives value it less than socialists um okay yeah but also like
like um uh fascists value authority overwhelmingly other than the other than the other five um you
find that conservatives tend to value loyalty more um religious people tend to value sanctity more
and progressives tend to value care and harm more liberals just like normally like central
centrist liberals tend to value fairness more right so you you have these different views of
morality that map onto different views of politics and i've seen so many very very progressive people
talk about like like harm reduction harm reduction is a great example harm reduction is like the
let's um let's not be so harsh on people who have drug addictions will give them like safe supplies
of heroin as if you ever have such a thing which is a good pro no needle programs do work we have
a lot of data about that yeah but like you also don't want to enable someone's addiction you don't
want it like like you you do want to have them to not be addicts first and foremost right sure but
i mean being out on the street like you know using dirty needles and getting all kinds of terrible
diseases it costs the public a ton of money it's not doing the many favors and it's an opportunity
to talk about getting them into treatment right that's true that's all true however you know if
if you have a different moral way of looking at it you might ask the question well i don't want to
be the person who gives a druggie some drugs that would not be obviously yeah yeah so so i agree
with you yes yeah so like there's there's different ways to view it right but you know with
with harm reduction does come the sense of if we just reduce as much harm as possible because
things are so like things are so terrible just just we have to reduce harm reduce harm you know
we can't worry about anything else just reduce the harm it's like well you're not building anything
virtuous there it's like yeah okay you're reducing harm but you're just like lessening the negative
you're not making anything positive if that makes sense so there's because you mentioned um aa and
aa has a religious component if you believe that religion is negative a net negative for society
then you might have the opinion of well i'm just gonna say fuck aa because it has these other
negative things that come along with it because i want i want the perfect answer and right isn't it
you know is this reflected just real quick and like the people who are critical of mr base who
built 100 wells or cured blindness and a thousand people and say well that's part of it because you
haven't fixed the structural issues you've just enabled the structural issues to keep uh to keep
going and your charity is actually uh causing long-term harm so yeah is that that's like that
that's part of it there's also another aspect of that though um that comes out of um angles
writing angles a socialist and marks and angles you know angle angles wrote about how basically
charity is evil because it is given at the discretion of the capitalist of the rich person
so he can make himself feel good by giving money to solve problems that he caused and it's like
well that's just ridiculous but it's like well i don't even agree with that point of view but
even if that were the truth it's still good to give the money right like the charity still has
its place but but it was his view that like well no the working class deserves the money so if you
if if a rich person gives it to them they're doing the bare minimum and you can't you can't give them
any sort of positive feedback for that and it's like well that seems almost sociopathic to me
can i circle around about something you were talking about because aa is a really good example
i think about this feeling of utopianism on the left and how this is so poorly i think it results
in really bad public policy so from my perspective my home state of mississippi has no resources
almost for drug addiction right i was very fortunate to have a family that could afford
to send me to thirty thousand dollar live at the rehab like therapy for you know two months
like and paid that out of pocket my god was i lucky about that but most people don't right
it's not going to surprise you mississippi does not have uh free for everyone drug and alcohol
uh uh treatment programs on the corner they do have a lot of churches that will lend space for
people so aa has a principle where you don't have to make god your higher power you can make aa
your higher power you can make spiritualism your higher power doesn't matter what you want to make
there are secular ways to do that and they are literally i see my own side talking about aa
as if this utopian let's make everything secular that itself is the goal the goal is not give
people that are addicted to drugs and alcohol a path to treatment and sobriety the goal is to be
morally pure and it's just so counterproductive i know more people that got sober from aa than i
do from rehab matthew perry in his book before he died have wonderful things to say about aa and i
just this is just this tendency of of having to have a perfect solution that i don't think is
resulting in good public policy yeah yeah and i think that that comes from heights moral
foundations right so i mean it's it's it's on wikipedia it's a pretty well-known idea if you
want to look at it in depth but basically like when you have two different people with two
different moral foundations you know one of them cares about care harm the other one cares about
you know loyalty betrayal so that would be like a progressive and a conservative
you put those two together they're going to view each other as immoral and not because one of them
is necessarily right and one is necessarily wrong but because they have different psychology right
so so the progressive might say hey you're hurting people with your behavior you should stop that
because we should be maximizing for care and the conservative might say you're betraying somebody
and we should stop that we should be maximizing for loyalty right so they're going to have
different they almost like it's almost like they speak a different moral language when they're
oh we do i i don't know if you've ever read this book what is the name of it it's talking about
the psychology of republicans and why um they kind of tend towards authoritarianism in ways
that the left doesn't but there is there's a like something i think that's really underappreciated
on the left is how the the foundation of how conservatives think really starts with this idea
of a a father figure in the home whose job it is to protect the family from harm in a lot of of
their of terrible ways right and that's making decisions listening providing like that's just
kind of the moral foundation of how a lot of conservatives think and i i see so many people
on my own side sneering at that but i think they're really out of touch with how a large part
of the country uh just views itself and what those relationships are like i don't know if
that's true um and let let's let's if if i may if you'll give me the title of the book if you'll
give me a minute yeah yeah it was a bestseller book but my my this idea that the right is
just tends towards more authoritarianism than the left i uh i don't know i don't it might be true
but i've seen a lot of authoritarian lefties in my day maybe it's a selection bias but i
hear this is an excellent book i highly recommend what's it called again republican brain by chris
mooney okay it is look i i think it's very clear like in recent events that the left is not pure
of this completely right but there is just more of a tendency it depends so there's like two
different types of authoritarianism right so there's like the autocratic authoritarian so the
the the strong man the person who who consolidates power into himself so that would be like the
fascist leader or the monarch you know the the singular strong entity but then on the left you
have like you have like democratic tyranny where it's it's mob rule and it's just simply by what
the majority wants which can also be very destructive so it's two different types of
authoritarianism i think yeah even then though right there are uh portions of the left um
though i guess some more authoritarian portions um that are democratic to an extent but then they
say something should never be voted on and it happens to be their most important uh values
as they think right like that yeah and so i don't i don't i don't know i don't know i'd have to look
into it more um i'm i well i i think i think that's just a practical necessity of obtaining
and wielding power you know that's just kind of how it has to be oh speaking of practical
necessities and uh retaining and wielding power and things like that um what do we think if i may
get your guys to i i see you chat i see you chat i know you want to talk about the gamer gate thing
i will ask a question about gamer gate thing i will i promise but let me let's let's let's save
it for the end to say about gamer gate is there anything new to say well we haven't sent it to
each other exactly exactly we will bury this hatchet but first right i am gonna spoil i i'm
not gonna get in a fight tonight i'm just not okay that's that's fine that's fine um but let
me ask this question instead uh for now um what do we think is the most likely outcome of this
upcoming election so tuesday we got a glimpse i think of where at least policy-wise the electorate's
at right now uh republicans got thrashed um ohio um formalized abortion and it's a uh a codified
abortion i should say and it's a constitution uh the virginia or the kentucky i should say the
kentucky governor won reelection he's a democrat uh almost across the board democrats had a really
good night um we could juxtapose that with the doom and gloom we saw on social media about how
people never vote democrat never vote for biden never vote for anyone um that isn't calling for
a ceasefire etc etc etc um but do we think that this uh constant calls will have an effect going
forward on the 2024 election these constant calls to just boycott um biden boycott um the left or
anything or or is this all just hot air i gotta be honest i have not paid attention to american
politics in the past week or so so i don't know what you're useless to me okay fair enough sorry
whoo go ahead uh i i think it's very serious um you know uh i i think as part of my job i did look
a lot at the the outcome from tuesday obviously i'm happy when democrats win uh don't read too
much into it okay just don't uh biden's poll numbers are extremely weak right now we're seeing
the number of muslims that are currently planning to vote for him i'm not talking
to twitter conversations i'm talking about real polls uh it's not a good situation uh his numbers
with jewish people are down as well uh if the election were held today joe biden would lose
by a lot and joe mansion is not deciding not to run again because he's tired of having power
he's not running again because he's looking at biden uh he's seeing a path for him to win the
presidency this is extremely obvious and we need to take this really seriously the reason biden is
failing right now in the polls is the first best job of the president is to lead on messaging
and look i think he's been a really consequential president but he um he is older and it affects
his ability to give speeches and connect emotionally with the with the public and um
his current strategy of hiding is not working out uh his uh you know his campaign has 91 million
dollars on hand the last time i checked uh they need to be investing massively uh across the board
in messaging and helping set a new conversation in my view yeah i mean biden's kind of a zombie
at this point he's he's really old it's there's no way to remedy that when you're that old you're
just you're just kind of done to be honest at the same time like there have been some some things to
come out of his administration that i like i really like the chips act yeah yeah i have always i've
been i feel like i'm a hipster when it comes to china i was where i was worried about them before
it was cool to be worried about china but um like there's been some if you if you stay plugged into
like the right wing online ecosystem you you'd think that the world's completely falling apart
and it's not there's some problems but it's not nearly that bad um but i do think that biden just
i think based almost solely on his age and now maybe on the october 7th response like he might
not be the guy for for the democrats but at the same time um the republicans are in shambles as
well you know all of those republican primaries are basically just the the the debate of who is
going to eventually lose to trump and trump seems to be he he's not a very good president
and he's also extremely popular on the right yeah so gotta get more serious
yeah okay i mean it it's the man trump's like a wild card right now right because for 2024
imagine the possibility of trump wins the election and then also gets convicted on one of
those one of those charges what a shit show oh my holy shit but like if trump's gone you know if if
he if he actually is found guilty and he's locked away and he can't be president like who do the
republicans have i i think this is what rhonda santis is hoping for just a miracle at this point
so um yeah yeah i don't think they rally around this but anyway i don't want to get too much into
finish your thought uh dev and uh basically if we're just talking strategy de santis should
have waited he should have waited for trump's i like to for trump to finally be either vanquished
or get a second term and then come along next time this was not the time for i think i think
de santis basically destroyed his political career jumping in maybe um i know that uh
it would be an open question at this point right who would take that uh standard from
trump trump goes away unfortunately i don't think trump's going away i think that uh whoever
that biden will be facing trump in the 2024 runoff um and we'll see uh i i see the polling today
the polling isn't uh it isn't comforting not to say the least but years a long time years a long
time i guess to to kind of maybe bring it into something that you have been following
um we've seen israel's messaging um of light how do you think they're doing dev do you see the
snl style skit they did the other day no i didn't see that either you didn't dev what are you are
you not paying attention to anything i've been away for a little bit i've been away for a little
bit sorry oh you're killing me bro you kill me okay um i i do know that like man when it comes
to the the israel-palestine conflict as a whole i'm like soft pro-israel but soft pro-israel you
know but man it's that's that's just that's just a shit show you have basically two sides that
i think beneath the mask they both want to genocide each other and one side is capable
of doing it the other side if the power balance were reversed they would be doing it so it's like
well like what the fuck you're gonna do at that point i don't think there's much that that the
west can do frankly i think it's like a hopeless situation fair enough i think we are seeing i was
talking to a really good uh jewish friend of mine about this about why there's such a generational
divide on on israel right now and i think it really comes down to the fact you know my friend
i believe he's in his uh 60s you know i'm in my 40s and yet we're both old enough to remember when
israel was really making a public messaging push and trying to help the public understand
why like the need for israel to exist was important you know things like that right now
we're really seeing one side uh make that case particularly to the left and uh you know i think
that when israel comes out and uh their response to a whole bunch of civilians getting killed in a
a strike that hits a hospital uh to basically kill one person it's like civilians die in war
which is nearly a direct paraphrase of what they said um you know it's it's really bad
messaging right um so i think uh anyone serious about uh national security will tell you that
um you're weighing the hearts and minds of people helping them understand and empathize with you is
a really critical part of that i think under netanyahu uh they're basically running the exact
same playbook that bush did which is harder right harder fringe messaging doing it in really moral
terms and not really making that effort to make the same number of friends so uh no wick i think
uh israel has been really really bad at messaging lately and i think if they don't change course i
think it's going to be there's going to be less and less willpower in washington to support them
and certainly all this uh you know horrific inexcusable level of civilian death is not
aiding that either so um i think they're i think it's really dire it has been a kind of like a mind
fuck almost yeah to watch the horrific images coming out of gaza um coming out of the airstrikes
and things like and then to have israel um put out an snl skit about it right um and you're like
someone is making these decisions consciously like is someone that they need to replace whoever
is in charge of that i understand why they're doing it i understand why they think they need
to use memes and comedy to appeal to the youth because as polling recently has shown
to put it mildly israel has a youth problem here in the west um they have been bleeding
support um from like again it's it's just a thing we grew up knowing that america supports israel
but i don't know if that's going to be the same in 20 years from now right
as the new cohort takes power and seeing not only the online response but also the polling also uh
the massive amounts of youth young people going into the streets not just saying free palestine
but gas the jews kill the jews israel needs to be destroyed intifada intifada from britain to gaza
right um there is a problem here um and i think israel knows it has to try to
reverse that trend i just don't think it knows how um what do you think that was just a public
messaging problem i think that you know look netanyahu and lakud party i mean they've taken
israel in a very very right wing direction and i think anyone that's being paid anyone that's
been paying attention to this including i would say the majority of jews in this country have
been increasingly um disturbed by the foreign policy direction of israel for quite a while
right so i certainly see that i don't think it's just a messaging problem i think it's
actually kind of analogous to america's reputation in the world following the iraq war right you know
no no any thoughts on this dad before we move on
if i were to like put myself in the headspace of somebody who let's say is very pro israel
who's who's in israel and is very pro israel i it feels like what they're probably thinking
is something like they saw what happened on october 7th and they saw all the memes come out
about paragliders and they're like oh okay so i guess we're just cool with killing civilians
and memeing about it now and so they're saying well then let's do that for our side
fair enough i don't think i think they real they they don't realize though that's not how
how the game works here we don't yeah it's not it's not tit for tat it's um we do it to egg you
on so that when you do it we can call you out for it and ignore that we did it too and then just
paint you as the worst actor ever uh fair enough uh let me read a super chat i got for you and then
we'll move on to the next question 10 bucks from lives and dev's walls i'm assuming it's someone
from your community sir yes how do we restore faith in or the integrity of necessary institutions
amid clear failures stopping the spread of ludicrous conspiracies requires viable claims
to be handled properly the way epstein wasn't and i would and this is my words now right to
maybe move away from the epstein thing one of the reasons that people think especially you think
america bad is because of the horrendous way that america handled foreign policy with the afghan
and iraq war especially the iraq war right um and the just uh abysmal failures um from the
foreign policy community um and how we have handled all these things so to his question
how do we restore faith in the integrity of it because just because america is wrong sometimes
doesn't mean america is wrong all the time but that seems to be the lesson that a lot of people
took from the last 20 years is that america is just that right so i i can speak to this from
the the point of view of like more right-wing people that i know right because they all believe
that 2020 was a stolen election i did on the night of 2020 and i don't now and i went through
a process of figuring out why it wasn't so i'm sure you've both seen that that that video that's
been shared around millions of times where the polling station closes up and then one of the
workers you know pulls back the tablecloth and brings out a case of new ballots right
then wheels it over and starts counting the narrative on the night of the election was
that that was a case full of fraudulent ballots right and it needed to be investigated and it
needed to be it needed to be answered for like why is this woman pulling these ballots out
um and that's what everyone was saying including me on the night of the election
um it turned out that as the as the court cases and went through and the audits went through and
all all these sorts of things to see if the election was actually real or not it turns out
that um if you actually go back and like read some of the buried articles about that specific case
the judge said okay i sat down and i watched all the security camera footage and that was
actually a case full of legitimate ballots that was brought in earlier and the reason that it was
brought in is because republicans in that state had changed the laws such that mail-in ballots
could not be counted until after all the other ballots were counted so they were just being
stored under the table until it was time to count them so it was actually one of those things where
republicans changed the law and then it created a video that they got that they then had a
conspiracy theory about right but all of my right-leaning friends didn't keep up with any
of these investigations or any of these trials or any of these audits they they had you know
that the 15 that the 15 minutes news cycle on twitter and then moved on to the next thing right
and so after a month or two of investigations no one's talking about it anymore so
pretty much like i i kept i kept my finger on the pulse of all these stories because i wanted
to know but like nobody else that i know on the right did and now here we are three years on and
people are still bringing up that exact same video clip as if it's as if it's it's proof of something
and it's not so i i think it's it's social media it's a shortened attention span and it's people
being in echo chambers and and that is causing people to spin up completely different theories
about about how things are actually functioning and because they never actually return back to
rethink those ideas through they just kind of sit in their brains for for a few years that becomes
what actually happened we see it playing out live like we see this video i saw of a helicopter an
apache helicopter blowing away hamas terrace it was originally shared saying that it was israel
just indiscriminately firing into the crowd at the uh the rave killing both innocent civilians
and hamas terrace and see look the idf calls most of these deaths um it was obviously shown to be
no they were attacking an entirely different place these were just hamas terrace that were trying to
run back into gaza after they had done their thing uh but it was too late it had gotten millions of
views hundreds and thousands of likes and no one's going to go back to that right no one's
going to to check it again it's now it's now it's now a fact and they are going to run with it right
yeah after it goes viral people aren't going to come back you know a week later or a month later
after the investigation is done they're just going to remember it as it was i think that's why like
you know look i i hear what you're saying about this being a problem it's certainly correct my
mind always always always goes what is the public policy solution how can we how can we start to do
this i think like something i'm trying to do as a public figure and someone that works in this
field and trying to talk more with people on the other side and trying to have civil conversations
i think it's really important for those of us to model this i think that but i think the real
problem that's really difficult to solve is it really comes down to the algorithm right we have
a fundamentally different information space now that rewards sensationalism it rewards conflict
it rewards hyperbole and it it's how do you square that with the fact i think all of us here
agree with free speech we agree with open expression we don't want anyone censoring those
hot takes but we've got to come up with the way that the american people are being better served
by the information that we're getting and let's be really clear this is not just an american
problem democracy is weakening all around the world and yet this being the way we consume
information is part of why it's it's destabilizing our country so i think this is i think it's really
really important and i i don't think that say facebook should have the amount of power it does
over the news uh that they do um maybe the answer is break them up i i truly don't know
but i i think something's got to change i don't know about uh policy uh like policies that can
be adopted to uh to improve this i'm not sure about that i do know that i have very little
influence over policy but i can control what i do right and so i can at least do better personally
and that's at least a little bit like you know if you are part of the world and you are if you
do better you've made the world slightly better so if all i can do is look at it from an individualist
perspective then that's what i do fair enough fair enough okay i'm going to ask the question
that my audience i know i know i know but it's it's it's here it's the elephant in the room and again
um well we gotta talk about it gamergate i've thought about the best way to do this
conversation for a little bit well then why not take it take it away dev man go ahead okay um
you don't have to get too in detail i guess but what was gamergate about from your
side from your perspective because you were anti-gamergate i was pro-gamergate so
since you're on opposite sides of the conversation i mean having seen me talk about this a million
times in media i mean so gamergate was about a organized harassment campaign against women in
the game industry i know y'all don't want to believe it was a real thing it was it hurt a lot
of people's lives and her reputations many of my friends quit the game industry uh permanently and
it was uh in my view the start of this playbook that when someone's saying or doing something you
don't like uh investigate them go through everything they've ever said find something
to smear them with and uh just try to destroy them by the with the mob um well speaking of
destroying with the mob sunday thanks for watching i see you making tweets about me
yeah you know i hope you like the channel as well but continue
so that's basically it what about you dev from your perspective so
um the pro-gamergate side is that it wasn't about harassment and it was actually about
there was ethical problems in in the gaming industry at the time
and i was definitely on board for the ethical problems i breanna i think you saw my my video
about phil fish and the investigation that i did like 10 years ago into the actual ethical
problems that that he was a part of because he did do some underhanded stuff um stardust at one
point when she when she was going to talk to you actually like was it six months ago or a year ago
or something yeah she she asked me about gamergate because she knew that i was involved in it and i
gave her my playlist of gamergate videos and she went she went through a few of them just to get
get a feeling of what it was like on the pro-gamergate side back then and i watched
a bit of her reacting to my old videos i hadn't seen my videos in 10 years and in the second video
i specifically say at the very start okay before we get in today's into today's content
i see that some of you guys are are actually harassing people and you guys need not to do
that you need to stop that shit so i was definitely even back then very cognizant about
the fact that there were some people who were taking it too far and also there were some people
who were simply hitching themselves to the situation to try and boost their own career
right people don't know this nowadays but milo came out of gamergate right yep um uh mike
cernovich came out of gamergate milo yanopoulos to be clear yes okay fair enough yeah yeah they
both yeah i don't have any issue with that yeah i've been friends with hat for my god 10 years
now right like he's one of those people trained as a journalist genuinely interested in the
the ethical concerns of that i just i think if all of us on this show tonight agree that uh the
outcome of progressive policies right now isn't always talking about health care it's about a
bunch of unrelated like cultural things that we do that are are not ethical i think we can
be honest and that like gamergate did a lot of that as well what's your biggest regret dev
what's your biggest regret from the gamer gate years my biggest regret from the gamer gate years
is that when phil fish sent me a cease and desist i listened to it and i took my video down
because i shouldn't have i shouldn't have given in to that kind of uh intimidation
can you just remind me like i like i i haven't spoken to phil in like
10 years but can you remind me what your ethical issue was with him
basically he he uh his game fez was the only game to win an award at the igf for two separate years
sure and one of them was for the demo of fez and one of them was for the actual release of fez
and the igf kind of hand waved up by saying oh it's a demo so it's not the same game
but it's the only game they give that treatment to that treatment too and then when phil fish's
company got hacked it came out that there were a bunch of people who were judges at the igf who
had invested in his company and they served and they they they were in a position to to
personally profit from the fact that the ig that that fez won so many awards and and was the only
game to win awards in two separate years it was like 2007 2012 or something like that yeah that's
pretty bad uh in to play i'm not defending that fez is a really good game though yeah yeah yeah
but i hear i hear you that's not defensible obviously they should uh ever use themselves
i just think you know directionally if you look at the state of the game industry today
i mean uh let's just be blunt uh ign is weaker than it's ever been kotaku hasn't been a force in
in the game industry in a while and you know when it comes to game coverage i think you know
skill up do a really good job uh but i think there's a whole host of youtubers that do
a much much worse job and they are directly being paid by these companies to come cover their
product right so i think if you look at i i just haven't seen that same level of anger at the
current state of the game industry which i think is way more rife with problems than it was a decade
ago i mean i'm i'm still like i'm still a pretty small channel in terms of the big leagues right
i know that like 150 000 subs is like kind of big but it's also kind of small to be honest
i don't have millions i don't have that much much reach um no i still talk 150 000 okay you know
what i mean like like there's guys out there with millions of subs yeah yeah so much i'm i'm okay
what i mean to say is like i can only do so much but i do talk about like shitty youtubers as well
sure on my channel yeah i i do my part channel mostly you shut a lot of progressives on tik tok
you have a like most of your videos are tik tok tuesday nowadays which is a shame because i like
your last foreign content so much more that is it's only because i'm lazy and and your situation
with them causing so much noise at your house so fair yeah there's been there's been some
construction and also i've been quite lazy do you think um i guess i'll ask this right
for the many years you've been covering culture around games games etc um dev what is what is
have we improved overall or as rihanna wu has asserted have we have we just gotten worse i know
for me right when i was growing up and i wanted to know if a game was good there was some magazines
i would read or pick up or Nintendo power yeah things like that i would look through them and
i would get the strategy there no ethical issues yeah i would get the strategy guides and things
like that and i would pour through them i would go to blockbuster and look at the cool games that
were up for rent and i'd do that nowadays if i want to get a game right uh or if i want to see
if a game is worth getting uh i will go and look at either a youtube playthrough through it and see
some reviews or a let's play i will go to the steam user reviews and kind of click through a
few of them positive negative um so that as a normie someone who isn't like a super gamer
that's how i usually engage with the gaming industry today versus back then so i guess from
someone who covers that kind of thing and someone who i would consider much more of a gamer and a
nerd than i am um dev what better worse what do you think
hmm i don't think it's better or worse i think it's very different things have definitely
changed but i think we're probably about the same level as we were well then let's go to individual
let's go away from the the overall then so what into an individual instance is what do we do
better and what do we do worse okay um well gaming press like you said breanna gaming press
is definitely weakened right like all these sites are shutting down and and the the institution the
the career of journalists doesn't have the prestige that it used to have so that's probably worse
right and now you can argue whether or not that's because they were bad at their jobs or whether it
was because we don't respect them anymore it's probably a mix of both because there's been some
really bad journalism as well um the issue with youtubers and this goes beyond what you're what
you're mentioning wick but it does also involve this um is that youtubers don't take themselves
seriously enough i think and streamers don't take themselves seriously enough this is not related
to gaming but have you met streamers like i what we take ourselves way too seriously but go on
i meant in terms of like professional ethics oh fair enough that's true but we take ourselves
super seriously go on drama yes but like okay okay this is not related to gaming but it
definitely you can use this logic on a whole bunch of gaming youtubers right do you remember recently
um hasan i think he went on it was on national tv or it was somewhere and he said i'm just a
streamer man i have no control over anything i can't i can't control what my audience does
i can't i can't set any sort of narrative and it's like hold on if you're the biggest leftist
streamer in the world you should have some ability to set the narrative are we talking
about hamas piker okay gary yes that's what we're talking about but like that's not gaming but the
point still stands is that like if you have a platform and it's a reasonably big platform like
we're talking like millions of subs or you know tens of thousands of viewers on twitch or something
you do have the ability to to set to set um to set conversations basically yeah and i and i think
that streamers they when it comes time for them to let's say be ethical in how they behave they
say i'm just a guy in my living room in my bedroom i don't know what's going on i can't affect
anything but when it comes time for them to take massive bags of cash from ubisoft or whoever they
take the massive bag of cash you know what i mean i do know what you mean um let me ask you directly
then um okay how do you fill your audience in this how do you abdicate your responsibility
have you or are you above the fray
well i don't take massive bags of cash there's that's one thing like i i've made i've made a
deal with myself that if i'm ever going to do out like a product sponsorship for example
it has to be something that i actually like and use myself i won't i won't like i know i don't
use vpns um until i start using one i'm not going to take a deal for a vpn for my channel right
it's one of those it's one of those types of things that's kind of how i view it is like
i i want even if you disagree with me i want people to trust in the fact that i'm saying what
i actually think even if you don't like it yeah yeah i feel the same way i take a i take a lot of
pride in the you know my professional integrity i mean i really try very hard to tell the truth
i try to answer questions even when they're unpleasant when they're asked of me and i try
to engage issues honestly and yeah sometimes that comes from critiquing my own side um you know and
it's it's hard i mean i feel like all the incentives now this is something i see over
and over again in the streaming space like wick my assessment is there are a lot of really
fundamentally dishonest people in this space it's really hard trying to figure out who to talk to
who to interact with who not to what have you uh like so i know we've talked off screen right
about different people and things like that but i i just want to get a well i have two questions
for you one to go back to the same question i asked dev and speaking of asking hard questions
um i know you talked about um how one of your regrets is keeping it online and not taking it
offline and do things but other than that regarding your behavior towards others right
yeah do you have any regrets oh my god can you absolutely maybe talk about that a little bit
and then i i did i my second question to keep in mind would be um that since we live in as dev set
a space where there are people with a lot of influence who's abdicated for it how do you how
do you sift the wheaten from the chaff who do you decide how to why did you pick me to to work with
instead of sunday for example like like how do you how do you filter i guess go on well you're
not a congenital liar well true but no you know what i mean i'm being hyperbolic but you know what
i'm saying how do you sift the wheat from the chat so i feel like i've answered the same question a
million times i'll do it again um you know i know gamergate wants to pretend like what they did
didn't traumatize me but it did i had a clinical ace of trauma alive women in the game industry
also had clinical aces of trauma um it fucking broke me uh the stuff that went on um
so i can look back at my behavior and see how reactive and angry i was and i was not
always responding to things in a way that was productive right so i think if i did it over
again you know i would have unplugged from twitter a lot sooner um i think i would have
held on a lot of media appearances until i could react without so much anger in the moment um
so i just you know i feel like i squandered this opportunity to really advocate for better policy
for women in the the game industry and just on a personal note you know i cause so much pain
like one of the things is when you're traumatized you you you hurt the people around you um you know
i hurt my friends um i hurt uh you know i love frank dearly but i think he saw me at uh the
worst in some ways during gamergate right um so just just in the the midst of trauma i acted with
a lot of pain into things i'm not proud of right i do want to point out real quick sure um my
my involvement with gamergate was only on the ethics side of it and i certainly wasn't
responsible for any of that i'm sorry that it happened to you though i appreciate that thank
you can we can consider the hatchet berry of enemies uh of all they become i consider you a
friend i mean i well maybe not a friend i think we have a respect for each other we have a respect
for each other right like i like you i like your content i don't agree i preferred friend but okay
let's see if you want to be my friend i'll be your friend what's up dev what's what's your favorite
part what's your favorite thing about brianna woo today what's your favorite what's brianna
woo's best quality what do you like about her most friend of brianna
irrespective of of how victimized you were 10 years ago you definitely had some crazy takes
yeah back then and you do not seem like that crazy person now and that's actually that's
actually quite heartening because so many people just get worse over time well i i'm sure that
that probably sounded like a backhanded combat i didn't mean it to you but i i get it i think
that running for office did teach me a hell of a lot about how to advocate for things that i
believed in right um so i think that was part of it was a real growing up experience so um thanks
i guess i i would hope that you would see me as somebody with integrity
you know do you make friends a lot dad do you have a lot of friends like uh just curious
kind of okay i have you you recognize that it was just a like sort of a shit answer but go on
no it's it's there's a lot of people that that i think can't stand me and sometimes i wonder why
and it's like well like is it my personality that's a problem is it like but then i realize
usually it's because like i'm i'm pretty honest and that can drive a lot of people away and it
doesn't mean that i'm like a perfect truth teller i just i i do i i don't i talk the same way online
is off i talk the same way public as in private you know i found that just like keeping secrets
and kind of like being a backroom schemer it it makes you a worse person in the long run
so i don't do that and that rubs some people the wrong way but five dollars from cryborn to say i
like brianna's pragmatism and recent work with bringing together left-wing streamers thank you
for the five dollars and thank you for a good example of a good answer to that question um
i guess uh
well same thing uh i think you already said about his videos but
you consider him a friend what about him that you like right personally i i think you have
really insightful criticisms of the right and the left um i don't i don't think you're as much of a
centrist from my point of views i think you you you tell yourself that you are but i think you
are i'm sorry am i a right winger from your point of view i don't know if right winger i think you
have a kind of instinctual distrust of anything um i think that when someone comes to you and
tells you they don't feel like they're getting a fair shake in society i think you have a kind of
instinctual uh tendency to dismiss that um that and i don't think you're coming to that like
inauthentically or i don't think it's egregious right uh i i just i don't think it's the right
answer right uh but what i appreciate about you is i think in the the course of your i think you
produce some extremely thoughtful videos i think you're actually a really friendly person and
honestly i really this is silly thing but the way you talk about your um is it your girlfriend or
your wife naomi uh it's really apparent how much you care for her and uh i i think that uh i don't
know it just makes my heart grow three sizes every time i hear that i'm actually told that
a lot that like i relate whenever our relationship bleeds into online people really like it yeah
yes how did y'all meet if i can ask um we both worked the same awful part-time job back when i
was in school yeah and we just kind of stayed together even after i left you know no five
dollars from artemis fowl dev is my favorite white nationalist communist
thank you oh my god so yeah like there was that there was that one short of demon mama
demon almost called me a fascist so many times at this point but there was that one where like
it was demon mama was lambasting you for talking to me brianna meanwhile i can go to some very far
right youtube channels where i'm being discussed and i'm like this leftist subversive communist
cuck who's trying to get into right-wing spaces to like convert people so one of the big reasons
why i do think that i'm a centrist is because so many people say the same things about me on two
extreme sides but they're inverted and it's like okay there's something here i think there's something
i deal with that too dev that doesn't make me a centrist i'm not you know like the exact same
thing happens to have the left screaming at me i've certainly had the right screaming at me
i mean how is it's it's the same thing right maybe the difference um i have a i have a saying
i've been this is i think this is gonna become my like my dev saying this would be my branding
it's this idea that um governments should be liberal and people should be conservative
that's kind of how i i lay out my approach to politics because can you elaborate on that
sure sure so um when it comes to government policy like big big ticket things what what federal level
governments should do in america or in canada or in other other similarly sized states i tend
to agree more with liberals than with conservatives not consistently you know i'm definitely more pro
gun than the average canadian for sure but i mean my stance on health care i think americans would
consider americans who aren't terminally online would consider to be far left right something
like that however when it comes to how i think you should organize your life on a personal level on
like a local level i'm much more conservative because i think those things are generally just
better for people right you know like having having you know uh a good family life for example
that's that's more of a that's more of a conservative thing than let's say a progressive
thing but it's very important for people right having like more traditional family roles people
tend to be happier on average when they engage with those with with those types of of lifestyles
it doesn't mean you should be forced into it there's lots of conservatives that think you
should be forced into it i don't think that at all right if you're if you're you know cut from
a different cloth then go ahead and do your thing right here's a good example okay so i think i was
talking to dylan burns a few months back um and i want like i was outlying to him you know the
conservative case for gay marriage right and basically the the argument that i was playing
to him is let's say that you're a young gay man and you have two life paths ahead of you right
and down one life path is you could get into like a monogamous relationship and adopt some kids and
raise them right get a decent job and contribute to your community be a be a productive person
you know and but these are all very conservative things even though it's a gay person doing them
or you could you know go go to the gay bar and be very promiscuous maybe catch a few diseases
you know debase yourself debase other people make people not proud of you you know what what would
be you're allowed to to to engage in hedonism because that's what a free society is but
what should you do you know what would be better for you what we what would be better for
the people around you if we what what character should you have as a person right and it seems
like more often than not organizing your life in a conservative way not necessary not necessarily
a religious way but a conservative way does seem to make people happier and healthier so
on the local level i'm pretty conservative on the national level i'm pretty liberal
you know i've been married for 15 years i'm a pretty you know i've got a house i've got a
job you know like i i certainly agree with that i think where i i would really ask you and i don't
mean this disrespectfully but my my critique of you would be the exact same as tim pool in
the sense that there's such a a disproportionate amount of of um criticism that i think happens
on your channel right um and and i agree with that like i certainly have had plenty of criticism for
the fringe left lately but it's also true my day job is 100 about beating the republicans at the
ballot box right that's what i'm paid you know to do so i mean how can you see yourself in the
middle when so much of your content is about going after the left the main reason i do that
is because it's very criticism of the rights very simple right we all kind of intuitively get it's
like you know should you oppress gay people no obviously right like should you be racist
no it doesn't it doesn't take much brain power to explain why you shouldn't be a racist or why
you shouldn't be a homophobe you can easily lay these arguments out criticism of the leftist
complex it takes a lot more thought um you have to understand a lot more about i think about
certain things because i i think it's not that it's not that leftist ideas are necessarily more
complicated it's that they're more ubiquitous you know what i mean it's like it's here it's like
you know what is your your stereotype of a conservative it's like a you know like a you
know a redneck living in a flyover state who's kind of an educated he might be a bigot right
he's kind of an easy enemy to attack in a sense like what is your average left-leaning person
well he generally higher IQ generally makes more money lives in a more affluent area he seems to
have more markers of success going his way it is in terms of philosophy leftism i think is in a
stronger position than rightism and so it requires more in-depth critiques i think i i hear with i
hear what you're saying and i agree with you the problem with leftism is a more interesting
conversation i i think the reason i think a problem i see consistently on your channels i
think you really underestimate the cultural power of the right i just went to south carolina
to debate john doyle i talked to a lot of students on campus i talked to a lot of people down there
in the south it was really conservative and i think that uh your vantage point of living in
canada and having your perceptions of the country primarily filtered through media i think if you
had worked in election cycle in ohio or new hampshire i think that that would really change
your perception very very quickly yes it also might be the case that um canada does not have
the same kind of right wing that america does yeah well i think that's that's just also a you
big like just a true statement right yes obviously canada the right wing and america right wing i
think are not in the same place and now you can point to some um overlap i know that canada
canadians often complain about how american politics kind of seeps over the border a little
bit uh and influences their uh electorate and things like that i i yeah it's just different
problems different things if i may read a couple super chats um and then i will kind of wrap this
up but i want to take calls do you guys want to take some calls right yeah let's do it people in
here let me read these super chats and uh and and have some closing thoughts here and then we'll get
into i had a couple of questions i wanted to ask down oh no if you have questions by all means i
will i'll step back but money first money first five dollars from lives and death walls public
service announcement just buy a tortilla press and masa harina more than worth the extra effort for
the difference in quality the leftovers can be made into chips well thank you for such a uh that
service announcement it will be go to service and two dollars from the same individual nooms is cool
i'm assuming noons is naomi um yes fair enough i gotta go i'll be back in a second oh oh and
i guess in the meantime then gang if you're liking this content if you're enjoying what you're saying
uh feel free to hit that like button hit that subscribe button um if you're following me on
kick or on twitch uh hit the follow button and throw some bits my way subs my way if you want
to have your chat read on stream i will do so for your money if you give me your money i will read
it uh we got some great things coming up uh next week on monday we're gonna have pixie we're gonna
have xena and we're gonna have cherry we're gonna talk about mental illness in the streaming world
that should be fun uh tuesday will be food shops versus uh admiral gibbs admiral gibbs has made the
audacious claim that food shops supports hamas and so we're going to have uh we're gonna have him
uh defend his assertation and food shops will be there to challenge that um i am also going to be
talking uh to no opinion saktan left and brianna whoa on thursday the 16th um that will be fun
that's a i don't know if you guys know who no opinion is he's one of the largest uh sub i
think he is the largest sub stack uh out there um he's got hundreds and thousands of followers and
readers um and he's been making blog posts about sucked on left and brianna will brianna will you
gotta mention in his latest one i don't know if you read it um and so yeah we connected and he
wants to talk to him and so i'm going to facilitate that conversation that should be fun i'm really
looking forward to that he is so smart and so thoughtful i really appreciate him well he's
he's very left-leaning right but i think he sees a lot of the same well what's the title of his
latest piece give me uh let me get get it up a second it's basically uh yes it's possible to
imagine progressive dystopias so he has seen a lot and been very critical of the left the far left's
response some among the far left's response to the october seventh thing and so he has really
come out and stood against that so it should be a fun and interesting discussion he's also so pro
national security very very smart on national security i'm not in this war hawk like you know
let's bomb our way to utopia kind of way like really thoughtful about uh you know what our
investment in the military gets us the good sides the downsides our need to you know think about uh
when we're talking america withdrawing from the world uh what happens when china and russia uh
go into the power vacuum just just a really thoughtful person so i'm really looking forward
to this i'm very very curious uh ten dollars from artemis fowl can anyone tell me why lefties are
up in arms about giving palestinians a state slash one state but don't say anything about
kurtistan or tibet seems like progs are simply hypocritical i for one remember when free tibet
was the left's reason to tear right like they were very big on free tibet um i i don't know
uh to answer your question i'm not sure uh what do you think what do i think about that uh
uh no i really agree with that i think that there's something
i i don't want to accuse people of like it only being about anti-semitism but it's hard to not
notice that some people are being held to a different rule set uh when it comes to this so
maybe a more charitable answer would be that looking at the uh you know oppressor oppressed
dynamics and having that be your pathway to coming with every single answer is not always
a very good way to do it probably so welcome back i'm back i'm back yeah i know honestly
i think when it comes to tibet it's honestly because 20 years ago china was not nearly as
powerful as it is now that's simply that's just it and you think because they are now
a major power that the left has stopped uh they're they're a major power and there's
multiple avenues for them to morally browbeat people who are far left they can use the race
angle they can use the socialist angle it's very easy for them to say to say whatever it is to to
get them to stop talking about tibet because that was like a leftist cause 20 years ago yeah
absolutely free tibet was a big thing um i know that brianna had questions just a couple questions
okay i want you to look over here do you see this corner my office that is an original parasite
poster from uh japan and that is the original final fantasy 8 poster from japan those cost me
an ungodly amount of money so i wanted to ask uh why are these both uh uh these this is the
soundtrack to your channel so i've always wanted to ask you is parasite eve like is that an
important game for you the same way it is for me um i don't know how important it is i don't
think it's on my top 10 but it's really it's on my top 20 for sure as far as the soundtrack it's
got to be in the top oh so so when i'm choosing soundtracks i'm i'm looking for something that
fits a specific not it's not droning droning is not the right word but it's kind of like droning
where it's almost like investigative all right so i use yeah that's why i use the timber soundtrack
well that was uninvestigated that was goofy yeah right okay but but like parasite even a lot of
parasite eve tracks um the police station for sure and also the central park track yes those
are both they both feel like you're in an investigation so i use those for for investigative
videos oh i was hoping you were a huge fan that's so sad no i i am a huge fan but i'm not like
they're like man it is in my top 20 so i guess i am like a pretty big fan but i'm not like the top
tier of fan if that makes sense okay fair enough my favorite game of all time is earthbound which
is a very lefty answer i love earthbound good game i have an original earthbound and i don't
even want to tell you how much i spent on that is it is it inbox with with the book no no i don't
do that i i have games to play so um but uh yeah i love that thing oh my gosh i think you know
it like for all this talk about like making america great again i think that there's a
political movement based on just bringing back the greatness to the video game industry of that ps1
square soft era of games which gave you vagrant story which gave you ein hander which is this
under valued amazing ps1 shooter with the most amazing soundtrack like all the final fantasies
final fantasy tactics all of these games make a movement to like bring that back to the game
industry and i don't even care if it's fascism i will be on board with that i miss that so much
yeah there were some good games and man their attempts to like redo it they're really hit and
miss like you go play like oh yeah traveler yeah like upper hill is pretty good but it's not the
same as like final fantasy 6 it lacks it kind of it's hard to put my finger on right it's
the certain if you will it just it feels too formulaic too clean too um too processed i guess
when you're playing octopax traveler it's the fact that you can play as all the characters
or none at any point in time so they can't have any meaningful interactions with each other
so it's always like a lack of meaningful choice is what you're saying to me no not choice
interactions so if you play like like a final fantasy 6 or a final fantasy 7 the characters
are always going to have the same interactions at the same point in the story right yeah you
play it multiple times if you play octopath traveler because you can get you can recruit
the characters in any order you want all of their plot lines happen independently of each other
and they never had the characters never feel like they're actually on an adventure together
and that's a big problem um second big problem is that the writing is just needs to be edited down
there's like three times too much dialogue in octopath and i think that's because like
if you're thinking back to like the ps1 or the snes you're uh like and you're thinking back to
when you were like nine years old or something because i was i was pretty young when those games
came out the it feels like in your memory there's way more dialogue than there actually is yeah if
you go back to like final fantasy 6 right now and just like emulate it and speed through it there's
not much dialogue not really um but it felt like a lot as a kid so to get the same feel they just
bloat the dialogue up in a game like octopath traveling just way too much i don't i feel like
one of the things that made final fantasy 6 so good is they really thought about the amount of
grinding that you have to do one of the reasons 8 is so great is because grinding doesn't do
anything for you in final fantasy 8 and you can actually like you can do a final fantasy 6 play
through in 10 hours if you know where you're going so i think i think these games are so bloated
nowadays that they lose a lot of that magic in my view yeah i think a lot of the bloat really
comes from the fact that when you were a kid you know 60 hours seemed like a lot more than
it does when you're an adult yeah and also you know that was your one game for like six months
or something if you get anymore yeah um i like all the same games that you do well you mentioned
earlier in this conversation right like the it's the um too much access i think that maybe
too with games is the same thing yeah too much it's also um fifty dollars just real quick fifty
dollars for mark swain's revenge uh do you guys think that fundamentalist islam which compels
men to emulate the prophet muhammad is inherently dangerous for all non-fundamentalist islamists
it's a spicy one that's pretty spicy anyone want to take a crack at it well so i mean the answer
is going to be yes on some level and you can make the same argument for other religions like every
religion has its fanatical version that is dangerous to other people um i think islam might
be unique because it carries within it a doctrine of how to set up a religious state and most
religions don't have that in their in their doctrine so it might be uniquely dangerous
that doesn't mean obviously that all muslims are dangerous or anything like that
i think that if you got out into the world and the democratic party you would see that at least
here in this country a lot of the muslim americans that are here are some of the most progressive
thoughtful smart kind loving people that you will ever meet in your whole life um you know like jink
is not um he's not muslim like extremist when it comes down to it so uh i'm not comfortable
i'm not comfortable with blanket statements like that i think that um a lot of muslim countries
are not democracies uh and i think that uh that obviously causes a lot of problems and repression
i mean it's the same it's it's the same that canada doesn't we have like a huge muslim population
but we have a very big sikh population it's the same with them right like their their religion
is overall very peaceful and yet canada has recently had like the sikh terrorist issues
which probably didn't make it into the american news but like there's there's stuff happening
up here that well they uh they uh assassinated that's not all sikhs obviously uh i think
india uh struck them like killed one of the sikhs in canada i believe is yeah yeah so the tldr the
tldr that is that the sikhs want like an and they want an ethno state for the sikh religion in india
in an area called calistan they're trying to break it off the indian government obviously
doesn't want that um there is a big i i think i think the violence hit its peak in 85 when they
blew up a flight going to canada all right well okay real real quick the tldr is that a bunch of
the calisthenian um extremists moved to canada they kind of blended in because canadians are
like they're very they're very nice and polite and open and welcoming from their country so of
course come here of course not knowing what was actually happening and so now there is this this
growing calisthenian issue in canada where canada might be harboring some legit terrorists and india
has now um assassinated one of them on canadian soil which has caused an international incident
absolutely so that's something happening here that americans aren't americans aren't paying
attention to it it's happening right real quick five dollars is lizam right about women that is
a troll obviously not our artemis fowl i know him he donates a lot of money yes he trolls every
single time i am okay with that uh but you had a question a last question and we have some colors
backstage gang if you want to get uh in line uh well they were backstage where they go uh
exclamation point discord and chat or click the link that i provide in the youtube chat
uh accept the rules and then jump backstage and we'll pull you on one at a time to talk to these
wonderful individuals but go ahead last uh i'm good to go let's get to the colors oh no no it
was like a video game question maybe uh i it's covered it's cool i'm cool oh okay okay okay um
actually i i have a question for you then okay like you're very clearly a squaresoft fan yes
yeah okay um you like earthbound so you have to like rpgs probably like chrono trigger as well
yeah it's really good it's really good yeah um how about like like western rpgs like vampire the
masquerade bloodlines that's considered a classic it's good i've never done a complete playthrough
of it i mean does mass effect count as a western rpg i think that's the greatest video game ever
made i mean which one uh well two is obviously the best but all three of them in order i mean
come on that's the greatest story our our industry has ever produced in my view
i uh i keep everyone says two is the best i think one is better than two
this story is better but the gameplay is not i i like that old style of kind of
uncompromisingly janky gameplay well which class do you play because i do uh assassin
and sniper rifle so maybe that's why we have a different perspective uh engineer so i've
never done an engineer play through how does that work um well in the in the future games you get
drones and you get turrets and those are those are really nice you can basically like there's
a way to play mass effect where it's basically the loneliest shepherd where you recruit as few
people as possible you kill off as many partners as possible and you go it alone for as much as
the game and you play in engineers that all you have are like robot buddies it's a really fun
way to play the game but like it's everyone is dead and you can actually pretty much break the
game by the end of the playthrough in mass effect 3 because the game doesn't know what to do because
everyone's gone so if you're on vermyer you're sending ashley and caden to go die basically
um okay what one last question yes how about how about deadly premonition i i don't know this game
what are you talking about it is a horror game from the 360 yes i remember this this is the one
where paranoia affects your your sense of stuff right uh no okay i'm thinking something else no
uh it's basically twin peaks the game oh my god and i i i definitely have like a hipster sense
of taste when it comes to uh to to games and tv and movies so i love twin peaks
i love that whole aesthetic and that that's that type of storytelling and deadly premonition is
twin peaks the game it recently got a switch re-release you can play it on modern consoles but
it's it's like unfinished and kind of comedically it's comedically unfinished but the charm of the
game is just it's over the top i love it it's it's on my list of top 10 it's twin peaks yeah
i like it when your channel talks about games you had a really salient thoughtful
analysis of final fantasy 16 that uh i i didn't agree with all your conclusions but i thought
it was a really interesting thought uh like analysis of the plot and the the political
subtext of it so i wish you'd do more of that there's one coming tomorrow oh fancy okay so yeah
the tldr of it is basically um there's this idea that conservatives they they're media illiterate
you know we're talking about this before before before we started the idea is like they they watch
the boys and they see homelander and then they like seal clap not recognizing that it's it's
criticizing america and criticizing like american like exceptionalism right and there's probably a
lot of truth to that at the same time though there's this view again mainly among breadtubers
all right it's it's it is it is leftist crazies who are terminally online they believe that like
all media and all all entertainment media has messages that are exclusively for them and
if conservatives enjoy something that they're um they're coping or they're like intellectually
dishonest or they have some sort of dissonance in their heads and it's like no no there are
actually good conservative stories right legend of zelda i gave you the example legend of zelda
is a conservative story because in every single game link is restoring the monarchy all right
there is a there is a hard conservative subtext in legend of zelda for sure so i'm i'm i'm making
the argument libtards coping and ceasing right now i i'm making the argument that there are
definitely like anon is authoritarian though anon is authoritarian yeah of course he is yeah
yeah but i mean authoritarianism isn't isn't exclusively a rightist thing and monarchy is
certainly a monarchy is certainly exclusively a rightist thing every single time link puts
princess zelda back on the throne that is reaffirming monarchy it's unclear how much
political power zelda actually holds i am i am not prepared for this debate but fair enough let's do
it um but let me read these first five dollars from tempered squeal for giving me lovely
background noise while i work love the conversation and five pounds from conus x
since vampire the masquerade was mentioned i am dying to hear dev's opinion on werewolf
the apocalypse the tabletop not the video game i don't know much about it sorry my only experience
with is it is it what is it called like it's called the dark something that universe i don't
know what it is my only experience is with a vampire unfortunately fair enough um gang yeah
call in there was a few of you earlier waiting um and then we took too long i guess but uh i guess
we're going to go into the column portion so if you've been watching this and you have questions
that you think wick why didn't you bring this up wick why didn't you ask brianne about this wick
why didn't you ask why didn't your whole dad's feet to the fire about this right now is your
chance to call in and talk to these lovely individuals yeah we've had a nice pleasant
conversation let's add some conflict and let's let's ruin it by bringing in the chatters okay
well you know you're dirty dirty chatters okay you're only there to be seen not heard normally
but now i am dining and giving you i am condescending to opening up the floor to you
dear chatter to for a brief moment in time to fill that void that uh exists within your empty
lives with a little bit of attention right so jump backstage i see we're getting a couple
colors right now but jump backstage and we'll pull you in two dollars dev where's the trucker video
uh plus one day plus one day let's bring in the first caller
hello a lot
hey guys how you doing um hi it's too friendly in here i i'm gonna try to get you guys to fight
with each other a little bit uh no i'm just kidding uh i mean maybe um my question is mainly
brianna esta if you want to answer you can you guys like briefly touched on cancel culture earlier
i was just curious uh brianna if if you see any um because to me there's a there's a pretty
discernible party line between the type of emotion that the phrase cancel culture like evokes in
people um you know like like people right-leaning conservatives tend to think of it as like the
villain the big bad bogey and then um left-leaning people generally see it as like a dog whistle for
basically anti-wokeness or anti-progressivism um as a figure of yourself do you see any um
can you identify any concerning aspects of cancel culture like what it's done to progressives
oh um yeah first of all i think this is one of these things where no one is taking a long enough
historical view of this i'm old enough to remember what happened to people that spoke out against the
iraq war of which i was one of them right and there was a very real sense if you spoke out
against president bush right after 9 11 that you would lose your job um you know there was um so
i think the conservatives have been running you know cancel culture for a long time um yeah i
think i have a different assessment i don't um i do think i i actually want higher standards for
people in how we express ourselves publicly but i think uh it's really obvious that this current
playbook of trying to get everyone fired over the most minor statements and just making witch hunt
witch hunt witch hunt the uh way that we advocate for change it's it's not working uh i think a lot
of people think progressives are assholes uh now i think that we have less cultural power today than
we did 10 years ago and um i i think there is certainly an illiberal element to this you know
i think that no matter your views at the end of the day we're a democracy we need to settle our
differences at the ballot box and i think there does need to be more tolerance for allowing people
on the other side to have their say so um i realize that's a more nuanced uh view than just
cancel culture bad but this stuff is really like free speech is this there's a lot it really matters
how you approach that principle and how you safeguard it right just to give one super quick
example when it comes to national security we all agree with free speech but like russia is
weaponizing our ideals against us and by using bot farms to exacerbate our divisions here in
this country make it seem like things are more inflamed than they are and now the new warfare
against the united states is it happens with trying to basically inflame these differences
between people what is the answer for that like we can't like start just censoring uh people
disagreeing with each other but we should certainly have a policy to like identify bot farms
um so all this stuff is really complicated um okay do you do you care more about progressives
looking like assholes or do you care more about um potential like sustained casualties from um
people catching strays i guess from uh from as a result of cancel culture and what it's done to
progressivism i genuinely care about both um i think both are extremely high downsides
like on a priority list i would say both of those are an a-level priority
okay so do you agree with your honor we were do you have a more um negative outlook on it
um you have to repeat a little bit sorry i spaced i'm just curious
uh so beyond has identified uh basically that uh cancel culture uh oh why don't you i don't want to
um brianne if you could give them a summation it started with dixie chicks basically or like
not didn't start but like the right was doing it earlier and you had like dixie chicks that
could get canceled i remember that from back in the day yeah yeah um but i do think freezing it
as conservatives have been running cancel culture for a long time is probably not the
most accurate way of characterizing it i don't think this is the dark part of the human heart
it's no one side has political power gamergate was about cancel culture in a large way against
feminists in the game industry i mean everyone's gonna like everyone's gonna say like i'm against
cancel culture but here's my political opponent and here's some evidence that he might have raped
someone so let's get him fired everyone's gonna feel like that's just in the moment right but it
probably isn't especially if the evidence is not good so ah it's it's tough it's one of those
things where it's like do you do you really want to have complete free speech because then you do
get the russian bot farms that like you mentioned before but i don't know i will say there's there's
this sorry go ahead no um i will say this about the whole thing uh we're going to see a lot of
people speaking out rightly so in my opinion i want to be clear this is good that they're
speaking out against it the people losing their jobs over pro-palestinian stances in the coming
months right we're going to see that happen over and over again on the left and if we had not
created the mechanisms to get people fired from their academic jobs for right-wing views right
um we would not be seeing this today at least not at the numbers we are so this is the thing
if we want to be able to say and speak out on controversial important issues we have to keep
that shield strong when people we don't like in fact may hate come out and say things that we hate
or oppose and i think that keeping that shield strong to protect us all is going to be what
gets us out of this mess and we just have to re-return to our roots as a nation and say
i may not respect what you say but i respect your right to say it and i think we need to really
cling to that again um sorry dev i didn't mean to cut you off but i i like free speech is my thing
okay this is what i that like like that that sounds really good but i think there's probably
some logistical problems in there because for example if you like you later on this but go on
let's say you have two political parties right and you know the political power is being handed
between them each election and one political party is completely fine with censoring their
opponents so they don't even give a shit the other political party says you know what no free speech
for everyone we're all everyone's gonna we're all gonna play by the same rules you end up you end up
in a position where every time the free speech party takes power their opponents get to run
get to run wild with free speech every time they the free speech party is on the outs
they get censored and it becomes this one-way battle right so you almost have to have a standard
of you're only going to censor the censors in a sense but i think that censorship right uh
in a real way it's cutting off it's getting short-term games absolutely short-term gains
can be gained from it absolutely but i in a very real way i think it undercuts and undermines your
own position so while yes the one party who engages in censorship while the other doesn't
uh short term it's going to have a lot of success when it gets power to be able to censor and cut
off its enemies but i think at the end of the day like the good guys are good guys for a reason it's
because they don't do the things the bad guys do right um and i know that's a simplistic way
of looking at it but i think most of my audience are simpletons so we're gonna keep with the
analogy here this is where like respect i know we fight on this but go on you're obviously a
really smart guy but let me give you a really concrete example of where i think it's just a
little bit more complicated than i i think you acknowledge so uh here's a really good example
my good friend carrie gold book's amazing book on this talks about some of her fights to try to get
big tech to do things that are correct when it wasn't in their uh profit interest right she
runs a really great law firm um and one really concrete example of this is someone uh was on
grinder and they had a jilted former boyfriend who sent made a habit day after day after day after
day of sending random strangers to his house to have sex with him so he would be cooking dinner
somebody would be knocking on the door trying to have sex with him right just did this constantly
she tried everything possible to try to get um basically grinder to expand their own terms of
service and take action against this they just would not do anything about this you know under
hold on like the way you're talking about this like that's a free speech issue they're making
their own account right so i think all of these things if you really dig into the policy of like
ways away 230 is implemented in this country i want to keep 230 but i think the critics have
some real fair points that deserve a policy answer so i think the more you know about this subject
the more complicated all of it actually gets but that's the thing the situation you described isn't
sure speech because speech when i say free speech and absolute free speech i'm thinking the ability
to express ideas without censorship for that what you're describing is something that is different
that i'm fine with um i i we we have no i have no compulsion or compunction with you um engaging in
mechanisms that shut that kind of behavior down because it's a different style of thing now it's
like the heckler's veto right um it's cutting the mic instead of allowing people to speak and there's
a such a difference there but i don't want to hog this conversation up porsche ran away because we
stopped talking to him uh it's color time right um but if you guys question real quick yeah but
if you guys want to just real quick if i may if you guys want to read the best book i've ever read
on free speech kindly inquisitors look it up check it out it's great i forget the author off the top
of my head but kindly inquisitors you can google it and find out um it's a very very good uh
treaties on why free speech matters and why it's important i wanted to ask this but i forgot i've
remembered it was was that the ikea trans shark in the background as well
oh yeah yeah yeah it's wahaj all right yeah yeah okay i figured i thought it was what i
don't know so i just wanted to confirm yeah so i had blachage before blachage was a trans icon
believe it or not there was an article that came out i think it was back in 2017 about ikea
canceling this shark and a whole bunch of russians getting angry about it and i saw
this story of it i was like oh my god that is the cutest thing i've ever seen i've got to get that
shark and then like years later blachage became a huge trans icon so i was in way before the trend
all right okay guys ready for the next caller let's do it speaking of trolling
artemis foul welcome hi artemis what's up you're live how's it going
artemis yes i understand i'm unmuting myself hey hey how's it going how come you're not
involved in the project zomboid server with kibbs i have a a job that is very important
that makes a lot of money do you think i have time to play in the middle of the day when everybody
else is supposed to be at work well that that is our job sorry yeah so i do have a question for
everybody here so the right back in the day in the 90s was pearl clutching about you know evil
satanists and stuff like this and doing the slippery slippery slope argument of they're
going to destroy everything or it's the end times that the left gets what they want right
now seeing how far the left has gone in terms of its policies and enacting them
would we say more or less that the right was correct in that where it was heading or
or is it not because for my example c.s lewis talks about the moral tyrant right that never
sleeps whereas the the republicans are evil in a lot of aspects but at least at some point they
stop messing with you they have so go ahead i mean no we'll finish your question then we'll
respond i promise is is the it was is the right was the right correct about the slippery slope
of the left because from what everybody can see in the last 10 years the slippery slope is not
no longer a fallacy but just a an inevitability at this point can i help you with it can i help you
out with an example go ahead so i i think i don't think i agree with you but i think i know what
you're getting at okay so there was definitely this idea back when it was uh being uh gay
marriage is being debated is that if if we if we allow gay marriage they're going to be having sex
with animals they're going to be having sex with children they're going to be doing all this weird
shit and that was that was the right wing argument and everyone back then you know kind of rolled
their eyes and said okay grandma like this is obviously stupid right and now you have a lot
of right wing accounts online that are promoting instances and they in my opinion they're isolated
instances but they are bad instances of let's say trans people doing weird things with children
and i think even though that's that's i think it's a minority of instances it's enough and it's been
amplified enough that right wingers are currently saying we were right the whole time is that what
you're getting at basically well the right wingers will say that but i'm just saying is it can anybody
see the argument there i can see the argument but i don't think i agree with it necessarily
i think both sides have you know slid more and more and more into extremes and i think uh
probably one of the failures uh is i've engaged this tonight i think we haven't acknowledged how
crazy the republicans are now some absurdly high number of republicans nowadays don't even believe
in democracy when when mitt romney that's not my opinion that's mitt romney's opinion when he
resigned from the from the senate right so um i'm not gonna tell you that the hyperbole of my own
side does not go to crazy town it does it absolutely does but i don't think that issue is
limited to to one side i'm not gonna um i'm not gonna tell you who but it was a pretty famous
person on the right and i was talking to this person the other day they were telling me how
uh with their algorithm when they go on to instagram it's like recipe of how to make a bomb
like recipe on how to like create your own like flammables for a riot right like it's this
constant deluge of stuff to literally bring out an insurrection right and just how stunning they
feel about how their own side is behaving so um like i think dev i know you have a really good
video criticizing this word reactionary and i know i'm misusing it according to your definition here
but i do think that all of us are coming just so emotionally charged in the way we
respond to each other it's it's it's leading some really crazy stuff
what about you wick well i talk a lot about on my channel about reciprocal radicalization
and how both sides have driven as brianna said each other into more and more extremes because
they have to fight the other side so when you talk about like um was the right correct that
the left was going to go this direction um yes and no but it's it's a self-fulfilling prophecy
because i'm very they are they have created this monster they are responsible for this monster in
a lot of ways um and i don't think they can solely take blame obviously right i think the left has
autonomy um but at the end of the day there is a party of sanity still and i i say it's squarely
on and most issues the democrats um republicans they're again they're i i don't want to i don't
want to like i have a large republican audience right they are not crazy they're sane but their
leadership and a lot of the policy positions that have been pushed by some of these people are out
of the out of out of this this world now that isn't to say that the left doesn't also have
crazy policies that they pass or push right like this idea that they're going to to remove
standards for eighth graders on um you know uh math or Washington and things like that right it's
it's it's again for a very specific group of people sure yeah yeah but they are they are it's
a it's a there it's a tit for tat right it's a tip for tat we have to go hard because if we don't
go hard they're gonna go hard like mansion has decided not to run again because he's gotten so
he again this man joe mansion i'm gonna stand him for a little bit right he got it a huge uh
win for energy for american energy past he also was again an important seat he voted progressive
what 90 of the time and but because he didn't vote for it a hundred percent he got crucified
and that's not going to make the next replacement be less radical right or uh it's not that's the
argument against joe mansion i think i think the issue is is that most people in the left
thinking it was a blue dog and a republican in a uh an all but name it's the corruption
it's the outright corruption in the uh medical industry well i think that you know like
ruling on issues of like uh basically the use of fossil fuels and sabotaging bills while he's
actually owning one of those companies i think that's pretty outright corruption
do you think that no but do you think oh brianna come on you you don't think that when the left
criticizes mansion that's not what they're criticizing at least that's not what i see
that's not there's certainly a portion of the left that does that but um you know we are a
political party and when one person is sabotaging you know our president's efforts to get certain
legislation passed i think he should expect blowback i mean mansion certainly gets this i
mean this is democracy functioning but mansions replace like we have cut okay no this is where
i agree with uh matt matty glacius right he talks about how mansions and the problem is that we need
a lot more mansions the and hold on before progressive tour crucifies me the problem is the
senate is like as a structure is fundamentally stacked against the democrats it always will be
this is the reason we have a bicameral system in the first place in this country is because they
knew that uh you know they wanted to have uh continue slavery and they knew um that if you
leave these issues up to just the popular will the people they're a lot of powerful interests
are going to be crushed the senate is fundamentally stacked in favor of the republicans so if you have
more moderate people out there that we're growing to be able to win some of these states that are
more conservative leaning like west virginia that will over time give democrats more power and i
agree with that hold on there's there's definitely better arguments for the existence of the senate
as it currently stands in that though yes it serves a good function yeah the senate the senate
is there to tamper uh tampin expectations on like situations of high intense fervor from passing
through the the lower house that the house and then that's the that's the whole point is just
for change incrementally so that people don't go and say and start a war that destroys the
nation that's the whole point of the senate and to provide some type of check and balances
against large population centers look i i look i am an institutionalist at my core i don't have
a big problem with the senate i'm talking about a strategy about how the democrats can get more
power uh you know if mansion stepping down we don't have candidates on deck that are moderate
that can win in west virginia so um i would love like don't get me wrong i'm a pro-abortion
pro-feminist uh progressive but i think if we are interested in keeping the senate it makes sense to
have candidates on deck on those states that we can run and win and get political power for
ourselves so i got a question on the ohio thing oh one last question but we do have a uh do have a
line so yeah one last thing i'll get you so why do you think that the ohio abortion thing is a
knock against uh republicans what do you mean because republicans are staunchly about letting
states decide abortion rather than allowing the overall federal government to make a sweeping
judgment on it uh i think that it is going to be terrible look this if you want to make this
an abortion question it's going to take a whole hour so not about the abortion but about the
allowing the states to the individual state to decide their own policies it's terrible for
women's public health this is a right men would never allow a law like this to be passed about
their own bodies it is leading to terrible outcomes and like it's horrible top to bottom
so i do not support that okay that's fair i was just going to say that that argument would have
had valid before 2020 and the covered lockdown but the but that that covered lockdown destroyed
that argument because nobody cared about self self uh choice when it comes to medical procedures
oh during that time so okay this might be it's true this might be its own thing no that's fine
you know me yeah thank you for your statement on that that's it i i i just wanted to know but
thank you okay um and val thank you for coming on and thank you for the super chats uh so here's the
thing i can considering what i know about artemis's job i know that he's a glowy if you know what that
means he's actually yeah he actually is a glowy yeah okay that that would actually be an interesting
conversation you and him because you probably both know way more about the american government
than i do sure so because he actually does work in in it to some i i can't talk about how but he
does he has are you doxing are you doxing this guy is this no no i am not okay i just don't
want you to like oh i know that guy here's his address and name and he he has overthrown several
south american dictatorships i'm not anti-law enforcement kind of gal i mean you know i've
worked with the fbi multiple occasions of multiple projects at this point you know when
my congressional campaign was hacked by russia they stepped in and was really impressed by the
skill of their cyber security team i think it's really important for national security right so
um was actually hacked by russia yeah how do you know that because i can't get into it but i do
know this okay there are new stories about it go read them okay fair enough okay yeah uh next caller
soy addle hello
soy addle soy addle oh there he goes uh oh he's gone don't click the join voice button
don't click it i'm sorry discord silly um unmute yourself and go go ahead yeah
so dev when did gamergate actually start was it like pax 2014 was it uh a week before
when adam baldwin tweeted about gamergate or was it long before then
what why are you a shark i figured i'd telegraph my position as and trigger you a little bit
oh jeez when did like when did it start i don't fucking know dude was it when adam baldwin tweeted
gamergate was that like because that was like it didn't have a name was it wasn't a nameless
movement before then or it was like it was it was the same movement but it probably it was
nothing less before then yeah but it was a movement yeah so so we we've got a narrative
that that's coming from the author of the gamer gate book that uh you had to be a time traveler
that you had to be a time traveler to do everything that has been attributed to gamergate
and this kind of debunks that so if it was a movement before adam baldwin then that narrative
doesn't play out and i want to make sure that we're honest about that yeah so all right what
was what was sort of this the the the the incentive the uh sorry the the spark that set off
yeah it was the most it was the zoe post right okay so no well but then you're saying i don't
agree with that by the way i think it was adam baldwin and and all that that's when we got the
name in in my view i think uh zoe is incorrectly uh credited as the catalyst for game again i
actually think it started with amita sarkeesian before then and a feminist frequency gang founded
because right after that what is not historically recognized is how that playbook immediately
started bleeding over into the personal lives of women in the game industry they've been talking
about equality so um yeah i think that's when it started i i can only tell you what i remember
i remember you know you know hanging out in 4chan and anita was making videos and everyone was
shitting on her and saying these are bad videos she doesn't know what she's talking about she's
not a real gamer all that was happening but i don't remember any sort of like consistent united
until the zoe post dropped and then until like the next day or two when you had a bunch of those
gamers or dead articles drop that's when i i remember specifically everyone coming together
to be like there's something wrong here yeah so from inside hold on just one second because i
love this uh there's an article i wrote just before all of that stuff happened it's called
no skin is thick enough uh for polygon i was told at the time that was the third most read piece for
that year um and this was before the zoe post it was talking about the horror and shit show
that was happening to women in the game industry um you know starting with uh samantha allen
basically quitting the entire game industry because of the doxing and harassment that she got
uh there's just been erased from all of this so um i i hear you and i believe you when you say
that you weren't really aware of that but women in the game industry
were it was really really bad for us two dollars to tell uh soya to put the shark back but uh go
ahead okay well i'll get your two dollars back later but basically if um you know from my
perspective being in a different part of the games industry yeah it it there were conversations
around how do we expand the customers how do we get away from the toxic xbox call of duty crowd
and this is where the gamers are dead sentiment was built i know that we had like the journal
the journal list conspiracy which which was kind of proven and i've seen like different
groups of people in media gather in private messages but then of course we also had similar
things happen political organizing in 2016 so we we no one's innocent here from from like this
collusion back back channels but it certainly did sort of like this overall position of the
industry pushing for expanded customer base dismantling the aggression like dick wolves
episode and all of this was pressing on industry to perform its image and i think that's why even
if it was coordinated behind the scenes that's why we did have sentiment redefine gamers somehow
and just one more word on this um because i really i have nothing new to say on gamergate but just to
to tackle what you're talking about people miss this historic part of the industry because this
was when mobile started eating the lunch of triple a studios before gamergate one of this
bad game that i still enjoy it's called alpha protocol it's a mass effect clone i was made by
sega i think the budget was like 20 million dollars or something this was this b-tier game
that the game industry was able to produce just a few years before gamergate but mobile started
changing it so much that we were looking for new audiences and we were realizing we couldn't keep
talking to the exact same kind of people making these same kind of games because development was
getting more expensive audiences were looking for something new so i like a lot of this stuff that
got the core gamer so angry i i don't want to sound like a communist but it was capitalism
right it was this force in the game industry to like find new people to buy your stuff
i mean that's true to an extent um this is something i'm trying to i'm trying to work out
in my head oh god and it's a it's much more complicated for this for this conversation um
capitalism and communism don't really operate in the kind of dichotomy that most people think
that it does you know because your answer to this question capitalism is okay fair enough go ahead
well they they they both have like universalizing forces within them right because capitalism wants
to um as you said in increase the consumer base in order to do that you need to appeal to a whole
bunch of different demographics with different tastes which means you're gonna get yours too
i don't have one this is not fair so basically as you as you increase your uh your install base
for a product that means you have to start appealing to different types of people who
all have different different ideas about what they want to buy which means some sort of
universalization of what you're offering right it has to be it has to be acceptable to 10 different
types of people all with 10 different sensibilities which which necessarily leads to some sort of
watering down so there's a capitalism has this universalizing effect but communism also has a
universalizing effect and they're kind of like twins in that regard this is something that i
don't fully understand yet i'm still trying to work it out in my head but i think like
there is there is something corrosive to small communities whether they be online communities
or even real life communities like small towns that capitalism brings into the equation that
socialism or communism cannot actually solve it only exacerbates and i don't know what to do about
it i don't quite know how to formulate this idea very vague i will say and also i can tell why some
people might say that you're a subversive communist infiltrating right-wing spaces okay yeah probably
yeah anything else before we let you go so i don't know yeah that kind of ironically what dev said
kind of ironically goes into why i think the left is so bad on palestine right now because they are
identity opportunists rather than being on mission and on mission would mean dismantling structures
of oppression this is yes yeah and somewhat relating to what dev's saying is that okay so
bland market consumer level you know twitch subscriber level socialism doesn't solve it
because that's all about land back and you know all of the these groups of people are good and
we should support them rather than we need to smash gender hierarchy and that's yeah that's
what being a leftist is well so that'll thank you for being here thank you for your questions and
thank you for the blah i don't know if i'm saying that right let's see let's go i love
i could be mispronouncing his looks so new he's new on the blah train i've been here for years
okay oh god five dollars from artemis dev was picking me weak for caving to online harassment
he wants me to you know i'll just say yes fuck you this is like a meme in my community
i'm not familiar but fair enough don't cave to the harassers gang it only makes them stronger never
apologize um that's not true you should apologize if you do something wrong but there is a the crowd
doesn't want you to say sorry it wants your blood right and it will so here's the thing like yeah
i'm sure i've never experienced anything as bad as you have as you have as you have during gamer
gabriella but i've been harassed on the internet as well you know yeah if you have if you have a
channel of of any sort of size you get harassed for something somewhere right and the lesson i've
learned is just never back down never apologize if you think you're right and it's a hard lesson
to learn for sure but it's definitely served me well over the years where it's like no i actually
think that i'm correct about this and i don't care if there's a thousand people who want my head
i'm not going to give in i think there's some quality some psychology of you that i haven't
quite figured out yet where you you mention a lot like there's like five or six videos about how you
don't have trolls remorse and i i don't mean to put you on the psychologist couch but i think
there's some part of you where your identity of yourself and the way you perceive yourself
is is based in this kind of the edgy chats you were having back in the 2000s
and i still have don't worry and i i think it affects your analysis of things in a way that
doesn't help you get to the right answers always maybe i i think it's just that you can
you can always it never hurts to have a greater constitution you know sure and that's kind of how
how i viewed i viewed things like that okay let's bring out we got a we got a few more
now i want to get through on the callers gang i had um i know that i want to respect your time
as well i'm just about done yeah i know so we'll we'll get through the current crop i'll make sure
they are in a timely manner and then we'll close it out oh let's get them in hello you're live you
got a question or a comment i suppose uh yes can you hear me we can what's up hello this is one of
my viewers what's up dude uh hello uh i was just wondering do you think uh horseshoe theory is
correct me or brianna brianna uh i'm getting sold on it
uh it's hard to think it's right another one is do you guys think government should break up
monopolies like intervene i think one of the things that makes america different than china
is if you look at the ascendance of something like bite dance uh you know china and the prc
are just synonymous with bite dance anyone that tells you they're not is just lying to you
outright and i do think that a good thing about this country is america tends to be a little bit
more laissez faire in picking winners and losers so i i think that i actually really agree with
elizabeth warren that when it comes to some of these really really big companies in the tech
space though um we're really limiting innovation because no one else can operate in the space they
get either bought up immediately or just crushed or a company like facebook will will just come in
and dominate them by stealing their features so um i think in general i think over my lifetime the
the government has gotten less willing to use their power to break up monopolies but i also
think it needs to be done extremely extremely thoughtfully um because it's not always bad a
really good example is uh in the game industry we've seen a move towards uh the model of things
like game games pass right where uh microsoft or sony will actually own the studio and then will
fund direct development these kind of b-tier games this is good in some ways and it sustains a lot of
smaller development studios that also leads to you know more vertical integration in the game
industry so i i don't think it's like either or i think that it's um i think we need to look at
these situations but i think overall we've not used that power enough
okay uh did you get your questions answered sir uh i got one more one more quickly uh
hey dev what's that font you use in your videos uh the old one was called handy sands
but in order for me to start using it legally it was gonna cost you like ten thousand fucking
dollars pieces yeah so i switched over to atma and i use atma bold all right find that you can
find that for free on google fonts thanks all right thank you those are my questions all right
bye go to blambot.com uh i've used them for my professional design work for years uh their
licensing fees are very very reasonable very awesome awesome i guess real quick regarding his
his horseshoe theory uh question the more i'll be very quick wick i'm sorry no it's not like we
could like look we can we could talk all night if you want i just don't have to go yeah um
basically like the more that i've been reading political theory the more that i've been convinced
by horseshoe theory because i've yeah i keep i keep finding like these 1920s and 1930s socialists
who are writing like fascists and i'm like how did this come about why is there this
link between these two ideologies and the more i read the more that i'm like okay there's like
a pipeline here or something something has to be going on here and it's been like obscured in the
modern era because nobody reads political theory anymore but something's going on yeah i would uh
on this i i don't know if policy wise it holds up horseshoe theory but i know behavior wise it
absolutely does um the further you go to the extremes the more willing they are to engage
in certain types of behaviors that if you go away from those extremes are seen as unacceptable
so in that way i think horseshoe theory is is is a circle honestly um the more extreme fringes
of certain beliefs are willing to any means necessary it no bad tactics just bad targets
and we can see that on both sides and it is a problem it is absolutely it is something that
we need to get away from immediately but yeah that's my thought uh you guys ready for the next
call let's do it real quick real quick artemis foul two dollars ask dev how he lost his license
he wants to reveal all my deep lore okay he's gonna have to if he wants to interrupt and and
and things like that that's cool we like your money driver's license but uh when i was like 21
i'm i'm not 21 anymore and i can i i'm fine now okay but way back in the day i drove a
dump truck for the city of toronto i worked for the municipality awesome i was driving around
with the back up because i had dumped a load and i forgot to put the bed down so i was driving down
down the street with with the bed up and i went right through an intersection and took down all
the power lines and the city was without power for for a little while so i was like you know what
i i lost my license i got demoted i was i was back down to picking up garbage for the city again
and uh it was a rough time for me for a while so i will tell you a quick story about driving
a dump truck myself so in mississippi there's very very little to do but one of my best friends
growing up uh his uh grandfather had uh basically this pit in the middle of the woods and they were
out there you know chopping down the trees like basically chopping down the forest to make a bunch
of money from it right so uh i actually learned how to pick locks in high school so we could then
open the gate and go into the sand pit and this is the same year that i learned how to make fake ids
so i was the only person in my high school class that could actually get us alcohol and i did so
we would go out there and throw these huge parties in this bonfire pit and a bunch of 16 year olds
getting drunk out of our mind and driving the wrecking ball around driving the dump truck around
while students are in the back passed out of their mind like going and uh like like cranes bulldozers
all this stuff i actually know how to operate all of that equipment because of the extremely
illegal stuff i was doing back then all right disavow all illegal activities i wag my finger
okay well is this actually limitations passed on that or yeah yeah okay yeah good because people
will sit on it and try to use it well anyway i've told this story many times president sunday's
watching you know he might true true um go ahead uh new caller i'm sorry i don't know your name i
stream things up hi you're live hey yeah it's grayboard oh i know cryborn one of my
community members hello so uh brianna i um i was hoping uh you could you could kind of
remind people what's at stake should republicans win in 2024 and why the uh left wing infighting
is so so dangerous thank you for such a great question um you know trump is an existential
threat to democracy and uh you know he's certainly going to abuse his power to uh
basically get revenge on his enemies and stop the uh rule of law from being implemented against him
uh you know he has nothing to lose he's looking at prison time so you know uh trump himself is
this existential threat to democracy additionally you know if you look at the uh fringe rightward
tilt of the court i think one of the worst things that could happen is trump uh like appointing even
more uh judges uh to the judiciary so it's really not an exaggeration to say if we don't get our
shit together and work on winning 2024 i genuinely am not sure we're still going to have a country
damn actually i have a question for you i have a question for you if you don't mind um
do you think that trump genuinely believes that he won 2020 and he's just wrong about it
or do you think that he knows he lost and he's just been coping i i don't have to surmise about
this because it's all come out in the the cases against him where he's admitted in private
people testified how he knows he lost and uh it was him just trying to keep power so don't take
my word for it take it from the people that were there um if you have those could you send them to
me i'm kind of curious yeah i'm it's very easily found but i will do that after the show
okay great whoa wow thank you getting some information answered well thanks
for being here cryborn cryborn you know i love you right love you too wick
everybody always has these cool streamer nicknames i've been thinking so much i need
my i'm just brianna right we got wick you're the wu the wu effect right we can we can the
what should mine be like i don't actually wu effect is not bad wu's warriors that could be
your uh your community name right wu fast wu furious that works too i like it i like that
uh uwu right we could do that oh there you go okay i'm probably changing my name sometime soon
it's not a great name yeah yeah i know everyone knows it's not it's not is it a metal gear
reference what i don't i've looked at that so many times i'm like what the hell uh so i started the
channel in 2009 when it was like me and my friends kind of running around my small town with a camera
and we were shooting um we were shooting anime content and the name just stuck from when i was
younger it just stuck around so like yeah you know 2009 that was the era of like channel awesome on
the internet right this was long before a lot of the nonsense we're facing now so we were like
we're gonna be anime reviewers and we're gonna make it onto doug walker's website and that was
like our big dream it didn't work out but actually i have like a bit of deep lore on that for for
anybody who cares about fucking channel awesome lore from 15 years ago um we and after the channel
got bigger we ended up applying again and they took us and then i rejected it because i just
wanted to see that i could oh fightful okay spiteful one victory i have way over thought
this that i've thought for years because you know your voice is yeah you've got like you could be a
voice actor professional voice actor you're really good at that right um and there's such a disconnect
between like short fat otaku and your voice so i'm like is this an ironic commentary is this
and i find out it's one of these situations like when you're playing somebody online
and their username is like boobs are awesome and you're like okay they were 14 when they made that
username that's that's basically what it is yeah yeah we got we got two more colors i want to be
real quick with them then we're gonna let blue off the leash here and get get her out of here
um uh but let's bring them on hello friend
why we wait for him 10 more bucks from artemis fowl if the last message about
trump being an existential threat is as important as you think it is why is trump gaining support
across the board including 20 22 of african americans now we'll answer that question later
uh but i would say it's simply uh the fact that people are tired they they view the economy as
doing poorly whether or not or not it is that's how they view the economy and i think that's
just driving things right i agree okay um okay you're here great excellent what's up
you're live hey so first off since people already know i'm in the military so any statements i make
are personal opinions are reflective of department of defense or the army anything like that got to
do which uh which place should you serve in uh i'm in the army officer thank you very much for that
no officer though oh well you guys are working i wish we had someone who worked for a living on
but go ahead okay so i'll ask uh just one short question so i'm a big fan of jonathan height
rider and elephant kind of stuff yeah so what what do you guys do to actually check
your policies and social prescriptions that you support to make sure it's not the elephant in
charge what's the elephant in charge can you help me understand that yeah yeah so okay so the basic
idea is most people are not as rational as they think they are you're primarily controlled by
instincts and emotion which is kind of like an elephant and then your rational mind is the person
riding on top of the elephant the rider thinks they're in control but the elephant just kind
of does what it does and you post hoc rationalize afterwards um i will answer this question first
if i may um and then i'll let the stars of the show go but one of the things that i personally
do to make sure that i am checking my biases making sure i'm not just knee-jerking is building
a community like this where most of my community yells at me all the time right where i'm constantly
challenged i am in a space where i have other elephants to check my elephant if that makes sense
right where i am challenged and i have we normalize being able to come to me directly and say wick
you're being stupid you're being wrong you're being um irrational that's that's what i it's
not perfect but that's that's my go-to anyway i think for me i mean earlier in the show i talked
about how reactionary i was during gamergate uh you know speaking of trauma right so i think
that's a really good example of where i failed um i can't think of any situation where i got really
really angry and posted a tweet response to that that it worked out well and i think part of the
good part of getting older is you you learn to uh to don't react that emotionally as often uh i
clearly fail at this all the time uh you know my passion is just a part of my personality
it's probably never going to go away but i think you try to surround yourself uh with uh people
you that you really value their counsel um something i think that has really been good at
helping me get the right answer dev i think it's clear from this conversation tonight i genuinely
watch your youtube channel even though i've had many criticisms of parts of that tonight right
i i do spend a lot of time watching content i don't agree with because i do think it helps me
make sure that my opinions are correct and yeah there's some stuff you've said that i've changed
my mind on and i've admitted as much but yeah i think that uh that ability to hear another side
is really really important i guess without a view it is when it comes to oh thanks by the way i do
appreciate the fluffing um when it's genuine um when it comes to um the elephant and the rider
when jonathan height lays out that example what he's basically saying is that if the elephant is
calm the rider is capable of directing the elephant in the general direction that the
rider wants to go but if the elephant is agitated the rider has no hope right and the best way you
can do that is you can make the road as clear as possible so a lot of things that you can do
to help along your own rationality is to before you get into any sort of heated debate before you
ever actually have to use those precious cycles of brain power which are quite limited per day
make sure that like your your environment is set you know make sure that your house is in order
make sure your ideas are in order make sure that you've studied you've read make sure that you
considered other things before you have to be tested on them right that that's probably the
best way that you can avoid you know that that is the best way you can avoid saying something stupid
okay okay fair enough and and before i head off i will recommend to rihanna that you should
absolutely read the righteous mind by jonathan height uh yes so yeah why isn't even this
righteous mind tell me about this the righteous mind by jonathan height that is basically his
his magnum opus it's the psychology of morality it's the six moral foundations we talked about
earlier that that is that is the and it is free on audible i'm buying it right now boom
you won't regret it thank you yeah what if i can ask what do you do in the army
yeah so uh i'm just an infantry officer so i'm not going to go into my specific job but i've done
things from platoon leader company officership s3 in the shop time so just kind of all different
kinds of jobs yeah just generally my branch is infantry thank you very much i appreciate
veterans day tomorrow right i think it is uh i think though i think we're doing free
applebees or something tomorrow but yeah uh again thanks for calling thanks for coming by and uh
we'll see you later buddy no thanks for having me on officers i was an enlisted um it's a little
bit of a different world yeah we don't have veterans day here but we have remembrance day
and it's pretty much the same thing um do americans have the tradition of wearing poppies for it or no
no i've never heard of that no um no pretty much just just uh we put a support the troops sticker
on our car and then send them off for war and then give them no health care fireworks and
barbecues fireworks yeah but listen if you're if you're ever in canada or or the uk or in australia
or new zealand there's a tradition where on november 11th which is remembrance day in these
countries everyone wears a poppy on their shirt and you can generally buy a poppy for like 25
cents at any store and all that money goes towards the military oh that's a good idea like like
veteran stuff yeah uh one last caller i'm sorry there's two and things but one came in a little
late sorry uh let's get infallible foul infallible foul you're live you're on air what is up i was
wondering about something you guys were talking about a little bit earlier and maybe that's a
little bit of bias that i have just because i'm not seeing this from a right wing perspective
but when i feel like when people talk about the right and they talk about usually the individual
like this person did this wrong this person did that but i've been hearing a lot especially in
the spit this space around here is the left has progressives have an anti-Semitic problem
i've been seeing earlier you said horseshoe theory now uh what is it do you think about
having maybe like a little bit more fiscally liberal policies would make somebody more of
a scumbag and have more about far bright extremist opinion in life i don't
that was apparently like we were talking horseshoe theory
what do you mean i don't understand what you're saying yeah rephrase sir if you can't oh wick
you're talking about horseshoe theory you had a title up that said uh the left anti-semitism
problem that is not willing so when we say the left right um it's not just oh i'm a leftist
because i have i believe in these fiscal policies and things like that the left as a term covers a
broad tent of belief structures and things like that um and this is by design um so that we can
uh coalesce and do this kind of like a cooperative action this community action in order to get
things passed so we'll put aside our differences in order to come together to fight against the
things that we think are bad and to promote the things that we think are good my whole um thing
that i have observed of late after october 7th especially is how many people are willing to
overlook anti-semitism because they believe in the oppressor versus the oppressed kind of dynamic
going on in the israeli-palestine conflict and they don't just keep their um criticism
towards the israeli state but they again talk in the most extreme terms and are willing to put up
with again just dehumanizing jewish individuals um in order to because they hate israel so much
they're willing to overlook anti-semitism and that's a problem and we need to address that
that's my i i just think there is a lot a large part of the audience that does feel like it was
kind of generalized and a lot of them were frustrated with you and i think that's that's
fair to be frustrated but they i'm frustrated with them right back because again i am not saying that
everyone on the left is anti-semitic obviously not but if we we can't pretend that there's none
and when people bring it up you can't can't get mad at it we have to clean our own house
we have to keep it in order we cannot let the cancer spread we saw what happened to the right
when the right let its crazies take over and dictate and become the elephant that drove the
rider we cannot let that happen and so we must push back excise and get rid of the people who
are cancer in our party and in our movements and there are many many many that i think are
mask on amongst us but for a brief moment on october 7th they dropped their mask and we saw
this with um not only online activity with people asking like what do you think decolonization looks
like and gang next every time i hear could be colonized that that is as a term tainted for me
forever yeah right i will never hear decolonization said in a way that doesn't
make me think oh that's what they mean right that was ugly okay so if i can take a swing at that yeah
i hear what you're saying wick um so when i know if you're a traditional republican that wants
low taxes and you know little government regulation maybe even you have a some questions about uh what
our school board policy should be and how much we're talking about like same-sex marriage stuff
like that that to me is just bread and butter normie republican stuff uh i don't have any issue
with that i want to beat you at the ballot box i don't agree with you but i think that is democracy
these are some stats this is according to the university of washington uh so this is from maga
supporters and the percentage of maga supporters according to the university of washington that
supported trump's election fraud claims was almost 98 the number of maga sports distrust the 2020
presidential election results was 97 the number of maga people that believe voting shouldn't be
easier is over 90 distrust this distrust the 2020 congressional results is almost uh 80 percent so
over and over and over again i think you're seeing this more on the right it certainly exists on the
left but there's a strain on the right of fundamentally not believing in democracy not
believing in the rule of law and seeing the opposition as an enemy in a way that you truly
want to see them destroyed not just beating them at the ballot box but you think they're so evil
that you just want to like this is why you see the national divorce and talk of the second civil war
from the right so i and what really worries me is i see the same sentiment growing on the left
part of why i'm taking this blow like professionally in calling it out is i
don't want the left to become a mirror of the right i think that would be a really dark fate
for the country any thoughts on this sfo i know it's uh yeah you're the opposition here but go
ahead well i mean you're you're characterized him as a right right away now look at that
i guess that's not what i said that's not what i said no no rick just did yeah because it's
funny but go ahead so here's the thing right like i don't remember what it was but there was
definitely something that made me feel over 10 years ago what basically you're feeling right
now brianna it's like oh there is actually some some dark evil underneath all of the good rhetoric
of the left and there is actually some serious problems here and i think anyone who ever went
through like that i'm leaving the left or i've been abandoned by the left arc which you hear
like tim pool says that about himself i think she won head might say it about herself maybe yeah
there's been like a bunch of people online who have said that i think a lot of that is it's not
that the left has has left anyone behind it's a realization that not in terms of policy because
policy is different from location to location in terms of philosophy the left actually is not
morally superior to the right and when that comes out people are kind of stunned like oh
oh okay and then then they have to go through like a moment of awakening i think
so if it's i i don't think i've ever thought we were morally i mean you gotta understand because
of my unique background like when i think about republicans i do think about all the people i
know back down home in mississippi right they're they're good people they go to church uh they are
living in society that is still very much bearing the weight this open wound of segregation in the
civil war has been largely forgotten by the rest of the country i think they are racist in ways
they don't understand i think their policies are wrong and i think we need to um to denounce that
but are they fundamentally evil people and i'm a good person i don't i've never thought that's
true right like i think people are people and i think the more time you spend like actually going
out and doing politics in the real world you'll see like there's the like i've never talked to
anyone i couldn't find something that i liked something about them right so i i don't know
i've just never seen it in that moral black and white and i think that's why what's happening to
you right now is happening yeah i've definitely met leftists both online and off who thought that
they were just superior for their beliefs yeah well that is that is a thing and it does speak
to horseshoe theory um but like i look i i've been going off on this for a while now on my show i
know people are probably tired about it but i think it's very very important that we have to
recognize our own internal issues because if we don't it's going to be a problem and it's hard i
know it's hard it's hard to recognize that the people you thought were on your side are probably
probably not on your side really um and yeah it's just a struggle we're going to write actually i
actually want to amend what i said it's not only that they think that they're superior it's a it's
that even in their superiority if it were real they have no humility about it and that's really
the killer because sometimes you do just just have a better idea right but you you have to
you have to be humble in victory and i think that's something the left has a problem with
yeah i i agree with that i think that's why you see a lot of this rhetoric where like i've been
called a genocide supporter more times today than i can even count even though i'm very strong
strongly pro-palestine i've said many times like we need to stop civilian death there right so i
certainly understand that tendency to really moralize things really really quickly so okay
and fallible owl thank you for calling in any last comment any last words comrade before we
send you to the void yeah i was just gonna say that i think that a little bit that you have to
think about because i think you they get it you look at it from a moderate perspective and you
think moderates are the good ones and no bad people from all sides moderate moderation people
moderation moderates there there's times to be radical and extreme there's time to be moderate
and you have to be able to recognize which is which um i do think that moderates tend to do
less harm overall simply by dint of their style of engaging with things but that doesn't mean that
they're right um and i'm not like people call me like a centrist but i'm not i'm solidly well on
progressive right i'm solidly left-leaning i'm not a hundred percent left-leaning but i'm pretty
close um i do i do really think that extremism is way worse in moderation though in most cases
i can set myself a little bit further left but i call out people on the left to do shit that
i don't agree with well then when they're when they're celebrating hamas in the streets i think
you should call that out brother thank you for coming on foul thanks okay um i know that you
have to go well so i'm going to give you the mic to tell people is it time who you are i mean it's
9 20 it's a three hour and 20 minute show i mean i'm i'm i'm down for i gotta read a couple more
super chats here so i'll be on for a little bit longer take your time take your time so here's
the thing just just real quickly i've been taking notes and there's probably too many things to
really go into today because there's like this is how every conversation is right like you have an
idea but then the conversation moves on and like you could have gone a different way so we should
probably do this again sometime yeah and and i just just really quickly though i i've noticed
there's like a trend with you and me on twitter where i will dig up something that is like truly
ridiculous on the left and you're like flabbergasted i mean you're like do you know what i'm talking
about yeah yeah because there's the one time where it's like hey here's an article by some random
leftist who thinks that we should abolish nuclear families because it would be better for liberation
and then see when i say things like um government should be liberal people should be conservative
i'm looking at you know the the end result of the march of progress where we're now tearing
down things that are essential and we're slandering them as conservative and tearing
things down as essential to like human life and it's like well i don't want to do that you know
i think that nuclear families are actually good you know it's good for most people to be in a
nuclear family so that's kind of where i'm coming from yeah no i get it i get it um i mean i watch
your tick tock tuesday videos they're my favorite but i think you do you don't have to watch those
they're ridiculous no but you show some stuff that's crazy and it blows my mind genuinely so
there it is okay um where where could people find you what would you if you could will like pitch
anything to my audience right now to dev's audience what would it be i get involved with
the 2024 election i'm doing a ton of work with progressive victory uh we are going to be starting
an mvp canvassing house with death with destiny very very soon i'm really excited about that
uh deep canvassing is something we've really learned in the democratic party and this is the
way it works um if you have people that are kind of embedded in the community and they're constantly
going out to you know fish fries and knocking on doors and truly getting to know people in the
community and forming those deep relationships um it doesn't just help you win one election it
helps you start to turn a whole community around and you know something steven has never gotten
credit for is his commitment to electoral politics and really making a difference i understand why
his hot takes uh uh get the most attention but i think underneath that is someone who truly
loves this country and wants to do his part so uh that's going to be coming up really soon
uh we're going to have ways for y'all to get uh involved with that so i hope that you will
this country's worth fighting for well thank you uh brianna for spending some time with us today
and we'll see you next week when we have just one thing and that's looking forward to that
and maybe uh uh deb may sometime we can play smash brothers or something on your strength
that'd be a good old time do you play do you play street fighter six uh no no what i'm playing
project zomboid right now actually that's the big one there we go learn street fighter six my jury's
pretty fierce rihanna rihanna wants to take you to task okay rihanna we're gonna let you go we'll
see you later bye-bye have a good evening what a great what a great you just kick her out and
she leave i i i move them off move along all right once they're done okay we do what we do
we got to keep it snappy okay efficiency okay okay that's okay um so now i have you here just
i won't keep you very much longer but i do have a question we can stay till the end i mean it's
super chats to do right yeah yeah super chats to do um but before we get to those i will ask you
this um how do you think that went um about what i thought like there's uh there was definitely
some people who were saying who were like messaging me and being like don't talk to
brianna she's a snake and i'm like you know i can kind of understand that point of view because she
was crazy 10 years ago but i've also seen her make the rounds for the like past year or so and she's
been very reasonable i do i i whatever faults she had 10 years ago that created this negative um
this negative view of her on on some parts of the internet they're they're definitely it's she's not
who she was and i kind of knew that it was going to be a much more reasonable conversation um and
it was pretty much what i expected you know no i get you i think that there's this tendency for us
to hang the worst or worst selves onto onto others like their worst selves their worst moments
and that's all they ever are um i can i can attest that through working with her right i didn't know
her very much i didn't know her at all i didn't talk to her at all during the gamergate years or
things like that probably wouldn't have um but she's always been square with me she's always
treated me fairly and i haven't seen her um do anything duplicitous or backstabby or anything
like that if there were snake times before fair enough but i don't see them now um i will say that
like she's genuine when she wants to just work with others not just because um it's just a good
thing to do and want to change but like from a pragmatic standpoint it's just it's just better
to build than to tear down it's better to build bridges like that and i think that um we're
we're working on it we're bringing her around so we'll smooth out that's a conservative point of
view wick you're not liberating things you're conserving them you know what my policies that
i advocate for um much like you're saying right are writ large for the community as a whole when
it comes to my personal stances and things like that i do believe that we are masters of our own
destiny and we need to take um accountability and responsibility for what we do and what we
put into the world and i do think that things are worth conserving i'm not i'm not progress
i'm not i'm not progressive for progress's sake there i want to progress to certain things to
certain points to certain outcomes and i don't think we need to throw the baby out with the
bath water in order to get there um there's just no need for it to tear down when we can uh reform
and rebuild but i don't know um let's ask these uh super chats real quick because
artemis fowl has been very generous and i want to make sure that he gets his money
he has that glowy money and you know what i'm here for it okay i'm here for it um ten dollars
the same side that claimed that supporting israel and jews in israel is anti-semitic but became
amazingly nuanced when it comes to hamas and the palestinians who support the killing of jews
i guess it's not a question so much but yeah it's it's one of those things where
it's it's so easy to be hypocritical because you can have like 18 million different stances and
18 million different topics and so whatever ends up serving your politics i think is what a lot of
extreme people do they will like they'll think they'll they will um you know i i gotta find that
exact jesus christ i think i think my brain's starting to melt let me find it here yeah so
basically they'll they'll claim racism when it cuts one way and they'll claim liberation when
it cuts the other way you know it's one of those things where it doesn't matter that it doesn't
make sense what only matters is that you say the two statements far enough apart from each other
that no one notices and this is this is why i'm harping on this and i know people are tired of me
harping on this but people are seeing this like we see people high profile figures have left very
leftist chapters the dsa has bleeding membership right from high profile members like there there's
october 7th has created this fissure amongst the left that i don't think we've reckoned with yet
and not just the left the rights rights the right's currently trying to to decide which
it hates more muslims or jews right and they're going to fight about that for a while but on the
left like we have this uh there there are people who thought we were going for one thing that
have realized that oh no those memes that the republicans were trying to make you into
no those are actually that's actually what you actually wanted and uh what and so we have this
kind of uh fight going on right now but we'll get through it we'll get we'll get past it hopefully
yeah um five more dollars there's nothing more delicious or decadent than to be able to hate with
a moral conscience that is currently the only thing the left offers i don't think that's true
but fair enough that's a huxley quote quote it is uh well a bastardized huxley quote he didn't
talk about the left but fair enough yeah okay is there anything um that you thought we should
have gotten to that we didn't get to tonight my entire list of things well fair enough fair
enough maybe like something like was there any like elephants in the room that we didn't tackle
that you like wick i can't believe you didn't bring up this um no i don't think so i don't
think so i mean a lot of everything was brought up it's just that i probably had more to say on
a topic but then it kind of moved on it's like oh well that's how it is that's how it is sometimes
um two dollars from testicle johnson vote vivek 2024 um thank you for the two dollars okay um
and if there's nothing else though i mean dev looks like a professional smash player that's one
of them oh there you go two dollars from artemis valley i'm looking at him i do need to get better
at reading these things i need to figure out like either a time where like in the middle of the
discussion we can pause i can just read them all or at the end or something but people want to
people want to get their question into the discussion and so i've been trying to
figure out the best way to integrate it it's a struggle but we'll get through it there's
definitely like it's good to like have breaks or like minutes where you go to the washroom or
something and you start checking out the super chats something like that that's pretty normal
i think fair enough okay um well thank you for coming on today is there anything uh you want
to say before i let you go um i don't think so okay i mean your honor agreed to talk again and
we can always talk again i just i will absolutely reach out to you and uh have you on again for a
variety of ideas so i have on my calendar for some reason wick 15 november 15 did you give me
a date for anything if i have i'm gonna have to check my messages i document all the things that
i invite people to so i'll have to look do you have anything going on in the 15th no but the
16th is when no opinion comes on so okay maybe this is just an aspirational thing that you wanted
to come on the 15th for i don't know what i'm doing oh you know what it might have been
there was that there was that one person on twitter what's their what's their name i don't
remember yeah but they wanted to talk but then like it kind of like fell apart maybe that's what
it was um yeah i look if we still want that to happen i know that you're tagging me all the time
to bring people on to fight you it's fun i'm just like no i could still make that one happen that
one is something that i can make happen i just don't like they on talking to them i don't know
precisely what the issue is like with carl max i knew what you guys were going to talk about right
um with this one i don't i think she just doesn't like you i i think i think it would be a bog
standard socialism is better conversation fair enough and i think even as somebody who's not
a debater i think that would i could just like kind of walk through that and just be like yep
here it is yep yep but yeah i'll uh if you want i'll uh reach out to that and see if they can make
me happy i know sunday's been desperately trying to get you on from anything but uh
it's funny to watch you tell him no so yeah i just here i know he's listening i understand
here here's your your one drop of attention here you go but you know in terms of i think
her name was jaylen or something um i mean like i'm interested in talking to her it's always fun
okay because but i think it wouldn't be a fruitful conversation i think it would be rehashing why
socialism sucks and then coping and then it would be like okay well there we go those can be fun
and those can be uh look we go through the the the what the the standards the classics if you will
of debates right like there's certain types of content that will always draw views they're
evergreen um are women bad in the various forms gets a lot of attention gets a lot of views right
you know socialism versus capitalism that's another one that gets a lot of attention a lot
of views so there's these uh these evergreen topics we can always make it work uh people
are asking are you going to stream are you going to start doing streaming uh no they're they're
asking me if i'm going to do my gaming stream oh so here's the thing here's the thing whenever i
fire up fiber politics stream because i'm not i'm not a consistent streamer like like everyone
else in twitch poll i don't i do not do that sort of thing i've thought about it like streaming
every day for twitch poll but i don't know i don't know if that's that's me right but um
i do stream once a week like a weekly news show on sunday and whenever i stream that lowest point
i get like 200 viewers highest point i get like a thousand so i can do pretty good for myself as a
streamer i think very cool when i stream video games i get between like 20 and 50 those are
wick numbers right there but now it's it's that's great but like the the core viewers love that
shit they love the gaming streams and they're always tuning in and they're
so the ones who ask me dev where are you are you streaming tonight dev it's always like that core
audience and they're the ones who want the the smaller like intimate streams and they ask me
like every night every night what i'm doing probably not tonight guys i think i think this
ran too late and also i was working on uh i was hoping to get the next video out today it's
probably going to be tomorrow at this rate but i was working on that all day so i don't i think
basically um i'm doing the archcast tomorrow afternoon so i'll either stream some gaming
stuff either before or after the archcast tomorrow i think okay well with that gang
we're gonna let you go remember monday we're gonna have the mental illness stream with uh
xena cherry and pixie um tuesday will be food stamps versus admiral gibbs and then thursday
will be noah opinion with brianna woo and sdl um so if you guys want to see that kind of content
give me a follow give me a like give me a subscribe that's great dev thank you again
and we will see you later bye no problem