So people are looking for the Jojo's Bizarre Adventure stream that I did with Lilith Lovett,
where we talked about Joe Jorgensen's impact on the 2020 election, and I think that stream is lost
to time. I can't find an archived copy of it, it's no longer up on YouTube, and the file that I
uploaded to Bitchute is refusing to process, so I think, unfortunately, that might just be a video
that is gone. I hate to say it, because I really don't like the idea of the canon of my content
having a hole in it, but I can't find the file. I just can't find the file. I think I deleted it
after uploading it to Bitchute, but I didn't wait for it to process, and now it's gone. I'm really
sorry. So if you're looking for that stream, unless I find it somewhere, I think it's been
lost to time. Don't worry, I'm pissed at myself too. I'm sorry about this. I'll talk to you later.
I love you.