So I was having a very enlightening conversation on stream last night. It was the The Last of Us 2
stream. And to be fair, I was actually doing quite poorly at it. And the main reason for that is
because, well, I was operating on about one and a half hours sleep. Yeah, it's it's it's been kind
of a rough, a rough past couple days, if you know what I mean. But nonetheless, my chatroom was
making some very good points. And I would like at least the opportunity to ruminate on them and
maybe answer some questions at a time when I have, you know, had a full night's sleep and had some
coffee and I'm actually kind of at least halfway put together right now. Okay, so the contention
was over my use of the terms, you know, leftist, centrist, and I guess rightist. And the way I've
always seen things is that you have, you know, the left-right spectrum of politics. I know that it's
it's very simplistic. Most people like to use either like the the eight axis spectrum of
politics. Sometimes they like to use the left-right freedom order grid of politics. I think all of
these tools have their place when talking about politics. The way that I conceptualize the the
one axis system where it's just left and right is that it's relatively unchanging and that the
Overton window is a box on this left-right politics that kind of shifts leftward or rightward
as basically the larger public opinion changes. Which is how, you know, my support in the late
1990s of say gay marriage and universal health care and things like that. Those were a very
solidly leftist position but as the Overton window has shifted much further left and now that it's
all about, you know, hard socialism or the demonization of masculinity and other things
like this that things have kind of gone too far left to me. Well within the Overton window I now
look like somebody who is right wing which is why a lot of the far left nowadays calls me right
wing. And why I call them the far left because see if the entire spectrum is left center right
then I am still the center left and the far left is now the far left. However, and this is something
that I genuinely didn't know about this is this is news to me, some people actually view the left
right center labels as being part of the Overton window itself. So the definitions of left center
and right will change as the Overton window moves. Okay that makes sense to me. I think it's a dumb
way of doing things but if that is how we are going to understand these concepts then maybe we
should change up the conversation entirely. For example a person on discord DMed me this a couple
months ago and I wish I could remember which one it was. Was it Sushimaru? I'm sorry I can't remember
who it was. I'm sorry but you know who you are. You showed me this idea. Other than having an axis
with two ends you have a triangle. When the enlightenment basically philosophically shattered
the idea of the old theocracies and the old monarchies once and for all we got primarily
three schools of thought out of it and those three schools of thought are properly described by
the French motto liberty equality and fraternity with liberty generally mapping onto liberalism
equality generally mapping onto communism and fraternity generally mapping onto fascism.
These also correspondingly map onto the human values of freedom equality and tradition and
really it's it's not too hard to see how this is the case the liberals the original liberals the
classical liberals they're more concerned with personal freedom than they are with tradition
or equality the free speech of liberalism is a direct challenge to tradition meanwhile the free
markets of liberalism are a direct challenge to equality meanwhile the communist in valuing
equality over both freedom and tradition will try to see that everyone is equal oftentimes
they will claim to do this by raising everyone up to the highest standard but oftentimes that
is impossible and in practice communism often drags everyone to the lowest standard one of the
great jokes about communism is that we might all be poor but at least we're all equal fascism
meanwhile in its valuing of tradition over both freedom and equality always devolves into tyrannical
states that bind themselves together by some kind of unifying force with the Italians it was
nationalism with Germans it was the race but it's always some kind of characteristic like that
that keeps the society together so okay we've got these three schools of thought and they are all
opposed to each other in equal measure for example the liberal with freedom as his highest order value
correctly views both fascism and communism as being anti-freedom the traditional life that the
fascist would impose on everyone is fundamentally anti-freedom because people would not be free to
reject it meanwhile the redistribution policies that the communists would impose on the marketplace
as well as in practice the mass slaughtering of those people that they deemed to be the bourgeoisie
like say the kulaks the peasantry who were you know these serfs that finally managed to get
a little bit of land for themselves did well because they were actually competent farmers
and then got slaughtered by the soviets when they resisted the collectivization of their rightly
owned lands remember the kulaks were heroes sorry about that that little side rant my main point is
the liberal with freedom as his highest order value when push comes to shove will reject both
tradition and equality because those values in their purest form infringe on the freedom of the
individual meanwhile the communist with equality as his highest order value will reject both
freedom and tradition but for different reasons tradition because tradition because that is the
thing that they are trying to destroy they want to directly revolt and wash away those old orders and
all of their problems like with monarchy and feudalism as well as with what they perceive to
be problems in capitalism but they also do oppose individual freedom because freedom means the
freedom not to go along with their revolution that's why they label these people as bootlickers
as counter-revolutionary elements as reactionaries they do fundamentally believe that there is a
proper politics that there is only one way for progress to actually go that there is only one
path to follow so if you're a fascist and therefore in the name of tradition you reject
progress the communist will oppose you however if you are a liberal and therefore you don't reject
progress but you have a different idea of what progress is if you don't agree with them well
then the communist will oppose you as well and this is also why communists often conflate
liberals and fascists you'll often see things like liberalism is the handmaiden of fascism or you'll
see fascism is just capitalism and decay you know stuff like this it's because they believe they
have an exclusive claim to what progressivism is they believe they are the arbiter of progress and
so even the act of debating it is to them fascism counter-intuitively enough it's why you constantly
see these people deplatforming others or initiating violence in the streets or slandering everyone who
doesn't agree with them as a nazi or something right meanwhile the fascist rejects the liberal
for the same reason that the liberal rejects the fascist freedom means having the option to not
be traditional or live a traditional life and if tradition is your highest order of value then
freedom is in natural opposition to that meanwhile tradition is also in natural opposition to
equality because the traditional hierarchy was not an equal one the old orders were not orders
of equality and therefore the communists and fascists also fundamentally disagreed on that
you'll notice that i've spent more time talking about the flaws of communism than the flaws of
fascism in this video so far that is not out of any love of the fascist rather it's because
i don't think we really need to go over the flaws of fascism anymore do we the 20th century kind of
showed the flaws pretty clearly of both fascism and communism to the point that i can't believe
we're still fucking debating it like 80 years later but the difference is as i talked about
in my yuri bezbanov video yesterday it's that fascists never culturally integrated themselves
into the west the way the communists did there are no fascist university professors teaching the next
round of kids to be white supremacists or something but there are a shit ton of marxists
out there i personally have had the unfortunate pleasure of being taught by a bunch of them and
i'm very grateful that i managed to pull myself out of that the point is you have this triangle
right of these opposing values and i'd say the classical liberal is probably about here if you
go extremely high up on the freedom scale you get to like the anarcho stuff like the anarcho
capitalists and stuff the classical liberal is is not quite so high you've got the basic bitch
conservative you know the conservative that you would find in like a regular first world democracy
they're going to be leaning a bit more towards order you have the social democrat who's probably
leaning a bit more towards equality but they still have some aspects of freedom in them you of course
have the pure fascist and the pure communist meanwhile the nazis specifically they were
actually probably a little bit more towards equality than freedom though they were definitely
still within tradition because if you read a lot of a lot of hitler's writings you'll realize
that he adopted some socialist policy he simply wanted to be a nationalized variant of it not a
globalized variant he wanted socialism for only the germans that's why it was national socialism
the mere image of that would probably be the tankies because you know the the stalin types
they weren't pure ideological communists but they definitely filled in that gap with
authoritarianism and not personal freedom and so we have a very rough but i think at least
somewhat useful political map and since the terms leftist or or center left or right wing centrist
whatever they've kind of become nebulous i think i'm going to try and stick with with this graphic
from now on in terms of how i declare myself politically because i do believe myself to be
a classical liberal i'm not a communist i'm not a fascist personal freedom is the highest order
value for me and i think the most successful societies are the ones that value personal
freedom over both equality and tradition i spend so much of my time on this channel talking about
the communists because that seems to be the resurgent political ideology right now go over
to breadtube you can find a shit ton of socialist channels over there there's marxist apologists
all over the place is there actually like a resurgent fascism you got like guys like richard
spencer or or nick fuentes in the alt-right but who the hell are they does anyone care they had
their peak like four years ago and they peaked at what maybe maybe at the most like 20 000 people
the remnants of what was once the alt-right basically just became ethan ralph's fan base
like there's nothing left to them they're absolutely gone the current political war
right now is between the liberals and the communists and because the communist views
liberalism and fascism as being hand in hand that's why they all call everyone fascist i've
been talking about all this for a while now because i want to show how liberalism communism
and fascism while they're connected they all oppose each other for very specific reasons
and they have connected yet different views on a lot of topics for example regarding the state the
liberal views the state as a necessary evil it exists as a night watchman it stays out of people's
way it has no real moral opinion and it only gets involved when someone's rights are violated
the socialist state meanwhile is a temporary evil because the socialist state is meant to transition
towards pure communism the state is totalitarian it is as marks described it a dictatorship of the
proletariat it's run by the workers revolution which spends its time forcibly re-educating the
people towards communist thought until the state can naturally wither away into a stateless society
so they view the state as a temporary evil the fascist meanwhile views the state as the ultimate
good the eternal mechanism through which the people are best expressed as mussolini wrote
and everything the people the property everything is subservient to the state
speaking of property the liberals view property as an inherently good thing they view it as an
expression of a person's labor if you work you create property or you get paid and money and then
use the money to buy property either way at some point you're working at something and you're
creating property out of it and in fact it's out of the concept of property that human rights come
about because we own our lives as if it is property we own our bodies as if they are property
communism meanwhile views property as inherently evil all property is communal property including
the individual and of course this view of property and money in the economy fails to take into
account natural human greed which believe it or not you can't be re-educated out of which is why
it always takes a tremendous amount of force directly from the government in order to impose
this sort of thing on the people that is the main reason why socialism will never actually
wither away and become communism because no bureaucracy ever voluntarily shrinks itself
meanwhile fascists view property as a necessary evil they recognize that people will work harder
if they work for themselves but ultimately all property is state-owned again including the
individual and speaking of the individual the liberal views the purpose of the state itself
to be the citizens of it the people create the state for their purposes laws are written at the
whim of the people the liberal state is almost like a patchwork piece where free people will
debate vote and ultimately change up the making of the state as circumstance demands socialism
views the citizen as inconsequential they hope for a global worldwide communist revolution and
everyone will simply be communal fascism meanwhile views people as being owned directly by the state
the state controls and guides them as an eternal father and while the liberals believe that the
people create the state the fascists believe that the state creates the people so while these three
forces exist in opposition to each other they also sometimes agree as you can see the liberals and
fascists both agree that the state should exist meanwhile the communists do not therefore the
communists often see the liberals as fascists or at least as fascist helpers or vulnerable to
fascism liberals and communists both hate the elitism of the fascist the purpose of the fascist
state is to create and enforce a strict hierarchy of power while the communist wishes to do away
with hierarchy altogether and the liberal prefers a hierarchy of competence communists and fascists
both agree with mass slavery fascism enslaves people directly in the name of the state
communism does it indirectly by the collectivization of the means of production
and the mass re-education of people to think the same way which in practice also results in slavery
the liberal opposes both communism and fascism as revolutionary ideologies destructive to the
freedom of the individual so with this in place you can kind of see why someone from a liberal
point of view will look at a communist and a fascist and say those are both totalitarian
they're anti-freedom i don't want that the communist meanwhile looks at a liberal
and screams fascist nazi collaborator bootlicker etc etc meanwhile the fascist views both of them
as disorderly as rejecting the natural state of the world some of my fans have linked to me
i i'd say about five different breadtubers at this point voshes is only one of them
but five different breadtubers who have done videos on me people who have done you know
reply girl videos to some of the things that i've done um i haven't really watched much of them to
be honest you know the drama scene is not exactly my cup of tea anymore you know but even though i
don't watch those videos fans of those communities definitely come into my videos and start leaving
comments and starting debates that's fine of course that's their freedom of speech but in
talking with them i've kind of discovered a few things um i've discovered why these people think
the way that they do about progress you know we we had the whole reactionary video we had we had
the talk on progressivism what progress is and that's because in general the communist worships
progress they are an entirely materialistic philosophy there's no there's no spiritual
aspect to them at all they're all about progress but they're all about a very narrow definition of
what progress is and it's also why i think most people who are who are progressives or who are
on the progressive left or whatever i think that's why most of them end up being communists or
socialists in the end but the fascist rejects the idea of progress entirely in favor of tradition
they say no that's something new that's progress we're not going that way we are sticking to the
old ways that is the way of the fascist meanwhile the liberal is different from both of these things
the liberal doesn't reject progress as a concept the way that the fascist does but the liberal
does not agree with the narrow-minded definition of what progress is that the communist believes
in the communist you know skimmed over the little red book and said oh this is the road map of
progress we follow these steps like their commandments and will reach the promised land
the communist utopia the communists lacking a spiritual aspect of their philosophy and being
entirely materialistic worship progressivism as if it is a religion in a sense they believe that
there is only one path for humanity to take for things to progress and that everyone who doesn't
follow that path is a reactionary a counter-revolutionary something like that i talked
about this a little bit at the start of the video but but here's kind of the main point the liberal's
view of progress is much broader than the socialist's view of progress for the liberal
progress is a spectrum you could say for the liberal what progress is isn't predetermined or
predefined written by a prophet in an ancient text or by a philosopher in a manifesto progress is the
future it's the unknown we don't know what progress is how can you know the thing that you haven't
thought up yet so for the liberal progress is experimentation progress is trying new things
progress is a thousand different paths that may or may not lead somewhere it is not inherited knowledge
brought down it is not inherited knowledge brought down by god himself meanwhile the
socialist believes that they have the perfect knowledge of what progressivism is they believe
that they have the perfect politics they know the one true way just like every other religious zealot
and therefore every person who disagrees with them regardless of whether they're disagreeing with them
on the utility of progress itself or the direction that progress should take they're labeled as a
heretic or you know a reactionary and since the ideological war right now is between the
liberals and the socialists and this war is fought not over whether or not we should progress
but what form that progress should take it is no surprise to me that breadtubers for example
view liberals as reactionaries just like the communists view liberals as fascists if they
categorically understand the one true path of progress then everyone else's opinion
must simply be going backwards but we know that's not the truth of the matter
all right i'm done guys make sure to speak freely i'll talk to you next time i love you