I hate to be a downer
Hello ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the right opinion the home of a twat with too much free time and Matt Hoss
What a scumbag
Yes
The sheer amount of mental turmoil that he has put h2a3 over a single video has guaranteed him a special seat in hell
Regardless of what you think of their content
Vape nation
I genuinely cannot stand the man a selfish egomaniac whose videos were no better than mediocre in the first place
He recently announced the date of the supposed court hearing
I didn't watch the video as I didn't want to grant him that thousandth of a cent for the view
I found it out. Otherwise, hopefully I think it's sometime in April, but I found that on reddit
So if I'm wrong, tell me I can be wrong on facts
Not opinions though, of course, but everyone's relatively confident, right? Right?
I'm not well not as much as I'd like to be at least you see we as a YouTube community know that this whole lawsuit
Is ridiculous and the video contained enough commentary to be described as constructive
We wouldn't watch Matt Hoss's video if Ethan and Hila hadn't provided their banterous remarks to add on to it
But we're not there to tell them that talking and we can't trust them to take Ethan's word on that
For example, they didn't believe Ray William Johnson when he went up against Duke and media and actually ruled in favor of the large video
Sharing corporation and to be fair Matt Hoss doesn't have quite the same weight as Duke and media
Regardless of what he thinks of himself my parents put me in pussy
I've been a champion ever since and h3h3 do more than Ray William Johnson
Whereas Johnson was more of a reporter even the healer are more commentators
But one of the problems that makes h3h3 productions an easier time at the most commentary channels
Is that they've always labeled themselves as a reaction channel and that makes them vulnerable to being tarred with the same brush with these other
Channels that don't add anything on as a reaction is different to criticism
Even though I and many others have always considered h3h3 a channel that builds greatly on the content that they look at
I don't trust them to see the same picture and maybe that's just because I'm not very trusting person
But there are a lot of idiots in the world and you never know where they're gonna be
My main concern is that there's a court full of middle-aged people who don't have experience in this area
And in a way you don't always expect people to have an understanding of such a situation
But I think
Inexperience lends a disadvantage to Ethan healer on these accounts that if I was brushing the surface you could say that they're not doing anything
Transformative even though after watching many of their videos it's clear to me and many others
They do most of these creators a favor by giving them extra exposure Ethan and healers content is not malign
It's typically very casual very light-hearted and obviously as it's not as critical
It does make them a soft target and exploiting that especially when the video was nothing personal is pretty
reprehensible and the fact that Matt Hoss probably benefited of their initial video and then has the audacity to file a
Fucking lawsuit probably with some of the money he made from that fucking exposure that video gave fucking disgusting
And Ethan Nila have wasted copious amounts of money on lawyers just to maximize their chance and they did not have to do this
They could have just settle with four thousand dollars passing over to that twat and we'd all be
Fucking fucked by lawyers coming round like the fucking tax collectors asking us for money because we use their fucking videos
this is about the community and I really hope they do win because they deserve to and everyone is in near
Unanimous agreement that Matt Hoss is trying to ruin YouTube for everyone and I have a message for those like Matt Hoss
Who want to tear down the foundations?
There's so many have worked so hard and so look borously to put up that without it
Your pathetic little channel probably wouldn't exist in the first place
You won't even have a platform to perform your audacious publicity stunts
But remember we are stronger than you so you can fucking pull the carpet from under our feet and we will get up again
You can try to shackle us with your fucking
Egocentrism, but we will break the chains
You could plunge a stake through the heart of this community and we will pull every last
splinter out because for every
Narcissistic braggart like you there's a whole fan base willing to get behind
Positive cause that won't necessarily benefit them but because it's right and if there's one thing I know about
It's righteousness. I'm the right opinion
And here's to fair use
You