Well, here we are.
Fuck being on some chill shit. We go 0 to 100 nigga real quick.
Hello ladies and gentlemen, welcome to The Right Opinion, the home of a twat with too much free time.
And hey, that's pretty good.
It's taken its time, but I've made my first milestone a hundred.
Hopefully not my last achievement in my hugely successful lifespan.
And as a special treat, I'm going to reveal parts of my body.
This time, my finger.
Oh yeah, look at that symmetry, wow, what a wonderful finger.
If you get me to 500 I might even show you my hand.
It would be like a game of hangman, without the noose, hopefully.
But for real, I really appreciate it, the huge wave of support I've received recently
has been unreal, and without this wonderful amp discord, I doubt I'd be celebrating such
a pioneering accomplishment.
I've done some collabs, even a couple podcasts, expanding has been a lot of fun recently,
I also wouldn't have done it without the support of my friends to set this channel up.
I am eternally grateful, and the gratitude can be shown in the sidebar of my channel,
I suggest you check some of their content out.
Now as I'm such a generous, virtuous, ethical, principle, righteous human being, I'll take
suggestions on what to do to celebrate this huge feat on YouTube that I'm sure the management
are celebrating as well.
You can leave your suggestions in the comments below, or you can contact me over one of the
social mediums and I will decide what's most reasonable.
I won't do anything offensive by the actual definition, nor will I do a face reveal, that
will probably come at around 10 million subscribers, maybe something a bit more ambitious actually.
So yeah, drop me your suggestions and I might just listen to them, if I'm in a good mood
that is.
I look forward to hearing them.
Anyway, I'm The Right Opinion, and thanks, seriously.