People of YouTube, it is I, everyone's favorite YouTuber, EmperorLemon.
And today I'm coming at you guys with an unscripted commentary.
Gonna be trying to work on more unscripted commentaries in the future.
Throw out the scripts.
So let me know if you enjoy unscripted commentaries.
And today, on this wonderful summer afternoon, I have come here to talk to you about some YouTube news.
And no, this isn't about YouTube getting rid of thumbnails for 0.3% of users.
Oh no, I can no longer see people making ridiculous facial expressions on a brightly colored background with bold impact text.
Whatever will I do? My YouTube experience is ruined.
No, no, no, no. This isn't about that.
All you people need to relax out there, YouTube custom thumbnails aren't going anywhere, okay?
Do you seriously think that YouTube, out of all companies, is gonna try to make an effort to remove clickbait?
Are you kidding me?
But no, that didn't stop everyone from raising hell over it.
And yeah, I get the point, oh it's a shady experiment, oh they just sprung it on us without telling us.
And to that I have to say, come on, it's YouTube.
Like this is just par for the course for them.
Yeah it's shady, yeah they probably shouldn't randomly experiment with random YouTube users without their consent,
but come on, they've been doing this stuff for the last three years.
So I don't really see why this should be that big of a problem.
YouTube is absolutely not getting rid of custom thumbnails, so everyone should stop worrying about it.
What you should worry about is this actual piece of YouTube news, which is literally about YouTube and the news industry.
I can't do it! Do it live. Do it live!!
Etf
And it comes from everyone's favorite YouTube CEO.
Old W.
Susan Wojcickuchuchuch manages to make the safety-
coming out with a brand new announcement that YouTube has invested $25 million to, quote,
support the future of news in online video.
So what they've done, apparently, is make a significant investment towards emphasizing
trusted news sources such as Fox News and CNN.
Because if I want to tune into some very accurate and unscued, unbiased news, the first thing
I think of is Fox News and CNN.
Tide goes in, tide goes out, never a miscommunication.
You can't explain that.
I don't know what that means!
So clearly what YouTube is doing, they have once again sided with corporate interests
rather than the interests of common YouTubers by choosing to promote mainstream media legacy
news sources on their platform.
And they're doing this at a time when the public's trust in the mainstream news media
has never been lower.
And there's a pretty good reason behind that trend, considering that ever since the 2016
election, the mainstream media in America has become so unbelievably biased that it's
beyond absurd at this point.
He's not still going to be president by May.
That's it!
Oh!
When you talk about George Bush, I mean, say what you want, the World Trade Center came
down during his time.
So you can go take a look at the blog that Google posted.
I'll put a link to it in the description and you'll see them give their glossy little explanation
for all this, but we all really know why they're doing this.
They'll tell you it's about the integrity and the trusted news sources.
But really, really, they don't care about any of that.
This is strictly a business decision.
YouTube, the corporation, YouTube, they have been getting hammered in the media lately.
Whenever you see a story about YouTube in the mainstream media, it's not positive.
99% of the time, it's going to be about some stupid YouTube vlogger doing a stupid thing,
or it's going to be an investigative hit piece made for fat soccer moms talking about how
YouTube is so dangerous for your children.
So it's very clear that heading into this year, YouTube's portrayal in the news media
has been overwhelmingly negative.
But hey, would you look at this?
YouTube is suddenly partnering with the mainstream news media.
How about that?
Definitely can't see any conflicts of interest here that would prevent the news media from
reporting on anything negative about YouTube anymore.
So that's why they're doing this.
Let's be real here.
Legacy Media knows that their audience is tuning out by the millions because of their
horribly tilted and inaccurate coverage of pretty much every news story since 2016.
They know they're losing their audience.
They know young people don't give a shit about the CBS evening news.
They know they're struggling and they know their future as an industry is in complete
jeopardy.
I love the young people.
So YouTube comes up to them and they're probably like, all right, you guys, I'll cut you a
deal.
I'm voting the hell out of you on YouTube.
And in exchange, we would like you to sort of downplay all that negative stuff about
YouTube.
Okay?
So that's what's happening on YouTube.
And in the near future, you're probably going to see a lot more news pop up on your homepage.
And just like always, you will ignore it and watch an actual YouTuber instead of the news
because YouTube audiences don't care about mainstream news.
YouTube audiences want to get their news from YouTubers.
Does that make the least bit of sense to you guys?
Say what you want about Philly D, Keemstar, Scarce.
But there's a reason these guys get millions upon millions of views while videos from official
news sources often struggle to break 50,000 views.
YouTubers are far more compelling.
YouTubers have a much stronger connection to the actual audience.
But once again, it's yet another branch of YouTube where the homegrown grassroots independent
creators are going to get bullied out of existence by corporate interests.
And it's a shame, but at the same time, I can't say I'm surprised.
I talked about this same exact thing happening in my video last year about YouTube's downward
spiral.
It's no secret that for the longest time now, YouTube has been continuously siding with
mainstream and corporate entities rather than their genuine homegrown creators.
Ever since old W took over, it just seems like this website has been continually getting
more and more corporate.
And I'm not going to sit here and say that's necessarily a 100% bad thing.
It sure is a good thing from YouTube's perspective.
Especially for them, hedging all these business relationships with dependent dying media industries
is certainly going to help them stick around in the long run.
So from a strictly business perspective, it makes perfect sense for them.
But at the same time, I can't help but wonder just how disconnected the higher ups at YouTube
are from their core audience.
People on YouTube don't want to watch the NBC Nightly News with Lester Holt.
People on YouTube want to follow personalities.
They don't want to follow some corporate puppet that's been put in his position by
an industry think tank.
And once again, you can prove that idea by just looking at the views.
YouTube audiences don't care about the legacy media.
And YouTube ramming them down our throats certainly isn't going to change that.
As a matter of fact, it'll probably make us like them less.
And strictly speaking from the perspective of a YouTube viewer, you're damn right I'm
going to choose an independent YouTube news personality over a mainstream media corporation.
Why would I side with an entity who has time and time again been proven to be a bunch of
liars, hypocrites, and scam artists who want to do nothing more than push an agenda and
conform to corporate interests?
I don't care how fair and accurate they claim to be.
If I'm going to be getting opinion-based news, I might as well get it from the independent
YouTuber who's not in the pocket of a massive corporation.
So yeah, you're damn right I'm going to choose the guy who can actually speak freely
about issues.
But now in order to protect their investment, YouTube is probably going to downplay all
of those channels, which is a damn shame.
They'll call them fake news.
They'll call them conspiracy theorists.
They'll call them racist, alt-right, radical, whatever.
And meanwhile, at the same time that they'll slander all of their honest, independent,
free-thinking YouTubers, they'll turn around and shove the corrupt mainstream media right
down your throat.
And obviously, like I said, it's not going to make us like them anymore.
But as far as YouTube's concerned, that $25 million investment is worth every penny to
make sure that the mainstream media doesn't really talk about YouTube's problems anymore.
So that's what's going on in YouTube right now.
Feel free to care about it, or don't.
This is the end of the video.
Goodbye!
What the hell is this?
Austin face-to-face with McMahon!
They're shaking hands!
Don't call his shaking hands!
We're saving himself!
For the love of God, someone tell me this is not happening!
It's happening!
Stone Cold Steve Austin has sold his soul for the WWS title!