Hello everyone, it's your favorite YouTube guy
YO PURR LEMON
And today, I am here to explain why I left
Buzzfeed
Abracadabra fatnuts!
It's me, the mayor of Meme Town
The Duke of the Downward Spiral
It's your morally questionable, factually questionable boy, Emperor Lemon
And I am here with yet another update video that no one will watch
Actually, I'm not so sure about that
Because last summer I did one and nobody watched it
But as you guys are probably aware
A lot has changed since last summer
A lot has changed about this YouTube channel
And a lot has changed about the world
But let's start with the obvious
The year is 2017
We are in year 7 of this YouTube channel
Lucky 7, because this is 2017
This is my time
This is year 2 of the never ending Emperor Lemon Downward Spiral World Tour
And this year I uploaded 2 videos
That will forever change the status of this once anemic YouTube channel
You see, last summer I began the era of my YouTube life cycle that you all know as the downward spiral
And every step of the way I faced resistance, backlash, and naysayers
Everyone thought they knew what was good for my channel
Nobody understood the downward spiral
And everybody questioned it
You all questioned me
You all questioned my motives
You all questioned my goals
But most importantly, you questioned why the Simpsons were green
All I wanted to do was make green Simpsons videos
But you people had to ruin it by complaining
So you know what?
Now I've become the one who complains
I complain here, I complain there
I complain everywhere
All I ever do is complain
I complain about frying Dory and you complain back
So I complained even harder
And now frying Dory is an afterthought
Just as it should have been all along
And it's funny to me
Because you all considered me an afterthought
You all wrote me off
You all left this channel for dead
You put me on the downward spiral
So you know what I did?
I wrote that shit
I took the ball you people gave me and fucking ran with it
Because when you're in a downward spiral
There's no escaping it
So you might as well aim for the bottom
And guess what?
If you do it right, you just might end up on top
So that's what I did
And guess what?
The downward spiral brought me directly to the most successful period
In the history of this YouTube channel
You see, the downward spiral is not a bad thing
It's not a problem
It never was
The downward spiral is not an infection
It's the cure
The downward spiral is a metamorphosis
And much like the humble caterpillar
I too entered my transformation as a weak, callow larva
Powerless to the will of my surrounding universe
And just like the caterpillar's chrysalis
I abandoned everything I once presumed about my being
And surrendered myself to the mysterious powers of nature and instinct
Some may call it magic
Others call it the pure manifestation of one's DNA
The unalienable directive of life to not only survive, but thrive
I myself don't understand the true odds and ends of it
But what I do know is that when the downward spiral spat me out on the other side
I emerged more powerful than ever before
A true monarch
Much like the insect bearing the same title
I too had gained flight
I was now free
Free from the dominion of my so-called fans
Free from the authority imposed by the higher powers of this website
And it turns out I always had been
But I allowed myself to become deluded by fear, insecurity, and inexperience
These factors constrained me and chained me to the illusion that my actions were out of my control
However, it was the downward spiral that served as my path towards enlightenment
First I was lost
But now I'm found
And the chains
The chains are off, man!
The chains are off!
I am the one in control now
Me! You people don't have power over me anymore
YouTube doesn't have power over me anymore
I have grasped the reigns of this channel and I've led it to the greenest pastures it's ever seen
And sure, it hasn't been the smoothest ride
I've scorched the earth around me
I've become hated by a ton of people
But that's the price I'm willing to pay for true creative freedom
That's the price I'm willing to pay for unconditional respect
And you can hate me all you want from now on
You really can
It won't make a difference
I have ascended to a level on this website that few others have before me
I scream at people to unsubscribe
And people subscribe more than ever
I force memes so far down people's throats that I give them an opposite direction prostate exam
I then scoop up the shit-covered, shit-tier shitpost memes
Put them on a cheap t-shirt and sell it back to them for money
And in an age where YouTube is forcing everyone to neuter their content into kid-friendly preschool playtime for babies
I've made my content more vulgar, more repugnant, and more despicable than it's ever been
And you wanna know why I do this?
You wanna know why I give as little of a shit as I do?
It's because YouTube is not my job
And I don't mean that I don't make money
I certainly do plenty of that
I like money
I like being able to afford things
I earn money from YouTube but it's not my job
It's a part-time hobby meant for fun that I just so happen to get paid for
What I'm saying is that making money on YouTube is not, and has never been, my primary goal
My primary goal has always been to make content that I like
So it doesn't fucking matter if you don't like it
Or you disagree with it
Whatever, boohoo, too bad, so sad
I don't answer to you
YouTube is not my job
And you aren't my boss
I am my boss
I decide what I want to make
Not you, me
And you know what I wanna make?
More fucking Green Simpsons videos
Because that's what this is all about
I started YouTube drama, I worked the system
I put in all this effort and won all these people over just so I could get them to watch Green Simpsons
Welcome to the greenest years of our adventures
So stay tuned for more Green Simpsons
And shitposts
And ear rape
And forced memes
And complaining
And more meme theory too
But this time it won't have to do with YouTube drama
Just memes
And theorizing
And shitting on normies
And using the word memescape
Okay, maybe it's gonna be just as bad as YouTube drama
But I don't give a fuck
Normies will just get mad and feed me even more ad revenue
Welcome to the greenest years of our adventures
You know what? Scratch that
I'm not even gonna make videos
This whole time I've just been designing a new t-shirt instead of editing
So yeah
New t-shirt
Featuring your new favorite Emperor Lemon meme
Enough is enough
And if you think this is the end of the downward spiral
Well, I've got news for you, buddy
That shirt's still there too
As a matter of fact
The downward spiral shirt will always be on sale
As a permanent symbol
Of the never-ending
Emperor Lemon
Downward spiral world tour
So go ahead
Buy a shirt
I guarantee you'll be disappointed
Thanks for the money though
And hey
If you wanna give me your money and get nothing in return
I have a Patreon
Let's see, what else?
I also have a subreddit that I barely post on
Oh yeah, and
I'm also opening up a Discord channel
Because that's something all the pro
Two school for cool YouTubers are doing
Woo wee
Look at this big time big ticket YouTuber
With a Discord channel and subreddit
Wow, I'm sure he must be in the big time
Playing John Madden big time football
Big muscle, big biceps
Mega ultra super duper beef supreme gordita
And
Have 200,000 people really subscribed to this shit?
But you wanna know what I really wanna know?
Do you wanna know the real deep itching burning question here?
Will anyone actually watch this update video?
Anyway, that's why I left Team 10
Jake Paul is a foot
So tune in next time
For another episode of
YouTube
Drama
Exposed
Reaction
Try not to laugh
Frank
Gone viral
Gone sexual
Raw movie review
Theory compilation
Rant part 188
Thanks for watching!