And now it's time for Silly Songs with Ant Lemon, the part of the show where Ant Lemon
comes out and sings a silly song.
So without further ado, Silly Songs with Ant Lemon.
In the eye of the storm, in the skies a big cyclone,
floods the place, floods the state, yet another hurricane.
Boiling seas, summer stink, beneath the waves the houses sink.
When you think you'll survive, it goes category five.
Blacker Ma, won't you come and wash away my state.
Blacker Ma, won't you come, won't you come, won't you come.
From the swamps to the shores, board your windows and your doors,
time has come to repent for all our past mistakes.
Disney World, Maimi Beach, where the crowds once sought to reach,
Ocean Man claims the land, no one swims like you anymore.
Blacker Ma, won't you come and wash away my state.
Blacker Ma, won't you come, won't you come.
Blacker Ma!