Check this out. I'm on the the Dumping with Scrump podcast playlist. We've got
the interviewing Sofia Narwhits video right here on Slovenian politics. Okay, the
Skywalker saga is a failure. WHO lied. People died. There's a deleted video.
What's the deleted video, guys? I'll click on this. Oh, a copyright claim. It's
a copyright claim by Muso TNT Limited. Well, it's not actually by Muso TNT
Limited. It's by Sony. The missing Dumping with Scrump is the one on The
Last of Us 2. You know, the one that was comedically titled Let's Play Joel in One
Pro Golf. As you can see, it's still up on my Bitchute. Link in the description to
the Bitchute channel where you can watch this video if you want. I don't know if
I'll upload it on the the SFO backups channel because the copyright appeal is
still going through. We all know at this point that Sony has been basically
trying to scrub the entire internet of criticism of The Last of Us 2 simply
because the game seems to be an absolute shit show. So, link in the description. You
want to watch this podcast here does head over to my Bitchute channel and
while you're over there you might as well subscribe to me there too because I
put all my videos out over there at least most of my videos anyway I try the
the Bitchute like auto connector doesn't seem to work very well for my channel
videos don't go up in a timely manner and I'm not quite sure what to do about
it but who knows in any case the podcast is up over on Bitchute Sony's been
abusing the DMCA regarding my channel as they have been regarding so many other
youtubers and they can suck my dick