Size matters. Let's make Earth twice as large.
It now has a diameter of roughly 25,500 kilometers and is eight times as heavy.
It now rotates 32 times slower, meaning one day lasts more than a month.
The force of gravity is twice as strong and since weight is determined by gravity,
all objects on Earth would be twice as heavy.
Your life expectancy would decline as your heart would
now have to pump twice as hard to circulate blood in your body.
The weight of trees and plants would cause them to fall over.
This also concerns the plants we depend on for food,
leading to massive food shortages and starvation.
For animals, the situation is similar.
Hunting becomes more difficult, especially for larger animals,
as they are slowed down by increased gravity.
Over the course of many generations,
nature would find a way to deal with these changing conditions.
The bones of humans and animals will become thicker and stronger.
At the same time, our bodies are getting smaller, adapting to the increased force of gravity.
Also, the overall height of vegetation would decrease
to ensure a sufficient supply of water and nutrients.
Overall, we would live in a very different world, showing that Earth's...