This is a meme that raises far more questions than answers.
It's supposed to be this deep-fried, obscure, ironic meme,
yet it has seen widespread use and even some media coverage.
It's yet another installment in the series of one-letter memes.
B, H, T-pose, press F to pay respects.
Have memes become so saturated that we have resorted to using letters of the alphabet for comedy?
Or maybe these memes are just an ironic satire of the brain-numbing simplicity of modern mainstream memes.
Perhaps E is one of the first widespread cases of an anti-meme,
a pointless non-sequitur that's only designed to cause confusion and delay.
Or maybe it's the complete opposite.
Maybe E represents the absolute peak performance of a meme,
condensing an incredibly complex idea into a single letter.
Whatever the cause, this meme has redefined what can be considered a meme,
and internet humor will never be the same.