This video is primarily a message to Carrie from the um the KezBox channel who may end up locking
her twitter account as a result of this video because the last time I talked about her she did
the same thing but I just want to let you know beforehand you don't have to do that however if
you're just a regular viewer of mine watching this video let me give you the backstory and most
importantly of all uh please don't contact this person all right so here's the back end of my
channel there's the JK Rowling video the cancel crowd share video I hope you enjoyed that uh
that pun the Qtees video 9 11 am I a fascist that was a fun one uh but I'll just scroll down
check it out oh the uh the KezBox debate is back see it's no longer everyone can see this video
now it's not blocked or anything you can go to it
and as you can see it is available again now some of you may may remember this video was gone for a
while I mean it's three or four weeks old but it's back now so if you want to go watch it you
can go watch it if you like what this video is is I went on this person's um stream at their at
their request and just had a friendly chat with them at least I I thought it was a friendly chat
until after an hour and 12 minutes she kicked me off which is her right it's her stream
she doesn't need to talk to anybody that she doesn't want to talk to now I have a kind of
specific problem with myself I'm kind of anal about some things I like the work that I do to um
to not disappear I like watching old spoonie videos but the problem with spoonie is that
half of his catalog had disappeared since a lot of them were on blip tv so I have to go to like
five different spoonie fan channels on youtube that have like various commentaries and vlogs
and reviews that have since been lost the time and even though I know that I'm a small youtuber
I have always wanted some kind of canonical consistency with my work so even though this
channel is no longer about the old anime reviews from 2009 those still exist on a side channel
even though game boomers get significantly more traction on twitch than on youtube
I still upload all of the streams to the game boomers youtube channel even though there's
not really that many viewers of them but I just like things to be around I don't like the idea
of having content that is lost to time that kind of bothers me it bothers me when creators that
I watch do it so just in case there's somebody out there who actually cares about me I don't
want to do it to them so I like to archive everything that I do it's just a quirk of my
personality so I figured after this conversation with carrie I would simply put the video up on my
youtube channel so that it wouldn't get lost however she didn't like that she filed a copyright
strike on my channel on august 28th four days after I put the video up and I think five days
after the actual debate took place her reasoning was he's literally recorded and uploaded a chunk
of my live stream without my permission which I wouldn't have given I didn't even say I'd be in
a video of his well that's correct it was my recording of the live stream because it was a
conversation that both of us had and even though she filed a copyright strike to get the video
taken down it is my belief that that strike was likely incorrect this is from the university of
stanford's fair use page who owns the copyright in a joint work when two or more authors prepare
a work with the intent to combine their contributions into inseparable or interdependent
parts the work is considered joint work and the authors are considered joint copyright owners the
most common example of a joint work is when a book or article has two or more authors now I didn't
upload her entire stream nor would I have I didn't even upload the part after she kicked me out of it
where she spent some time discussing with her friends exactly what she thought of me I only
uploaded my contribution it just so happens that my contribution was in some way inseparable with
hers now it's not like she didn't want to make this combined work in fact she invited me on
the stream herself I mean you can hop on discord if you want that's not a problem
there you go you can hop off on discord if it'll be easier and she also tweeted about it short
photo talk was in my chat talking about the sargon video youtuber and sargon friend mentioned in
carl gone's new video as having a back and forth with shoe is in my fucking chat right the fuck now
she seemed quite excited at the prospect at least at the time this person here says if sargon of a
cat I don't think that's a real twitter account dude can't seem to understand the idea of socialist
democrats why doesn't he just talk to the surf's tv and then carrie says or me so she wants to talk
to sargon now the way his friend friend is in quotes do you not believe that sargon and I are
friends and defender stand tried to it just got boring considering he was unable to actually
answer a question well if you actually go back and watch our discussion there are multiple times
where carrie said something along the lines of I see what you're saying or I understand or that's
not a bad take she says imagine being so pathetic that you basically stalk and try to bully a small
streamer hilarious do these twats realize that it often makes us more popular well if it makes you
more popular why would you file a false copyright strike to get the video taken down surely you
would want the publicity and no I've never had any intention of bullying you or anybody else that
I've talked to I mean I've made some serious mistakes especially recently we don't have to
re-go over those I don't think but the point is I don't view size as being part of the discussion
I will talk to somebody who is much bigger than me I will talk to somebody who is much smaller
than me we are all fundamentally the same we're equal I figured that as somebody who prioritizes
the virtue of equality you would kind of appreciate that position it doesn't matter to
you if you have 200 subs or 2 million subs as long as you're willing to talk in good faith that's
fine with me I'm not out here trying to own anybody I just want to have decent discussions
maybe come to some sort of understanding that's all and it's not stalking to talk about you if
you're a public figure it's not stalking when you invite me on your own stream and then we have a
conversation that I guess you didn't like how it went and it's certainly not stalking to reply to
a false DMCA takedown so after that reactionary youtuber hopped into my chat SFO it wouldn't
surprise me if he ended up trying to own me for content in his next youtube video because I yeeted
him after an hour of him not answering questions and talking in pointless circles well we actually
covered multiple different topics of conversation we didn't go in circles we actually like
went through multiple full topics and kind of argued them to their conclusion because
I thought we were having a good faith discussion there were multiple times where I straight up
agreed with you and I still do and no this video is not the own that you're looking for
like I said I'm not here to blow you out so after deciding to harass a small twitch streamer who
wasn't even prepared for the conversation short fat otaku decided to upload it the comment section
is wild again you invited me on I didn't say anything harassing towards you and neither of
us were prepared for the conversation I was literally surfing through random channels on
twitch I saw the name Sargon in your twitch title and I checked you out that was it literally your
own SEO brought me to your stream which was basically the point to attract new viewers
wasn't it the commenter here says who wasn't prepared how did this conversation get arranged
and Carrie says I wasn't and it didn't well I wasn't prepared either I didn't really have
any sort like I had one source because I had used it earlier that day and something else but
I didn't have sources to back up what I was talking about I had to look up um the Vancouver
housing crisis because I had no sources and it got arranged by you inviting me on imagine having
almost 100k subs on youtube and deciding to spend your time debating extremely tiny twitch streamers
rather than you know vosh well regardless of my own problems with debating vosh at this point I
don't think vosh would actually do it and only for the reason because he's more than double my size
now he already said that he doesn't want to make somebody else's career he's kind of thinking in
the same terms that uh Styx Hexenhammer was thinking and when vosh challenged him to a debate
so I actually don't think that vosh would talk to me but let's keep reading he acts like he's the
big man here but refuses to engage in debate with people his own size and with significant debate
experience well one I have no significant debate experience again another reason why I wouldn't
debate vosh because I'm not a debate bro but secondly like I said I consider all of us to be
equal it doesn't matter who has more or less subs it doesn't matter who you are what matters are the
ideas of course Kerry says he also doesn't seem to realize that this sort of shit brings us more
viewers well again why did you copyright strike the video SFO is a reactionary who know that
they're garbage they refuse to engage with big lefty creators and instead harass small ones
for somebody who is all about the removal of hierarchy you're really depending on it here
aren't you let me make it absolutely clear in a way that I think you can appreciate Kerry there
is no difference between the two of us we're all human the only thing that's different is how we
think I think that you made this strike not truly knowing what the DMCA is for which is why by the
way youtube has taken my side and reinstated the video from a legal perspective I didn't
need your permission to re-upload my appearance on your stream because it is my appearance but
I can also understand the stages of thought that you went through on the 24th you invited me to be
there you were very happy that I was you were excited on the 25th you spent a significant
amount of time insulting me stating that you had no idea why I was there and talking about how
happy that you were that I gave you exposure and then on the 28th you abused youtube's DMCA
takedown notices to remove that very same source of exposure that three days earlier you were very
happy about so I kind of get it you went through the various stages you weren't necessarily
prepared even though I wasn't either but I understand I understand your position entirely
so even though I do not necessarily expect you to actually reply to this I will leave this on
the table and you can take me up on it anytime you like I understand being nervous I understand
feeling attacked even if you weren't actually attacked I understand feeling that way so for me
Kerry this is all water under the bridge if you ever want to continue our conversation you can
drop into my discord I'll stream it and I promise you I won't kick you out I won't mute you and we
can take as much time as you like getting to the bottom of some of these issues if for some reason
you'd rather not stream it and you'd rather us pre-record it I can do that too like I said I'm
not a debate bro because if you really watch that video in good faith I think we agreed more than we
disagree on a lot of things in any case Kerry the ball's in your court you don't have to take me up
on it in fact if you simply decided to shit talk me on twitter for another couple days and then
ignore that I ever existed fine I wouldn't take it personally and as always my friends please don't
go and harass this person all right this is not about the egos involved it truly is about the
issues all right I'll talk to you guys next time I love you