Ugana Knuckles is a textbook example of the tragedy of the commons applied to memes.
It started off as a promising little case study into the wild and bizarre autism of VRChat,
and it could have been a good meme had it just stayed within the confines of the online gaming community.
But for some unforeseen reason, this meme attracted a plague of normies who completely blow it up.
And much like maggots consuming a carcass, the normies stripped this meme down to the bone and removed any nuance it may have once had.
In just a matter of weeks, Ugandan Knuckles was reduced to just another image and catchphrase that got spammed to death on everyone's timeline,
and it got spammed so far that online journalists began to write hit pieces on it.
Yeah, turns out poking fun at Africans in today's political climate is a bit of a risky meme,
and it begs the question as to why normies would popularize this meme in the first place.
Whatever the reason, we can all agree that this meme lived a short life and died a horrific malnourished death, just like a true Ugandan.