Extremities is back and better than ever, but it's going to be different.
Much has changed since the last season of the Extremities podcast.
Travel screeched to a halt, and with this standstill went my ability to visit, document,
and share the stories of faraway places.
Yet, through all the changes and tumult brought on by the last 18 months, some things have
stayed quite the same.
Thankfully, telling stories of the world's most remote settlements remained a core interest
of mine.
And so, while serving the same purpose—to access and explain the isolated and difficult-to-comprehend
corners of the globe—Extremities is returning, but in a new form, and this time, you're
going to need a screen.
Extremities is relaunching as a standalone YouTube channel.
For those of you curious as to how a civil war influences one of the most biodiverse
islands on the planet, how French culture perpetuates in the subantarctic, and why centuries-old
Atlantic island communities have been all but abandoned over the course of just a few
decades, come on over to the Extremities channel right now and give it a watch.
The first two videos are up now, the third will go up in a week, or it's on Nebula
Now, and then more will go out every third Wednesday after that.
Each video features interviews with locals and experts alike, taking you to the place,
introducing you to its people, and telling its story.
Ad-free episodes, along with extended cuts of interviews, will also be available for
Nebula subscribers.
So head to this link, clickable at the top of the description, to watch and subscribe
to Wendover Productions' newest channel.