Today, we're gonna take a break from YouTube and set our sights on twitter.com the website
Everyone seems to know about but no one really uses and who can really blame them
It's not a place for normal people
You see normal people are content with broadcasting their opinions to their local community of friends and family on Twitter
You believe your opinions are important enough to share with the whole world
Of course, it's no surprise that this premise attracts a special kind of person
You almost have to have some sort of mental disorder to even tolerate this place
narcissism sociopathy downward spiral paranoia
Twitter is basically just a giant mental institution preventing these people from infesting the rest of the web
Twitter's user base is that dude you knew in high school who would smugly correct you about everything
Smug is actually one of the only three emotions. You're allowed to feel on Twitter the others being passive-aggressive and
It's an environment where you can slip up just once even in an honest mistake from years ago
And you'll get tarred and feathered by a mob of anime profile pics then beheaded by kpop stans and taxidermized by militant political
Activists if Instagram is the blissful blue pill of ignorance Twitter is like sticking a razor blade up your sinuses
Twitter is what would happen if you took YouTube's comment section and made that the entire website
I apologize for the long-winded diatribe
But I really have to hammer in the point of how little value Twitter has to its users on Twitter
You have nothing no game, but everything to lose
Youtubers get ad revenue Instagram models can work their way up to make sponsored posts even on reddit
You can at least get gold by being the biggest suck-up imaginable
There is no monetary incentive to use Twitter by the time you get big enough to make sponsored tweets
You're almost certainly at a status where you can make money in spite of yourself
If you're beneath this level then good luck getting anything out of Twitter. Well, that's not exactly true
There are at least a few things you can get from Twitter. You can get canceled. You can get suspended for no reason
Realistically, the only redeeming quality of Twitter is networking as a content creator
But if you're just a regular user, I have no idea how you tolerate this place
Except there is one other incentive to use Twitter
With no money to be made the theoretical endgame of Twitter is to get one of these
Twitter's verification badge the lone token of achievement in a cesspool of sin and misery
So, how do you get it?
Well step one be a reporter corporation or elite public figure if you're not any of these things then just give up
One day I got this joking reply to one of my tweets
But it raises a very valid question
Why is it so much harder to get verified on Twitter than anywhere else?
Grande 1.2 million Twitter followers not verified
Critical 5 million YouTube subscribers nearly a million twitch followers not verified
Call me Carson over a million Twitter followers all of his posts get over
50,000 likes he trended on Twitter from people wishing him. Happy birthday
Not verified you go to the official verification page on Twitter and it's been radio silent for the past two and a half years
They keep saying to check back later for the new and improved verification system, but later never comes what's going on here?
Pretty much every website has a verification system
YouTube Instagram Pornhub Edmodo once you accumulate a high enough status
Something has to prevent people from just
Impersonating you and damaging your reputation
This is the theoretical purpose of a verification system on any website and almost all websites have no issues whatsoever
implementing the system in practice
Last year my friend rusty cage got verified on Instagram while
Simultaneously being suspended multiple times without any chance for appeal on Twitter
It really just goes to show how differently Twitter treats its users than any other site
For some reason Twitter has taken this simple concept and corrupted it into a confusing and unrecognizable mess
How did this happen? And what steps can you take to actually get verified on this website?
Well using some of the Twitter connections I've made over the years. I'm gonna try my best to answer this question
First how did we get here and how has Twitter's verification system changed over time?
Back
In 2009 Twitter was becoming a big player in the world of social media on the world wide web
With celebrities from across the world flocking to the site to share their lives in 140 characters
The problem was some of these accounts claiming to be people of note to weren't who they said they were rather just imposters
When st. Louis Cardinals manager Tony La Russa found out someone was impersonating him on the site
He went on to sue Twitter for damages not wanting this to happen again the fine people at the internet startup devised a verification
System that would allow famous users to protect their identity from being stolen by those with nefarious motives in the early days
This was made specifically for celebrities
Musicians athletes and other public figures and a year or so later
Brands and companies would be added to that list the process to get a blue checkmark seemed to be on a need to know
Basis if you were popular enough to need one you'd know how to get it
The ad verified account is the public's best glimpse into the system at play as it follows every single person
That has been given verified status
between 2009 and 2016 the site verified on average
25,000 accounts per year totaling a hundred and eighty six thousand out of 300 million
Some of these seem more justifiable than others in the summer of 2016
Twitter released a public application for verification this event coincided with the last generation of youtubers to get verified a
Generation considered by some Twitter users to have set our culture back by a decade
Sometimes I wish I could go back a decade to a time when Twitter would actually verify youtubers
But I guess the next best thing is just asking these guys what the process was like now
I don't have contact with Joji or I dubs and Chad isn't verified
So that just leaves max mofo as my only option
Let's see what he had to say max told me that he didn't quite remember the specific process
But he thinks it probably happened as soon as the public application became available
The web archive shows that max was verified as of September 2016. So this timing appears to check out
What matters here is that the verification process back then was free and easy and the bar for entry was relatively low
Twitter's verification system was more equitable than ever before but it would not last long the time
Execute order 66
On November 9th 2017 Twitter announced that they were indefinitely suspending the verification process across the entire site
They would go on to strip verification from numerous controversial accounts
Most notably de-verifying prominent white nationalist Richard Spencer while many celebrated the announcement as a justified punishment
It didn't really make any sense administratively
Twitter's reasoning for de-verifying accounts was that an unnamed minority of users began to view the blue checkmark as an endorsement
Prior to the change. I found very little evidence of anyone publicly complaining about this as the nature of verification should be obvious
It's a simple demarcation of a public figure if Kim Jong-un were on Twitter should he be verified
What about Pablo Escobar or Ted Bundy surely?
No one at Twitter would endorse any of their actions
But as such highly publicized individuals it would be bizarre to imagine that these people wouldn't be verified on any public forum
The idea that verifications equal endorsements is incredibly flimsy
These two concepts are completely unrelated yet Twitter chose to conflate them based on an unknown number of
unspecified users getting confused
But let's get more confusing just one year earlier in 2016
Twitter suspended Richard Spencer and then reinstated him with his verification
Upholding that verification does not equal endorsement today when you look at Twitter's official verification page
It specifically states that verification does not equal endorsement and there's an important reason behind this
Recently President Trump threatened executive action against Twitter that would remove one of its safe harbor provisions
I've talked about a type of safe harbor before as it pertains to copyright law and a similar provision exists in section 230 of the
Communications Decency Act which protects sites like Twitter from being held liable for the conduct of their users
What's important here is that the exemption only exists if Twitter does not act as a publisher by treating verification as an endorsement
Twitter could potentially jeopardize their safe harbor protection by assuming responsibility over user conduct by choosing to curate
Verification along their own subjective standards Twitter could have been classified as a publisher of any content posted by verified accounts
Opening themselves up to potentially devastating liabilities now
I'm in no way a legal expert so I could be completely wrong here
But this is just my best explanation for why Twitter has been so inconsistent with this issue
So far seems that this whole campaign was just a bunch of lip service after 2017
They have made no major effort to de-verify controversial accounts
So was this whole exercise just completely pointless for users?
Yes, but for Twitter possibly not while Richard Spencer drew in all the attention from the incident
Nobody realized that this event would mark the end of equitable verification on Twitter entirely
Not only that but every existing support article about verification was subsequently removed
Links to these old articles now all redirect to a generic page with barely any information
To this day public verification on Twitter remains indefinitely suspended
So what led Twitter to quietly make such a drastic change to find out why we have to follow the money
In
2015 Twitter's active user base plateaued the site was no longer growing
Just one year afterwards Twitter stock price had fallen by 70%
The company's then CEO Dick Costello was pressured to step down and was replaced by current Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey
For most of 2017 the stock price remained stagnant while the rest of the market surged
Twitter was in bad shape and investors were rapidly losing confidence
Numerous financial publications listed Jack Dorsey among the worst CEOs in America
Starting November 9th Twitter suspended verification and then went on to post its first profitable quarter in company history
2018 saw Twitter's revenue increase by nearly 25%
Causing the stock price to effectively double it was at this point that the worthless blue checkmark became a commodity
But how do you convert a blue badge into green paper to find out we have to cross over to the corporate side of Twitter
Brand Twitter, there's nothing else really like it long ago
Pretty much every brand account on Twitter only existed to spam hashtags and submissively apologize to disgruntled customers
Then everything changed when Wendy's attacked all of a sudden every brand you can imagine was jockeying to see who can make the most
viral tweet this quickly escalated to empathetic moon pie consoling depressed Sunny D
You're looking at the future of marketing here people
Basically every brand who was any brand had to develop a sassy or relatable persona and playfully banter with each other on Twitter
It's so convincing they act just like people they show emotions just like people
But don't be fooled much like in general society
these brands are among the most powerful members of Twitter and there's a good reason for that as
Much as Twitter's leadership would like you to forget Twitter is a for-profit business first and a public forum second
Like many sites Twitter earns its revenue from advertising
Brands provide the funding that Twitter needs to survive as a business
So it should be no surprise why brands tend to receive the most preferential treatment brand accounts have the easiest path to verification
It's surprising to find one without a checkmark
You'd think they get it automatically, but it's actually not that simple while researching this video
I actually had to enter forbidden territory by consulting the wisdom of a real-life brand
Thankfully stake um had followed me some time ago
So I reached out to them for comment what they told me may shock you it turns out that after Twitter suspended
Verification the change was severe enough to affect some brands
Steak-um actually had to create their own guerrilla campaign in order to draw the attention of the right people
According to them Twitter prioritizes verifying companies that spend the most advertising money on the site
This key piece of information may explain why Twitter verification has seemed so inaccessible over the past few years
The checkmark itself doesn't generate revenue, but it rewards companies who do
Keeping the checkmark accessible would devalue its purpose as an incentive for ad spending
This could also explain why so many accounts in the news industry are verified
News media is one of the only industries to heavily rely on Twitter as part of the rat race to get clicks
There's no doubt that news articles play a heavy role in Twitter's information economy
Featured articles will drive the most traffic to their native sites and one has to wonder how much some of these media outlets spend to
Put themselves in that position now
I'm not saying that the checkmark is the sole reason for Twitter's boom in revenue
But it's almost certainly symptomatic of the site's more brand-happy business model as of late and based on its success so far
Verification may never return to how it once was
Welcome to the age of the blue filter where independent creators without industry backing may be stuck without a checkmark forever
In this age only a few creators have managed to buck the trend to get verified
So I reached out to as many as I could and asked them how they did it
Cavos is a youtuber you wouldn't expect to be verified on Twitter given the far more massive channels who still remain unverified
So I asked him how he did it and this is what he had to say
Cavos is part of the YouTube network BBTV
Sometime in 2019. He put in a request to the network to get him verified on Twitter three months later
The network succeeded so it appears that joining a YouTube network could help you get verified
However, most youtubers would generally not recommend joining a YouTube network
Given how many of them take a decent cut of your pay to do basically nothing
Occasionally, you'll get the rare goody like the coveted blue checkmark
but other than that networks tend to carry a great risk for creators with little benefit if
You have to resort to a management company. You may just want to pump and dump them like too mad, you know the vibes
Well, literally I signed with some management company and
They submitted me to some guy this guy named Zach Mazota
This guy's like I was gonna verify his people a lot of gaming guys
And I mean I had no idea was coming he just let me know like at one point like yo
I also submit you for verification. I was like, oh wait, really? Yeah, they replied. They said yeah, it should be done
Oh the way what really? Okay
So then after a little while it happened. I just got verified
Earlier this year alpha rats successfully became one of the only accounts in history to get verified with an anime profile picture
I saw some rumors that he may have encouraged his fans to impersonate him so he could force Twitter to verify him this same
Impersonation exploit is suggested in a video by tech boomers, but doesn't appear to have worked on their own account
Starting a mass impersonation campaign seems like a one-way ticket to getting banned
So I asked alpha rat if these rumors were true
It turns out he actually got verified with help from eSports organization Panda global
This explains how so many eSports competitors seem to get verified so easily
Unlike a YouTube network eSports organizations pay you to help manage your profile, but also unlike a YouTube network
You can't just sign up for FaZe Clan or Team Liquid
These organizations only tend to sponsor the most elite eSports players not exactly a practical option for content creators
Just looking to get verified on Twitter if you're looking for the most direct path to verification
You may have to follow in the footsteps of Cowbelly Studios
Recently, he shared this post detailing the process of how he got verified. So I asked him to elaborate on how the system works
Basically, he hired a specialized service to have Twitter review his account for verification
The service ran through a site called famous influencer.com and as part of the process they groomed his profile for success
Giving him the criteria that Twitter currently requires for verification
Some of the requirements are just cosmetic such as displaying your real name and face on your profile
personally, I found this somewhat counterintuitive as your followers should be used to your specific branding and persona and
Disrupting that is definitely gonna hurt your engagement
I mean should we expect rappers to display their real names before verifying their profiles?
It seems kind of dumb to me. This place isn't exactly LinkedIn
Here's the real kicker though
The most important factor in Twitter's new standards for verification is whether or not you've been featured in mainstream news articles
Now personally, I've actually been cited and interviewed for quite a few online articles one time
I even made the cover of meme insider. So where's my badge?
Well showing up in articles only takes you so far to actually get verified
You need to initiate a manual review by a contact at Twitter
Contact what are you talking about? The enigmatic Twitter contact is the final boss of verification
They are people speculated to work within Twitter's communications department who serve as the ultimate gatekeepers of the blue checkmark
You could meet all the criteria for verification
But without access to a contact the blue checkmark will forever remain out of reach
This is why someone like nerd city who has been featured in dozens of articles still remains
Unverified and as it turns out the lion's share of Twitter contacts are held by big companies political institutions and news publications
If multi-million dollar brands like stacum have trouble getting in touch with one then what chance do independent creators have?
PR agencies like famous influencer will sell you the opportunity to reach a contact for the low low price of
5,000 pounds and that's if you already have the mainstream news coverage
Famous influencer also has a network of mainstream press writers at their disposal to totally manufacture you into a media darling
Of course at the additional cost of thousands more
Over just a few years Twitter has managed to take a free feature and stick it behind what is essentially a paywall of thousands of
Dollars and they have deliberately tried to restrict access to any information about how the verification process even works
Twitter now resembles a pay-to-win game and I'm not really sure I want to play anymore
This site has become a permanent reminder to me that as bad as YouTube's leadership is it can still get worse
Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey always boasts about wanting to promote healthy conversation
Usually while introducing features that literally restrict
Conversation our platform promotes speech unless people violate our rules you listen to Twitter's officials talk about this site
Like they're building some sort of utopia of erudite public discourse. Have you seen the people on this site?
It's not a vocal minority go click on any trend on the discover page and you'll see enraged
Psychopaths viciously attacking each other like someone kicked over a hornet's nest
It's a site where otherwise calm people go to have an emotional meltdown
Basically, if you're looking for healthy discussion, you've come to the wrong place
Well, you think this is going to cause a little more anger the world is an angry place
But you know what certainly doesn't help the harmonious temperament of the site
Creating an arbitrary system to segregate the protected elites from the worthless plebs
Twitter has corrupted the
Verification system to such an extent where lots of people seem to have more respect for non verified people than verified people
The phrase blue checkmark has quite literally become a pejorative term against obnoxious verified accounts
But it's hard to blame the blue checkmarks for acting like any other user a few months ago critical made a point about twitches
inconsistent enforcement of their community guidelines
Specifically how certain female streamers seem immune from punishment. That's pretty much like the twitch mod team here
Just operating in secrecy, which is the worst way of doing things with no transparency
It just leads to a lot of confusion and a lot of bad things even for the streamers that they seem to want to protect
And I don't even know if that's the right word for it
I don't even know if they're making a conscious decision to protect streamers, but just this weird favoritism
They seem to play in this bias leads to these conspiracy theories where you know
All women are invincible on twitch because they're giving nude photos to the mod team for special treatment
He said that by arbitrarily protecting female streamers twitch encourages its community to unfairly target and resent them
Similarly, I feel that Twitter's inconsistent verification system has caused people to distrust verified accounts
I have no doubt in my mind that the commodification of the blue checkmark has contributed to the public's growing resentment of journalists
People new to the site have to wonder why a random reporter with five thousand followers is verified
but their favorite youtuber with
500,000 followers isn't this distinction can only create suspicion and discontent and it makes the site look incredibly out of touch with its users
Perhaps the gatekeeping wouldn't be as much of an issue if Twitter actually applied consistently strict standards to everyone
But when journalists get to act as unprofessionally as anyone else while flexing their I'm better than you badge
The whole thing reeks of systematic favoritism. Oh my gosh, is that an article?
You're a journalist. That's so great here. Why don't you take about ten of these give them to all your friends?
People may bash the blue checkmarks
But Twitter itself is to blame for administering such a skewed system at least YouTube
Despite all of its problems has managed to create and maintain an equitable verification system
There is no such stigma around gray checkmarks on YouTube
But still in classic YouTube fashion they had to at least try and ruin it
Remember last year when for absolutely no reason YouTube tried to overhaul the verification
System in a thinly veiled attempt to elevate corporate accounts
Remember how universally unpopular it was and how everyone flipped out to such an extent that YouTube backed out after
24 hours and never brought it up again
Well, guess what fellas that garbage system proposed by YouTube is how Twitter's verification system works right now and
Unlike YouTube Twitter shows no signs of remorse about it. They openly mock how they deliberately neglect their users
It's all just a big joke to them
You know
Maybe more people would actually use this site if the management didn't treat the average user with utter contempt and it's not just the
verification system that reflects this
Recently Twitter user lamest chris documented compelling evidence of a belligerent account
Abusing an insider connection at Twitter support to ban innocent users without any recourse for appeal
This is in addition to a never-ending string of DMCA takedowns in which Twitter allows trolls to submit unlimited false
Copyright claims with no proof whatsoever
This is a site where you can literally post gore and pornography
But god forbid you depict cheese at hitting the World Trade Center
Our platform promotes speech unless people violate our rules Twitter wants to be seen as a utopia
So why does using this site feel like I'm in Soviet Russia?
The site is in general disrepair people constantly disappear without warning and the corrupt
Delusional leadership would rather focus on a petty pissing contest with America's president than actually responding to the needs of its users
I'm sorry, but when state um is a better source of information than your own help page
Then maybe your site is a bit of a transparency issue. How does one acquire the illustrious checkmark on?
Twitter there's a guy named Kayvon. He's the verification god. So just go to him and he'll get you sorted
Oh
Brother this guy stinks
Actually as I was making this video it's been rumored that Twitter has plans to finally roll out a new public application for verification
I guess it took them two and a half years to fix something that wasn't even broken in the first place
Who knows maybe we'll be able to trim videos again before the end of the century
It just goes to show that the site has so little to offer that they stroke themselves off for adding features that already
Existed should have always existed and only don't exist because of their own incompetence. I owe Twitter
Can we get that edit button in 2020? The answer is no
So in conclusion Twitter is a terrible platform run by terrible people where terrible users have terrible discussions about terrible issues and
For some reason this site attracts a bunch of youtubers can't imagine why but at least it's good for networking
Because as youtubers, we know that Twitter will hold off on verifying us for as long as they possibly can
Almost none of the information I learned in this video came from Twitter itself. It was only made possible through the assortment of connections
I've made over the years
So despite being a general bane on society Twitter is good for at least one thing as for the blue checkmark
I don't even really want it anymore
Several thousand dollars is a steep price to pay for something that should be free and the whole machine around it
Just leaves a bad taste in my mouth
For all intents and purposes having the badge doesn't even do much you get to more easily interact with other verified accounts
But that's about it
None of the people I interviewed saw a huge improvement in their quality of life after being verified and it didn't seem to contribute to
any direct financial benefit
Honestly this whole video just made me sad frustrated and was overall just a big waste of time
So really no different than my experience browsing Twitter
I'm starting to see why PewDiePie left this place at the end of the day
I guess the blue checkmark wound up being the most appropriate symbol of Twitter as a whole
You have nothing to gain and everything to lose
And you'll be watching