Hey guys, no video today, sorry. Here's a quick update for you though. This channel has grown to
the point that I'm actually able to take on a full-time employee, finally. Before I had a couple
of people working part-time, but now it's actually become a real business, so that's pretty cool.
He's gonna be handing a lot of backend stuff, and the first thing he's doing is uploading the
entire catalog of SFO videos to Bitchute, Rumble, Odyssey, Dailymotion, and Brightion. That last one,
Brightion, is important right now, because I need 20,000 views across the Brightion channel over
there, to be able to unlock the ability to upload unlimited videos. So, if you feel inclined to help
out, please consider heading over to the Brightion SFO channel and rewatching some of your old
favorites. And, now that SFO is actually becoming a real thing, and not just me subsisting on
licking algae off the rocks, if you want to support the channel, please consider dropping
a tip over at the SFO subscribe star, Patreon, PayPal, the memberships button on the SFO channel,
or the subscription button on my gaming channel over on Twitch, Game Boomers. Any and all works
for me, so pick your poison. Thank you very much for contributing and supporting the channel.
Even if you can't contribute, that's okay too. Thanks very much for watching and being here.
It's been an amazing ride to 100k, and it'll be an amazing ride beyond it too.
I appreciate everything you've given me, and I'll keep working hard in return.
Alright, that about does it for me. Have a good day. I love you.
Also, yes, my assistant is Dave. It's this guy. It was always gonna be this guy.