Cutting sandwiches with much science. With a single straight cut, can you half a three-ingredient sandwich with all components perfectly halved?
There's actually real science about this, called the ham sandwich theorem. And the answer might seem obvious when you're looking at a theoretical
symmetrical sandwich, but in reality sandwiches are messy. But maths doesn't care about messiness, it still works.
It doesn't matter what form the three ingredients have or how they're positioned.
Imagine a slice of bread in Munich, Germany, a slice of ham at a farmers market in San Francisco,
USA, and a slice of cheese in a lunchbox on a plane to Indonesia.
Although this might not be a sandwich in the classical sense, there is a single perfect cut that halves all three slices at once.
We just need a very big knife. And there's more.
Maths says there's always a perfect cut for a four-piece sandwich in a four-dimensional space, same for a five-piece sandwich in a
five-dimensional space, and so on. Thanks maths. Now any multi-dimensional civilization can be