What's up Dave?
Do you want to tell all the people out there who are looking at you right now what's going
on today?
Because today is the 15th.
Oh yeah, I do.
Wait.
Is this a live thing?
Oh my god man.
This is when we get two videos a day from now on.
This has been No Talent Gaming Starts.
Yup, yup, yup, yup, June 15th.
Do you just have no talent in the rest of your life as well?
It is June 15th.
It is that day.
That day where life changes forever.
Life changes forever.
Two day, two day.
Two, two, two, two inches a day.
Guarantee, guarantee, guarantee, guarantee.
What games will they be Dave?
That will do Bangor Kazooie and Pokemon Soul Silver.
Are you really sure about that?
I'm HIV positive.