So it's I mean, I understand all ratings right? Oh, it's a business. It's a business. People are like the media has like an ethical
But
All the nice cutesy little epics that used to get talked about in journalism school you're just like that's adorable
That's adorable
On July 17th the video game retail site good old games
Otherwise known as gog.com made a tweet
advertising the game postal to the tweet reads as follows a game that wears its heart on its sleeve a
Sleeve that is rarely safe for work
Postal to paradise lost no filter
No DRM the tweet included a screenshot from the game showing the player pissing on a grave with the name of games journalism
This was taken from postal twos gamer gate DLC a tongue-in-cheek mode that included multiple gamer gate references
Including allowing players to kill my Leonopoulos
unsurprisingly social justice warriors started up the outrage machine games journalists crowed in their columns and
Terrorized on Twitter gog was pressured into removing the offending tweet and issuing a public apology
But this article from a relatively unknown progressive gaming site
VG 24-7 caught my eye
VG 24-7 is pulling its support of a gogs a storefront for the foreseeable future
The problem is that the gift can be interpreted as a dog whistle that patterns to hate group gamer gate
Which itself has been proven to lead to radicalism and even murder the murder they're referring to via that link is Ralph
Ritter writer Seattle for truths murder of his father when he was thrown out of his parents house
But here's the strange part of the article gamer gate has destroyed lives and we're very disappointed
That gog has furthered the divide between those who cover games and a vocal minority that hate games
Journalists women and minorities we hear this type of thing a lot SJWs have recognized that simply saying
Minorities is not enough because women aren't a minority so often
You'll see them list off a laundry basket full of social classes that they feel need special protection from the patriarchy women people of color
LGBTQIA plus folk as they like to say queer people disabled people immigrants
undocumented people etc etc and VG 24-7
Lumped games journalists into their own specific usage of this phenomenon as if the profession of journalism
Was itself a protected class of its own although this VG 24-7 article is about gaming journalism
It made me realize that most journalists in general the progressive leaning ones
Anyway believe that their choice of profession should afford them some type of social privilege and protection within the social justice
Hierarchy in much the same way that being gay or black or a woman offers benefits to these oppressed classes
Furthermore it's the expectation of this protection and the political rights refusal to acknowledge it that finally offers a clear explanation
For the media's erratic self-absorbed and downright immoral behavior since the 2016 election
US President Donald Trump has made the claim that the mainstream media is fake news more times than I can count going all the way back
to 2015
Don't we love that term fake what we've learned about fake over the last little while
Fake news, and I want you all to know that we are fighting the fake news. It's fake phony fake
Of the media he's said among other things that they are the true enemy of the people and that they should stop the endless
hostility against him and any look at the unending unrelenting media coverage of Trump over the past few years will certainly prove him correct attack after
attack hit piece after hit piece insults and glib remarks and all accusations of anti-semitism
nazism fascism
Racism sexism and as many other isms as you'd like it's almost all unfounded and when Trump decides to hit back
He's attacking the media. He's undermining the freedom of the press. He's tearing the people against the vaunted institution of journalism
Trump refuses to grant journalists the protected minority status that they view themselves as having he's punching down while they're punching up
This is why all of Trump's misdeeds make him literally Hitler
Literally while the misdeeds of the media can be ignored or hand-waved away for example
Project Veritas a group that goes undercover to record instances of political back-channeling and corruption in both the news media and political campaigns
Released a video from behind the scenes at Democratic Senator Claire McCaskill's re-election campaign
I can tell them because she does support a semi-automatic firearm
Because I won't say something I shouldn't say I think semi-automatic like in a semi-automatic rifle band, okay more so what she would support
So here's their real question
Claire holds off on impeachment to get the moderates
What do we tell the moderates after we drop the impeachment hammer afterwards?
Claire distant distancing herself from the party is gonna help her win more votes than it will
Saying like oh, here's Obama the former president of the United States to not speak on my behalf
Which is unfortunate cuz I love Obama to pieces
I'd love to see him come here, and they essentially have the same views on everything
What were you telling me last night about Planned Parenthood
How they never they don't donate to Claire because they want to ostracize
pro pro-life Democrats in Missouri
So
But they still somehow give get us money
They put it through like different like organizations. Yeah, I think it's like a tactic that's like not make them too far
Left to try to get the moderate voters
But we're still gonna support abortion, right? Yes
They go through other means to support and give them money they just don't directly give the money from there like packs
Oh
It's like we have to we have to lie to get elected
In response to this leak McCaskill's campaign declared that project Veritas had not only done something unethical
But illegal and demanded that the state's Attorney General appoint a special prosecutor to investigate these alleged crimes
Project Veritas is another subject entirely
but anyone with a brain can agree that it is journalism unless of course you're a person who believes that
Journalists are protected class and for some reason you happen to want the perks of that class
Stripped away from your political opponents like Brian Tao does he's a journalist for the Wall Street Journal
Specializing in law and regarding this project Veritas leak he had this to say project Veritas is not journalism
Journalists do not misrepresent themselves by setting up stings with some very rare exceptions
This article would be on better grounds defending them as engaged in protected First Amendment advocacy
Let's put aside the sheer audacity of the claim that journalists do not set up stings for a minute project Veritas is
Journalism hell even most YouTube talking heads can be classified as journalists though most would reject the label because unlike a lot of actual
Journalists it seems youtubers recognize that the social rank of journalist not only comes with some legitimate protections
But a lot of responsibility as well Tao's claim that certain groups of reporters and analysts are not true
Journalists is a self-destructive claim to make if you can de journalist project Veritas then certainly others can
Dejournalist the Wall Street Journal and that's exactly what's been happening to the Wall Street Journal for years now back in early
2017 the Wall Street Journal went toe-to-toe with PewDiePie taking jokes and clips out of
Context to make him sound like a racist a Nazi an anti-semite
You know all of the usual overused angles of attack that we've become so entirely
Desensitized to at this point that they've lost all meaning and the rest of the mainstream media along with gaming and tech
Journalists jumped on the bandwagon pewds ended up losing a lucrative business deal with Disney over the invented controversy
But it didn't kill his YouTube channel or slow down his growth as the world's biggest youtuber and in retrospect
This seemed like the death rattle of old media lashing out against youtubers and social media for usurping their role in the cultural consciousness
Journalists were starting to figure out that they no longer had the social privilege as a protected class that they once held
But they failed to recognize that a combination of not keeping up with modern technology and trends as well as their own behavior
Had cost them the trust of the public and this blatantly false attack on PewDiePie wasn't the beginning
But just another step down a long path of eroded trust in the institution of journalism
The Wall Street Journal hasn't learned from its misdeeds either a recent trending hashtag trending until Twitter suppressed
It anyway was hashtag
wsj kills kids this stems from an event from several weeks ago where a YouTube livestream show called the kill stream ran an event titled
The heel stream where all super chat money raised would be donated to st
Jude's Children's Research Hospital
Just like the PewDiePie event the Wall Street Journal saw an opportunity to stick it to both their main competitors and their political opponents
Yuri Co from the Wall Street Journal
Emailed the owner of the kill stream Ethan Ralph in regards to an upcoming story
I am working on a story about how alt-right personalities have utilized YouTube super chat function
We're mentioning some of your live streams in the story including one that was aired and deleted in which you spoke about the Pittsburgh shooting
It appears that the live stream generated over
$500 via super chat some of the comments both paid and unpaid were problematic
For instance one super chat comment said if you want to know if the synagogue shooting was a false flag
Then check out the lucky Larry life insurance policy on those dead juice
Jesus regarding that live stream. Did you delete it or was that YouTube?
Why we're also mentioning the Ralph retorts live stream from September 29th that raised
$26,000 for st. Jude's I wanted to reach out in case you'd like to comment on any of this
I also wanted to confirm that you share the revenue from your super chats with YouTube though Ralph would ultimately refuse Co's request
Here's the article that would come from her efforts hate speech on live super chats tests YouTube
Feature that gives paid comment special treatment generates revenue
But can include racist comments and here's a few quotes from this article during the live stream, which YouTube said mr
Ralph has since deleted one user paid two British pounds to write
How do you get a Jewish girl's number roll up her sleeve you want to know how despite the media's kicking and screaming they still?
Unduly exercise their privileges as a protected class my quoting that joke will likely get this video
Demonetized while Yuri Co will still be paid by the Wall Street Journal for the exact same content
YouTube said late on Friday that it had permanently removed. Mr
Ralph's channel the Ralph retort from its platform for policy violations and for going against its terms of service. Mr
Ralph whose channel had
22,500 subscribers is one of several far-right YouTube celebrities who have used the super chat function to make money Ralph would
Independently confirm this himself on Twitter stating that his super chat button would be disabled for his upcoming live streams on his next
He began to criticize the Wall Street Journal on air and in
retaliation YouTube turned off the stream on their end and suspended all of his channels from the platform a
Spokeswoman for YouTube owned by alphabet inks
Google said the company donates to charity the proceeds from any super chats that violate its hate speech policy
Except they don't because all
$26,000 raised by Ralph's stream for st. Jude's is confirmed to have been refunded by YouTube and st
Jude's has also confirmed that they never had any intention of accepting the money both of these revelations came to light
Of course after the Wall Street Journal had a private chat with both YouTube and st. Jude's. This is why the hashtag was
Wsj kills kids the Wall Street Journal is willing to deny st
Jude's charity funds is willing to twist YouTube into breaking its own rules in order to spite somebody they view as a political opponent in
their eyes money for charity takes a backseat to potentially offensive speech and despite any
Personal differences between Ralph and myself on principle. I cannot support his removal from YouTube free speech rights are paramount
Even if the speech in question is hateful or stupid, of course
It's not just the Wall Street Journal committing morally reprehensible acts under the guise of journalism
I'm sure we've all heard about blatant racists like Francesca Ramsey and Sarah John moving up the media ranks based on skin color alone
And then there's also lesser-known stories like the tale of crosswalk Kathy various progressive leading outlets began to write hit pieces on a private citizen
For calling the cops on a black man for parking improperly with some
SJW is going so far as to doxer and smear her as a racist
But eventually the truth of the matter came out the woman called the parking authority
Not the police on a vehicle because it was parked in the middle of a crosswalk and she didn't know the race of the vehicles
owner at all
But since we're on the topic of journalists using their position to attack random citizens guilty of wrongthink
There was also that time that CNN blackmailed a random reddit user for making this gif. No, I'm not joking
I did a podcast about it back in the day
But the long and short of it is the moral paragons over at CNN tracked the poster down
Accused him of the usual basket of SJW slurs and threatened to reveal his identity if he didn't leave the internet in their self-damning
Article titled how CNN found the reddit user behind the Trump wrestling gif CNN is not publishing
Han asshole solos name because he is a private citizen who has issued an extensive statement of apology
Showed his remorse by saying he has taken down all of his offending posts and because he said he is not going to repeat
This ugly behavior on social media again in addition
He said his statement could serve as an example to others not to do the same
CNN reserves the right to publish his identity should any of that change
This is why the protected status of journalists is no longer respected by Donald Trump by the conservative wing of politics
By most average people journalists no longer wield that privilege with restraint and wisdom
Instead they use it as a bludgeon against their opponents
I could keep going with examples of the media acting ridiculous and irresponsible at best and immoral and corrupt at worst like CNN's
Jim Acosta virtue signaling in public over Kanye West saying the word motherfucker in the Oval Office while in private
DMing fuck you to one of his critics on Twitter
But because I am a gamer let me indulge a bit with one final example from the gaming industry
Blizzcon 2018 happened recently and at the event
Blizzard took the opportunity to show off their new Diablo game Diablo immortal Diablo is a long-running much beloved PC RPG series
But this latest entry is a phone game on the gaming side of the story
There was a lot of funny stuff going down like the crowd heckling the developers and the developers
Exceptionally poor response in return. We want to use mobile devices as the platform for a new
Diablo game
Because nothing brings a family together like slaying demons
Hey, just was wondering is this an out-of-season April Fool's joke
No, it's it's a it's a fully
Fully fledged Diablo experience on on mobile which everybody will get to play
Is there any plans to make this playable on PC or is this a strictly mobile forever
Are there any yeah this the current plan is to be on mobile both?
Android and iOS
We don't have any plans at the moment to do PC
Do
You guys want have phone yeah you guys
If you want to know more we'll be back here on the mythic stage in just a few minutes
We are gonna have
Sorry
Or the company tasking YouTube to delete hundreds of thousands of downvotes and negative comments on the official Diablo immortal reveal trailers
a fact that can be verified by comparing the live numbers to the numbers tracked on social blade or that the response was so
overwhelmingly negative to Diablo immortal that all the Diablo social media accounts switched their icons and official branding from the new Diablo immortal stuff
Back to Diablo 3 or that it was discovered by the Internet's greatest autistic minds
The Diablo immortal was outsourced to a Chinese company known for making Diablo mobile ripoffs and that Chinese company simply took one of their
Pre-existing games and
Reskinned it with the Diablo brand or Blizzard's main competitors directly making fun of the massive Diablo immortal fumble on social media or that Blizzard
Themselves as an April Fool's joke in 2014 announced a Diablo mobile game specifically making fun of how diluted
dumbed down and
Disrespectful to existing IPs that phone games can be or that the red shirted bald hero that was willing to stick it to the developers
Live not only posted on 4chan asking what he should say before it was his turn but also that his reddit history showed that he
Routinely fucks other women with his wife and threesomes
Forget about EA's constant fuck-ups with Star Wars or Microsoft's self-destruction of the Xbox one by claiming that consumers who don't like it can
Just play the Xbox 360
I think blizzards taken the crown on the best way to shotgun yourself in the face
But while that's all good fun
The relevant part is the journalist response to the outrage
Diablo immortal is actually fun you entitled babies the people that bash on mobile gaming are an offshoot of toxic masculinity
They get off on hating something that they've traditionally associated with a heavily female audience don't like playing a specific kind of game on mobile
That's cool. Reject mobile platforms whatsoever and pretend they are inferior. Yeah, that's pretty toxic. This wasn't savagery
It was fucking obnoxious embarrassing behavior. I get why people are mad
I really do but you can be critical without being an asshole to people who spend their lives trying to entertain you
Of course the first thing I see when I wake up is Diablo immortal haters now saying that Blizzcon was a slap in the face
I roll gif if you can't see the potential of a Diablo game on mobile
You know shit all about video games the reaction to Diablo eternal. You got that wrong there champ
Don't expect any Blizzard shill shekels the reaction to Diablo eternal from so many
Gamers makes me want to not play video games or have anything to do with gaming anymore fans react to Diablo immortal like
Disrespectful edgelords hot take after hot take shill after shill virtue signal after virtue signal
Assertions that gamers are man-babies demands that consumers blindly purchase whatever companies give them
Accusations that complainers are ungrateful because they dislike a product not having learned a single goddamn thing from gamergate lefty games journalists
Demonize their own audience ignore the legitimate arguments against Diablo immortal inside with the 83 billion dollar company over the concerns of an average
Person and should you one of those average people decide to call them out on this you'll be contributing to Trump's demonization of the media
You'll be vilifying journalism
You'll be disrespecting the journalists rightful place as a protected class alongside women and minorities
But the journalist is not a protected class
Maybe in an ideal world due to the nature of the job that a good journalist should perform
Maybe they should be somewhat protected exposing corrupt governments or corporations speaking truth to power
Uncovering scandals and holding people accountable
These are the jobs of the journalist and these are the jobs that we need to see done
Society is better as a whole when a good journalist is successful
But none of the journalists anymore seem to be good from something as benign as video games all the way up to the White House
Journalists have decided that their job is no longer to report on events
But to create the context of those events that people they look down upon must be obligated to consume. Why is this happened?
I don't know. Maybe it's because social justice controls both academia and entertainment right now and the long-term results of that
Is that SJW kids from 10 or 15 years ago are now SJW journalists today?
Maybe it's because as multiple articles in
2017 pointed out with glee new studies have shown that journalists brains function at lower levels in the average persons due to an excess
consumption of alcohol caffeine and sugar rendering them unable to think objectively
multitask problem-solve or be creative in any case
Journalists are not a protected class as long as they behave
So grotesquely we can never accept them as one if they want the privilege of social protection in order to do their dangerous work
They need to actually start doing that work again until then. They're simply fake news
You