TWL is back… kinda, and not here.
As of today, there's a brand new channel by Wendover Productions and it's called
Half as Interesting.
The videos are about half as long and probably about half as good as the ones here.
It's essentially the continuation of the old TWL series without the restriction of
only picking topics from that Wikipedia list.
There's no more waiting because the first video is up now and it's about what's
the longest drivable distance on earth.
Videos will be going up there weekly every Thursday at 10.30 am eastern.
Wendover Productions will remain just as it always has, the only difference is that you
can go listen to more and more of this voice over there.
I'd really appreciate it if you go over there and subscribe to at least give it a
try for a few episodes.
I've been putting a lot of work into developing that channel and hopefully it will end up
being something great.
I'll see you next time.