We're back for another round of Lord of the Rings, the Rings of Power.
This time, Arch is with us.
How are you doing, Arch?
Thick.
Still recovering.
Are you still recovering, Arch, are you okay?
Death is no longer near, but it is in the vicinity.
So before we get into anything else, I would just like to quickly touch base with you,
Arch.
TLDR, what did you think of the last episode?
The creation of Mount Doom.
Everything's got to have an origin story, Arch, we have to explain everything.
I mean, we actually know how Mount Doom was created, but details.
Wait, did we actually?
What's the lore on that?
It was created by Morgoth.
Uh-uh, not according to the show, Arch.
Morgoth didn't create it, it was the water.
The water made it.
That was a big splash.
That's one of those problems, because in the actual story, Mount Doom was created by literal
Satan, which gives it power, which is why it's the only place the ring could be created.
Now it's just a volcano, which means the ring could have been destroyed wherever.
Like, Gandalf could have made a fire and that would have fixed the whole problem.
Maybe...
Definitely made it a lot less special.
Yeah.
Maybe somebody, maybe a wizard will be walking by one day and like drop his magic potions
and do it accidentally and make it special.
It's like, oops!
You know what they'll do?
They'll throw the Harfoots in there.
That's how they did it.
Yeah.
As soon as Sauron, that's Sauron, Jesus, as soon as Sauron regains his senses, and is
like, oh, I'm actually a person, he'll lead the Harfoots over and just dump them in.
That's how it'll work.
Now hold on, was this a Freudian slip?
Like Sauron's like the great evil, like what are you doing, dude?
No one tell them.
Mordor just turned Mordor into a giant Applebee's.
Look, I finished outloading the episode.
You already torrented it while we were doing our little preamble intro?
Oh shit.
Wait, hold on.
Wait, Arch!
Is your internet fast now?
Yes.
A nice man came to my house and he put a cable inside of my house and I'm using that cable
to transmit lights at a high speed and this light turns into information.
You finally got fiber optic out in the wilderness of Norway.
Another bit of news on the ratings front, because we've talked about ratings a few times
over the course of this series.
This was published.
Amazon's Rings of Power isn't making as big of a splash as HBO's House of the Dragon,
and it shows the potential risks of dueling big budget fantasy shows.
This does seem to be a thing that everyone's saying now that both shows have been, they've
been getting through their stories and the seasons are kind of coming to a close.
I've been watching both of them and I have to say, as a whole package, House of the Dragon
is so much better than Rings of Power, it's not even funny.
Still shit though.
I'd rather, I'd rather watch The Next Generation or something old.
What, you mean Degrassi The Next Generation, Kibs?
Hold on.
Sit down, Dev.
Well, first of all, I don't, I don't know that lore nearly is as much, so what's happening
in that show is still kind of surprising me a bit.
Secondly, they just seem to have that Game of Thrones edge that, you know, they're willing
to do a few things that Lord of the Rings is probably never going to be willing to do.
Like for example, having an underage niece and an uncle fuck, that's like, all right,
fair enough.
It was the medieval period, I get it.
Everyone's comparing them in terms of like popularity, right?
And it, it really seemed like when Amazon was talking about, you know, the 25 million
viewers in the first episode, they were really trying to take a stab at HBO over this, because
these are the two shows that are competing right now.
There was a leak from, you guys know who Overlord is on YouTube?
I'm sure you do, Arch.
No?
Okay.
Well, he, he has reliably leaked things from the industry before.
He can't, he doesn't reveal a source because they're in Hollywood, but he has reliably
leaked things, things that turned out to be true.
And he is saying that he has an inside word that Amazon's first episode numbers were 9.5
million and then they dropped by half for episode three.
So not the 25 that everyone's saying.
See that is the problem.
We have no actually genuinely reliable information because first we're told like a 1.8 million,
but that wasn't all devices.
Okay.
And House of the Dragon had more than that, more than that at 4.8, then we're told 25
million.
All right.
That's one fuck of a leap.
And now it's like nine, but it's, was cut in half.
Meanwhile, uh, House of Dragons, I've seen the numbers go drastically down to the point
now they're talking about maybe only a million million.
Okay.
Like, what do we believe if I can House of Dragons right now is like a zero one point
over cyberpunk edge runners, which I just watched the other day.
Like there is no comparing those two shows.
I haven't seen that.
Is that good?
It is very good.
Barge is also in the desperate camp I see.
It seems to be the case that like quasi indie animation has really taken off.
Finally, we're getting out of the CalArts era and into some decent stuff.
Hold on.
That's not indie.
Fuck.
Yeah, no.
That's triple A.
Studio Trigger is not an indie studio.
Oh, is that who's doing it?
Okay.
Nevermind.
Jesus.
All right.
They got a lot of flack for recycling a lot of similar, well, let's just say things were
similar in designs.
Oh, I was thinking of the League of Legends show.
Nevermind.
Okay.
Oh yeah.
The story in Arcane is not amazing.
It's quite standard, but the animation quality is beyond this world.
Also the dragon is better.
It's a soap opera though.
Yeah, it is.
It is.
It needs like a Tyrion.
It needs a Tyrion character to lighten the mood sometimes, but it's mostly a pretty good
show so far.
I also think it needs more like variety in the storytelling.
Yes.
Yeah.
But you know what?
Considering how shit everything else has been, I'll take it.
Yeah, no.
Wow.
Settling for less.
Yeah.
Sometimes you have to man.
This is literally the problem.
The reason why House of Dragon has like an 8.7 score, which is ridiculous for that piece
of shit show is because of people who are like Dev who's like, everything's shocked.
Not just Dev, that boss too.
Like, wow, this cereal only has 75% horse feces in it.
Amazing.
I compare, I only mostly notice it.
He can feel the fucking half digested oats crunch, but doing these teething still chewing.
Could be worse.
Dev, it could be worse, at least you're not Anthony Burch.
It could be worse.
You might be watching Rings of Power.
I actually enjoy House of the Dragon.
I don't know why you think it's shit, Arch.
I think it's actually like half decent.
I'm enjoying it.
I enjoyed the part where the children were killing one another.
I quite liked that, but beyond that, I liked very little.
Really?
Pacing for me.
Very stupid show.
It's so fast.
What is it, stupid?
Every single episode has commenced with an enormous time skip.
The smallest of which has been a measly six months.
Yeah.
I mean, it's because like in the book, it's just like almost bullet points and there's
like a lot of history and they're really trying to like expand it as much as possible.
I think they can just slow down the pacing and make it a longer series.
I height almost every single casting choice.
You have young Raheamon, who looks like fetal alcohol syndrome, the advertisement.
You have Daemon, who's just, his face is weird and I don't like it.
The king is rotting and yet he refuses to fucking die, even though they've been like,
oh, he's dead like seven times now.
And then there's the goddamn Valerians, who are all black now, which annoys me because
her children aren't black and nobody seems to be raising this point.
It's like, hold on, your children are the wrong color, Raheamon.
This is suspicious.
And the king is like, no, you can't say that.
But seriously, though, yeah, that was the clip from Gordon Ramsay.
It's black.
The worst part is about, this is in the House of the Dragon show or something, but I'm just
going to, you know, as a quick aside.
The worst part is, is the reason they made the Valerians black is because the main character
of the Valerians, the grandfather of the entire clan, Corallus Valerian, he was described
as having like olive or tan skin.
Not because he was black, but because he was the only person from that family to like sail
around the world.
And he spent a lot of time on ships.
He was very tanned.
He spent a lot of time outdoors.
And there's like pictures of like, there's like lore pictures of him from the other books.
And he's standing with like other people from Westeros, and he's clearly darker than the
rest of them.
But he's not black.
And I think that that that really just seemed to be shoehorning representation and of course,
his entire clan is black now, like the Valerians are black, it just means they get to pass.
It also means we get to hear that fucking ancient annoying defense again, like what
dragons are okay, but not black people.
Yes.
In a universe where dragons are literally more commonplace than like people.
It's not even just the Valerians, there's random extras who are black and it just annoys
me these days because I look at that.
And I think to myself, that was a boardroom decision, not a writing one.
And yeah, for me, it ruins my interest in the show because I'm like, okay, well, this
is political.
I don't want that.
These black person, they ruined.
Yes.
Oh, God.
At least in medieval England, it's like, hello, hi, how did you come here?
Very long thought, right?
Are we are we a show full of racists?
Yes.
All I'm saying is that when I was at what it is, I love Jews too.
I am going to make a Shaka Zulu TV show and there's going to be one white person in Shaka's
army.
No one will ever mention him.
He'll just be there in every single fucking scene.
Just in the background, hanging out.
Yep.
He's going to look like everybody else.
He's going to have his cowhide shield and he's going to be pale as fuck and a ginger
and nobody's ever going to mention it.
Taftaz is just like quietly like, I don't want to get canceled.
I can't say anything.
I can't afford.
I'm just starting my channel.
I can't.
I think I've already been canceled for lots of things.
Oh, yeah, that's true.
I've, I've seen some of your debates regarding trans issues.
I know what's going on.
So someone who watches us actually bought that cringy elf ears shirt.
It's I mean, it's not, it's not a bad shirt, but it's very clearly just like a regular
blue shirt that you might get for five cents from China with this shit just printed right
on top of it.
And it'll wash out after about a year or two going through the washing machine.
Well, like most diversity, it doesn't stand up to water well.
Oh, my God, Arch, you are going to get my channel fucking banned.
Arch is racist.
You know this.
We all know this.
I guess the final thing I'll point out before we get on the road here is I did a video maybe
a year ago looking at like the initial Vanity Fair expose, it was an expose.
It was what was it like a preview of the show.
As I was making that video, I dug into why this was happening.
And basically what happened was Tolkien's son died because Tolkien's son wasn't letting
any of this shit happen.
But as soon as he died, the floodgates kind of opened.
And then back in like 2015 or 2016, Amazon quietly bought a bunch just dropped a bunch
of money to get to pick up the series and like quietly started beginning making this.
This came out just a few days ago on The Hollywood Reporter.
This is an interview with some people who are showrunners of the show, and they're talking
about season two and, you know, the poor fan reception and all this.
But one nugget right in the middle of it.
Basically back while the series was still, you know, safely, safely guarded by those
who care about it.
Netflix actually pitched a show before Amazon got involved.
And Netflix said their plan was to basically turn it into Marvel where they're going to
have like, they're going to have like multiple different properties happening at once.
They were going to do like a Gandalf side series, they were going to do an Aragorn series,
they were just going to do, they're just going to give everyone their own show and just do
like an extended universe that like interweaves very Marvel, very Marvel like because the
Tolkien estate was still in charge of things.
They were immediately like, Oh my God, we can never let any of these people ever do
any of this.
We can't, we have to like, and they cut off everyone, they're like, Nope, nope, not doing
anything.
Nope.
Fuck you.
I don't care how much money you give us.
No.
And that basically persisted until Tolkien's son died.
I have a feeling that Amazon might have the same like long term vision for this.
Oh, without a doubt, this is just the beginning.
Yeah.
The thing is, we already know the Rings of Power is a flop from Amazon's point of view,
but very interesting.
And I'll make a video about this probably for Friday.
Because recently, you know, they've been shooting all this in New Zealand, etc.
It's been really expensive.
And they've said that all this is going to cost like $5 billion for the five seasons.
Very quietly, they've sold all of their studio equipment in New Zealand, and they've moved
to London now where they will be starting to shoot just inside of a regular studio.
Oh, quiet.
So in all due likelihood, Amazon has given up and but they can't cancel it.
They know they can't cancel it.
So they've shifted them off to some dark back corner office in London and just make
movie.
Well, actually, this is something that I saw another media recently, what they often do
now rather than go to locations, they did this, I think he did it in London, and they
did it for the Mandalorian is they'll actually computer generate an entire landscape.
However, it's not like they just insert them on a green screen and put them in front of
it.
They don't they don't do that anymore.
Because that looks kind of fake.
And you know, it is fake, what they'll do almost like a VR headset, they'll 360 view
an entire computer generated landscape, and then project that onto a dome and the actor
goes into the dome and then acts the scene.
So it looks like that they're outside, but they're not.
And the acting dome, the acting apparently, it's really hard to do this.
It's hard on the people working on the set.
Because if you don't, it's it's tuned to exactly where the actor is in the dome.
And if you're not where he is, or where the camera is, or the camera is, if you're not
in the exact spot, all the images like just look distorted because you're looking at them
from the wrong angle.
Everyone who works in the acting dome is getting like motion sickness and shit.
But that's how it rather than going to places.
That's how they're shooting these now.
Fuck actors.
It's better than getting shot on set, I guess.
I hope they get put into the wage cages to Jesus arch arch, you're relentless tonight
people.
So I've got my my mug, piping full of piping hot soup broth, as I do in the evenings.
That's just just chicken noodle.
Just put it in there and boil it up.
And no longer to drink coffee at nights anymore.
So but kids, I think it's time.
It's time for us to watch the eyes.
Oh my god, an hour and 12 minutes.
I'm never going to bed.
Let's go.
Because we're gonna see the eye of Sauron in it.
Honestly, probably that obvious.
Oh, for God's sake.
Oh, look, the legend of Vox Maxima.
I tried to use that.
It was not very good.
No, I don't know why you did.
But then again, your tastes are, but I was desperate.
Recap skip.
Oh boy, we're gonna see the Harfoot's again.
I miss those guys.
I don't.
Oh, Jesus.
That sounds like it was your fetish tap Tash.
Oh, the Harfoot's.
I'm so happy.
Oh, dirty eye.
Gross.
Yeah, now, Galadriel is dead, by the way.
I don't accept this.
Yeah.
She's dead.
She would not be alive.
She's an L.
Oh, yeah.
So that actually reminds me.
There was a video on, like, I think on LiveLeak at one point.
And it was just a Russian guy who gets like an explosion goes off in his face.
And you can tell by the way he's speaking that he singed the inside of his lungs.
And he's like, I'm totally fine, guys.
Don't worry about it.
But with the way that those injuries go is as soon as your lungs start to swell, you're
just gonna die.
You have like 20 minutes to live, and that's it.
And it's kind of grotesque being on a ticking time bomb like that.
But that's what happens to everyone who gets like a fireball of ash in the face.
And everyone should be dead.
Everyone is dead.
The rest of the show is just a fever dream.
Very before death, yep.
Oh, the flaming horse!
Runner or no.
God dammit.
It had one chance to make its life worth something.
I mean, they did the right thing.
You know, died.
Well, we'll see about that.
These are the corpses of all the people banned from Twitch for saying Cracker.
No, these are all the banned reviews.
Lake has been warm enough for wood to spontaneously combust, but humans are still fine in this
area.
Yeah, it's a bit much.
All the water would have been boiled out of you instantly.
Oh, cool.
Even the babies are alive.
Impressive.
You know, we've always been told that babies are fragile and you shouldn't drop them on
the ground, but clearly they're quite sturdy.
I think this would be a big problem, but it turns out it's actually not.
Have I ever told any of you that I was actually unironically dropped as a baby?
No, but your behavior is sort of made again.
My dad put me on the kitchen counter to answer a phone call, and I immediately rolled off.
You are going to use that against you, Dev.
Oh my god, they're just walking past burning people?
Wow.
You're not going to throw something on that guy?
Heroes, ladies and gentlemen.
It's like, help, I'm burning to death slowly.
I like how every named character is okay.
Well, of course.
My queen, you're black.
Surely you must be fire resistant.
Lift.
Jesus.
Ah, the queen had to do it.
Wait, Arch.
The woman had to do it.
Arch, first water, now fire.
What the fuck is with you and black people and the elements?
Well, no, I said diversity doesn't survive water.
Black people survive fire, as you can clearly see by this show.
Other friend died.
Oh no.
Oh no, I'm just saying.
Prophecy didn't really make us care about that character in your show.
I don't kill anything.
Oh, was that supposed to be a character we know?
That's the other friend in the trio friend group.
Yeah, it's the third guy that never got named.
The AK red shirt of the friend group.
Oh no, the death of other friend.
His actor's like, this'll totally launch my career, guys.
I think that was symbolic of what happened to his career for being in the show.
Yep, this entire situation.
This is actually just the Amazon HQ right now that we're looking at.
I mean, yeah, when the reviews came in.
And Bezos is just inside.
Everything's fine.
It's okay.
Wait, why is there a fireball?
Because that's how fire functions die.
He wasn't important.
No, no, he's fine.
Because AZ is over.
Nice, yeah.
Oh yay, what a transition.
Wish he had some of this water, eh?
There's slaves back there.
They just leave him alone.
I will laugh if everyone knows.
Yes, I was about to say it's all going to be burnt to shit.
There you go.
How did you guys fuck this up?
Well, they were back in Bragg and then suddenly...
Ah, the rocks.
Oh.
That's a long flight, but...
Wait, do you think that we're going to see Ents in this show?
I feel like we already have.
Oh, maybe.
I don't know about that, dude.
Well, he almost fixed it.
Wait, hold on.
Here, Kibbs, if you don't mind, go back a bit.
There.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure he pushed her under the tree.
Look at the wood.
I feel like whoever made the show hasn't ever seen burning wood before.
Because that's just wood painted black.
You mean it's been diversified?
It is diversified.
It only burns from the edge.
Yeah, it's not actually burnt wood.
It's not burnt wood!
It's painted dried wood.
It wouldn't even be asked to burn the wood.
Oh my god.
I know that I come from a small town, right?
But even city kids have to do a campfire once in a while, right?
Or they've seen something burn, right?
I don't know enough.
I went to camping once or twice.
Okay.
If it's burnt like that bad, then normally what happens is the inside's also black or ash.
Yeah, everything's just ash, and it crumbles.
And it's very dry.
This is just clearly painted wood.
Why should we trust any elf?
Why shouldn't you?
All this fucking retarded elf hate.
Aren't you guys already working together?
But Elrond half elf.
Ah, he's half elf.
He's a bastard.
Wait, was Elrond always a half elf?
No.
How to talk to short people.
I hate this entire plotline.
Like, Mithril wasn't... this isn't Mithril.
Like, they knew about Mithril before this.
They were making shit out of Mithril before this.
Don't be bothered by it. It's not Lord of the Rings.
So Kibbs, I've noticed whenever you move the mouse,
over top of the feed,
you get a nice little handy list of all the people
in the side who will never get an acting job again after the show bombs.
I mean, I like the x-ray function when I'm watching good shows.
This is useless here.
I don't care about any of these.
The fate of the elves was decided many ages ago.
My mind's much wiser,
much farther-seeing than our own.
You know, the Amazon Rising stuff.
You know, the elves are still pretty long-lived.
And you're gonna be king one day. You can just do it.
He just put his hand on the molten piece of metal.
He did, yes.
No, at least it was covered good.
I was about to say she was holding that piece of molten metal,
but no, there was a little thing wrapped around it.
When she put it in, there was no bubbling.
It was just fake steam and the ripple of putting a cold thing into water.
Otherwise, she'd have to hold onto something molten, which would hurt.
I'm sorry, elf. We Jews cannot give you your shiny ox.
I just come back in like 15 years when our king is dead.
Yeah.
Because dwarves don't live that long, do they?
They live the same amount of time as regular people.
I think they live a bit longer.
Also, the problem with this mysterious unknown fucking random-ass magic disease
is that they have given us no frame of reference for this.
Like, they're saying, like,
we'll all be dead tomorrow. Like, why?
Like, I thought this was a slow creeping corruption or something.
You're giving me your crack cocaine.
Please hit your head on the door.
The scene is so undermined by the plot, it's not even funny.
You know, I liked the elves and the dwarves shit, but I hate this
because it's just magic macguffin.
Like, ah, shiny rock under mountain, make elves live longer.
Why? What? How? When?
Also, surely the elves can go mine it themselves.
They know what it is now.
My god, symbolism.
Yep, look at that. Suddenly the leaf is like, I'm getting better now.
Yep.
The magic rock literally un-rots the leaf.
Oh god, this is very dumb.
The leaf gets up and starts walking, dancing.
They're very dramatic about it, too.
To be fair, if I saw a leaf de-age before my eyes, I'd be like, ugh.
You have to put those in the anti-aging creams.
Yeah, but magic space rock works.
It's magic tree rock, actually.
Ah, good. Back to death and destruction.
The show livens up a lot when the bad people are dying.
Wait, when did...
When did Theo get with Galadriel?
When they started walking together, I guess.
Last burning place. She picked him out of the wreckage and was like,
random person, come with me.
I don't know why our characters need to talk to each other,
because you're really nobody, but I need you to accompany me now.
It's like, okay.
It says here in the script, oh, okay, gotcha.
This is so forced.
Also, apparently the orcs survived this shit just fine.
I guess they are naturally resistant to fire.
They're orky borkies, Arch.
Orky borkies are impervious to many things.
That's a lot of survivors.
Yo, what the fuck? Everyone should be dead.
Yet nobody is.
We saw a few bad people, so it's fine.
I think everyone just likes the visual of
a snowstorm of ash.
Because they did kind of the same thing with Game of Thrones, right?
Four horses, right?
I left your son to die, because I'm
kind of shit at this whole queening thing.
It's fine, he's fine.
He still has to say no.
Yeah.
He's still plot relevant.
Also, I'm pretty sure her plate armor should be very, very
warm at this point.
Yeah.
A little bit uncomfortable.
They cast heat metal on it.
The ash that's collecting on it, making it even warmer.
Hold on, Numenor set their camp?
I thought they just galloped in the whole fucking way.
No, no, no. You must understand.
Dev, plot says camp.
Okay.
Numenorians established a base on the perimeter of the ash.
The orcs will move in daylight now.
No, they won't.
This is how the orcs should move.
This is how they do it.
No, they do it by a fucking magic.
The clouds that cover the orcs
when they are invading the world of Men
isn't ash, it's fucking magic.
Yeah, didn't Sauron summon
thunderclouds, basically?
It's fine, there's enough ash for them
to move through the daylight.
They explained it.
Yes, give the child your primary means
of defense after talking about how the orcs
can move in daylight now.
Thank you for handing me this, Swede.
I have no training whatsoever.
I'm far more likely to cut myself
rather than the enemy, but thanks anyways.
Yeah, swords are actually fairly
tricky weapons.
Wait, did she have two of them?
No, she just gave him
her only weapon.
Oh no, she has that knife.
The ice climbing knife.
I've downgraded my equipment to crap here.
You're level 2,
have this level 16 sword.
She has to level her knife skills.
It looks even worse when it's dirty.
How much further should we reach the encampment?
Are we there yet?
I know this is slow, isn't it?
Were you not there
when you set it up, Queen?
I have the Breaking Bad looks.
I was expecting her to hit her face again.
I thought they were going to have to like, thwap.
My queen, stop asking questions.
She really is just complaining, Jesus.
Freaking whiny ass little queen, Christ's sake.
She's blind!
She doesn't.
I do kind of feel bad for her.
Okay, that shot looked like
they were just walking through a regular forest
and they just kind of tinted it grey.
Like,
like a version of Day for Night.
But instead of blue, it was like
red and grey.
I was going to see that a part of the tree
is healed or something.
We're not going to see it.
There we go.
It's a flower now.
The flower's coming out.
The thing is, he's done as much bad
as he's done good.
Precisely because they don't want it to be obvious.
The problem is, if you do that,
it also means that there's no actual
building of the character.
It's just building of the plot.
Like, if this guy is a wizard now,
he's done so much fucking damage
to the half-woods.
Like, by bumbling around.
He's almost killed the few of them a couple of times.
He's almost frozen that chick's hands off.
Not to mention killing all of the Fireflies
with his bullshit magic.
And I can gather more.
But he's a confused hobble myth.
Yeah, it's not his fault.
He didn't know any better.
Listen, Lilith, you're in...
I will use it to keep the
doctors away.
Lilith, you're in California, right?
You probably see like a dozen guys like that a day
all bumbling around.
I've seen the videos.
They're walking around on fentanyl or whatever.
They be in downtown.
Is she
sharpening the wooden wheel with a rock?
Yep.
What?
It's like a spirit.
Everything's just an allegory
to the other movies and the books.
It's terrible.
This show has nothing original about it.
Does that remind you of the movie?
She's sharpening the wheel
with the rock.
Why?
Because she needs to do something on the set
that makes it look like she's doing something.
Simple.
So they hand her a rock, they hand her a wheel.
Here, rub this rock against the wheel.
It'll make you look, uh, working.
Trust me, you'll get a job after this.
Are you sure?
Jesus, I thought...
I tuned out there
for a minute and I thought you were doing like a casting
couch thing.
I was thinking about it.
It's like, kid, I just met you five
minutes ago.
How do you
know what happened?
Yeah.
Yeah, don't really know.
Oh, I should have known that the old guy would turn
the damn thing.
And that he had the sword
to begin with?
What?
All he knows is that he didn't have it.
Yes, this is one mighty
ass fucking leap of logic here.
Like, I don't have a sword, a volcano explodes.
Uh huh.
Oh hey, the orcs arrived. Lucky.
I guess that's
why they had to take them prisoners so that
they could live to threaten the party later.
The orcs
just smell them.
Yeah, they should be able to, eh?
The orc sense
of smell varies considerably based upon
what the block of mass is.
Also, shouldn't their scent
be slightly masked due to all the ash?
Yeah, I guess so, huh?
Also, shouldn't the orcs be covered in ash, too?
Now, they're the ones
hiding underground.
That guy
looks surprisingly
un-ashed.
Also, I love how the orcs who see in the dark
keep using fucking torches.
When you
see what they are...
I mean, it's better than
Game of Thrones, I guess, where everything is dark.
Yeah.
Is he gonna mine it himself?
These two
are probably the best part of the show.
Consistently.
Yep.
It's the only part I actually pay attention, really.
He found a chasm full of myth.
Wait a second.
Arch, I know you know something about
about this sort of thing.
About this sort of thing, specifically.
Is that how
veins of ore work?
Oh, yeah, totally.
No, it's not embedded in the rock or anything.
It's dramatically placed
on the surface of rocks.
That way, you can look at it and go,
gold!
Five minute walk back home.
I like the tiny drizzle of
water in the background there.
If this were like a
Disney movie, this is where he'd break
out in song.
This is the exact moment.
Yep.
A whole new friendship.
Something inside you
is ill-formed.
Jesus.
That's harsh.
Harsh?
Are dwarven babies
born with beards, too?
That was a euphemism.
Duh.
How dare you have a friend?
Great, you just did it.
Assassinate him.
No one will witness it.
Oh, no, his, uh, thing.
I don't know what that is, but yeah.
It was definitely a thing.
Yeah, it's probably like his
princely thing.
It's like in case somebody was looking at him
and was like, who the fuck are you?
And he lifts his beard.
Here's my cattle collar.
It's like, I'll just take it with me.
Looks back,
oh, I probably should.
Oh, you have to say it plot-wise.
It's not yours anymore.
The writing was great.
Wait, so what's his plan
for the throne then?
There's like another
civil war and succession crisis.
They sleep
with that shit in their hair.
Listen, all of the trees
have regrown. Why? Because
magic, that's why.
Because he was good and you were wrong, barge.
I'll never understand.
There's sodom apples.
Oh, wow.
We'll go to market with all the
crop we've got. What market?
Yeah,
didn't know they had markets.
I think it's pre-capitalism, guys.
Do they have a vibrant
harfoot economy?
Are there more harfoots?
Yeah, no doctors will fuck with you now.
Hurry, let's pick all of the apples
as quickly as possible.
That way they'll rot.
Yeah, like, maybe they're moving on, I guess.
They've got to get a bunch of them.
A better feast, I guess.
Yeah, but normally if they're making applesauce
they try to preserve it
instead of just picking all of it.
Ooh, wait.
They're supposed to be small people, right?
Like three foot tall, whatever?
Why is it that the apples are
regular human-sized in their hands?
Because Amazon doesn't care that much, Dev.
Oh, look, all of the fish are dead.
No?
That's a big person foot.
It's a big person, oh my no.
Hey, bring the bucket, why did you leave
the bucket? There's no reason to leave the bucket.
Well, now the bucket's its own character
going on an adventure.
Oh good, the bucket will demonstrate to us
the bad people.
Oh no.
It's like, aha, harfoots must be nearby.
And for some reason
they use human-sized buckets.
That's weird.
That would be really heavy for a harfoot.
I know that would probably sound like a stickler, but
the original movie did it so well,
the size difference thing.
And here, they really just don't fucking bother.
Look, hmm, this tree seems very
fruity. Let's destroy it.
I hate the armor design in this
fucking show so much.
Oh, flour.
How disgusting.
I pluck at it.
I look at it.
You know, maybe I'm just a weirdo.
But I do kind of find her hot in a weird way.
Yeah, that does make you a weirdo.
Oh, okay.
That's not right, Death.
I think so.
Oh, I mean, either way. I can go both ways on this one.
My turn.
Death. Dumpster.
In. Now.
Blow it out.
You know you want to.
Gonna use her hand to do it, not blow it.
Hmm.
Well, that's unusual.
Also,
they're doing the height difference thing with the hill
as a way to not
do the size difference thing.
Oh, shit.
All the apples.
They're all gonna die. Thank God.
Damn, none of them were asleep inside of their carts
when this happened. Quick, kill the wizards.
Kill the wizards.
At least all the apples will be cooked.
Yeah.
They weren't gonna preserve her.
Also, every single cock-sucking
one of the Harfoots were outside of their homes
when this happened.
At least kill some of them.
Like, the black one. Kill him.
He's not necessary anymore. He's done his part.
Of course, Arch wants the black one dead.
Someone, just kill some of them.
Arch's racism is showing. Nope, too late.
The only one who goes under the blackies.
Fucking Harfoots.
God, more people need to die
in this show.
Only specific
colors, right, Arch?
Sick bastard.
All those rumors were true
in the end, Arch.
I've just forced you to walk for days
with a giant gash in your side.
Well, okay.
I am horse, I speak English.
My master's still arrived.
He's dead, Beric.
You must give him up, Beric.
Well, I mean, he walked all this way here,
so clearly he will listen to some of you.
You gonna turn him loose so he can run home to daddy?
Yep.
Oh yeah, he's gonna go rescue fucking Isildur.
Right, why the fuck not?
I mean, why are you surprised,
Arch? Come on, get with the program here.
Thank you.
I'm going to find Measter now.
Measter.
Oh my god, it's like this thing where the horse rescues
Aragorn.
They're just copying the other movies now.
I hate this fucking show.
Yes, it would have saved all of us
a lot of television.
Yes, let's just walk into the queen's tent.
I'm sure there's no guards here or anything.
Yep, just...
It's fine.
Just straight in.
With your sword and all.
I don't think that's the queen's tent.
Yeah.
That's a fancy looking hospital tent.
Mummy?
Not mummy.
Mummy.
Oh, was I right?
Is she gone?
That's got to be a fake out.
It's got to be a stranger.
Yep.
But they already did that though.
She's going to show up in three, two...
I kind of hope she's dead.
Yep, there you go.
I'm so good at calling this shit, Arch.
You knew it.
I'm the best one now.
I hate you, Cib.
I repeat my previous statement.
More people need to die in this show.
Yeah, was anyone thinking,
like, oh god, I hope they don't kill her.
She was so integral.
Oh no, you're alive too.
You guys have like no ash on you either.
Like, you're just completely fine.
I mean, I assume they just put some on him.
They've had days to wipe off their face.
You know what I like the most?
It's the fact that his hair is still short and cropped.
Like, it's been...
fucking weeks now.
It feels like this show is just written by an algorithm.
It kind of does.
Ah, yes. Keep writing.
None will... None need... No!
Puts on a fucking blindfold.
Just in case people didn't know.
Ah, like it's...
It's the lack of attention to detail that pisses me off so much.
Because, yeah, okay.
It makes sense that the queen would be strong,
with her weakness, you know, keeping morale up.
Then the moment she's back to camp, now tie a blindfold on me so everyone will know.
Maybe she can touch her and make her feel better.
Oh, a gentle push ought to do that.
Ha ha!
Do not spend your pity on me, El.
Save it.
For our enemies.
Why should she pity her enemies?
For they do not know what they have begun.
Oh my Jesus, are we actually doing the Jesus... We are doing the Jesus thing.
She's like, I want revenge.
Like, they're talking as if they've fought some kind of great battle here and been defeated.
Like, none of this has happened.
A mountain blew up.
Like, are you going to fight the mountain?
This scene is so random. Oh my God.
Captain, I'm doubting and having second doubts. Oh!
Like, you know how you...
You know how you get the AI music that sounds pretty good, but just slightly off?
You get, like, AI pictures and artwork now?
Even the big boob AI woman that Sargon has been posting, there's just something slightly off, but it's like 99...
Yeah, it's like 99% good.
That's what this show feels like.
It's like all the moments, all the story beats, all, like, the five-second waits for something to happen.
It's all so predictable.
It feels like a computer wrote it.
It's soulless.
Is that all you think we have left in us?
We're horror foots.
Yeah.
Yeah, that means we're really, like, self-adventurous.
No, it doesn't.
The horror foots go to war.
Okay, listen here.
The horror foots will leave people behind if they've got a fucked up ankle.
They will leave them to die if they can't walk along with their...
They won't be able to put them on the cart.
And now it's like, we're horror foots.
That means we're really tough and could survive having our entire civilization burned to the ground.
No, you're dead.
All of you, dead.
Starved to death.
Now.
This is such bullshit.
They were literally ready to leave this fucking behind because he twisted his ankle.
Mhm.
I hate this fucking thing.
Well, like I said.
Or like Dev said, it's an algorithm.
Like, this whole thing is just...
Literally, it's like, now the horror foots are down on their luck.
So now somebody has to be like, we can do this.
And then everyone goes like, yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah, you actually can do it.
The horror friendship.
Arch, I feel like today, more than any other day,
you're really anti this show.
Like, the hatred of this show.
Yeah.
Like, the hatred's flowing today.
Caught him on a bad day.
The thing is, like,
so much of this has just been boring
and stupid, but
now the story beats
are coming together and I'm finally realizing
I really hate the story.
Well, yeah, because initially it was like,
well, maybe they'll pull it off.
Maybe they'll go in an interesting direction.
And now it's like, well,
no, they're not.
Not without us.
Ah, fuck, god, kill me now.
Shoot me.
It's time for us to go to heaven.
I'm a trained finder, what you go with them looks a brown person.
Me?
Listen, you're an expensive actor.
We're using you.
Oh.
I work right all the time.
I'll fetch provisions and get me stick.
I'm coming with you.
It's a good stick.
I hate all of you.
I hope so.
So, I recently read an article
where someone was complaining that
all of the Harfoot stuff was racist
because they all do really bad
Irish accents.
Does that look like a painting in the background?
The backdrop looks flat.
I agree.
I, too, am decidedly racist
against the Irish, and I fucking hate the Harfoots.
Oh my god,
Queen, if you wanted to keep morale up,
like... No, that was earlier.
It's different.
It's different now.
Also, they've only got one ship.
I guess they left the other two behind.
Is yester-eve a word?
No.
Convenient.
He can't ride.
He's gonna.
A vast gash on the side.
Like, his insides are
about to be his outsides, and you're gonna
put him on a horse.
You gotta shake it out of him, Arch.
I also love how...
One episode ago,
he was like, I don't want to go home.
Now he's like, I will not abandon them
to a mere volcanic explosion.
Like, I'm a king now.
And my people need me.
You know, that is strange
that he was, like, laying in bed looking like he was
about to die at Death's Door.
And now he's... he's walking.
I'm actually okay.
Thanks for the pep talk, guys.
Yeah. You see, wait.
I thought they were gonna, like, get him ready for
travel. He's like, I guess I'll just fucking go.
Alright. Can you ride? No?
Yeah.
Like, he's... this wound needs
11 medicine or he'll die.
Okay. Well, I guess he can ride, then.
Thank you.
Thank you. This is an enormously
precious 11 heirloom.
Thank you very much.
Goes to the next merchant.
He's like, oh, you just sold it for me.
He's like, yeah.
He'll probably get a good price for it, though.
Southland power.
Oh, they start out at a gallop right away.
Don't trot or anything to take it easy
on his wound. Just go on.
These scenes aren't realism.
They're shot for symbolism.
I fucking hate this show so much.
Like, now that the story's
actually come into its own, I fucking
realize how much I dislike it all.
Oh, dude.
Lilith, you mentioned the Sargon faces earlier.
They're like... they're like Pogchamp Sargons.
Should be an emote.
On the server.
It's your father's.
Yeah, it's your dad. Go fucking kill him.
Now.
Too suspicious.
His mind too feeble.
Kill him.
You should kill him.
Too many crests he hurls to the floor.
One day this will be your king.
You're the real one.
Oh my gosh, she's Lady McFeth-ing him.
Wait. Arch.
Make the racist comment we all know you want to make.
Go.
Goddammit, you're putting me on the spot.
What am I supposed to say?
Is it a black joke?
Is it a Jew joke?
Arch, it's the only thing you ever do
which is black jokes. Come on.
Yeah, but I don't see how this relates to her being black.
You'll find a way.
No, I'm leaning more towards Jewish right now.
You're so temperamental with your racism.
I'm going to dig.
Black people don't dig.
Arch, she's just a black Israelite, okay?
Look, he figured it out.
Good job Arch, come on.
Fucking hell.
I don't care how many dwarves have lost me.
If the whole room's looking at Arch, it's going to be like,
say the line, Arch.
Yeah, basically.
See, my racism is very organic, okay?
I can't just turn it on and off like that.
Are we going to see the balrog?
Is the balrog going to burn the leaf?
Come on, balrog.
I know you're in there.
Where the fuck is it going?
It's going where the balrog is.
Dude, it's glowing.
Yes, step on it.
No!
It's a leaf!
It's the balrog!
At the end of the day,
it wasn't Durin who digged deep
and greatly, it was that cunt who threw
a leaf in there and woke him.
Yep.
Hills that you should not litter.
Hey, what do you think happened
to the old man who opened the dam?
Is he just dead?
He's right there, dead.
Is that him?
Oh my fuck, I can't tell, it's all ashy.
Oh, he named Mordor.
Mordor.
Ah, Birmingham.
They call it Adar?
The Southland under race, is it?
Yep.
Oh my god!
Okay, they should have
had someone say that.
That should have been a line.
Yeah, but it would have come out of nowhere.
Like, what would that even be the lead up?
Like, what are we going to name it? Hold on.
Mordor. What does that mean?
No, well, but...
They could have also just left
it without, and then like,
weighed it a little bit.
Also, wait, why was it called the eye?
I was half expecting
the Southlands to get
Wait, wait, Kibbs, shut it up.
Kibbs, figure it out.
Shut up, Kibbs.
We're on the opening of the episode right here.
Wow, when fucking Galadriel
is like opening her eyes and being like
Darth Vader.
We could also extend the list to the fact that Mordor
is a thing, but that's not really
related directly to Sauron, because it would require
the tower, and the tower takes thousands of years to build.
Yep, yep, yep.
They're obviously appealing to that, right?
And also, what's her name lost her eyes?
There's that.
Oh, too many eyes.
But,
what would have been
far, far better.
Just name the episode Mordor.
Okay, that sucks, but name it Mordor.
And then just end on that
exact scene. What do we name it?
But then don't show that lame
thing where the word Mordor
fades in. Don't show that.
Almost anything else.
If you just name the episode Mordor
and then end it on
what do we name the new land?
And then have it like a long fade out.
It would work, it would actually work.
It's like so desperate to be like, guys, you know
Mordor, you know the thing.
The thing, by the way, guys.
Yeah, exactly. Nailed it on the head with that.
Ugh.
It's painful.
But it's because it doesn't
speak for itself, right?
Everything about this show has been,
remember when the movies did this?
Yes. It's very
referential, and that's the issue.
The thing that you guys like, right?
Yeah. It's the I member berries.
It's like, remember guys? Remember when
Photobag, I just went on a vid,
I member. It's like, okay.
Fuck.
Okay.
This is exactly it though.
Up until this point, we've been watching this show
and mostly it's just
the scene boring.
And occasionally there's been a scene which Dev,
the simp, has gone like, this isn't too bad,
and everyone else has yelled at him.
But this, finally now,
after seven hours,
the story has
culminated,
and I realize I hate the story.
Like, that's literally what we've
arrived at here. The story has finally
arrived, and I wish it would never have.
You wish you'd just be dicking around with
what's bumbling in the forest for
a full, you know,
eight or nine or ten episodes.
At least they're not gonna let you in.
It's like mystery box storytelling, right?
Where they're like, what could this be?
It could be really interesting.
And, like, as long as you don't know what it is,
it's like, sure, it could be interesting.
And then you know what it is, and it's like, oh.
Well, the problem is though,
the problem is though, we know what it is
because this is a prequel.
There's no mystery boxes in a prequel.
I mean, like, the sword.
Like, we didn't know what it was, and then it's like, oh, it's a key.
And it's like, oh.
Yeah, but like, all the important mystery boxes,
like, oh, we get it. It's obviously Mithril, right?
Or it's obviously Mount Doom.
Or it's obviously Creation of Mortals. Like, oh, okay.
Then they make shit up.
Where now Mithril is magical
crack rock that saves the elves.
It's so dumb. I hate it so much.
Arch.
Hold on, Dev. Same issue with, like,
prequels, right? Because they're trying to,
like, why did you want to watch the prequels?
It was to figure out who Darth Vader was before he became
Darth Vader, you know? How did he become that way?
There was a mystery still
that needed solving. We knew
the result, but we didn't know how we got there.
This doesn't really have
that, does it?
No, because it doesn't explain how you
got there. It makes shit up.
Yeah, exactly.
None of it's canon, anyway.
Like, okay, well, how did the dwarves delve too deep
and too greedily? Well, you see,
an old man threw a leaf down a hole
and the bad rug was like, LEAF.
Oh, I'm gonna kill dwarves
now.
How was Mount Doom created? Well, an old dude
put a sword in a rock and it
made water and shit. Like,
the thing is, if you're gonna do a prequel- So why did he go
all the way to the hole
just to throw the leaf
down?
Yeah, I don't know. I've talked about this when it comes to
40k. Was there no garbage can?
40k did his own
whole prequel thing with the Horus Heresy.
The way you do a prequel
well is when you add
to the story, when you build
to it, when you add value
to the story. Like,
when a character- like with
Darth Vader is actually a pretty good example.
They added value to him by
showing his fall. They added
depth to him. But here, all they're
doing is subtracting.
Thus, knowing that Mount Doom was created by an
old fart who stuck a stick in a rock
doesn't add to Mount Doom.
It subtracts from it. It's no longer
a mountain volcano
created by Satan.
It's a rando thing built by some rando
to create ash so he could live with his orcs
friends there.
His orc friends. Aww, that's kind of endearing
me, by the way. They're also
subtracting from Amazon's bank account
by trying to make this show.
And it's not working out.
The fall of duty.
Think of what an amazing
story it could be.
It's not a question of helping the elves.
It's simply the dwarves digging deep
and greedily for their own greed's
sake. No, that's not it at all.
It's a fucking leaf.
It's an old person.
That's an interesting insight into greed
and the nature of
pushing yourself too hard for
just want.
The issue is
that entire story is supposed
to be a story of greed, right?
How they continuously justify
it. Like, they know this is dangerous
but we just want a little bit more gold.
Instead, they've subtracted
that and now if they don't dig,
all of the elves just fucking die.
Like, it's no longer greed. It's altruism.
I do like how, as usual,
it's a fucking leaf that
ruins everything.
Yep. We have the rags soon, Dev.
In real life.
Oh god.
I mean, there's the usual stuff of
every important character survives
a cataclysm, but
I mean, that's just normal movie logic.
I mean,
again, it's like not having the will
to actually have
your story beats make
sense or like, play out. Like, you're not
really committing to them. No one really dies.
No one important happens.
Like, okay.
Do the fucking stupid
running away from lava thing
where it's like, oh, the mountain's acting
weird. We must evacuate and then
have the mountain explode. The mountain explodes,
covers everything in the ash, burns everything
with a temperature high enough to
have wood spontaneously combust
yet there are still survivors.
You know what they could have done?
They could have actually done the exact
same story. They just
they could have, man,
I was just thinking of this.
They didn't need to make it so that you take the
sword and then put it in the keyhole and then
open the dam, which then floods all the
water down into the volcano and causes the volcano.
They could have just made it so that it was a
magic sword and a magic
keyhole that creates a magic volcano.
Yeah.
Magic. And it would have
worked a lot better. Like, yes, you
put the sword in, the ground starts rumbling,
you know, the sigil of Sauron appears
in the mountain and like the top blows off of it or something
like, you could, you could just make this
shit up. They're already making it up anyway.
They might as well make it up good.
No.
That's what they decided.
We are against the concept of quality
here at Amazon Studios.
We'll use an algorithm.
In any other show, I'd
call it a cop-out, but in a show like
this, where you are
in the time of legends and myth,
literally just make an artifact
of Morgoth and it's like when
this artifact is like placed upon the
thingamabob, like darkness will descend
upon the land and what does it mean?
And then you blow up Mount Doom.
Yeah, exactly.
Just pour water.
You could have like a legend
attached to it and the legend, yeah,
it says like, darkness will come to the land and no one knows what
it means and they're like, we have to make sure that
the enemy doesn't get it to the altar
and they have like a back and forth
over it and like it gets lost and then found
again and there's like a mad scramble for it.
And then the heroes fail right in
the last moment and then, you know, the
old man plunges it into the
into the altar and then the volcano
explodes. Like it could be a whole thing!
And I'll dev...
...water.
Don't do it.
It's just...
It is anti-Tolkean almost
every step of the way.
I hate the horse. I hate the horse
too. The horse walks
all the way back to camp.
But suddenly it's convenient.
It's like, the horse won't
listen to any of us. He walked all the way back
here though. Like, no, it won't listen.
Okay. And he takes off the bridle and the horse
goes, yes to!
And runs away.
It's gonna be the air form scene. Like, that's how it's gonna do it.
Like, he's gonna lick him awake, you know, and he's like, ugh.
Yeah, no, no, he's
gonna be lying there covered in ash
and you're gonna see the horse now just
hoof, hoof, hoof.
And then you're like, oh, horse, you came for me! Horse!
Two days later.
Me and his horse
and me and his best friend?
That's what the show's saying.
I hate it. And the
thing is too,
the reason why I hate it so much
is because this is just
a movie plotline.
That is all it is. The only reason,
like, we haven't seen him build any
relationship with this fucking horse.
Like, it's not like we saw him
carrying out his stable master duties
or pet the horse or like,
oh, you're a good horse, you're feeding cats
or anything, no. We saw one scene of that.
We saw one scene of that. Only one.
Yeah. No, not even that.
Like, that was his daddy coming over like,
you know, a horse would make a bond with you if you're nice
with a horse. Like, but he never did
that. Like, he was whining over
how a horse was like, horse, why are you bitching
about the scratch? Again, it is
just a movie plot.
Alright, sure. Would you say that you're racist
against horses too? Yes.
Species too.
Barch's
biases are only growing from the show.
His hatred is...
Wait, Kibbs,
you're a horse right now, dude.
Yes, that's true.
But also,
I'm watching the Harfoot scene now
where their entire little retarded village is
burnt to the ground and there's
shitloads of stuff that isn't burnt.
Like, there's like pieces of wooden
like, bowls just fine.
There's pieces of their fucking retarded camo netting
just lying over the flames.
That's just fine.
It's like they just created
a set of burnt out carts.
Yeah, this show seems to consistently
just be weird about fire.
Cause there was that, the broken tree branch
that was just painted to be burned, but not actually
burned. Like,
I think they just don't know what like,
what fire is. They just don't get it.
It's not that.
It's an active resistance to attention to detail.
That's the thing. Like, cause
they don't actually give a fuck.
Again, the queen,
it's writing by
scene, by numbers, right?
Queen is sitting on her horse, and you're like
oh my god, she's blind. And she's like
I don't want to show my weakness to the soldiers.
Okay. Makes a lot of
sense. And then next scene, she's
sitting there with a fucking blindfold.
Yeah, no explanation whatsoever.
I mean, now it's okay to break
the moral, I guess.
Either it was always
okay, or like
what happened in between.
Yeah.
Yeah, um
I don't, I don't think I agree with you there.
I actually think that it's ignorance. I think that it's
ignorance, because like, I'm sure
we've all heard that story of the university
professor who is very
intelligent, like a math professor or physics
professor or something. He's very intelligent, but he doesn't
know what a supply chain is. So he asks
the question, why do people hunt for
food? Why not just get your food from the grocery store?
We don't need to kill animals anymore, just go to the grocery store.
It's like, well, he doesn't know
what, like how the food gets to the grocery
store, right? Like, there's that story that I think
we've all heard at least once.
I genuinely think the people who
wrote this show don't know
how fire or heat works.
They're like, oh yeah, things kind of get pretty
hot, you know, I turn on the heating in my house and like
heats up a bit, maybe it's a little bit too hot, but
it's not a big deal.
I genuinely think they don't
get it. They've never been around like a campfire
before or a real fire.
The thing is like, I'm sure they're idiots
as well, Dev. I'm not
I'm not saying they're not retards
also, but no, it
is the consistent lack
of attention to detail. It's like with their
armor. Galadriel doesn't have her
armor until Galadriel
suddenly has her fucking armor.
And the Halibrand too.
In one scene, there's like a
man in him, basically dead on the side of the road
like only elephant medicine can cure him.
Can you ride? Yep.
And he's just
walking perfectly healthy.
It's like, where are we riding to?
To get the elephant medicine that'll cure you.
But I'm riding.
Like his medicine is falling out.
Why don't you pick up the
medicine yourself and come back
for him and he can rest
and hopefully not die.
Put him in a fucking cart
or something.
I mean, I don't
know if anybody here has
ridden a horse, but
they're not the most stable.
Yeah, they're quite bumpy.
Again, it is
the consistent lack of attention
to detail because they
think of a scene
of, wouldn't it be cool if Halibrand
was like wounded and they had to get like
elephant medicine. Yeah, that's like from those
movies things. Yeah, let's do that.
But then they also rode a scene
later on that needs to have Halibrand
with Galadriel and so they're like, fuck.
Why don't you have him ride? It's fine.
Lilith, Lilith, you have to understand
everyone in this call rides Kibs at least
once a day.
So, also, also, also.
Galadriel arrives at camp,
right? And then five minutes
later, her plate armor is perfectly
spotlessly clean, including her
chainmail.
I guarantee you, Arch, there's a bunch of simps in
that camp we'll just lick it off for.
Probably.
Okay, so
I think we all have heard
Arch's rant at this point.
Does anybody else want to throw in their two cents?
I forgot what we were talking about. I sort of zoned out.
We're talking about whores.
You mean there's not
I feel like there's not much to say.
The show just
kind of speaks to her itself.
Let's hope the
next episode will be better because
there's just lots of
I think we pretty much complain about everything
you're used to complain. There is no fucking way
the show gets any better.
Like, maybe, maybe by season two
but this season's going to be a
trash fire all the way down.
The thing is, this
this was the payoff.
This was supposed to be the big moment
and the storylines actually got started
after seven hours.
Well
I know that it was meant to be
the money shot and I do feel like
I got fucked.
I do like that the camp is like
conveniently
outside of the range of
Mount Doom.
Yeah.
Well, good thing they have the foresight.
Actually, you know what?
So they mentioned in the last episode
how they got that far inland.
Apparently the ships they have
can also sail up rivers.
So they just sailed all the way
up to the Southlands.
That's not out of the ordinary
in fact, that's pretty common for ships like that.
Is it?
But ships that can hold 500 guys?
Yeah, no, no, no, no, no.
As the resident fucking Norwegian here
for people who invented river faring ships
Yeah, you guys did that.
This is for shallow draft
ships. Like, these are not shallow
draft ships. These are fucking galleons.
Yeah, and the rivers are deep.
You put your foot in, Cib.
Oh, God.
Amazon, hire me. I can explain
away everything.
Wait, Cibs, it turns
out that you're just the Amazon plant in the group
the whole time. I've been sabotaging it.
It's actually pretty good, guys.
There's no rivers
leading up to Mount Doom.
Like, none.
Like, they still have to cross the fucking
mountain range.
Listen, I don't want to hear any more of your
details, Arch, okay?
The closest they could get
is, like, one of the rivers that leads
to the southern edge of the
wall of mountains. And then they'd
have to cross literally the
entirety of Mordor
to reach Mount Doom.
Yep. It was kind of why Frodo, it was such a big deal for
Frodo and Sam to get in there because
there's really no other way to get past the mountains.
Yeah, I'd also like to point out
these mountains,
they're not like hills.
It's an enormous fucking barrier.
Particularly for
people on horses.
And for a plus two.
This is 300 men.
Like, the amount of food,
supplies, parts,
they've set up a fucking tent town.
Well, you see, Arch,
Hannibal Barca did it, and he did it with
elephants and the Alps, okay?
I broke Arch.
No, they operated on a Russian line of thinking
supply lines?
What supply lines?
What supplies?
Scavenger we go.
This is a nitpick that's
almost pointless, but since we're going
at it, there's no way those fucking
We're going at it.
carried 300 fucking horses.
Well, there's no way to
carry 300 men either.
There's a lot of meme art showing the ship,
and then it shows the side interior,
and underneath it goes like
40 feet deep, and there's like 30 decks.
It's like a giant
barge underwater.
Oh, okay, that's where the other 300 men is.
They show
a shot of the ship's deck,
and there's like 10-12 people, and it looks
crowded.
Those ships
can't carry 300 men, I'm sorry,
but that's just not possible.
Not including horses, no.
Again, it is the consistent
fucking lack of attention to deal.
This is Numenor.
There's just CGI ships. There's no reason
why they couldn't have shown like
100 fucking ships setting sail from
Numenor. That would look cool.
The Numenoreans are going to war,
and there's this massive armada just
cresting the sea. Yeah, instead,
it's five boats, and then two of them
have three boats left.
You would think that
a show like this would have more
budget behind it.
Okay.
Let's just give
a few more CGI ships.
I think I know.
I think I know why not.
I think I know why not. So earlier,
I mentioned that it's like a lack of real-world
experience as to why they don't know how fire works.
Okay. Assume
that these writers are very sheltered
living in LA their whole lives
or something. They don't know how anything works.
And then, also, assume
that they're, let's say, extremely
extremely left-leaning.
Okay, let's just make these two assumptions.
Okay.
The only ships they would have heard about
would have been African slave ships
and how they crowded
them full with hundreds of people.
I like where we're
going. Of course you would,
aren't you? Fuck. But like,
that's why they're like, we can
clearly put 500
guys in a ship. That's how it worked, right?
Obviously. I remember hearing about that.
That was their line of logic.
This is so annoying, though, because
when you're a writer and you're writing
fantasy or writing science fiction,
most of your work is actually just reading
or Google searching, literally.
Okay, how does this work?
Or you call up somebody, a friend who
is actually an architect. How do these buildings work?
It's a lot of research.
More time spent researching than you'll ever
spend writing. They didn't do any of the right research.
They ought to be like the pawn stars. Hold on, let me
call up my expert.
Yeah, it says you're going to need
a lot more boats.
No, no, no. This
explains a lot. The reason why Numenor
is so diverse is because the white
people use the black people as
slave warriors, and they pack them into their
boats really tight. Look at this. See, Arch
can't hold back. He just has to.
I know this was Dev's idea. I'm just
expanding upon it. It's like a pop-up army.
It's kind of like the droids
from Star Wars, like the side of the ships
Arch and stuff.
Black people extend out
like the fucking droid army starts
playing like, bear, bear, bear.
Fucking no way.
Where do they keep the horses, Dev?
Yeah, we've answered
that question.
We know how they've stacked up the humans, but
where are the fucking horses?
Where's the horses' food?
Did they stack them up too?
Did they stack them like, black person, horse,
black person, horse?
Damn, Arch.
Just smashed in there?
What would the horse think?
I'm going to have to start distancing
myself, but I think it's too late.
Dev, remember me?
Next
episode, Arch is completely
replaced.
We just pretend we never knew it.
Guys, Arch is sick with
Covid again.
And Arch comes
in on horses
wearing clan hoods, like
in Birth of the Nation.
What if the horses
were black too? Could they store them
as easily? Arch, you
have Fehrman syndrome.
Oh, does Fehrman? I guess Fehrman's
German, right? He always is racist.
Let me Google, do
black horses fold?
Wait, hold on.
We'll get
Fehrman in for the next one.
We can see if he can out-racist
Arch with his German-ness.
The thing is, he doesn't
really do the racism thing, he just
does the anti-semitism thing.
Yeah.
He's like...
A while ago, he was talking
about how his mouse was busted, and he's
like, back in Auschwitz, our gear
was on top shape.
Jesus.
There's more than a problem in Poland.
I don't remember Fehrman's alt-right Arch,
but we're going with it now.