This is a meme so bland and repetitive that it actually made some people say enough is enough.
In order to explain what makes this meme so poor, you have to delve into the context of the meme itself.
So what exactly makes the Krusty Krab better than the Chum Bucket?
Well, Mr. Krab simply came up with a delicious original recipe that was better than anything Plankton was selling.
But rather than trying to come up with something new and innovative, Plankton insists on stealing the formula to save his business.
Of course, on TV, Plankton always fails, but this meme represents what happens when Plankton succeeds five times in a row.
This meme is just a stolen formula. Reposted memes are just stolen formulas.
Heck, even this series is a stolen formula, the difference being that I remixed it into something new and distinct.
There's a fine line between innovating an idea and straight-up copying it, and this meme crosses that line.
Supporting this meme is supporting the business model of the Chum Bucket, so stop celebrating unoriginality.
There are plenty of other restaurants in Bikini Bottom.