In Vosch's debate with Count Dankula over whether or not Dankula was a white supremacist the point
was made that talking about things like policy or opinions with a white supremacist was pointless
because they would just lie and so Vosch starting from the position that Dankula was a hidden white
supremacist a crypto supremacist if you will didn't actually want to ask relevant questions
but simply say shit like you told a racist joke therefore you're a racist
I made racist jokes in the past doesn't mean that I'm racist they're just jokes
right so I want to open up oh sorry I've got a way to sort of do that straight now you feel
that there's certain beliefs that obviously that white supremacists have correct uh well
yeah I mean they'd have to well why not ask me if I believe in those things oh sure yeah
the answer is because I think you guys lie because you're spineless cowards that's the main reason
this is something Vosch would repeat in his conversation with Lilith only now Dankula's
graduated from white supremacist to fascist do you people like Count Dankula for example
who like when he makes comments that like seem openly fash it's always like a joke and he can
walk it back but his audience loves those comments they're not joking they like it you know but but
he's joking wink well I I mean me personally I think he's a fascist or he's not ideologically
consistent enough to know that he is but from what I've seen that seems to be like the underlying
political message that he's pushed and hey I'm thrown in there as well I know short fat otaku
does this to some extent as well and there are other prominent libertarians who I think kind of
play cover a lot you know I mean I'm not even conservative republican or a libertarian if you
watch enough of Vosch's content you see this sort of thing repeated over and over to the point that
he now believes that all conservatives all republicans all libertarians and pretty much
almost everybody who is to the right of him are fascists if you have a conservative family member
I'm sorry they're part of the problem if you a conservative friend I'm sorry they're part of the
problem and every conservative every republican is on the hook for this every last one of them
people will be treating maga material the exact same way we treat holocaust or world war II or
vermont or ss materials today at some point Vosch has also said something to the effect of
fascism isn't a coherent political ideology it's simply a naked power grab that adopts the rhetoric
of other philosophies as a means to an end while not actually implementing the goals of those
philosophies and no I don't have a clip for this one you can only watch so much brain rot at once
but his video about social fascism contains a bit that has a lot of the same spirit fascism is a
disease it's a creeping mold that spreads from person to person using ideas like nationalism
and racism as vectors and every once in a while you get a you want to call it a super spreader
like QAnon you get these wacky ideas and you can spread to many people very quickly but it always
requires a bad idea and it spreads Vosch's guiding thesis here is that fascism is subversive that
it's incoherent it has no real political philosophy so it lies about everything in its
attempt to overthrow liberal democracy and Vosch is correct but he's correct for the wrong reasons
consider the claim that fascism has no real canon it's not just Vosch this is a common belief among
socialists look online wherever this sort of discussion is happening you'll hear about
subversive fascists co-opting socialist language or how fascism is inherently contradictory some
of the socialists I've talked to on this channel have said that as well fascism is kind of like
very incoherent in its uh philosophy um a lot of it is like complete nonsense the problem is
it isn't really true but I can tell you at least one of the reasons why they think that
Wikipedia yeah I've had this passage quoted to me by commies more times than I can count
this is from Giovanni Gentile's Wikipedia page the philosopher of fascism with gentile and with
fascism the problem of the party existed by virtue of the fact that the fascist party arose
organically rather than from a tracked or pre-established sociopolitical doctrine
this complicated the matter for gentile as it left no consensus to any way of thinking among
the fascists but ironically this aspect was to gentile's view of how a state or party doctrine
should live out its existence with natural organic growth and dialectical opposition intact
a dialectical opposition they're referencing Hegel's thesis antithesis synthesis method
gentile like Marx was a neo-hagalian philosopher this objection seems to stem from the observation
as well as gentile's own acceptance of that observation that fascism arose organically
without a guiding philosophy rather than a philosophy first being written and then a
social movement following it a Marxist critique of fascism is that this lack of a philosophical
basis leads to a fundamental irrationality within fascist movements creating a vacuum that almost
inevitably boils down to raw power as justification for their existence and you have to admit there
is something to this view but again it's not the whole story socialists commonly regurgitate
their misreading of the wikipedia passage in order to win twitter debates but none of them
will actually read the whole article as being quoted presumably because none of them have a
login to j store i still do though to be honest i thought it would have been canceled by now i've
been at school for like eight years the truth is the reference text is literally called the
problem of the party in italian fascism published in the journal of contemporary history volume 9
number 2 april of 1984 by emilio gentile no relation to giovanni gentile by the way it's
a funny coincidence that italy's philosopher of fascism as a political movement as well as italy's
foremost scholar of fascism from historic context both happen to share the same family name but
emilio is a liberal and there really is no political or genetic connection in the article
gentile amelio gentile writes the fascist party was in no sense a homogenous organism not only
because the inevitable mutations which all parties are subject but also because within the structure
and functions of the party there were a number of clearly distinct attitudes and modes of operation
during its history the fascist party underwent a real metamorphosis which substantially modified
its original characteristics without however completely wiping up the typical features by
which its historical identity can be recognized in spite of the structural and functional changes
it would however be superficial to attribute these changes only to circumstance and premeditated
interventions class interests and power plays these changes in fact correspond to a logic
which we might define as specifically totalitarian consistent with the conception of mass politics
characteristic of fascism in other words while the socialists are correct in describing fascism
as growing organically and therefore that method might seem outwardly contradictory and therefore
subversive the socialists are entirely incorrect when they assert that nothing exists below the
surface of fascism no there is certainly a coherent logic it is certainly a thing that
can be concretely identified not simply a vague creeping rot as vosh described it and if these
brainlets ever actually did any reading they'd know that it's actually kind of incredible if
you point out that you've read meinkampf or mussolini's doctrine of fascism or alfredo
rocco's political doctrine of fascism every socialist will scream at you that you're a
crypto fascist if you reply with the obvious response that you're reading about fascism not
because you're a fascist but to learn about fascism the socialist will tell you not to
bother because fascist theory is inherently contradictory and fascists all lie about what
they believe oh also that large swaths of the population are fascist even when they're not
even if they're bad in some other non-fascist way fascism is authoritarianism and conservatism
mixed together that's what fascism is i don't need i don't need this
umberto eco's fucking fucking take on it these same people if you happen to have some
misconceptions about socialism or communism or anarchism they'll demand that you read marx or
kropotkin or proudhon and they will happily love bombingly direct you towards any sources you
require because unlike fascist theorists their guys aren't incoherent their guys wouldn't lie
yeah when somebody tells you to accept their propaganda unthinkingly but don't you dare read
that other guy's heretical works or else you're pure evil who's being the subversive now personally
i would just tell you to read everything read it with a critical eye but read it
nonetheless that being said what the socialists see as irrationality within fascism the fascists
describe themselves as pragmatism in rocco's political doctrine of fascism he states fascism
solves the eternal problem of economic freedom and of state interference considering both as
mere methods which may or may not be employed in accordance with the social needs of the moment
and that fascists differ fundamentally from the liberals the latter see in liberty a principle
the fascists accepted as a method by the liberals freedom is granted in the interest of the citizens
the fascists granted in the interest of society the point here isn't that fascism is contradictory
it's that fascism is a consequentialist ideology happy to use the methods of other political
ideologies if the end result is good for fascism of course considering that a lot of socialists are
die-hard consequentialists it's no wonder they prefer that you not read about this stuff there
are also other theorists and other books they prefer you not read about as well zeve sternhill
a polish born jew who survived the holocaust to become a historian and academic on the topic of
fascism was the first to recognize that fascism was socialist tactics wearing a nationalist
uniform sargon did a premium lotus eaters video on one of his history texts a video i bullied him
for months to make and if you have premium there it's worth a watch sternhill also identified
george sorrell or georges i i can't pronounce french names guys as the missing evolutionary
link between marxism and fascism sorrell was a syndicalist who after observing that the proletariat
did not actually rise up in revolt when called upon to fight the first world war declared marxism
a failure sorrell discovered that the proletariat is always the most reactionary force in any
society and considered marx to be incorrect about the revolutionary potential sorrell also correctly
recognized that the proletariat are often driven to act when they believe in a collective mythos
whether that be the state or the people or the religion sorrell spent much of his life advocating
for socialism achieved through his conception of national syndicalism and both mussolini and
lenin are considered equal successors to cerulean thought for doing what sorrell described as
the union of the national and the social something i have studied without ever developing the idea
sorrell's philosophy acting as the bridge between marxism and fascism is more extensively explored
in james misel's article a premature fascist published in the western political quarterly
volume 3 number one march 1950 and we will absolutely return to sorrell's philosophy in
a future video because there is some interesting stuff in there another common bit of nonsense is
that fascism is somehow capitalism in decay and that late stage capitalism is simply another step
along this inevitable march it should be pointed out that it's no surprise that a proud ethno
nationalist would endorse an economic system whose final form is fascism after all the dictatorial
regimes of franco mussolini and hitler all followed a set pattern an authoritarian
salvation of the capitalist system resulting in their oversight over its industries the issue
with this view is again a lack of knowledge on the part of the socialists if you were to actually
question a breadtuber about this and get a real answer rather than snark and toxicity they would
probably say either one of two things one that the word privatization was literally invented
to describe fascist economics and it wasn't or two they would pull out this mussolini quote
fascism should more appropriately be called corporatism because it is a merger of state
and corporate power and this is where the breadtuber stops reading secure in their
knowledge that corporations are fascist and therefore they're bad but alas it is not so
simple here is how things read when you don't simply stop as soon as your preconceived biases
are confirmed the corporate state considers that private enterprise in the sphere of production
is the most effective and useful instrument in the interest of the nation in view of the fact that
private organization of production is a function of national concern the organizer of the enterprise
is responsible to the state for the direction given to production Giovanni Gentile's philosophy
contained multiple Hegelian innovations to the socialism of old he believed that publicness and
privateness would cease to exist within a fascist system synthesized into a state of incorporation
where everything all people and all property became organs of the state in line with Hegel's
view that the state is the highest embodiment of the divine idea on earth back in a premature
fascist miso states fascism while preserving the framework of capitalism and tolerating the
entrepreneurs and financiers as individuals was destroying their power as a class the fascist
answer to the class struggle was not a revolt by the proletariat against the bourgeoisie that would
seize the means of production and make them community owned as Marx described it was the
incorporation of the proletariat and the bourgeoisie and the means of production into the state as the
state was the ideal vessel for the community most importantly of all though none of this nonsense
is liberal economics in fact this idea of incorporation which can rightfully be called
fascist economics bears no relation to liberalism at all and is in fact nearly identical to what the
breadtubers derisively call state capitalism the soviet union china cuba venezuela derisively
even as they support them nonetheless this is why you hear such sayings as fascism is honest
socialism even though that's not fully accurate it's more like fascism is post-marxist socialism
here's the biggest kicker though these idiots don't actually believe that fascism is capitalism
and decay if they did surely they'd be accelerationists right if centrism truly
enabled fascism if liberalism inevitably decayed into fascism which inevitably collapsed into
socialism if marx was right about it all and gentile was not wouldn't you want this process
to continue at least the socialists of old had the good sense to be consistent and call social
democracy social fascism for its part in helping the working class while preventing a revolution
oh wait vash thinks that's true too there were a number of left-wing political parties which
basically took their orders directly from the kremlin in the 1920s and 1930s which adopted the
mantra of uh or at least the the idea that this thing exists this thing called social fascism
and the argument was that fascism that that is one thing and then you have another thing and that
other thing is social fascism and social fascism is everything that isn't fascism or or or socialism
essentially uh social fascism so named because it procures the social conditions which lead to
fascism and there is a crumb of truth in here as well take liberalism for example does liberalism
lead to fascism well yeah and with that vosh clip we come to the apex of this discussion
fascism is subversive but not because it's incoherent the idea that fascism has no guiding
doctrine is itself a marxist subversion designed to hide the fact that fascism is a post marxist
socialism and that fascism versus socialism marx versus gentile is not a battle between two ends of
an ideological dipole but instead a civil war between two factions both aiming to inherit
hagel's anti-liberal crown fascism is subversive because socialism is subversive and this shouldn't
be a surprise to anybody we've all seen this subterfuge that's not real communism or not real
socialism is heard all over the place not because it's a true statement it's always real socialism
but because it never does what they want it to do so they don't count it but that's just surface
level stuff consider how often that socialist environmentalists object to non-socialist
environmental plans because those plans do not also implement socialism and dismantle capitalism
while solving the climate crisis climate change is a problem about equity it's a problem about
race it's a problem about how we relate to one another and so i think this climate crisis
actually might provide us with an opportunity in a weird way consider the mass subversion of
cultural institutions by people with explicitly marxist agendas under the guise of everything
being political and neutrality being a bourgeois privilege in fact to the point that subversion
is often literally a stated goal by the wokest of the woke consider the account of yuri besmenov
a former kgb agent whose career revolved around a form of subversion the soviets called active
measures where cultural and academic institutions would be infiltrated and seeded with marxism and
consider this back at the start of this video vosch asserted that you cannot truly know who
a fascist is because they'll never tell you you have to intuit it through things like his humor
at this point in the video have you managed to figure out exactly what is wrong with vosh's view
of things in 1921 fruccio geniglia an italian marxist was killed by one of mussolini's fascist
black shirts by a gunshot to the head there was a public outcry against political violence within
a liberal state where voting and debate should take the place of beatings and killings but the
black shirts didn't care in 1922 giacomo madiati the leader of the italian unitary socialist party
decried mussolini's election as fraudulent he was kidnapped by the black shirts thrown into the
trunk of a car stabbed to death and dumped in the woods again there's a public outcry but the black
shirts didn't care in july of 1925 giovanni amandola the leader of the italian democratic
liberal party an outspoken critic of mussolini had the absolute shit beat out of him by 15 black
shirts with clubs and suffered a long slow death over the next nine months mussolini did not play
word games with these events he didn't dog whistle he didn't virtue signal he openly stated in
parliament the black shirts were his that he wanted these men dead and that he did not care
about what others thought about it and for his efforts mussolini was made dictator for life and
the people for a time were bent to his will does this sound like a man who is lying who will never
ever tell you that he is a fascist or does this sound like a man who is open and brazen about it
and who is hoping that the average liberal or the politically online citizen will be desensitized to
his violence someone like you because though subversion is a tool in the fascist handbook
it's not a requirement the fascist doesn't even need to make you a fascist he just needs to get
you to accept his violence as normal without protesting at some point in time vash has also
stated that any socialist will simply tell you they're socialist that socialists are open and
honest about their politics again i can't refine this clip but he says it often enough that i don't
think he would object and yet you can find close to people who are absolutely socialists refusing
to even countenance the question there's a point i really have to put you and and you'll be aware
of this because there's been a lot of um of commentary about this in the british media about
you you've been a member of the communist party for about 40 years now you're still a member
and we know that that communism is basically statist we look at communist countries around
the world and we see that they are tremendously top-down dominant and controlled societies that
they that they rule over and i just wonder i'm putting this question on behalf of those who
wonder about your politics if your politics actually informs your sense of control
it's not just it's not just the medical argument but you have a kind of a political bent to want
the state to tell people what to do i've come on your program as a scientist as to all people
who come onto your program as scientists they come on to talk about the evidence relevant theories
how we approach our scientific disciplines and you don't ask other scientists about politics so
i'm very happy to speak about science which is what my job is um and to limit it to that
so you're saying that your politics doesn't inform your opinion on this subject i'm saying
that i agree to come on this program as a scientist and i'm very happy to talk to you
about the issues that you're raising as a scientist you can even find clips of vosh
describing how good it is to hide the fact that you're a socialist for tactical reasons
uh if you want to come off like really cool when you're a socialist you can just say you're an
internationalist and it means basically the same thing from a leftist perspective but people won't
look at you like you just said you're a hillary clinton supporter uh basically if you're ever
around shoe on head and you want to say that you support like cooperation uh amidst like economic
political systems the world around okay you say you're an internationalist all right you say
you're an internationalist and you'll be fine it's not just public figures there's also a specific
type of boiling the frog in all socialist speech i've had this exact same conversation with like a
dozen online crypto socialists now and the next time you see this you should try it too
maybe you're talking to a libertarian socialist or a democratic socialist or maybe you're talking to
somebody who outwardly identifies as a social democrat but they're advocating quite strongly
for for one topic maybe it's universal health care maybe it's universal worker co-ops or blanket free
college or something like that and inevitably if you ask them about what their politics looks like
after they've implemented this thing they're talking about they'll almost always say something
like well that's a good first step then you got to ask what's the second step what's the third
step where's the point when you say okay here is good there's no reason to go any further than this
this example on screen right now is one of many who advocate for something small and unassuming
but his next steps are a stateless moneyless classless society making him not a sock dem or
a socialist but a communist and in fact when i point this out in our conversation he suddenly
becomes a lot less friendly your politics are not what you advocate for right now but what
your ideal end state is after all of the right now's have been accomplished this is why for
example when xuan head said i'm not a socialist because i like socialism but it's not feasible
right now she's actually a socialist maybe it's just me and my sensibilities but hiding your power
level like that seems subversive as fuck and speaking of hiding your power level vosh calls
himself a market socialist basically they're still trading with money but your whole economy is worker
co-ops but do you actually think he is a market socialist let's hear it from his own mouth in your
mind is market socialism temporary or permanent oh temporary i just look okay so here's the issue
okay are you ready for it okay let's say shit-topia goes socialist shit-topia is right here
right there shit-topia goes socialist okay it's right there all right now here's the issue okay
how do they go socialist well they take the traditional route so what they do
is the workers have an uprising they seize control of the state then after seizing control
of the state they kick out uh all foreign investors all foreign businesses they nationalize
the industry in their country and they start producing everything for the people by the people
okay congratulations we've done it now here's the issue with that all right shit-topia has made a
critical error okay shit-topia is no longer a market society meaning that the goods which are
produced within the borders of this country are not produced for the purpose of selling others
now that's great in concept decommodification is good but here's the issue i'm going to uh
paint in black every country that's going to trade with them now wait that's not going to trade with
them okay the issue is that with the abolition of a market society you no longer have an ability
to meaningfully trade with neighboring nations and if you can't do that not only does your country
suffer because there's a lot of shit you can't produce just in your own country it also means
every other country on earth has absolutely no reason to not just go in there and fucking
annihilate you okay why the fuck if you're completely cut off from the markets of the world
why the fuck would what incentive is there for any other country in the world to tolerate your
existence from their perspective all the resources in your country are just locked off to the
universe the reason why i like market socialism is because it means you can bide your time and
wait for other countries to start popping up that are also worker controlled and once those countries
start popping up you can form trade blocks which is pivotal because if you form trade blocks you
gain the ability to trade with first world nations and in doing so you disincentivize
military action against your countries the united states stands to lose a tremendous amount of
wealth resources labor what have you from the collective trade block that you're invading as
the u.s there is a benefit to remaining a market society now you only do this for long enough
that it's necessary eventually if enough of the world ends up being socialist fuck socialist
socialist once there are enough countries working together it's now possible for them to represent
enough of an economic and military block that the rest of the countries in the world don't
really have a way of meaningfully opposing them the real goal is to make capitalist countries
dependent on market socialist countries in the end vosch is not actually a market socialist
his ideal end state is literally talking about soviet style top-down command economies but only
after market socialism has managed to subvert enough of the world that it becomes the dominant
power block and then is able to impose its will on the rest of the planet whether they want it
or not by the way vosh what country is currently implementing your exact plan anyway can you
imagine by the way what would happen if america went to war with china and we didn't get any more
chinese goods in this country this country would fucking collapse okay we don't need nukes to
destroy america all we need to do is cut off uh trade from china all right we would this country
would be fucking done everything we rely on bye-bye and whoever started that war is not
getting re-elected next election okay if you are sufficiently economically powerful you're just not
going the war is not going to happen because in democracies there is a threat that comes along
with depriving your population of material comfort so the goal in market socialism is to preserve
your relation to those economic transactions long enough that you can provide a sufficient
deterrent against military action against you it also means you don't hurt your own population
because whether you guys like it or not being a market economy is way the fuck more fruitful
than being um a command economy right now in this era like factually the reason why vietnam's gdp
rose was because of market reform isn't this what china is doing well china's not socialist so
so it kind of defeats the purpose a little bit yeah so it turns out vashj's plan is literally
the plan of deng zhao ping and he's too dishonest to admit it because socialism is always subversive
and bread tube is never honest in this video i have described to you how fascism is a revolutionary
philosophy seeking to remake and incorporate society and how liberals and conservatives
not socialists are most likely to oppose it i have described to you how fascism is subversive
sometimes by hiding their power levels but more often than not through desensitizing their
opponents to political terror by constantly performing brazen acts of street violence
i have described to you how fascism despises liberalism using its own institutions to destroy
it from within i have described to you how fascism has a totalitarian ideology that must incorporate
everything into its structures and violently destroy anything that cannot be incorporated
and most importantly of all i have shown you how each of these points that apply to fascism
apply to socialism in equal measure from their revolutionary ideals to their brazen
political violence to their hatred of liberals and liberal institutions and to their totalizing
nature we will dig into the political theory of marx and gentile the feuding brothers in a future
video but for now remember this it's very easy to find a friendly socialist they're often young
idealistic maybe a little dumb sometimes but almost always good-natured and looking to do
what they think will make things better and even though they won't actually make things better
don't blame them when all you read is marx how can you know any better but it's not so for their
talking heads every point that every breadtuber makes about fascism can just as easily be applied
to themselves their hatred of ideological difference their revolutionary rhetoric their
lies and their bad faith their support of political violence as praxis just as on the other
side of their mouth they decry political violence if done by their enemies and their constant
overwhelming deafening refrain about how despite what our lion eyes see they totally seriously
hate the tankies guys the reality is all forms of socialism from marxism to fascism to everything
in between are all the moral equivalents of each other and as liberals our only option is to oppose
them thank you for watching my friends if you enjoyed this video please feel free to share it
around and do all of the other algorithm positive stuff that the youtube engagement metrics like
i don't know sub for more or hit up my patreon or subscribe star if you want to keep it coming
and be sure to stick around because i'm putting up a new video every single day
so i'll see you tomorrow i love you