So I'm getting some new artwork made so that Lilith and I can actually do more content
together that is outside of the the DWS podcast label and that's not ready yet so unfortunately
it's just me today but I do have to credit Lilith because she's done a lot of the legwork
on this topic and here's the topic a couple weeks ago there was a shooting in Colorado
and before we knew anything people started saying stuff like this it's horrible our nation
begins opening up and the shooting starts white male terrorist killers America we have
a problem another mass shooting today a white man has had a bad day it's become quite the
norm and without gun reform it will remain exactly that way I just heard that the suspect
in Colorado was taken alive at least we know he's white so when we inevitably find out
that the shooter is a white supremacist will conservatives finally admit that it's a problem
or is it gonna be like all the other times they sent their thoughts and prayers you gun toting
Second Amendment new index promoting that job responsible for these white supremacists doing
these mass shootings I'm trying to figure out why mass shooters always survive and end up in custody
and probably be taken to McDonald's oh yes I'll have the shooter special but men of color get
killed unarmed for a damn traffic stop and we do have this meme where it appears that the guy is
white ten people shot an officer killed and he gets a leisurely walk to the car George Floyd had
a counterfeit $20 bill and he was murdered by police this is privilege but it turns out it
wasn't white he was an Arab police identify 21 year old Ahmad al-allawi Alissa as suspect in
Boulder shooting oops and check out this flip-flopping guys police confirm at least six
dead and shooting the white male mass shooter was arrested alive hashtag where was he radicalized
another white male mass shooter who had a bad day and killed multiple people terrorized a community
and arrested alive never forget police absolutely know how to de-escalate and peacefully arrest even
the most violent culprits the next day police identify Ahmad Alissa as the terrorist who killed
the ten innocent people in Colorado yesterday unless you're interested in finally passing a
common-sense gun reform legislation I don't want to hear your excuses or responses oh it was all
about race before now the topics gun control what happened to the racial angle don't you want to
talk about this guy's race is there a conversation to be had there here's Amy six and the shooter is
was taken into custody um you might want to check your grammar there in other words it was almost
certainly a white man again if he were black or brown he would be dead oh is that the case
let's mourn the victims but not glorify the killer with the attention of having his name widely known
is it because the name isn't European Amy is is that where we're going with this of course
illin Omar is gonna say something stupid back in the Asian massage parlor shooting she said it
isn't hard to understand why it's so normalized for law enforcement to protect the humanity of
white mass murderers and their willingness to continually make excuses for them and then
regarding this mass shooting her tune seems to have changed the shooters race or ethnicity seems
front and center when they aren't white otherwise it's just a mentally ill young man having a bad
day are you sure that race and ethnicity is not front and center when they're white because uh
it seems to be so front and center that leftists are now immediately jumping to the conclusion
that they're white before there's any evidence of it extremely tired of people's lives depending
on whether a white man with an ar-15 is having a good day or not my inbox and DMS are full of
extremely upset white men who don't give a damn about mass shootings but are demanding I issue a
blanket apology to white men to which I say no it's completely fine to be racist towards white
people it's just punching up to say that all white men are shooters even when they're not and if you
think this is a problem with only the terminally verified you got another thing coming check out
the official Twitter trending page for the story before and after the race of the perpetrator came
out here's before people are comparing the arrests of the white male suspects at the center of the
recent shooting in Boulder and Atlanta to the 2019 death of unarmed black man Elijah McClain
white male of course and after suspect in Colorado shooting incident charged with first-degree
murder Boulder police confirm not a single mention of race I've said this before and I'll say it
again if 9-eleven happened today the media would tell us that there is no way we can possibly know
the motivations of the terrorists the checkmarks will tell us that we're racist for even asking
the question and the socialists will tell us that we deserved it anyway check this one out suspect
in Boulder not antifa BLM Muslim it's a white male when is our society gonna learn while I may
be wrong about the boulder shooting by a man who has an ethnic name no info about his religion
available it is a fact that the majority of mass shooters are white and male this is straight up
what about isn't and it's also factually inaccurate mass shootings dot info I can't believe that site
exists I guess we're at that point is a mass shooting database in 2020 in the United States
there were 612 mass shootings of those shootings 149 have known perpetrators of those 149 roughly
27 were white that's less than 1 5th and you may notice looking at this collage of people there
seems to be an an overwhelming amount of representation from one group and I won't say
anything more than that what the fuck is up with this guy's neck I see he stole it from this guy
so everybody assumed that Ahmad here was a white supremacist alt-right gamer Gator of course it
turns out he was actually a Muslim he ranted about Islamophobia online he reposted content
about mass migration and yes this is not simply a religion issue he was also very antisocial
paranoid and mentally ill it's very easy to radicalize people into anything whether that's
far-right terrorism Islamic terrorism in cell-based terrorism antifa based terrorism whatever if the
person in question is isolated or depressed now you think these idiots who have done this
nonsense would have learned their lesson right like this is just a couple weeks ago it was March
23rd or something but yesterday April 2nd there was another attack and the same type of people
did the exact same fucking thing this time the attack was at the US Capitol and the authorities
said that it did not appear to be terror related and look at these idiots fall for it again so he
was white so it was a white Trump supporter without having the slightest clue about the
security incident at the Capitol I'm gonna go ahead and call white nationalist terrorism on
this one someone Rams vehicle into officer and kills him at the US Capitol attacks others with
a knife apparently it's not terrorism related I don't know yet but I'm guessing that means the
suspect was white ah so they were white it's a white person I guess translation it was a white
guy who are all these no-name checkmarks I don't recognize a single one of these idiots and of
course it turned out to be a black man and more importantly than that a Nation of Islam follower
you know like the the Louis Farrakhan black supremacist types as soon as that came out to
check out what the journalists were saying multiple senior law enforcement officials
briefed on the investigation to say that Noah Greene a 25 year old male from Indiana is the
person who attacked the Capitol today reports say 25 year old Indiana man named Noah Greene
etc etc nobody's mentioning race nobody's mentioning ideology nobody's posting a picture and we know
for a fact this is the kind of stuff that they do if it's say a white in cell or something these
people just got bamboozled last week and then it happens again and they do the same fucking thing
again I wonder if you remember this shooting from September 24th 2017 deadly Tennessee Church
shooting Sudanese immigrant arrested a man named Emmanuel Cadega Sampson opened fire at a church
in Antioch Tennessee he shot six people killing one and was eventually stopped by a good guy with
a gun now the main reason you didn't hear about this shooting is because it happened at the exact
same time as the Las Vegas sniper and fair enough it's not just that the Las Vegas sniper was white
he managed to kill and hurt a lot more people in the fact that it was a sniper it was in a hotel
room there's more of a dramatic angle to the story there's the celebrity aspect because he
was shooting down into into a concert I think it's definitely a story that captures the imagination
more than others but nonetheless there were protests regarding the Las Vegas shootings
saying that it was white supremacist violence and white male rage and all this other nonsense
but nobody even said a peep about Tennessee shooting okay maybe it was just overshadowed
due to the sheer amount of dead involved fair enough we all know the George Floyd story right
knee on the neck Floyd dies in custody sparks a year of violent antifa riots well back in 2018
another man died in the exact same way that George Floyd did Timothy Kaufman a white person this time
was resisting arrest like Floyd put on the ground like Floyd and then need in the back of the neck
like Floyd until he died drugs were a factor in both deaths but in both deaths they still died in
police custody why did only one of these events trigger widespread protests okay okay okay maybe
it's just the fact that the public didn't know back in 2018 and now they know now that the George
Floyd thing has happened everyone knows February 22nd 2021 Angelo Quinto dies after the police
kneel on his neck for five minutes this is nearly a year after George Floyd did any of you even hear
of this story or was it simply buried because the victim was not of the right race now we can have
a different discussion on the responsibility of the police in these scenarios and that is a
legitimate discussion to have that is not the focus that is not the focus of this video but
it will be the focus of a future video the conversation today is about the hypocrisy
of selective outrage while it's never good for anybody to die in police custody it is very clear
that only a certain type of person has the privilege of being deified after their death
or having widespread protests happen regarding the injustice of their case or having widespread
violence and riots happen in their name and if you look at cases like Rayshard Brooks or Jacob Blake
which are in my opinion a lot more clear-cut on the side of the police you begin to realize
that the common variable is not police brutality at all but rather the race of the victim and you
know what it's not just white people as I've talked about in multiple videos recently black
on Asian crime has ramped up considerably and black on black crime is a far greater killer
than say white on black crime and yet according to the leftist view white people are still to blame
for that black on Asian crimes only occur because of our system of white supremacy that strips
african-americans of their economic opportunities while taking respect and dignity away from Asian
Americans yes of course of course so when these black activists walk into this Asian owned nail
salon in Milwaukee complete with matching black panther outfits this is Whitey's fault is it are
you so completely reluctant to hold black people responsible for anything that you will blame the
actions of black supremacists on white people the way the left treats race is absolute insanity it
seems to me that white privilege is having your death at the hands of the police go completely
unnoticed by our society at large thank you for watching my friends if you enjoyed this video
please feel free to share it around and do all of the other algorithm positive stuff the YouTube
engagement metrics like I don't know sub for more or hit up my patreon or subscribe star if you want
to keep it coming and be sure to stick around because I'm putting up a new video every single
day so I'll see you tomorrow I love you