hello hello hey how's it going is your mouse working it's now working yeah sorry
so what's going on uh not much um uh was watching obama speak but i kind of got bored honestly um
yeah so usually i'm not gonna buy his his speeches but um yeah i just yeah i don't know even he's not
doing it today hey i guess not um so what's what's new with you okay just give me a minute
i'm gonna post in my discord that i'm chatting with you for a little bit here okay just give
me a minute you're gonna use that at everyone oh boy that's fun actually i have a new twitter
account now too don't tell anyone oh really yeah it's it's called morbius devo oh i'm new do we
know him yes this is uh sfo you recently watched my um three forms of fascism video yeah a few
weeks ago right well i was still sick and you were sick i was sick yeah i was just sick for a really
long time yeah it was a really good video i really like that oh well thank you yeah i think um it's
interesting because whenever i talk to people on the left who are always mad at me about who i
talk to about like um like for example if i'm talking to like far right people they never seem
the people who criticize me on the left or even libs never seem to fully understand what they're
criticizing like they don't know the basics of that sphere and then they think that they have the
knowledge to like debate me on whether i should be talking to them or not if they don't even know
that it's not even called the alt-right anymore like like this is years old information like
and people are are so like just out of touch and they still think like richard spencer's around or
something yeah he's still relevant and stuff no he i mean look he's still doing whatever i don't
know what the fuck he's doing but he's doing something with his friend but nobody listens
to him anymore you know yeah yeah yeah fuck no i think things have changed you know since since
2016 since politics really blew up online things have kind of gone through several waves you know
we had like the alt-right they were doing their thing for a while then bread tube but now bread
tubes kind of gone like no one watches them anymore yeah i don't even yeah i i don't know
what happened to bread tube but somebody called me a breadtuber the other day and i
i don't know it was weird that a few times actually yeah yeah well there's a thing right
now because the right also doesn't understand the left online either so yeah you know sargon
you know sargon and i were good friends we talk every day but he has he has taken to calling
everyone who's not as right wing as him a communist and i'm just like well no i've heard
his logic and i can explain his logic and the logic is basically that the promises of liberalism
always go ultimately unfulfilled by liberalism so liberalism always degenerates into communism
so if you're a liberal it's only a matter of time that sounds like a mixed vivian wolf argument
honestly uh like the opposite of one like oh liberals always turn into fascists because they
always help fascists or something yes yeah and they both kind of think that of of each other i've
noticed that so if you were to actually search like hold on let me just give me give me a second here
all right if you search like the the phrase the promises of liberalism right you will see a lot
you'll find articles and and um and papers and all these things basically about how the liberals
promised under the french revolution they promised um liberty equality and fraternity and the
socialists believe they haven't actually brought any of those values into into politics but
socialism well socialism promises more liberty and more equality and more fraternity does does
socialism on paper i don't even know if on paper it does but okay yeah so on paper it's like in
reality it does not it cannot actually achieve these things but on paper though i mean you hear
this all the time right if you're talking to some breadtuber they'll say listen you like democracy
right stardust well we just want to expand democracy we're expanding it into the workplace
so they're appealing to this idea that the promises of liberalism have failed
and so sargon who has read a lot of the far left stuff he's like oh i guess they're correct so if
you're a liberal you're always going to generate into a communist so sargon is now a conservative
and that's his logic for it it's like well all right wow so so he and like i'm i'm still good
friends with him but he and i we have like arguments all the time i enjoy the arguments
they're fun because we can still be friends even though we disagree right yeah but um you know he's
he's off doing his his lotus eaters thing and it seems you're working out well for him he's got a
couple hundred thousand subs he's built a few new channels like he's doing okay he has like an
office and a staff like a dozen people like he's doing that's based yeah good for him yeah so he's
still he's still doing okay um i expected well i guess i understand his argument but i guess i
just would have expected some more nuance from him but yeah he so he's been doing a lot of reading
hey tidge how's it going he's been tidge is like the resident femboy of my community
what up femboy sorry i should probably call you by your name what up tidge
all right sargon's are doing a lot of reading oh yeah honestly a lot of the same reading that
i did for the fascism video just to understand some of this stuff you know yeah and a lot of
it has led him down a traditionalist rabbit hole interesting and also i think a lot of that is just
the fact that he's uh he's a dad now you know people tend to become more conservative when
they have parent when they have kids yeah just like a normal trend you know i don't blame him
um there was one thing i noticed i was watching your obama video
he talked about the nancy pelosi husband hammer attacker right it was just a few days ago that
a friend of mine paul pelosi was attacked in his own home somebody breaks into his house looking
for his wife nancy the speaker of the house and thankfully he's he's back home now and we're
going to let investigators do their jobs but but here's what's clear pittsburgh
this habit we've had we have of demonizing political opponents of saying crazy stuff
it creates a dangerous climate and and when you have people who are in leadership positions
who promote or ignore over the top rhetoric and then when there's an attack like this they make
light of it they joke about it then more people are going to get hurt
and more than that we violate the basic spirit of our democracy the spirit of who we are as
americans and how like people on on the right are kind of making fun of it or they're saying that
you know it might have been like a guy who was trying to have sex with him and then it went awry
and like there's all these things going on with that story and we don't know what's going on yet
um he seems to be correct i mean i don't expect obama to necessarily be bipartisan he's clearly
a democrat right but like did you hear about the shooting of the republican candidate a couple days
ago no i did not yeah so this is yeah let me just pull it out real quick i i talked about it this
morning on the weekly sip do i still have it um yeah republican congressional candidate candidates
pat herrington's house was shot up and his children were inside holy shit he's running against
democrat jeff jackson and yeah they're okay he's running against democrat jeff jackson in district
14 the fbi is investigating let's see if i can find an article so you don't just have to take my
word for it which state is this again uh let me see let me see let me see uh pat herrington is
the name uh harrigan sorry north carolina okay here here's the ap news article so one thing i've
noticed is that the right wing of the internet is talking about this like 24 7 right now okay
they're talking about how there's some deranged leftoid who's going around shooting up uh
republican candidates who are running for office and how this is ridiculous and the left has gone
too far and this is too much meanwhile at the same time you ignore on the left on the left
side of the internet's talking about this but no one on the right is talking about any violence
that their guys commit you know like we we've reached this point in politics where it seems like
it seems like both sides are just willing to point the finger at their opponents but ignore it when
their side does it you know what i mean yeah okay i could see that um yeah do they know who did the
shooting not yet the fbi is still investigating this is like two days old this is two days old
damn i know you watched another one of my videos where i went over just like a lot of the stuff
that like a lot of people who were just regular republican voters who were getting harassed over
the course like like that i know i know you watched the video and you like exclaimed a lot
of shock at the one guy who got his like eye socket broken um yeah where he like he was like
an asian guy in new york he just like wore a mega hat around and then a bunch of people just kicked
the shit out of them you know and you don't see that reported on so i i think i think we've
reached this point in at least american politics where both sides are existing in a completely
different news bubble and they're only seeing the stuff that makes them look like victims and makes
their political opponents look like basically nazis and that's a pretty dangerous place to be
in because no one people aren't talking the same language anymore yeah that is dangerous that's
very dangerous um it's interesting there's that you say like victim and like then the other side
is the aggressor um and i find that that like repeating in a lot of different um spheres online
and in person where um there's like this paint i don't know what it is but it seems like everybody
right now is kind of like bent on painting themselves as victims of uh of someone or you
know whatever like i don't know it just seems it seems like people are very obsessed with the whole
victimhood thing yeah yeah so there's there's a paper that was written maybe in 2009 it was a
philosophy paper i know sargon showed it to me i know that taftaj has read it but i forget the
name of the guy i can tell you the ideas but i forget the name of the guy who wrote it but he
basically said that all of politics and all of morality does ultimately come down to justifying
victimhood and how every political camp behaves in the exact same way they just have different
targets and his argument was basically that if you look at fascists right the fascists they
always claim to be victims of something you know there there's some group out there that is
oppressing them it can be the jews or it can be the blacks or it can be it could be race mixers
it can be it can be marxists or liberals or whoever but there's a group out there that's
oppressing them and they're doing things to them that violate their nazi code of ethics
and so they are they're victims and they're justified in oppressing them back
and from the nazi point of view they're correct because the nazis happen to have an ethical code
that they follow and the liberals necessarily have to oppress them so they are actually victims
and the socialists say the same thing the socialists always say well we're victims of
the capitalist system and and of the and of a you know like a you know the bourgeois and whoever
right and from their point of view they're also correct so they because they have defined what
aggression is as capitalist action if you know if you own property that's aggression right
things like that and then if you look at the liberals liberals do the same thing because
the liberals will say well we only oppress people who are censors or who who do oppressing first
but that's still ultimately oppressing the liberal political opponents because it's only the
liberals who value non-aggression who or who values self-defense as its own virtue so like
whenever when when people say there was a debate it was destiny versus a muslim guy
like last year or something and the muslim guy basically said well we like the liberals are
oppressing us and the destiny said well how are the liberals oppressing you it's like well they
won't let us right sorry who do you know his name yeah i think it's daniel hikikichu it might be i
don't remember his name but he said that he basically said that the liberals are preventing
us from applying sharia law and it's like well isn't sharia law oppressive and he's like not
to us it isn't because every political camp defines what constitutes aggression and what
constitutes oppression in in basically in their in their own favor and so after they've created
that normativity they can then go after their political opponents for violating the normativity
so liberals and socialists and fascists they all behave in the same way in the end they just have
different targets and it really just boils down to well what targets do you find do you think are
morally acceptable to go after and as soon as you realize that's what politics is everything becomes
very scary you know what i mean yeah because now now it's much harder to actually negotiate
anything and i think that's that's like the road that we've all gone down recently is that no one's
negotiating anymore no one's listening to each other anymore yeah um yeah no it does it seems
like even like 10 years ago um politics used to be like way more bipartisan i'm not really sure
if it's like social media and algorithms that's made people more siloed or what um
but i mean part of that yeah yeah it's part of it but i think there are some sacrifices that we do
need to to make right like if liberalism is oppressive to towards people who want to
practice sharia law unfortunately we are going by like what the majority wants here
the majority does not want sharia law the majority um would not um be okay with sharia law
uh so i mean at a certain point we like yeah it may be oppressive in some sort of way to you but
um i would say it is justified i guess sure but but then all that means is that if you ever lose
the majority then you're you're automatically wrong right so for example if you go to a muslim
majority country and you're relying on on that sentiment to to basically guide your morality
well now suddenly it's moral to to oppress gay people if you live in a muslim majority country
so that also has its own pitfalls that that's why you know i was we were both i know you were
on the call and i was listening to the call yeah of um over on destiny's channel earlier about the
whole like anti-democracy arc or whatever and like there's a decent argument there's actually
a few solid decent arguments to be to just strictly being anti-democracy and i think like
the you know do you want to live in a country where the majority of people want to oppress you
that's a pretty good one right there right like if you're if you're gay living in saudi arabia
it is the democratic will of the people that you be thrown off the building and it's like well
that's no good you know there there's there has to be some some kind of virtue system that is
above democracy i think which is a very strange way to put it because i'm still a liberal but
you know what i mean yeah there's something going on here um okay
i mean i i don't know i feel i i guess what i would hope for if i were living in one of
those countries is that over time you know culture would change and that through the culture changing
um people would enact change in their government and things like that but uh yeah if if everybody
if if i guess if a majority of the population occupies a place and it's like an actual democracy
and majority that population believes in things that are going to be oppressive very oppressive
to specific groups then i guess you yeah you have a point um and to be fair that is the world we
live in now yeah you know because because we do oppress non-liberals in liberal countries you know
we don't let the socialists you know have their violent revolution here we have to oppress them
someone's always getting oppressed yeah that's that's just the nature of politics right yeah
i guess so yeah i guess i would just say it's justified but then whether
i i would say it's justified that um that they are getting oppressed in some sort of way but
if it were the opposite like you're saying um in a different country where
the majority wants to throw somebody off a building um i i don't know that i i would
necessarily say that it's justified to throw them off the building but i would just say it's
justified for them to enact that because the majority voted that way i guess maybe i don't
know yeah that's where we get to the part that like democracy can be just as oppressive as any
kind of dictatorship in the end where it all depends on on what the power is used for right
so sure sure yeah it can be um it can be but i think there's less i think there's more
opportunities for it to not be oppressive i guess oh sure like here's the thing i'm still
ultimately pro-democracy i just know the anti-democracy argument very well like like
for example the um i don't know if you've made it public where you live do you are you in california
or la i'm not no okay but you know but you know about the um the urban sprawl problem there right
how it's just like hundreds of miles of houses yeah it sucks yeah yeah so that's a problem
that's uh that's unique to democracy actually because if you have you know you have a
neighborhood where everyone where there's a bunch of small landowners right and well what's what's
what would be good for that neighborhood is if you build an apartment block because if you build
an apartment block that those are going to be cheaper places to rent that poor people can go
live in and then now suddenly demand for all that housing goes way down but and so now people can
actually buy houses and own houses the middle class can actually have houses again like they
could 50 years ago but the problem with that is that that also means that um the property values
go down and every single person who owns property in la is never ever ever going to vote for a
zoning reform that will allow giant apartment blocks to be built because it actually hurts
their own bottom line so this is an instance where every single voter will always vote in
their own interest but that interest destroys society and so so like nimbyism itself is is
a problem unique to democracy right um it's the same thing with like prison reform nobody likes
how american prisons are but no one ever actually votes to change them and no one ever wants a
prison built in their backyard no one ever wants prisoners to be released into their community you
know so so nimbyism like if you had a let's say a a benevolent philosopher king he would just build
the apartment block and he would just build the prison as the society needed it you know and uh
i don't know i feel like nimbyism is one of those things that would be changed even through
democracy like i think that there are enough people that that it's plausible that there are
enough people eventually who would want um who would be willing to make that sacrifice in their
in their home like their property value going down uh just to fix the um the problem of people
not having enough places to live uh like is that maybe we haven't seen it yet though you know
i mean there's a little bit of a movement right like there's a little bit of a movement kind of
starting up around it maybe maybe it might happen but i don't know like it's that's a tough one i
mean another like if here do you do you want the ultimate black pill sure okay so when when trump
was refusing to concede the election right yeah who was it who was it on the right that was
actually standing up to trump uh pence um um pence did a little bit yeah and and to his credit
to his credit but every single republican politician who who basically had their jobs
on the line because they were being voted in and they knew how um how popular trump was they
didn't say a single thing it was it was republican judges that looked into the cases and said no
these have no merit it was um the attorney general whose position was appointed not elected you know
it was the head of the fbi these are all positions that they don't need to worry about um public
popularity and they were the ones that had the political space to oppose trump from the right
and ultimately it was those guys who did their part in saving democracy the all the ones who
who were in like unsafe seats and who had to get re-elected they didn't say a single thing
you know yeah the ultimate black pill is that it was the anti-democratic elements of
the american republic that saved democracy interesting
and so i i think that's why like america has both democratic and autocratic elements because because
you need both of them in some sense you need you need a component of your government that
is outside the democratic process in order to be able to accurately judge it
okay that makes sense couch man in the in the chat's been converted he now loves authoritarianism
based nice
yeah i guess that i guess i guess that's true yeah it was it was the
okay that's that's interesting i feel like my brain isn't big enough for this but i think
i'm getting what you're saying here i'll give you one final one final black pill hold on let me find
this let me just pull this up real quick isn't something else taftage has sent me she's got a big
brain she knows what's going on oh yeah she does yeah you've spoken to her before
uh yeah yeah i have i like her a lot yeah it's funny like as soon as she went on destiny that
first time i messaged her and i was like oh yeah you know you seem really cool and and then she
like immediately follows me back on twitter and then fangirls out because apparently she's been
watching me for years and i was like oh okay that's so base okay i'll i'll pull i'll give you
this study here from cambridge testing theories of american politics elites interest groups and
average citizens um so the tldr of this study is let me just let me just find that tldr the tldr
the study is basically it's basically that the statistical correlation between
how much money you make and whether or not the policies that you vote for actually get implemented
goes up the more money you make and so when you have when you're in the lowest income bracket in
the united states who you vote for basically doesn't matter and as your income goes up
the more likely it is that the policies you want and that you vote for end up coming true
which is a very interesting way to look at democracy is that you know if you if you are
a very poor person and you vote for a candidate because he says he's going to do xyz the chances
of him doing xyz is actually very low yeah okay there are ways to change that though right like
from a local advocacy point right like a i don't know like you're right this study is right sure
um i guess um i don't know what i'm getting at here i have no idea what i'm saying
take the authoritarian pill stardust i don't think i i don't think i can just yeah but um i don't
know god become god emperor trump and or biden whoever you want it's got to be a god emperor
though i don't mind being god emperor you know but i just feel like i i still strongly believe
in and advocating for people to get out and vote because because yeah the the i mean the less you
vote the less it really does matter i guess like it i don't know i feel like it takes it takes two
to tango right like we you can't expect um you can't expect your your hopes to be fulfilled when
you can't even elect the people that want to um to help you achieve that goal yeah see so like
at the end of it i'm still pro-democracy right i'm just i'm not i am i am kind of larping here i
understand the other point of view but i am pro-democracy democracy you know it's just that i
understand that democracy it can't be the the ultimate value it can't be the highest political
value it has to be only a part of your political process sure what do you think the other values
are oh well in the united states it's the constitution right the constitution the whole
point of the constitution is that these are things that even if the population votes for them the
government cannot do and so if you have that limit on democracy then you can at least rein in the
excesses of the tyranny of the majority that's the that's the reason that your republic is set
up the way that it is okay and you know there's there's it's more on the left than on the right
because on the right you at least have the libertarians on the left they just do not give
a shit about the constitution they're like any institution that stands in the way of us
implementing our politics is an illegitimate institution and must be dismantled and overthrown
and subverted because our politics are just that moral and righteous that's a lot of what the left
says right now and that's insane like no there needs to be some limit on everyone's politics
including yours you know i would agree with that yeah yeah so i i finally i and and you know the
right does it too because the right has now gone on like this anti-democracy arc of their own
because they lost an election right like um i think i mentioned in the fascism video i mentioned
something along the lines of um fascists tend to as soon as an institution produces a result that
they don't like they tend to completely delegitimize the institution they attack the rules of the game
rather than accepting the fact that they lost the game you know yeah and you see fascists on the
left do this and fascists on the right do this because fascism is neither left nor right yeah
in the oh i hate it when also when i i hear like um leftists who try to say that like oh fascism
is inherently right-wing and it's like well not um not really no no yeah um but yeah like the
it's just the acceptance like i know americans they really harp on about democracy a lot how
good it is and how moral it is and you know we're the country is like all this stuff but like there
there's other parts of politics that also need their due respect i think you know i'm not an
anarcho-capitalist i don't like the anarcho-capitalists i have read some of their
stuff and the one political innovation that's actually good that comes from the anarcho-capitalists
is when um hop i think i think he did it in democracy the god that failed hop said something
like rights are inherently anti-democratic yeah you know what you're saying exactly that makes
sense i get i get that makes sense yeah yeah you don't vote on rights yeah yeah the idea is that
like you know if you own a house you have a right to it and if a hundred people walk into your house
and vote themselves the owners of your house well no you own it your your right overrides their
democracy and you have the right to remove them with force you know so if you have a right to a
thing then the public's vote doesn't matter you know you know if you're if you have a right to
be gay it doesn't matter if the majority doesn't want you to be gay you can do what you want in
your private life you know so i think that's like the limit on that's a reasonable limit on
democracy is the idea of rights um yeah it's we we just seem to be in like a dark time right now
politically dark time what do you think the solution is um fuck the more that i look into
it the more the solution is probably just going to be a fight you know like like if you look at
like a fist fight or what no possibly a civil war in the united states i'm not gonna go i'm
not going full tim pool on you here i think it's a far i think like it's it might happen in the next
hundred years it might be a long time but like anytime you see tensions like this where you have
two groups that just live in different realities they tend over the course of history they've
always tended to just form their own nations you know like an east united states and a west united
states there would be like the coasts and the interior or something like that you know they
tend to like they tend to split up you know damn happens in the balkans east and west roman empire
like pick a country and it happens the only place it doesn't really happen is china china has always
had like massive wars of reunification they tend to stay together but like european history is
always about the history of of ethnicities and peoples and nations breaking up because they just
start living in different realities i wonder what that would look like i wonder if it was like the
postal united states and then there would be like the i don't know in in inside or whatever i don't
know what that would look like yeah i know um do you watch what if i'll test uh i don't what is that
uh what if i'll test he is primarily a history youtuber but he's also got a big brain here
let me find so he did he did a two-part video series where is it
a two-part video series two months ago and it's called explaining america's nine nations it's
a good it's a good it's like a two-hour watch it's a great watch oh shit he just goes really
he goes yeah he goes into detail of basically these nine ethnicities that exist on the american
continent and you've got like the caribbeans and you've got the midwesterners and you've got the
people living on like the west coast you've got the the kobeckers the kobeckers you know
the um the acadians that live in like the the northeast um northeast america and canada like
and it's just these are the ethnic okay i'm using ethnic in a in a european sense um yeah
like cultural traditions and habits the the differences between these nine these
nine geographic locations in north america yeah and they i mean it might here's the thing like
i don't want any sort of civil war i hope america like america has had some moments
where it's been pre-divided and usually they can bring it back to the center and like
hold on right i hope that happens again but it might not you know who who knows what the
future is going to bring who knows yeah wow but he he's a great channel he does so much
good stuff and he's um he is like a center right-leaning kind of guy and and sometimes
that comes through but he tends to focus mainly on just history and so he's i highly recommend
stuff yeah i'll take a look at his stuff it's super cool i know he uh he he debated vosh
like maybe six months ago or so and like he would have absolutely dumpstered vosh but
but he has no charisma and vosh is all charisma yeah so like clearly what if alt-hist had the
knowledge to just run circles around vosh but he didn't know how to say it and vosh just basically
went like squeaked through on the fumes it was a really funny debate to watch though
i i think it's interesting um i've noticed in these debates now that you can prepare a lot you
can know everything about a subject but if you know how to kind of work the conversation i feel
like you can know next to nothing about a subject and still make the other person look like an
idiot basically oh yeah fucking terrible and it's and it's and i feel like i've used it to
my advantage a couple of times and i feel a little bit bad about it so yeah um i know like
like back in 2017 the alt-right was learning that the whole the hard way because you had like the
you had like um you know the warski show warski live or whatever it was you had tonka's show and
stuff and they all just got by in charisma and it worked for a while but eventually you know reality
snaps back and they all got they all fell apart because i know um destiny debated them a bunch
sargon debated them a bunch and they all just kind of crumbled you know because eventually
that that stops working eventually people kind of figure it out eventually yeah yeah there's a guy
in the in your chat i think his name is elective tool he said that this guy this guy is sus i bet
i know his his idea on ukraine what do you think my idea on ukraine is dude yeah what is your idea
on ukraine i mean i'm i'm pro ukraine obviously yeah yeah i mean some people think that i'm like
oh god i mean it's because of the friends that i have right but like i'm not like a pro russia
simp that some of the people on the right seem to be like they that's that's fucking insane
that shit is weird to me like uh talk about they're siding with like like russia and and
i don't know they're buying up like russia and china talking points and it's like
bro you don't like china is the communist or they were the communists like you know this like what
are you doing why are you why are you backing the guy who wants to bring the ussr back again i mean
i don't know if he actually does but like you know like that's kind of what they're known for there
you you guys are literally backing them like you know what's going on there's a few reasons for
that um do you watch kraut's videos you know kraut is uh yeah i love kraut i used to watch
um his a lot of his videos actually um he just did a video on um on the political ideology of
putin's russia another hour-long video but it's amazing it's great um actually he used he i know
that he watched and critiqued my uh my fascism video and he actually got my reading list and
he used some of his some of my books for his video so that's that was actually pretty cool
to see um yeah but he um he goes basically into it's two russian fascists and then one
german and their political basically their political science writing and how these three
guys basically have influenced putin's putin's outlook on life and on politics
um and and basically when you see people when you see like western rightists they're simping
for russia and simping for putin their their view is some of it's going to be religious
because they they see the west as this decadent globohomo lgbtq rainbow capitalist nightmare
and it's and the only place that is um pushing forward traditional values
and and christian values is russia and the russian orthodox church and so this is the
only christianity we can get in politics we'll take it so some of them are siding with russia
for religious reasons um some of them are siding with russia because so so in this case this is
like the paul joseph watson's if you go over to his channel he has a video he made in the past
few months called like the end of the liberal world order or something like that and and what
these guys believe when they say liberal world order what they're talking about is like uh free
trade and you know just just the idea that the neo lib idea that like if you liberalize markets it
liberalizes politics which to be fair has actually failed at this point um the germans were buying
oil from the russians hoping that that the russians liberalizing their market would also
liberalize russian politics and it did not you know americans have been buying cheap shit from
china for 25 years because clinton and bush both believed that if china opened up its markets it
would liberalize their politics and it didn't so the neo libs were wrong on that um but there's
the they'll also call it like the rules based world order and basically these are guys that
want to see that collapsed and pulled apart as part of dismantling liberal hegemony because
they want to return to a more conservative way of viewing the world and and of doing politics
are more like insular we don't interfere in each of those countries anymore so we're dismantling
nato we're dismantling all these global alliances and everyone just stays in their lane i did call
bush a neo lib because bush was actually a neo lib the neo cons are neo libs yeah interesting
okay these economically i mean economically they are um so so you have guys like paul just
watson who are like listen if we want to challenge the the western liberal stranglehold on politics
and the western and the dominant western liberal block we need somebody who's willing to show that
all of the rules are just they're just a sham they're they're a paper tiger
so they want russia to win and in fact these people have basically been completely btfo'd
by the fact that ukraine has been winning the war they these are people who thought that the
war would be over in two weeks um so you have like the political reason you have the religious reason
and then you just have the fact that the russians are are basically like a new a new variant of
neo-fascist and then you have a bunch of post fascists in in the in the west and they're
basically just siding with them for that reason and so those are the three main reasons why you
see a lot of people on the right supporting russia and then there's like a fourth one and
the fourth one is like conspiracy laden where they just they just don't trust the west's
interpretation and you know to be fair the west has done some weird shit with propaganda as well
like we're not innocent of this so i i get it right you know you always have the cia overthrowing
governments in like the third world and you know people lying about this or that like you've seen
that in our history so they're basically saying hey what if all of the liberal history we've been
taught is just propaganda and so now they're like this is this is like for example what like aden
paladin thinks um on the right where like it where the entire narrative about ukraine cannot
be trusted because we've all seen it filtered through an american lens and the americans aren't
impartial yeah aden paladin is a um is i just talked to her recently i was really surprised
to hear that she's a monarchist um yes she's a libertarian monarchist actually yeah yeah that
was really which is a ridiculous idea idea yeah libertarian almost kind of like it
monarchist like man i i don't i'm i'm still wrapping my head around that one
yeah yeah she's really into patriarchal stuff she really likes the patriarchal
you know uh aspect of of like a religious kind of like monarchy or something like that
i mean i i hate to say it but i think part of that might just be sexual with her
um but i know part of it for sure yeah yeah you know i don't want to go too hard because
aden and i have had like it recently had a big fight oh okay yeah she basically whatever you
want to say well the tldr is that she she leaked my dms and i don't take that kindly so i i've
stopped associated she there's nothing like bad in them because i don't say bad things but i still
think it's like a breach of privacy so i was like you know what maybe you and i shouldn't
talk anymore you know um yeah but in terms of ideology the whole libertarian monarchist thing
is basically that she believes that government is a corporation and so to best run government
you should structure it like it's a corporation like it's privately owned so you have a monarch
who is like a president or a ceo someone who owns the company and then the landed aristocracy they're
like your middle managers and then your serfs are your employees and so the reason that she believes
that this makes sense is because someone who owns the company is not incentivized to destroy their
own company because they own it they generate wealth from it they care about it it's their
creation meanwhile an elected president can go into an office fuck it up for four years
you know his his his his um the next guy in line will will pardon him for any of his crimes then
he goes on to live a private life he gets a book deal you know he gets he gets he gets to go on tv
talk about how how he did these great things for four years as he fucked your country up
and so the the american presidential system means that individual bad actors have no accountability
if they come into power but in the libertarian monarchist system you are at least incentivized
to maintain the social structure because you are enriching yourself through it
now this is a retarded idea but i can see her point of view yeah i can at least see her point
of view oh hey pangas what's up man i guess i think you want pangas watches me and destiny
i think both of us oh cool so yeah yeah um i don't know how okay yeah i guess
dude i'm i'm just sorry about ranting so much no it's cool it's cool um i guess i don't know
how you can have a real like a libertarian monarchy with like a religious monarchy though
i just don't i just don't get it don't um i have to think about it some more
to be fair to her um she's come to religion recently and mainly out of her knowledge of
psychology because she's very well educated on psychology she has i think a master's degree in
psych yeah um she knows her stuff for sure so i i think a lot of a lot of her religious her
a lot of her recent religious experiences has been grounded in in psych to be fair that's how
a lot of people nowadays are get are getting to religions generally through psychology you know
they're they're reaching some limits of their own mind and and of their own they're like they're
starting to think about like oh well why are we this way and you know why do we think like this
why do we have these effects you know yeah um i think a lot of them come to religion because
they're you know psychology kind of leads them there i i don't fully understand that
myself because i'm an atheist yeah i i i need to look into this at some point i've been reading
some some psychology i i i took like intro to psych and then abnormal psych like 10 to 15 years
ago it's been a long time since i've been in school yeah um that's hens hops taking a nutshell
yeah yeah it is um hans herman hop he's the anacap guy okay okay um yeah i i don't know um much about
psychology um i guess one thing that i found interesting in in the psych world or whatever
or like the pseudo psych world is all all of these like youtube body language uh analyzers
have you found that weird because i find that shit really weird i actually don't know what
you're talking about oh yeah there are all these like youtubers who are like body language
analyzers and they try to tell you everything about somebody um based on like based based on
like uh the body language that they display during an interview or something like that
and they'll like over analyze it and it's super cringe in my opinion
i mean there's probably something to it you can definitely see like oh if you know if you sit
this way or you use your hands in this way like there's probably something there but i can see how
like all that stuff can also be faked if you're smart enough right so who actually knows you know
the issue is that i think when it comes to deception versus intuition the the perfect
i don't know deceptionist will always beat the perfect intuitionist in a lot of sense in a lot
of senses because you can always fake a thing and you can always fake it just as well as it can be
real when it comes to body language or how you speak how you lie you know so i think i i there's
probably something there but it's probably not like it's probably not anything that's universal
you know i'm sure a lot of it is just youtube nonsense because there's so much youtube nonsense
out there yeah actually that reminds me um when you were reacting to the um my fascism video
you i got to the part where i talked about the guy who said that that socialists should have sex with
children as a form of anti-fascism and you you kind of lost your mind a bit do you remember that
i don't remember what i said there but no what like what do you what happened i recall
or what do you recall i guess so the um well just that you you thought it was insane and you were
just like you're incredulous but but basically the idea was um you've got wilhelm reich who
wrote the mass psychology of fascism he was a socialist also a german psych psychoanalyst
and his view was that um sexual repression is what causes people to vote
fascist if they grow up in a sexually repressive society if they themselves are sexually repressed
then they're going if their politics will lean fascist these are one of the people that you that
that weren't fascists that wrote about fascism right yes yes okay all right makes a lot of sense
yeah and so his his view was because he like wrote in like the the prime age of freud's he
was very freudian right oh really okay yeah so it was all about sex it was all it's always about
sex with freud so he was he was basically talking about um how if we you know part of the socialist
project has to be a loosening of traditional sexual morality to be more inclusive and that
will combat fascism but then and i mean maybe there's something to that maybe there's not who
knows right but then continuing from his work was the italian communist mario mielli and he
continued on by saying oh yeah so he that guy was so correct that um we should actually have sex
with children because if we have sex with children it will create in them a form of sexuality that is
so open that they can never become fascists and he basically said that if you are a gay man
you must also be a pedophile for the good of the socialist project
i don't know i feel like this dude was just trying to take advantage of like
of what he can get do some such shit that's what i think honestly yes yeah obviously right yeah
like he he wrote this whole like 90 page manifesto on like the communist politics of italy and and
how like and how and how in order to prevent fascism from ever coming to power again in italy
you had to do certain things sexually with children like it was a whole big fucking thing
it's it's it was extremely ridiculous some of the things that he wrote about but holy fuck um
the one thing that i didn't mention in the video one thing because it was too spicy it was too
spicy yeah is that uh i know vosh swears by wilhelm reich in the mass psychology of fascism
and i don't know if he knows if if mario mielli like spun off from his work
yeah but you know that's that's just another point on the vosh sus list somebody's getting
longer and longer somebody should tell him maybe you should like be like yo do you know about this
like i don't know if you want to be associated with this guy like well to be fair vosh vosh
thinks i'm a fascist and he won't talk to me so oh really oh okay i don't know what vosh thinks
about me anymore i know that he liked talking to me at some point um and he would like possibly
pop into my streams uh pretty often and he would like talk to me every now and then but um i don't
know i think yeah i think because i'm like friendly with like pretty much everybody um
i don't know i think he's a little bit sus of me though yeah yeah i think i think the the the
destiny fault line went right through all you lefty tubers and you and rose wrist and econoboi
and all all these people have ended up on the destiny side of the uh of the earthquake you know
yeah damn i mean to be fair econobo is also really smart i've spoken to him too and he's
actually a pretty smart guy econobo is so smart yeah he is so smart he and i went back and forth
on about um about student loan debt forgiveness in the states and i said that it might be a
good idea but it's probably the wrong time to do it because it seems like it's a massive wealth
transfer from the um the lower class to the middle class so maybe not a good idea right
now because things are already pretty heated up in the american economy what did you think of that
of that policy i think um i think the way that that they are doing it seems pretty effective
like they're targeting specifically people who had pell grants right um those are going to be
people who probably need uh that relief the most so yes it is like a massive um transfer of wealth
i guess um but but it is it's alleviating things for like the people who need it the most and i
think i'm kind of okay with that but um yeah so so my argument against it was that you know if
the the libertarians seem to correctly say that if you print money you get inflation like those
are there's a correlation there you know yeah now there are some ways in which you can print money
that won't cause inflation um but that's like responsible money printing and sometimes the fed
is not so responsible it all always depends on what's going there's a bunch of different factors
here right so because you know for example if you wanted to start a business and if if money
and production are kind of like these two variables that you want to keep in line
if you print a bunch of money but don't increase production you've just caused inflation
but if you print money and then give that money out in terms of grants to people who can now start
businesses that wouldn't be able to start them well now they're more productive so production
actually goes up so there's ways to print money that actually also increases production so you
don't actually get inflation out of printing money it's possible um just you have to be really
responsible about it but if you print money to forgive debt what ends up happening is that you
have a bunch of middle class people who hold the debt because they're they're the students who have
gone to college and a college degree means you're going to make more money than people who don't go
to college generally speaking so you have this this middle class group of students who get their
debt forgiven and you're printing money to do it so the rich don't care because one the rich hold
not wealth but assets so they don't have like liquid money that's being devalued in their
bank accounts they have buildings and property and whatever um but even if they do they don't
care they're rich like who cares if food prices go up right but for the poor the absolute poorest of
the poor they might only have like 10 20 100 bucks in their account or something the guys
live in paycheck to paycheck well now everything's more expensive for them um and so if you're
printing money to give to the middle class that seems to be siphoning meaningful wealth directly
out of the lower class to do it um and in my opinion it just seems to not have been the right
time to do that policy considering all the other stimulus biden had done you know because there's
so much stimulus you can do at one point at one point in time before it starts causing inflation
you know maybe i should have waited a bit i mean i'm sure he did it just to try to win the midterms
right so i mean there's a political reason too well kind of boy did make a good point though
that like for for what we're experiencing he like did a breakdown of like the percentages right of
like how much something is contributing to inflation and like um how much stimulus was
was contributing to inflation all of this right and he and he basically made a breakdown he
basically made the argument that whatever inflation we are incurring from these um
from from these um policies or these these things that biden is uh like passing um it's worth it
because what we're getting in return is so much more is essentially what he's been saying um
i don't know if he's done that for the student loan thing i think he did it for the uh
uh the the covid stimulus probably yeah the code stimulus yeah yeah yeah i i and here's the thing
i i did a similar video um i just called it bidenflation with a bunch of meme symbols in
it because it was kind of fun i know my audience got mad at me for it but i did a similar analysis
we probably used the same um the same report that came out because there was a report that came out
like at the start of the year about how much money biden had spent on stimulus so we probably covered
the same thing but the idea was basically like um if inflation is eight percent we can attribute
maybe two percent of that to the war in ukraine we can attribute one to two percent of that at
uh background inflation which is normal and then we can attribute four percent of that to um
to biden stimulus and so if you have four percent as actually the result of biden printing money to
give out to people to try and keep the economy afloat during covid um well then what did you
get for that four percent inflation and you could say like well we save so many jobs and we you know
so many people had certain debts relieved and so many people were able to like you know um
keep their keep their heads above water when they had no money and so maybe you can say that four
percent inflation is worth that and there's an argument to be made on the numbers there
you know how much did you get and is four percent inflation worth it um but i think the right wing
accurately points out that a lot of that inflation happened because of the lockdowns anyway
and now the right doesn't care about the negative effects of covid right they some of them don't
believe that they're it's real some of them say it's not that bad some of them say you know what
our personal liberties are more important and you shouldn't have locked us down that's probably the
most reasonable argument on the right is that you know this wasn't worth what we paid for it
you shouldn't have locked us down okay fair enough we can accept that um just for argument's sake we
can accept it so yeah they're going to say hey listen biden you don't get credit for keeping
people afloat when it was government action that put their heads below water anyway and i think
that's a fair criticism okay yeah yeah if that's the case i can definitely see their their argument
there um yeah i don't know um the the thing though is that they're wrong but yeah um like
that's you know yeah maybe maybe like explain you know if you lock down and then that destroys
businesses and destroys jobs and destroys industries well then you have to ask well
was the lockdown worth it was the amount of locking down that you did worth the economic
damage that you incurred and if the answer is no well then you can't really give biden the credit
for saying well i offset it by printing a bunch of money and giving it to you it's like well
that was kind of a band-aid though like i don't know if america would have been better off if you
had more infections more deaths but more freedom that's a hard question to answer you know maybe
maybe i don't know that it would be because i think our already our medical facilities were
like um pretty swamped i had friends who worked in the medical industry um just with the way that
it was with with the lockdowns that we had um medical professionals have been like retiring
left and right um and i had friends who were nurses who were experiencing so much more death
than they were used to um so i think that that was a huge strain on that industry and i think
that industry is going to be recovering for a really long time and if it had been any worse
i'm not really sure what uh would have happened i guess to that industry you know that's fair but
at the same time you know i live in canada where we had a much more strict lockdown than you guys
did in the states and we experienced all that stuff too we have nurse burnout we have we have
deaths we have businesses that have been destroyed you know um we had a trucker protest which is you
know that you know rebelling against the government might be a normal occurrence in the united states
that never happens here like that was a once in in a generation event here in canada um so like
it see it may be the case that locking down prevented some catastrophe but i feel like
like you really have to lock down to prevent all the catastrophe like china has gone full
authoritarian mode destroying everything in their path and it hasn't helped that much you know what
i mean so i think there's there's like there's diminishing returns on lockdowns and it may be the
case that some people on the left went too far or advocated going too far despite the cost that
they would have paid otherwise you know what i mean like it seems like there was no good answer here
yeah it's really hard to say like you're right it's um it's it's really hard to say
how things would have been different when we didn't do those things i guess
so in the chat says we should have done the florida protocol for the entire uia
us where old people were kept inside and young people were able to be out and about
i mean maybe because young people weren't like affected that much by covid in the end it was all
old people you know so maybe maybe and then here's the other here's the other side of the
conversation we never fully locked down like we were supposed to if we had done it right it would
have been worth it without question are you sure about that though because early in the pandemic
you saw like chinese people being welded into their apartment blocks and you had like soldiers
on the street blasting like cleaners everywhere on the roads and and like people getting arrested
for going outside like you want like a full fully locked down where no one moves no one goes to
work like everything shuts down i don't think that would have been worth it like you have yeah well
them giga like if you want to see what a full a true lockdown is you can look at china and
like that was insane like that was nuts yeah that is and i think they're still they're still doing
they're still doing their like zero covid policy i believe like or at least i saw like a couple
of months ago like people were getting like transported to different facilities that they
tested positive for uh for covid and that shit's fucking crazy yep yeah so like it seems like there
was just no good answer here it was like either lots of people die and you have your freedom or
like you have varying restrictions that get more and more draconian
yeah you can walk down people without going so far as to people in their homes no you can't
because people are going to go outside they want to you know uh china's still welding people into
their apartments apparently i i was not aware of that but they apparently like they have some weird
i don't know i don't know if this is true or not because this could just be chinese like propaganda
or whatever but they were talking about they have this uh this this cool like grocery app and you
can get gross groceries delivered to you or whatever and i don't know how how real that is
you know so yeah well i mean we have like instacart over here and stuff so yeah maybe right maybe
no i've seen a lot of um did you see oh fuck so i do a podcast with lilith lovett if you know who
that is i don't know uh sorry she's this whole space she's um she's she's a trans porn actress
okay but she's but she's chinese she's from taiwan um and so we we did a video um on china maybe two
or three weeks ago no i was i was sick back then it was longer than that we did something
and we did just what what was happening in china and we watched a bunch of videos and she
translated and there was like people who were stuck in apartment blocks in shanghai who were
just starving in their apartments and they were all like hanging out their windows on their
balconies um like yelling stuff like we're starving we're dying in here and then like
a government drone flew in and like on loudspeaker on the drone told them all to shut up
and it was like this is like this is the dystopian cyberpunk future you know yeah
wow oh panga sent you a video of the apartments if you want to see it
um i think i have to get going though at this point just take a look let me see did you send
it on twitter um thank you for hanging out with me um it was super interesting yeah no problem
i'm sorry i didn't have a whole lot to say i feel like um there's like a i'm sorry i'm sorry for
dominating the conversation no it's cool i i i uh it was interesting for sure let me see oh you know
what i think i did see something about this i i did see their videos twitter yeah um i saw videos
of of like just screaming um in some of the streets uh in china yeah yeah that's why i had
little translate because i didn't know what was going on like you know i spent some time in china
like 15 years ago i used to know like basic comp it's all gone i've it's it's amazing how as you
get older you lose languages it's nuts i don't i couldn't i couldn't i i could like get a few
words when i was listening to it i was like look you gotta help me out here yeah okay i dated a
chinese girl when i was like 21 so i learned a bit but yeah uh okay chad i just found it here it is
sorry let me share it with you
what game have you been playing by the way anyway uh rimworld
okay i'm addicted to it it's terrible that's your factorial huh yeah pretty much yeah
oh why did it freeze
oh my god
so
yeah you can see the sparks coming from underneath yeah so crazy and hold on
i do gotta take off pretty much now but i'm gonna send you one more thing before i go
okay just find it here i autistically save like everything for videos and streams
i was going to my china file for a minute the zenshine nine says china was so extreme
there should be a middle ground somewhere at least we should not have had politicians lying to us
saying it was all a planned world unleashed pandemic or that dems made it happen on purpose
that would have been nice yeah that would have been nice uh i mean i i understand like the
the anger about some of the um uh what's what i'm trying to say here there's anger about
how people seem to be very hypocritical about who gets to say what you know like if you said that
if you said that this was a lab leak you know in 2020 or 2021 you'd be banned off social media you
were called like a nazi conspiracy theorist alex jones watcher and until john stewart said it on
his show and then it's like oh why is he allowed to say it now you know and now you have people in
congress saying i was like well come on guys like there was so much double standards on what you
were allowed to say whether or not it was correct like maybe it would have been all just conspiracy
theory but people shouldn't have been like kicked out of the internet for saying it i think i think
the issue is that when the original the original person who talked about it being a lab leak was
not talking about it being a a malicious lab leak right the person who was initially saying that it
was it could have been a leak from from one of the labs was saying that basically they were known um
for for going into bat caves without the proper gear and they were known for not wearing the
proper gear when taking samples from different places and that um and that it may have been a
leak um through i guess just just over exposure and and you know not enough protective gear right
i think that's what it was basically so it was like a negligence leak and not not like a man-made
virus that was leaked out into the world it was just they were doing testing on um on these
different caves and these different areas and uh and probably were not um following the safest
protocol um but i think i think there's a huge difference between saying that and then saying
that like it was man-made the cdc funded the you know funded it the cdc funded it and created it
and unleashed it upon us and all of that right i think there's a huge difference
yeah yeah i completely agree with you i think that there's like there's a shredding of social
trust when it comes to what you're allowed to say online right now like for example on unlike
on right-wing twitter you can see like a 10-minute collage of people who are democratic party members
and like elected people even biden and hillary um this 10-minute collage of them openly saying
that donald trump didn't win 2016 and it's like well jesus christ we've been talking about how
dangerous it is to how dangerous it is to democracy to deny the 2020 election what have
you guys been doing for four fucking years you know like on the right there's this deep sense
that everything is just hypocritical right now and that people aren't playing by the same rules
and it's like what the fuck so like yeah i don't fully agree with them but i get where they're
coming from i understand where they're coming from but again like hillary didn't take a whole
long time to concede she she conceded the next day yeah you know so yeah she conceded the next day
um and you know whether or not she said well i won the popular vote well the popular vote doesn't
really matter right like we know the way that the election works um well i i think i think one of
the clips though was like in 2018 where she's like donald trump is an illegitimate president
she's like outright says like jesus christ like come on that's a bit irresponsible yeah yeah
stupid for her to say that yeah i think i might do a video on that because i do know at least some
people on the on the center left watch me so i want to i want to like expose both sides to what
they're missing you know what i mean that's kind of been my goal from the channel recently sure
i think that i think that's a you know really fair thing to say and i'm willing to concede that like
you know she's said things that maybe she shouldn't have said there are things that
democratic candidates have said that they shouldn't have said but like when it comes
down to the actual actions at least she conceded the next day at least she didn't um uh end up
suing like you know trying to sue a whole bunch of states and and stirring up a whole bunch of
um people who who honestly feel like um the rug was pulled from under them and
honestly you know feel like they have to fight you know the government basically right like i
feel like at least she didn't do that i feel like there's a there's still a difference in like the
amount of of extremes that both sides are going to i don't know no i agree i agree with you yeah
in the end you know there's something that you say two years later on cnn to rile your base
up and then there's what you actually file in court those are two different things for sure
yeah and and you know also just regarding the whole russian thing like i kind of um i kind of
side with like what julia yafi has said on it um and she said that basically like the russian uh
like the fsb um them finding what they found like with the emails or whatever um was kind of
like a fluke accident right it wasn't like they were trying to make hillary lose the election
they they weren't sure like how how effective they would be um in in hurting her campaign
um but it ended up like it was like they she describes it as like when you're trying to like
uh push push a bully back right or push a bully and you're trying to like um you're trying to
show them who's you know that you're like you can push them around a little bit but then you end up
accidentally pushing them a you know just a little bit the wrong way and they end up like breaking
their nose you never meant to break their nose right like they fall and they break their nose
and there's blood everywhere and she's like it's kind of she describes it kind of like that like
they meant to kind of like just kind of shove hillary a little bit and they ended up pushing
her and like her falling over and breaking her nose so that's kind of like what the whole like
email shit ended up being so right yeah yeah yeah i don't know if i described that correctly i'm
sorry i'm really no i got it i got it i think i know what you're saying yeah yeah i i do have
to go though because it's it is bedtime and my girlfriend's already in bed so okay well have a
good one i i dug up four videos if you want to watch them from uh on the china stuff they're
like four little clips right yeah they kind of show off what was going on with like the protests
and the and the rounding of people up and all that so you can check those out if you like um
and yeah like if you if you need more videos to watch what if alt-hist is great and kraut's new
uh putin video is excellent okay yeah i have to take those yeah so uh this is actually a
conversation i want to have you at some point but i can't do it right now so we'll do it next time
okay okay sounds good yeah yeah yeah um all right cool thanks thanks for for uh chatting with me
hope you have a great night yeah no problem and i'll see you next time see ya this is more funny
from tonight couples should sleep separately don't kiss hug is not allowed eat separately
thank you for your cooperation
isn't
So, couple should sleep separately, don't kiss, hug is not allowed and eat separately.
The next thing is doctor, oh I love Dr. Eric, Eric Fagleding, I like this guy.
He lives in Shanghai screaming from high-rise apartments after seven straight days of the city lockdown.
The narrator worries that there will be major problems.
In Shanghainese dialect, predicts people can't hold out much longer, he implies tragedy.
This is from months ago.
This is the first time in my life that I've ever seen a man like this in my life.
I've never seen a man like this in my life.
Thank you for gifting a sub to my little homie.
They have COVID police that arrest political dissidents because they are infected now.
I do remember seeing this couple vlog and they had been detained and put in a different facility because they had been infected with COVID.
So this couple was kind of vlogging about the experience and it just looked like fucking hell.
It was like they were all staying in a fucking camp.