it's time for us to check back in on the valde school shooting situation and
before we get going just know that there is no way this video gets monetized so
please consider hitting up the channel subscribe star or memberships button or
anything else you use to give us a float I first cover this event during a tub
cast with Lilith right when it happened and back then we could only go by word
of mouth on what happened but since then a full video of events has come out I
won't show anything gruesome but I will use it to narrate so here's a quick
recap on May 24th 2022 Salvador Ramos started his day by shooting his
grandmother in the face severely wounding her she miraculously survived
being released from the hospital on June 28th though she will likely never speak
again the current theory is they got into a fight over her disappointment
that he failed to graduate from high school after the fight Ramos drove to
the school where he actually crashed his car into a ditch people from a nearby
funeral home came out to assist but he began shooting at them causing them to
run away and call the cops afterward Ramos leisurely walked into the school
barricaded himself into a classroom and began executing students he was
astonishingly given approximately an hour and a half to basically do whatever
he wanted by the responding police because the ranking officer Pedro
Arradondo misidentified the event as a hostage situation and not an active
shooter in response the police called in tactical officers from the nearby border
patrol unit which was 70 miles away cordoned off the school campus from the
public took up a defensive posture and attempted to make contact with her most
in order to negotiate all things that you should do during a hostage situation
but also all things that you shouldn't do during an active shooter situation
because all that does is give them more time time that Ramos used to do two
sweeps of classroom one one one and one one two allowing him to shoot each
person a second time to ensure that nobody survived and only one child did
survive in the end incredulously this led to mistakes like the cops saying if
you need help shout a student shouting help which alerted Ramos who then move
between one one one and one one two through a shared back office killing her
it would be a comedy of errors if it weren't so grotesque eventually it was
the border patrol seen here in camo with helmets and heavier armor that took a
janitor's key opened the door to the classroom and finally killed Ramos while
the police under the command of Arradondo stood back and watched it's
important to note at this point that Arradondo is the police chief of the
uvalde consolidated independent school district and that the officers seen
throughout most of the videos are ucisd officers they're not the police force of
the city of uvalde but rather the school district's own security their
jurisdiction is only the schools within the district at the time of the shooting
Arradondo had six officers working under school boards started having their own
police forces assigned directly to them in Texas after the 2018 Santa Fe
shooting so since we've last talked about this there's been a number of very
fishy developments the police responsible have been rapidly changing
their public stance as new information keeps coming to light they've hired on a
private law firm with the hopes to resist in court any release of police
body cam footage or other private records arguing that the files could be
highly embarrassing or evoke emotional or mental distress they've stopped
cooperating with the state of Texas's own investigation into the shooting and
how it was handled and of course this very ominous public statement that all
victims were killed by Salvador Ramos and nobody else makes it sound like
they're desperately trying to hide that their own officers fucked up however
despite how popular that theory was in social media the school security camera
footage seems to disprove that it shows officers hunkering down for a hostage
situation it shows many mistakes most blatant of all how they're just standing
around following Arradondo's orders even as they hear repeated waves of gunshots
go off it even shows an officer sanitizing his hands you gotta stop that
COVID spread but it doesn't show officers shooting children that being
said how did this footage get out anyway after all you've all day is fighting
tooth and nail against any investigative efforts even going so far as expelling
journalists and parents from a city council meeting where testimony and
security footage was being presented to city officials so why aren't wired you're
allowing reporters to stay in the building to date it intimidated by who
my reporters yeah so we have to leave the building is where you're saying
because people are intimidated by us yes
come in and protect our children are you a parent yeah yeah I can ask you why
they would be intimidated by us I understand that but why would they be
intimidated by us has someone complained to you sir about being intimidated yes
like me actually had a lady that had a panic attack last week because reporters
were in them yes she just freaked out well ultimately it was leaked by the
Austin American statesman a news outlet local to Texas two days ago they
published and edited a four-minute video which they released on their website and
is fit for TV while they dumped onto their YouTube channel the full hour and
a half including body cam footage school security cam footage and footage from
the funeral home across the street here's the city's response to this leak
from a recent city council meeting I'll say one thing since you brought up the
video and then the press will address your questions after the meeting but I
want to go on the record the way that video was released today is one of the
most chicken things I've ever seen yes I've wanted the video released but all
these news agencies knew that we were working with the with the House
Committee they were gonna have a meeting Sunday to give a report to the
family members Sunday morning and then Sunday afternoon at around two o'clock
they were going to come back and answer the family's questions and show them the
video every news agency knew that they were talking to the house the house went
to the Austin American statesmen and KVU TV and told them this was going to
happen and the response was well we all have a job to do there was no reason for
those families to have to see all I've seen is the first little segment of four
minutes but there's no reason for the families to have to see that I mean they
were gonna see the video but they didn't need to see the gunman coming in and
hear the gunshots they don't need to relive that they've been through enough
and that was the most chicken way to put this video out today whether it was
released by the DPS or who it was released for in my opinion was very
unprofessional which this investigation has been in my opinion since day one
this was the proper thing to do man you were dragging your heels it's a
journalist's job to report on events as accurately as possible to uncover the
truth even if it's politically uncomfortable and the response here
just seems to be pure cope yeah okay the families don't need to see it again fair
enough they can change the channel they can always not go to the website or to
the YouTube video but the rest of the public deserves to have access to it it
was chicken shit yeah to release that video the way you did it that part of
that video was not supposed to be in what they're doing on Sunday that was
not supposed to be there they did that for ratings and they did that for money
and that's only reason they put that out there ratings and money I mean I don't
even know if TV ratings matter anymore but what money how much YouTube revenue
do you think a video of a school shooting is gonna generate I know I'm
not getting anything we're gonna handle that Adam I'm not gonna get into an
argument with you on that you know I haven't seen the video yet but I can
tell you that one of the officers you've called they've got they got grace in
that deal in that video he goes back down that hall three times trying to get
in that room three different times three different times I know what
everybody thinks and we need to let the investigation come through and yeah this
is the best response just right to their face were the cops chicken shit and they
just dodge it I think they know that heads need to roll here you can see for
example the father of one of the victims who is also a police officer being held
back by his fellow officers because they were ordered not to go in it could be
cowardice it could be following the chain of command too strictly even though
clearly on the ground it's a different situation but man this was a massive
fuckup a transcript between the UCISD police and a Texas Department of Public
Safety agent makes it sound like a chain of command problem the agent asked are
there still kids in the classrooms if so they just need to go in the police
reply that he got back was it's unknown at this time the agent reiterated y'all
don't know if there's kids in there if there's kids in there we need to go in
there and the police reply was again whoever is in charge will determine that
the agent at this point exasperated took charge in evacuating parts of the school
that the UCISD officers left alone saying that at least he could save those
kids at this point the whole thing seems to be at least from the outside a
product of chief Arradondo's massive mistake and since the shooting he's
resigned from his position on the Yvalle City Council as well as been placed on
administrative leave from his position within the Yvalle school district
Arradondo meanwhile despite transcripts between the various parties clearly
show him calling the shots has since denied he was the ranking officer on the
scene Arradondo was the one trying all the janitors keys approximately 10
pounds worth of keys in a massive ring on an unrelated door in an attempt to
identify a master key that could unlock all the school's doors including 111 and
112 while at the same time a short distance away the police had access to a
halogen bar a device used by firefighters to open lock doors during a
house fire keep in mind this was their primary jurisdiction their police for
the school board why did they not have their own keys or know which keys went
where why did they not have a plan for this sort of thing why did they
mistakenly identify it as a hostage situation why did Arradondo ditch his
radio right when the event began yeah that happened too people are out here
saying that the cops killed kids accidentally and that's why it's being
covered up but that always seemed a bit far-fetched and it also doesn't seem to
be true at this point but frankly we don't need that to assign blame here the
police were incompetent they were unprepared they assessed the situation
wrong and nobody wanted to step up take ownership and be the leader of the
situation when it was desperately needed and we can probably pin at least a good
chunk of the blame on Arradondo in response people are calling for tighter
gun controls and I'm just thinking you fucking serious yeah the shooter got his
guns legally and fair enough but you want to concentrate all the legitimate
usage of guns into the hands of the police when they're this incompetent I
know not all cops but it's still a moronic idea if you want to put extra
barriers in the path of young people to get guns that's an idea you can probably
have some good faith compromise on they are underage but you don't want a world
where all the responsible adults are disarmed and all the cops are too
disorganized or worse too cowardly to do the job that they're supposed to do this
whole thing is just a cluster fuck this was a massive fuck-up on behalf of
Arradondo and it's looking like he's thankfully not gonna escape
responsibility for it something that does happen far too often I have said
from day one that every agency that was in that hallway has to be accountable
for their actions that day everyone no one will be exempt that includes local
school federal state everyone has to explain their actions that day everybody
has to be accountable these are the kind of mistakes that you can't afford to
make in this job if you want to know why all you need to do is look at the
memorial