Space, but without a spacesuit. A horrifying scenario.
First, the gases in your lungs and bloodstream expand.
Water will begin to boil and evaporate throughout your body, causing your skin and organs to stretch.
As your body swells, your circuitry system is still strong enough to keep your blood pressurized a bit longer.
It also provides enough oxygen for your brain to remain conscious for about 15 seconds.
However, within two minutes, you'll most likely die of asphyxiation.
If there are stars nearby, unfiltered solar radiation turns your dead body into a crisp.
However, in cold, deep space far away from stars, your body won't freeze immediately.
Thanks to the vacuum of space, you won't lose heat via convection or conduction, so it takes some time to get frozen.
Without oxygen and water and under extreme temperatures, your lifeless body wouldn't decompose the way it does on Earth,
and you could float unchanged through the emptiness of space for millions of years.
All in all, it's safe to say it's not a good idea to be in.