good morning my friends welcome to sj weekly what is this the sixth the seventh i forgot it
um but it's for august 5th 2018 and uh listen to this
that is the sound of a delicious morning coffee and yeah yeah i'm kind of a coffee
fag i i definitely like to uh indulge in a in a morning coffee it's one of the few
pleasures left in life it seems um but let's start with on the washington post and i'm actually
doing this incognito mode because they don't like ad blocker which i did finally get and they don't
like the fact that i've looked at too many articles on their site this month even though
it's only been five fucking days so is your spin class too young too thin and too white
the epitome of first world problems as boutique exercise studios expanded a rapid clip some are
questioning who's welcome after a few committed months of hot yoga at a studio in new york
christina rice had found her niche so when the studio announced that it was offering teacher
training she signed right up it was only when she arrived with her mat that she noticed something
striking there were 54 other women and men in the 10-week course and not one of them looked
like her she was the lone african-american in the class i did bond with some of the other students
says rice but i did feel very isolated at times there were no teachers of color i didn't have
another woman who looked like me who understood my struggles my insecurities it's it's just
fucking yoga dude do you really need to to be performing yoga of color this really sounds like
an entitled frankly rich black woman complaining that there aren't more entitled rich black women
for her to hang out with if you went to like any of the united states's poor black population
they would laugh this woman out of the hood boutique workout studios specialized exercise
specific gyms are exploding in gentrifying urban areas well maybe that's why you don't see many
black people there they include not only hot yoga but also crossfit which is everywhere berry's
boot camp soul cycle or orange theory they are the modern answer to the sprawling soulless gym
which insists on financial commitment but doesn't really care whether you actually work out in the
boutique world you make reservations you're greeted with smiles you're served an ice-cold
glass of the spin class is self-care kool-aid this really sounds like somebody who who just
couldn't make it at a regular gym gyms can be sprawling and they can be soulless but they
require you to be the engine not some kind of external force the point of a gym is that you go
and work out and you have to push yourself to work out and if you're incapable of pushing yourself to
lift those weights and you need something like say a boutique workout studio where you have
somebody leading you in the exercise you know of course if you want to pay your money and go do
that it's it's you're right right but this really sounds like it's looking down its nose at gyms and
by extension the people that can actually self-motivate and here's where we can see that
having a leader in your exercise is actually a privilege but some people have begun to question
the stark differences between the studios and the neighborhood ymca like the prices in washington
a single 50-minute barry's boot camp class is 34 spinning studio flywheel charges 30 solid core can
run as much as 37 or about half the cost of a monthly membership in most urban gyms that's
because these places come with trainers built into them if you go to a gym with a trainer it's going
to be a lot more expensive than if you just go to a gym and follow a workout that you found on fit
or something and like rice other fitness junkies have begun to notice who isn't coming sweat
through a class in one of these studios and it's very possible that you'll see it many many lith
young white bodies and few people of color or older or heavier exercisers maybe it's because
as you said this is happening in young white gentrifying areas maybe it's because a privilege
that only rich white kids can afford maybe maybe it's because older people generally don't want to
take care of themselves or at least not in this manner usually old people don't work out or if
they do work out they go to gyms but long who is african-american and hispanic is struck by what
she sees there what is their messaging saying about aging what is fit what is beauty i look at
everything from the signage to the marketing materials and all she sees are millennials how
open and inclusive is that well i mean what do you want to do do you want to force old black people
at gunpoint to come to these these gyms stanley who has gained some fame with her criticisms of
boutique workout and yoga culture's lack of diversity describes the studio she has visited
outside the big city bubble as anything but diverse she tackles the subject in her book
everybody yoga the issue she says extends beyond race i definitely want to find a copy of this book
now oh there's actually an amazon link well i'm not gonna pay for it um she's often the only fat
woman in the room as well she says and if you're looking for a mature crowd you have to keep looking
too by the health club association's reckoning the average age of studio exercisers is 30
the messaging says stanley is essentially you're allowed in the space if you're white slender able
body and less than 45 cisgender and heterosexual and if you're not then you're not welcome except
stanley you look like somebody who is none of those things and obviously you're attending
these studios maybe it's not that people aren't allowed in these studios maybe it's that they
don't want to go maybe it's that people have the freedom of choice to choose whether they want to
go to an exercise studio or a gym or to just work out at home or to not work out at all maybe it's
not a race and gender issue and maybe you don't need to make everything a race and gender issue
okay this is stupid i'm moving on to the next article uh i skimmed the rest of this off camera
and it's all literally just the same bullshit blaming white people because black people don't
want to attend these ridiculous fucking studios okay i'm done well maybe if those minorities had
more money in their pockets they would attend those studios but it turns out that might not be
the case finland's basic income test wasn't ambitious enough the payments encourage
beneficiaries to take work that doesn't pay a living wage kela the finnish social security agency
has failed to secure the funding it needs to extend its universal basic income experiment
beyond this year although it's sad that this grand leftist idea is suffering yet another setback
finland's trial effort deserved its fate before the experiment was approved by the government in
2016 kela officials talked about paying 800 euros or 974 a month in unconditional income to test a
group of working age citizens but by the time the program began early last year the amount was
whittled down to 560 euros if extended to the whole country the cost of the earlier proposal
would have exceeded the finnish government's entire revenue a similarly impractical approach
led to the failure of a 2016 swiss referendum on offering a payout of 2500 swiss francs it's almost
like if you keep giving away people's money for nothing you will run out of money it's all but
impossible to live on 560 euros in finland a one-bedroom apartment on the outskirts of helinski
rents for almost that much so the experiment's designer settled on not really paying the ubi to
the unemployed who kept a higher level of government support at least 32.4 euros a day
for the first 400 days after losing a job only the working poor would benefit significantly from it
i'm sure that you and i know that the reason this failed is because you can't just throw money at
problems and hope they go away there is definitely a problem with with grinding poverty there's
definitely a problem with people not being able to get an education or start a business or do what
they want to do with their lives but you can't just mindlessly throw gobs of cash and expect
the problem to fix itself but i have a feeling that this article i haven't i haven't read the
whole thing yet but i have a feeling that the slant is going to take is that they didn't give
enough money not that the idea of the ubi is inherently flawed finland has a low employment
rate for a rich country just 71% of the working age population compared to 77% in neighboring
sweden and almost 86 percent in iceland so the idea was to provide an incentive for the
unemployed to step into the job market even if it meant taking on part-time or badly paid work
the other goal was to simplify finland's complex system of housing child care and other benefits
by replacing them with the lump sum payment i don't know if giving people money for nothing
is going to incentivize them to take on part-time or badly paid work you know the the point of
something like a ubi is to one rescue people in grinding poverty who just cannot who have
nothing zero just can't get ahead because they have no base with which to start and two it's
to assist people in you know if they're if they're working something like part-time work or badly paid
work it's to assist them into having a buffer so that they can maybe invest in themselves or go
back to school or on the side start their business it's to help ambitious people however this article
and in general ubi supporters seem to assume that all people are ambitious people which is just not
the case the ubi is not going to get people into part-time or badly paid work it's designed to get
ambitious people without resources out of that work keela is not promising to release any results
of the experiment nobody's surprise there which involves 2 000 people until the end of 2019 or
even the beginning of 2020 but it was clear from the start that a basic income even such a low one
is an extremely expensive way to boost precarious forms of employment at 550 euros a month keela
calculated the ubi would cost 19.3 billion euros a year while the government would only save 3.6
billion euros on existing benefits as for getting people to return to the job market the center-right
cabinet of prime minister uh juha i don't know how to pronounce that juha sapila appears to be
more interested in cost-effective negative motivation for the unemployed than in rewarding
them for finding work that doesn't pay a living wage the government has proposed for example
requiring out-of-work people to apply for at least one job a week to keep receiving benefits unless
they're in job training programs i never i never really thought i'd see the day that i'd be agreeing
with right-leaning politicians or parliaments but that's really how things have been going the past
few years the ubi idea is not dead it's still worth watching other experiments especially the
ones that actually provide a living income these include oakland california which pays two thousand
dollars a month almost exactly the poverty line and the one in kenya which plays 23 a month about
half the average income in the country's rural areas other tests in dutch city of utrecht and
an upcoming one in ontario canada i'll i'll correct you right now that one has actually
ended and has not went well um offer low payouts relative to the living standard but still higher
than in the finished test i don't know the ubi is an answer to the right question but it's the
wrong answer at the very least though they are asking the right questions it's it's not quite
as bad as communists who just don't understand economics proponents of the ubi understand that
at least people need to work and they're saying well how about we just give them some money
and allow them to work on what they want well that's it's it's better than assuming that all
people are the same which is what communism does but it's still it's still not gonna work because
there will be too many people who will just take the money and not work in my opinion um loans or
grants for for school or loans or grants for starting small businesses um that's the way
that we should be going because that will actually provide people who are ambitious but poor
with the resources that they need to actually get their lives going not something like a ubi i still
can't quite tell which way this article is leaning which i guess is actually a good thing at least
it's it's somewhat neutral but uh here's an article that is just straight up parody and i
actually had to read the first couple sentences before i could figure it out um fact all tragedy
happens because of toxic masculinity and lack of communism this is uh during the time that
the mandalay bay shootings happened last year the think peace factory is an overdrive over the
las vegas massacre just about every thought piece you're going to read about las vegas will have one
of two themes about motive the tragedy happened because toxic masculinity which is the feminist
cop-out for everything or the tragedy happened because the lack of full communism in the presence
of white people which is the sociology pre-grad cop-out for everything i'm sure toxic masculinity
is what caused a sextagarian to commit mass murder it's also the reason why my crank case
is habitually low on oil why septa is late and why my hoagie has too few jalapenos in it
the other craptastic category of hot takes is a shitty reduction of economic theory when there are
any study sources they point to fringe theory that's not generally accepted or it's way out
of context or it's just bad quoting and use of stats and this article is basically about
uh shitty clickbait and it actually shows a real a real headline here can a shift in the perception
of masculinity curb mass violence so yeah people actually made made shit like this back when the
the mandalay bay shootings were happening people actually did blame it on toxic masculinity and we
have reached a point where satire of something like this article is nearly indistinguishable
and speaking of satire here's an article that frankly could be read as satire but it's not
women work longer as the men cut their hours now this is not how this originally read they have
changed the title and it used to read this woman work longer hours than men that's all it said
before and they realized that they had kind of fucked up and here's why a nationwide survey of
1600 employees found that women now work almost 34 hours a week on average half a day longer than
the figure of 30.4 hours five years ago over the same five-year period men's average work hours
fell from 45.5 hours per week to 44.8 hours although among the hardest working males the
number putting in more than 49 hours a week has passed the 3 million mark so even as the headline
says women work longer hours than men immediately in the first few paragraphs they contradict that
women now work almost 34 hours a week men's average work hours fell to 44.8 hours there is
no way the headline is in any way reflective of reality which is why the url of the article still
says women work longer hours than men and they changed the headline because they were immediately
found out as the hacks that the daily mail actually are and really if you want an explanation of the
gender pay gap it's right here all right women work 34 hours a week on average men work 44.8
hours a week on average that's a pretty decent explanation don't you think men are working 10
more hours per week on average maybe they're making 10 more hours per week worth of money
on average or here's another reason almost three quarters of those working long hours
that would be mostly men admitted that they were likely to go to work even if they were ill
while two-thirds had gone to the office on public holidays in the past year and a half
and said they would put work ahead of personal commitment well there you go maybe that's the
gender pay gap there's a lot of things that could be the gender pay gap how about this
women are also more likely to be found in relatively poorly paid caring professions than men
pushing down their overall average wages well it's not that women are to be found in these professions
women choose to be in these professions they take these jobs they go to these schools they
choose these careers for themselves but let's keep talking statistics with new hampshire 94 white
asks how do you diversify a whole state this is a ridiculous proposition for multiple reasons
one locations as in wide huge areas of land do not need to be diversified you do not need to push
out people who are currently living there you do not need to to force some kind of intermingling
or race mixing you just let people do what they want to do let them live where they want to live
in fact as i recall pushing out an entire group of people and replacing them with another group
of people even if you don't kill them is still considered to be ethnic cleansing under
international law so why would you want to diversify new hampshire why don't you just
keep it the way it is why don't you allow people to move as they see fit catalina selentano used
to hold trading sessions for hospital workers in lynn massachusetts to familiarize them with
the cultures of patients from cambodia russia and the dominican republic when she moved to
new hampshire she suddenly found herself in an ethnic vacuum well if being in an ethnic vacuum
was that distressing to you why did you move to new hampshire if you wanted to live in the culture
that you were born in and raised in why didn't you stay in the location and with the people from that
culture i went from being able to speak spanish every day to not speaking spanish at all because
there wasn't anybody to speak spanish to you don't get to move to a place and demand everyone
change to suit your needs new hampshire like its neighbors vermont and maine is nearly all white
this has posed an array of problems for new arrivals who often find themselves isolated
and alone without the comfort and support of a built-in community well that's why it's called
a built-in community somebody had to build it and if you're not up to the task of building a
community if you want the government to diversify new hampshire then you need to leave it's that
simple it has also posed problems for employers in these states who find that their homogeneity
can be a barrier to recruiting and retaining workers of different ethnicities and cultural
backgrounds again that's only a problem if you care about ticking off these these ridiculous
boxes on a list if you just hire the best people for the job and don't give a shit about race none
of this matters the issue prompted about a hundred business leaders government officials
and members of non-profit organizations to meet thursday to search for ways that new hampshire
which is 94 white might lure other racial and ethnic groups as well as younger people
maybe they don't explicitly need to do that maybe they just maybe they should just lure people you
know qualified people for the jobs that they have and then see who shows up and if it turns out that
a bunch more white people show up it shouldn't matter diversity quotas are going to be the
downfall of all of these initiatives with non-whites poised to make up a majority of
the american population in the next three decades diversity has become a bottom line imperative for
companies competing for talent especially for workers who can speak other languages man the
way that the term non-whites is used there it's almost the way that the kkk used it like 50 years
ago as it stands new hampshire is three percent latino two percent african-american and three
percent asian the nation as a whole is 17 latino 14 African-American and six percent asian well
that means that states that aren't new hampshire some other states they have a ratio of latinos
that is higher than 17 a ratio of african-americans that is higher than 14 and a ratio of asians that
is higher than six percent and nobody nobody is calling for more white people to be imported to
those states there's no massive call to diversify the latino and black south right now nobody cares
about that shit nobody cares about bringing white people into those states but when when white
people hold a 94 majority you got to start bringing people in it's it's a ridiculous idea
it doesn't matter the race doesn't matter it's not just the social justice groups that are doing this
it's the businesses we're talking about the economic engine of our state and we can't move
forward without them well you know what the businesses are going to tank because of the
social justice bullshit it doesn't sell we know it doesn't sell in fact i was saving this for
for a future video but it's relevant right now so i'll bring it up right now here's here's some bonus
stuff for you okay this is from a study called jumping to conclusions advocacy and application
of psychological research in the politics of social psychology from 2017 the psychologist
advancing implicit bias as the explanation for various societal inequalities and harms
jumped to the conclusion apparently in the sincere belief that the data would eventually support that
conclusion but it has not the accumulated data in fact now shows that measures of implicit bias
provide no more explanatory power than explicit bias even for socially sensitive topics and often
provide less explanatory power there is no reliable link between implicit bias and police
officers and police violence against minorities and there is no reliable link between implicit
bias and employment evaluations or employment outcomes for women and minorities if those behind
applications of implicit bias to the law really are committed to behavioral realism to taking
science seriously and making values secondary to science as they say then they must accept
that implicit bias has not turned out to be the explanatory juggernaut it was
optimistically expected to be despite these now undisputed facts the implicit bias construct
continues to play an influential role in public debates court cases in the making of governmental
and company policy millions of dollars are being spent on untested implicit bias training and
consulting disposing of the mistaken belief that implicit bias is a powerful and pervasive corruptor
of behavior will be slow and difficult now david arback who is an intellectual that i do follow
and read uh semi-regularly he summed this up implicit bias training in such measures were
initially promoted and adopted with the rhetoric of profit diversity is good for business now
they're being seen as financial losers and will be dropped by the same criteria and he's replying to
the tweet that says psychologists admit that by pushing implicit bias they have foisted a big
cash destruction machine on society that won't go away easily whether or not implicit bias is real
bias sure is justifying diversity programs on the grounds of profit margins was highly likely to
backfire but it's created a good deal of leftist corporate sympathy along the way so what does this
all mean uh this means that implicit bias isn't real it's it's most likely not real the idea that
you have some kind of subconscious or subliminal racist or sexist slants even when you try to not
be that person it's it's complete bs and the implicit bias training like the starbucks stuff
and other stuff that we've seen it's all useless and it's basically a giant cash hole and these
businesses thinking that diversity is the way forward have been duped into shoveling millions
and billions of dollars into these giant cash sinks that are basically just going straight to
sjws they're going to like the gender studies people they're going to the implicit bias people
they're going to the to the social justice warriors that that write this junk and promote this junk
and teach this junk and it's going to be a complete fucking nightmare it's already a complete
fucking nightmare but it's going to get worse because as companies realize that this does
nothing and this earns them nothing they're going to basically figure out they've been taken for a
ride you know they've had they have all these diversity hires that are doing nothing in their
companies and in the next decade when they wake up to that fact there's going to be a mass purge
from these companies and that's what's going on here in this article the new hampshire white
diversity article it's not just the social justice groups that are doing this it's the businesses
and they're doing it to their own folly this is going to destroy these businesses and of course
it's coming from the new york times um and we all know what the new york times has done recently
they've they've recently hired a very interesting young woman and i may do something on her this
week but until then i'll see you guys later i love you