This video is kind of a follow-up to a previous video, called consent is deontological. Here's
the TLDR. Consequentialist ethics are basically good is good ends. Deontological ethics are
basically good is good rules. The problem with deontology is that it's not hard to find a
situation where a corrupt set of rules causes evil, hence the idea of the pious churchgoer
hurting others in the name of God. The problem with consequentialism is it's very easy to justify
any sort of evil as long as it's theorized outcome is good, hence the phrase ends justify
the means. And in the video I describe how the concept of consent operates on deontological
ethics. The basic idea is when you give your consent to another person what you're actually
doing is outlining a set of rules almost always informal and unwritten ones but rules nonetheless
that you agree to abide by and this works not only for sexual consent but all types of consent.
Let's say I tell you I'll meet you at the pub at 7 p.m. that is a rule I give you my word I will
be at a place and time and if I breach it I will have failed morally in some small way given that
example but it's still a failure if I arrive at 715 you're justified in being a little annoyed
at me even if you are also late then we're both a little bit at fault let's say that you're late
because your car got hit on the way over and I'm late because I'm a little bit lazy even though the
outcome is the same that we're both late one of us has a greater moral culpability because it's
not only outcomes that matter but intentions as well that's why I made the point in that video
that fundamentally socialists don't care about consent and not simply because the socialist
community colloquially seems to contain more sex pests on average it's also because socialism
contains a disdain for the concept of private contracts or voluntary association or property
ownership or if you're dealing with the really progressive ones stuff like monogamous relationships
or concepts like prudence or honor socialists view your consent as an obstacle in the way of
the socialist project you call it selling out your principles I call it fucking winning and
that's my principle to win as a socialist not to lose as a socialist that's not my principle I
don't give a fuck about principled failure haha bringing it back vosh has been pretty good to me
with this clip I'm not gonna lie but I've been thinking about this idea a little bit more
recently I did that video on Roe v Wade where my position was basically that while I am pro-choice
myself the actual ruling of Roe v Wade was a bad way to implement abortion access it wasn't voted
on by the people of the United States on either the state or federal level rather it was imposed
on the population by the court access to abortion in the USA was gained not by passing legislature
but by bypassing the legislative process altogether using pretty shaky judicial reasoning to do so it's
not the court's job to spin up whole cloth new quasi legislature like Roe v Wade did it's the
court's job to judge whether or not a piece of actually passed legislation violates the
Constitution in other words I recognized that Roe v Wade violated the process and I've had a
few conversations with left-leaning people I'm friendly with in this topic at this point and the
question almost always boils down to the process they asked me why is violating the process so
important to you isn't the outcome good don't you want abortion access to and that's when I realized
yeah I do want abortion access I do think the outcome is good or at least unnecessary evil
definitely a lesser evil than if abortion were just blanket banned but I also realized the process
was important not simply for the sake of the process itself but because the process is the
upon which the consequences rest that's why Roe v Wade is falling apart regardless of how you feel
about how it was constructed the foundation has always been broken and as I was talking about this
with these people I realized that this is the same as the relationship between deontology and
consequentialism understanding that the process needs to be followed in order to create a solid
justification for the outcome is the same as understanding that you need deontological ethics
in order for consequentialist ethics to even make sense I gave the example in that previous video
about consent of the consequentialist atheist arguing with the consequentialist isis member
over whether or not it's ethical to throw gay people off of rooftops the atheist can appeal
to good ends you shouldn't kill people who haven't hurt anybody else being gay isn't bad and the isis
member can appeal to his good ends that's degenerate scrubbing society god is happy as sharia is
fulfilled both of these people are calculating out the best ends but what makes their results
different is that they each begin with a different deontological rule set the isis member is assuming
that killing gays is good a priori while the atheist assuming the opposite and their difference
and consequences are just post-hoc rationalizations there's no reason to assume
that either of them is objectively correct either there's no scientific consensus here the universe
itself doesn't care if the gays are killed or not the atheist might appeal to harm reduction but the
isis member will say that he's reducing harm to society the atheist might appeal to something
akin to the libertarian's non-aggression principle that the gay person didn't make any aggressive
actions toward anybody else simply living in private the isis member well he'll likely
actually say that being gay is itself an aggressive action but if he's smart he'll say that valuing
self-defense and non-aggression is itself subjective and he's under no obligation to
value those things in his calculations it seems like at least to me what is good is what feels
good and i don't mean feels good like it's pleasurable and i don't mean anything like that
i mean it feels like goodness it feels like it is moral and that's way more of a deontological
statement than a consequentialist one it makes sense then that all consequentialist calculations
require a deontological frame that's how you determine what makes good ends good that's why
the atheist and the isis member cannot come to the same conclusion despite both being
consequentialists if consequentialism is the mathematics telling you how to solve a formula
then deontology is the numbers you plug into the formula you're trying to solve they require each
other in a way i've also been thinking about the january 6th riots recently the issue with them
isn't that they were inherently unethical if the election was actually being stolen by a group of
anti-democratic elites then every single thing done on that day and far more would have been
entirely justified what else can you do if your vote's being stolen that's why i don't completely
blame the rioters they still did it there's still a level of culpability there like i said if you
truly believe you're about to lose your government and fall into a dictatorship there's no other
option that's why i don't buy some of the stuff that i hear coming out of the broader left right
now about how all the rioters were these evil fascist insurrectionists or whatever the issue
ultimately is was it actually being stolen i know that a lot of people who watch this channel
genuinely believe that it was they believe that the institutions were corrupted the votes were
rigged everybody was deep state agents operating to get rid of trump the whole thing at this point
i'm kind of on the fence i think the election was actually probably legit but if decisive evidence
dropped tomorrow that it wasn't i wouldn't be surprised for the sake of this conversation
though we're assuming that the election was completely valid trump lost fair and square
and that trump was not just a bumbling doofus who didn't know how much damage he was causing
or an egomaniac who huffed his own copium to the point that he also believed he won and was
unjustly being ousted but that trump was actually a budding dictator who knew he had lost and didn't
care because he a priori considered his victory to be more important than the vote assume that
for this conversation i know it's hard you can do it the democratic process is arguably the most
important institution in u.s history trump was fighting tooth and nail to undermine that
institution from poisoning the well on mail-in ballots months before the vote to saying to his
supporters we gotta march up there take back our country you don't fight like hell you're not gonna
have a country anymore we're going to try and give them the kind of pride and boldness that
they need to take back our country and admittedly yes also saying we need to peacefully make our
voices heard which to be fair is pretty good cover for his rhetoric i know that everyone here will
soon be marching over to the capitol building to peacefully and patriotically make your voices
heard they're calling up various governors saying you gotta find me more votes all i want to do is
this i just want to find uh 11 780 votes which is one more that we have to putting his own vice
president on blast when he refused to violate the procedure and crown trump president in other words
trump's behaviors and rhetoric tried to undermine the institutions of the united states at multiple
points and created an environment where average people believe the only possible redress they
had for their grievances if trump didn't win the election was political violence so if we assume
that one like i said before trump's actually a budding dictator not a copium huffer or a doofus
and two the institutions of the united states were not actually corrupted and were functioning as
intended then trump was acting in an ends justify the means worst case consequentialist scenario the
institutions of the united states are a deontological process maybe not in a moral
sense but certainly in a bureaucratic one the idea is no matter what the outcome is no matter who
wins the election we follow this process we follow these rules and it is the following of
these rules that makes that win that outcome legitimate and trump's undermining of public
trust in those institutions works to delegitimize those rules that process if it turns out that
trump wasn't actually a budding dictator and the institutions were functioning the situation is
mostly the same trump is just delusional instead but what if trump's not a budding dictator and
the institutions were actually broken like he claimed they were well then we get into that
what if the rules are bad critique of the deontological view deontology's great weakness
is that there's no easy way to reform the rules you have to rely on examining the ends to see if
the rules are fit for purpose which seems to track if evidence came out tomorrow that decisively
proved the election was actually stolen from trump the only proper thing to do would be to screw the
rules and give him his second term but even then that's not fully appealing to the ends in a sense
the end is trump gets what's rightfully his but it's that rightfully his part that is still an
appeal to deontology the process was corrupted but we still appeal to the process as it should
have functioned the rules were bad therefore we should have been following these good rules
by the way as for what i actually believe at this point i'm pretty sure that trump actually
huffed on his own copium too much i don't think he was a dictator with a plan to overthrow the
election while knowing full well he had lost it i think he genuinely believes it was stolen from
him just like his supporters genuinely believe it he's egotistical and probably delusional but not
a fascist one last thing too there's a lot of progressive radicals who are ultra democracy
cucked right now and fair enough but they take it way too far they scream about why is the electoral
college a thing why is the senate a vote by land and not by people why are judges not voted on why
isn't everything at all times voted on by everybody but you know what it's not democracy that gave
trump the ultimate pushback i guarantee i would put money on this there are absolutely republican
elected officials who inwardly think that trump is fucked up but they don't dare say it publicly
because they know that he's electorally popular among the right right now these people are bound
not to the truth or the good but to the popular that's the point of democracy and we've seen the
inverse too whenever trump did anything good during his presidency every single person on
the left bent themselves into fucking knots trying to play it up as evil because that's what was
popular for their electorate trump received his hardest pushback from people in appointed
positions judges and cabinet members who were aligned with him politically but didn't need to
worry about reelection and could investigate his claims with a more unbiased eye that too is
ultimately part of the process part of the institution and is deontological in how it
functions even william fucking bar trump's attorney general who spent a good chunk of
his term with his nose right up trump's asshole came out and said that there was no irregularities
in the election that would have changed its outcome he wasn't voted on he was appointed
that's not to say that appointed people can't be corrupted in other ways they certainly can
but they can't be corrupted by following the fickle whims of an electorate and that's what
makes a good process a good deontological code it has different conflicting components that all have
different strengths and weaknesses not everything in the u.s government is democratic because it
would be entirely at the whims of the weaknesses of democracy but you still need some democracy in
there because democracy's strengths cover the weaknesses of a fully appointed system too as i
said before trump set it up such that people would feel like their only course of redress if he
didn't win was political violence the point of liberal democratic institutions is to increase
the amount of space between somebody having a legitimate grievance and somebody resorting to
violence to redress that grievance in a liberal society there are many different non-violent ways
to redress a grievance you can compromise with people privately to secure a solution
you can take them to court you can run for office or vote for candidates who will implement changes
that help your situation you can speak out publicly and draw more people to your cause
you don't have to resort to violence except in the most extreme circumstances all anti-liberals
regardless of political stripe have one big thing in common their desire to reduce the amount of
space between having a legitimate grievance and having to resort to violence to solve it
not just trump on the right saying stuff that we got to take our country back but how many
leftists have you heard this phrase from i do feel like we engage in very very selective phony
outraged political violence depending on how angry we are the people who are advocating for it
politics is violence the fact by the way the only i also hate this i hate this um i hate when he
um does this shit where he says like um politics is violence like
it's such a stupid equivocation okay politics is violence what do you mean by that fosh that's
actually an anarchist phrase and both left and right anarchists use it the idea behind it is
that all conflict is necessarily violent and the idea of a non-violent conflict is a liberal
delusion if i don't like what you're doing i could kill you to make you stop or i could vote with
100 other people that you must stop and then if you don't give in to us then we kill you and our
killing of you is legitimized because a democratic apparatus did it but it's the same thing in the
end when you hear the phrase politics is violence or voting is violence what is being said by the
anarchist is that the result is the same regardless of what process produces the result aka the
consequences are the same regardless of what deontological principle leads to them for a person
to actually say this though they have to have never experienced real violence yeah it might be
the case that you have a great idea for society but the electorate disagrees with you and then
they outvote you and then society gets measurably worse as a result that sucks that might even be
violence on you because you didn't ask for this worst situation it was imposed on you by their
shitty inferior ideas but is it worse violence than them directly killing you i don't think so
and i don't think that anybody who's ever experienced true violence in the flesh would
ever make that claim there's two competing schools of classical liberal thought one that man is
naturally good in its society that makes him evil and two that man is naturally evil in its society
that makes him good if the first position were true then dismantling every single institution
would lead to a better world but considering the failure of all types of anarchism and our
current successes despite all of our problems i don't think that's true if the second position
were true that society's institutions make us good then how do we explain a totalitarian state that
grinds down all within it or an oppressive indifferent bureaucracy lost within its own
procedures these clearly don't create good people either but these are the bad rules of
a failed deontological system that doesn't mean that every deontological system is a failure
doesn't mean that good rules can't exist somewhere i don't exactly know where i'm going with this
most of this video has been a ramble these are kind of new ideas to me i've been thinking up
and frankly i've been gone for a while i needed something to put out it seems like to me a
prosperous liberal society is one that is democratic but not too democratic that allows for
the individual to override the democratic will in some important matters but not all of them that
doesn't chase good ends for the sake of building a utopia but instead grounds those good ends in
adhering to good rules and constantly updates what constitutes a good rule by examining what
kind of ends they produce a liberal society must simultaneously be deontological and consequentialist
it must be democratic but also have areas of life where the democratic will has no say the
liberal principles of universal standards and rule of law consent and voluntary action privacy
and individuality these are deontological principles liberal institutions must be
deontological because the consequentialism of liberal people is legitimized by that foundation