Are your friends more popular than you are?
They are, at least on average.
That's what science says.
The weird thing is that the same applies to most of your friends.
But how can that be?
It takes some maths to prove this paradox,
but simply put, it's just very likely that you're friends with someone who has a lot of friends.
For this example, let's say Duck is that friend.
Although people like Duck are rare,
they have so many friends that they change the expected average.
Pick a random person in your friend group and ask them how many friends their friends have.
Chances are high that those friends are friends with the popular Duck.
That way, the many friends of Duck contribute to the average more often,
nudging it up slightly.
You'll find this in your maths books as weighted average.
The result?
Most people in your group have fewer friends than their typical friend.
So you might feel weird about this, but the same will happen to most people.
The only question left is,
are you the popular friend or...