oh god oh my god you guys i accidentally deleted my libs of tiktok file i've been saving little
tidbits of info for months as i do you know i do this if you ever watched a video or stream where
i described my work process i figured it was finally time to do the video now that the whole
taylor lorenz thing is going on went to grab my file and it was gone and the worst part is i'm
pretty sure i just mindlessly deleted it when clearing out some old stuff because it was right
near the stuff i was deleting well that's what i get for being a boomer and keeping everything on
my desktop i guess but you know what maybe it's not so bad i think i can recreate everything i
had saved up well enough let's give it a shot before we can talk about taylor lorenz we have
to talk about libs of tiktok libs of tiktok is a twitter account that began with the gimmick of
dredging up especially cringy progressive and socialist videos on tiktok and reposting them
with limited or no commentary cue me getting angry at americans using the word liberal incorrectly
for the billionth time but you know whatever we all know what's going on at the beginning libs of
tiktok functioned a lot like the various posting their ells accounts these accounts would provide
little to no commentary of their own simply reposting other people's content the idea is
that while the audience of the original posters of that content would be supportive of the message
the audience of the ells account wouldn't be the ells account would therefore act as a quasi expose
even though the content they post is entirely public and accessible to anyone and the value
would come not through adding commentary but providing the content to an audience that is
explicitly poised against it now if you were to ask the question why is reposting other people's
content bad the surface level answer is of course you're stealing content without reacting to it
that's what i bitched at on efap for three weeks in a row recently regarding hasan go watch that
if you like but while hasan outright steals content wholesale playing it for a stream while
providing no additional commentary and no citation the courts have ruled that reposting content while
adding no additional commentary with the intention that the content nonetheless be seen in a
different light because it's being transmitted to a different audience by a different person
constitutes a transformative use that's the whole reason that sargon won his lawsuit against akila
obviously so since this sort of thing actually isn't theft what's the next level answer to the
question why is reposting other people's content bad and the progressive answer seems to be that
it has to be bad because while twitter and tiktok and other platforms don't ban the original posters
of the content they have banned some of the most infamous ells accounts like trans women posting
their ells e-girls posting their ells and vosh fans posting their ells you call it selling out
your principles not not today not this time even though these accounts also simply reposted content
while adding only some of their own commentary they all eventually got nuked from orbit by
twitter presumably because the act of shining a spotlight on the bad behavior of members of
protected classes or people who are politically correct just brings too much heat down on the
platform libs of tiktok for a long time managed to ride that line of culpability perfectly and
so they didn't get a quick ban like those other accounts that i mentioned the libs of tiktok
account was previously several other gimmick accounts tweeting about kuomo at one point and
then as a potted plant in the white house at another but the whole reposting people's manic
rants with no comment thing went viral repeatedly so that was the gimmick that stuck but like its
brethren libs of tiktok would eventually fly too close to the sun though the account posted all
sorts of leftist content initially libs of tiktok eventually focused in on posting videos made by
teachers in the context of florida's don't say gay bills where left-leaning teachers openly mocked
the liberal idea of neutrality in education defied the parents of children who may have been
lgbt questioning hey if your parents don't love and accept you for who you are this christmas
fuck them i'm your parents now i'm proud of you drink some water i love you bye advocated for the
position of pedophiles or as they call minor attracted persons um i use the term minor
attracted person or map in the title and throughout the book for multiple reasons
first of all because i think it's important to use terminology for groups that members of that group
want others to use for them and map advocacy groups like before you act have advocated for
use of the term map they've advocated for it primarily because it's less stigmatizing than
other terms like pedophile a lot of people when they hear the term pedophile they automatically
assume that it means a sex offender and that isn't true and it leads to a lot of misconceptions
about attractions toward minors i've definitely heard the idea that you brought up though that
the use of the term minor attracted person suggests that it's okay to be attracted to
children but using a term that communicates who someone is attracted to that doesn't indicate
anything about the morality of that attraction here's mocking that liberal idea of neutrality
again these people don't believe in the idea of an ideology free space where ideas can be formed
and tested to the conservative news source that wrote an article about me that seemed really
focused on the flags i have in my classroom um there's a couple of things you missed actually
in here the first thing you missed is all 13 principles of the black lives matter movement
hung up at the top of my wall here because i want my students to know that flag is not just
a decoration but that we actually live out these principles in our everyday life you definitely
missed my smaller posters including this one about getting vaccinated about voting all these ones i
have from jay salazar that are black historical figures man you missed a lot including some of
the memorabilia and awards i've won as michigan teacher of the year but like go off about my flags
talking to toddlers about intersex for some reason here's a developmentally appropriate way to talk
to toddlers about bodies and gender you know the body parts that your diaper or your panties
or your underwear cover those are called privates everyone has privates private means that they
belong to you and only you in the front everybody has genitals but there are different kinds of
genitals some genitals are called a penis some are called a vulva others look maybe a little bit
like each in some ways or kind of like neither or somewhere in between
people with those kind of genitals are called intersex when babies are born parents sometimes
guess their gender based on their genitals they tend to guess boy for babies who have a penis
and girl for babies who have a vulva sometimes parents guess wrong though and that's okay
everybody makes mistakes sometimes people whose parents guessed wrong about their gender are
called transgender and here's apologia for enthusiastic consent for children having sex
with adults also if young people are initiating sexual activities with adults or enthusiastically
involved we can't be effective in working with them if we assume that all such relationships
start with a predatory or criminally inclined inclined adult the as we're seeing in the
discussion young people bridle at being forced into this box of being seen as being the victim
of a predator i can actually keep this list going for a very long time literally just scroll down
the libs of tiktok account yourself if you want to see these clips there's got to be hundreds at
this point but as more and more teachers started making tiktok videos about the various ways in
which they were subverting the system libs of tiktok found more and more success shining a
spotlight on these people the account was so successful that tucker carlson gave it a shout
out on april 8th so in classrooms amaze.org isn't even necessary a lot of times some teachers do
the jobs themselves we know that in part because the hard work of a twitter account called libs of
tiktok which you ought to follow before it's banned if you want to know what may be happening
in your child's school libs of tiktok just unearthed this video shows a teacher bragging
to her students about her sex life little kids watch man y'all thought me uh teaching the children
about me being poly was crazy but not only that but they also know that i'm gender fluid
this was all well and good until october when i also explained to them that i'm pagan so i am
also a witch and i come into work and one of the children goes lois are you a boy you have short
hair and his sister goes no lois is a girl and a third child who's my favorite suddenly yells no
guys we've been over this lois isn't a boy or a girl lois is a witch so underneath all of this
needless to say and you can't say it enough is narcissism it's about me and my identity and my
journey it's not about you or your children teaching them anything it's about me let me talk
about me some more and by april 13th libs of tiktok had been brigaded and spam reported causing
twitter to temporarily ban the page for 12 hours the violation was hateful conduct even though
like i said before all they really did was repost and spotlight other people's stuff but the whole
thing really blew up with taylor lorenz the libs of tiktok account maintained its anonymity since
its creation as the creator has stated that they didn't want to be publicly known since they feared
backlash but taylor lorenz for some reason began to suspect christina pushaw the press secretary of
governor ron disantis as being involved with the account acting like every other scumbag reporter
lorenz emailed pushaw with extremely short notice hoping to be able to publish a line that would
read something like pushaw did not respond for comment because that looks a lot worse than it
actually is but pushaw did respond and also mocked lorenz publicly for the underhanded tactics
lorenz's reply read will note that you declined to comment on your relationship with the account
which was also mocked because the only relationship pushaw has with the libs of tiktok account is
liking the tweets in the end lorenz's article in the washington post would drop on april 19th in
which she described digging through archived versions of the libs of tiktok account or rather
she just took the digging that travis brown did a software developer but the research spanned back
to the white house potted plant gimmick the kuomo gimmick and even earlier where it was discovered
that the account was first known as shaya underscore ray and the owner publicly identified
herself as a real estate investor in brooklyn as shy array the account live tweeted from the january
6th capital riots claiming to have been in attendance the account's display name was chaya
raychick and when the website libs of tiktok.us was registered it was done so under that legal
name the phone number that website is registered to is also the same number attached to chaya
raychick's business profile in real estate when lorenz called the number she was hung up on and
when lorenz visited the address attached this information in la the woman at the door refused
to identify herself but the libs of tiktok account would later post a picture of lorenz through the
bars of a front door stating which of my relatives did you enjoy harassing the most at their homes
yesterday hey chaya is this you okay joking aside on the one hand i don't like this tendency of the
media to hunt down people with the incorrect political opinions and badger them at their
places of residence like this it reminds me of when cnn got so booty blasted they threatened
to dox a reddit user by the name of han asshole solo for making fun of cnn with a trump gift back
in the day but on the other hand keep in mind libs of tiktok does sometimes do comparable things they
expose the real faces and sometimes the real workplaces of the people that they put up for
display and libs of tiktok does it because they disagree with their politics both of them from
their own points of view believe they're doing the right thing and both of them consider some
form of doxing or public exposure or whatever you want to call it justified because of the actions
of their political opponents the question you have to ask though is it justified the person behind
the libs of tiktok account believes they're exposing groomers and saving kids and if that's
the case then there's probably a solid argument but taylor lorenz believes that the libs of tiktok
account is actively harming lgbt youth getting innocent teachers suspended and fired instituting
a witch hunt and if that's true that's also a solid argument against it so i guess we need to
find out which of these interpretations is true if either of them may be examining lorenz's claims
about the libs of tiktok account will help out claim one regarding tyler wren tyler wren a
former english teacher in oklahoma posted a video telling lgbtq kids shunned by their parents that
wren was proud of them and loved them it was featured on libs of tiktok last week since being
featured on the page wren has been barraged with harassment and death threats now this is a video
that we watched earlier and lorenz's description of the video's content is missing some key context
hey if your parents don't love and accept you for who you are this christmas fuck them i'm your
parents now i'm proud of you drink some water i love you bye lorenz excludes the part of the
clip where wren says i'm your parents now the clip's inclusion on the libs of tiktok page plays
into the rightest conception of the culture war to be sure but the exclamation that teachers should
supplant the parental role plays into the leftist conception of the culture war as well something
that lorenz left out in her claim claim too that libs of tiktok posted a video of a woman teaching
sex education to children in kentucky calling the woman in the video a predator again this isn't
entirely accurate here's what the actual thread looks like the first post reads this woman is
running a sexy summer camp for children in kentucky she says she thinks it's good for
toddlers to masturbate with this accompanying video clip that's how we should you know like get
down with yourself explore your own body masturbation is really healthy and i recommend it to people of
all ages all ages as soon as my nephews could talk they were doing that that's what they were doing
kids touch themselves kids start to ask questions and we teach them the language for their bodies
right that's your nose touch your nose show aunt t you can touch your nose but my sister's not
saying that when they're tugging at their penis right but it feels good right we have to learn
ways to talk to young people about this so that they know how to explore their body consensually
so that it's not in public right we don't want people exploring their bodies in public that's
not consensual but exploring your body at any age grandma's grandpa's all of us need to be exploring
our body the second post reads i work with the school systems my job was not to teach sex ed i
try to figure out ways to work this into the schools this woman is a predator so lorenz was
correct libs of tiktok did indeed call her a predator but lorenz left out all of the context
of exactly what was happening at this kentucky sexy summer camp and by the way the camp was
independently investigated separate from the whole libs of tiktok story by chris rufo writing for
city journal where he describes a non-profit coalition called sexy sex ed which organized a
series of sexy summer camp events targeted towards minors that included lessons on
sex liberation gender exploration bdsm being a sex worker self-managed abortions and sexual
activity while using licit and illicit drugs sexy sex ed's publicly available event calendar lists
the following classes and workshops sex with me self-pleasure workshop gender diversity let's talk
about sex sexy trans sex ed the three p's pee poop pee poop and pleasure sex on drugs and eugenics
and appalachia keep in mind this is a camp for teenagers going as young as 13 and hey while i
might have been jerking off at 13 women like this were the last thing on my mind as i was doing it
claim three that libs of tiktok was leaning hard into groomer discourse calling for any teacher
who comes out as gay to their students to be fired on the spot and yes that's actually exactly what
the tweet says here is the accompanying video so today i came out to my students here's a little
story so in my fifth grade classroom we have a unit where we talk about identity and how
people identify and we talk about traditions and customs that are handed down from ancestors
and things like that so i modeled for the kids today how i identify myself and in doing so i
told them that i identify as a mom as a sister and a daughter as a teacher i said and i identify as
a cis woman and i explained what that was because they had no idea what i was talking about and then
i said and i identify as gay in my 17 years of teaching i've never come out to my kids before
and i was so nervous to even say it out loud to them but they didn't even bat an eye it was really
awesome when i was in grade five that year was the first sex ed course we had and it dealt with
physical biological reproduction how it works in plants and bugs and various types of animals and
humans the social component of sex and puberty waited until grades six and seven what this
person is describing is not only the social component of sex but identity from an intersectional
framework and the intersectional lens is inherently political i didn't get into this
type of stuff until first year gender studies at university to me this seems like it's too much for
grade five it's not abusive it's not grooming but certainly inappropriate for the age range claim
four that libs of tiktok pushed the false conspiracy theory that schools were installing
litter boxes and bathrooms for students who identify as cats and yep i don't even need to
confirm this one i went over this in a weekly set myself that one felt a bit too funny to be true
no matter how accepted furries might be nowadays this is an l for libs of tiktok they got this one
wrong and claim five that libs of tiktok thinks learning about lgbt identities and issues is
abusive and that public schools are government-run indoctrination camps again the quotation is
correct but lorenz leaves out the included video where the teacher in question has set up a
preschool pride parade
acclimating kids to political activism before they even know what politics is does seem to be a form
of indoctrination to me most of the allegations that taylor lorenz levies against libs of tiktok
follows this pattern she gets some stuff right but she purposefully leaves out the context that
is the most damning to her position it is also probably important to talk about which popular
libs of tiktok posts that lorenz just straight up ignores even though they too are an important part
of the account's story like for example a new york state university professor's comments on
adult sexual activity with babies there's a couple things to say here one is even if you are looking
for a threshold let's say there's a threshold i'm making this number up but let's say it's at age
eight um still that tells you that some adult child sex is permissible second the notion that
it's wrong even with a one-year-old is not quite obvious to me there are reports in some cultures
of grandmothers fellating their the baby boys to calm them down when when a colicky now i don't
know if it's true but this is sort of widely reported as occurring in in at least one culture
and it working that the grandmothers believe believe this actually works if this were to be
true again i don't know it to be true if it were to be true it's hard to see what would be wrong
so yeah i guess i think no i don't think there's a blanket period beyond which this is permissible
if we're interested in willing participation which is the way i structured it then yeah there's
a point below which people aren't willing participants in anything because they don't
have intentions or they don't have the sort of mental states that allow for willing participation
but no i don't i don't think it's blanket wrong at any age where a medical student who admitted
to purposefully missing a person's vein and taking delight in jabbing them with the needle
twice after the patient laughed at her pronoun pin or the theater that advertised the family
sex show a theater show which opens up conversations around relationships offering
safe and positive learning to children young people and guardians about bodies and relationships
the show is advertised to families with young kids where the kids can come to learn about sex
masturbation all with fully nude actors on stage
some tickets to the show or you might just be wondering why we thought making it was a good
idea great question um we wanted to make something that uh came at the topic of relationships and sex
in a light way um in a way that would open conversations in a way that would encourage
people to ask questions um and to allow for that space of vulnerability and not knowing and making
mistakes um we hope that the show kind of adds to the more creative or alternative relationships
in sex education that is out there at the moment in all different forms and i guess we really
wanted to make the show that we wish that we'd had when we were younger and also part of our
adult selves felt like or feels like they need now as well um and mostly if we know our bodies then
we know our rights hello my name is ailey i'm programming and engagement manager at
tobacco factory theaters i am a white female with brown blonde hair and my pronouns are she her
family sex show is a fun and playful show for adults and children aged five and up it offers
an honest human sex education that is feminist queer non-binary inclusive and sex positive this
show can allow audiences of all ages to feel confident about their bodies their boundaries
and their sexual health and we really hope to see you here this is all stuff that your average
politically disengaged normie would see and immediately think what the fuck is happening
over there this is some crazy deranged pedo shit it's all stuff that libs of tik tok has rightfully
called out and it's all stuff that lorenz ignored in her expose because it doesn't fit the narrative
that she wanted to spin and it's not like lorenz is somehow innocent either she's got a history
of doing this sort of crybully back during the whole claudia conway shit show which was a part
of my video about people getting more conservative as they age it turned out that it was taylor
lorenz that even turned that into a story she had befriended the 15 year old daughter of kellyanne
conway encouraged her to make the tik tok videos that eventually went viral and then amplified
those tik toks when they came out on her own platform using them as fodder for anti-trump news
articles you know when a woman who's three times the age befriends a 15 year old and then pushes
her into making expose videos on her high profile parents also she can take them and turn around
and boost her own career that sounds like it might be grooming and that's not the only time that taylor
lorenz has done this sort of thing when she got a whiff that tech entrepreneur mark anderson used
the arcelor i'm assuming that's retard in an online chat room she rushed to tweet about it
for even confirming it was accurate information once it came out that it was fake news lorenz
issued a correction but what the fuck dude why did she feel the need to speed run over to twitter
and drop the news like a tattletale maybe the career boost of being the reporter who scalped
mark anderson mattered more to her than you know actually being accurate in august 2020 lorenz
published another expose this time about the company influences.com run by influencer talent
agent aradna jacob the company specializes in promoting influencers and content creation houses
a cancerous business model if ever heard one but lorenz claimed with no proof in her expose
that jacob leaked nude images of influencers working under her and exploited them in other ways
while simultaneously failing to disclose her relationship with jacob's competitor the united
talent agency jacob filed suit in august 2021 against lorenz and the new york times her then
employer but lorenz was already spinning up the victim machine months earlier where in reply to
jacob's allegations she tweeted out on march 9 2021 it's not an exaggeration to say that the
harassment and smear campaign i've had to endure over the past year has destroyed my life no one
should have to go through this bitch you golden parachuted your way out of the times over to
bezos's newsletter don't pretend your life is ruined it's exactly the opposite your target had
the gall to fight back you didn't get your clean victory and now you're taking offense that they
didn't just lay over and die and offer up their corpse for your nourishment because it turns out
that this was not taylor lorenz's first rodeo a taylor lorenz posting her ells account on twitter
was quickly made outlining all of the shit that she's done over the years jesus um these gimmick
accounts are getting really specific aren't they here's a scatter shot of some of the dumb shit
she's pulled over the years she has in no particular order falsely claimed that the judge
report is harassing her which was later refuted by drudge asked people to stop investigating her
public statements as a public figure saying that it makes her feel uncomfortable complained about
the bourgeois billionaire elite ruling class while simultaneously acting as their foot soldier and
megaphone and i think when we think about free speech we have to think about whose speech is
free right dox the mother of an instagram star for apparently hating muslims while crying about how
the blowback of publishing that article led to her apparently being doxed and harassed out of
her apartment screeched about being stalked when her book account got followed by the stalker and
how much anxiety and stress it causes her to have these boundaries crossed even though she of course
showed up at libs of tiktok's house there's been a bunch of smaller data points not on the lorenz
l's account to consider as well for example lorenz's investigations of the person behind
libs of tiktok led to her contacting an unrelated person with the same name and that person was
shortly after dog piled the internet archive has decided to exclude lorenz's twitter account from
the wayback machine despite the archive's stated mission to provide universal access to all
knowledge after the archive started turning up blanks lorenz's twitter account went from having
16 800 tweets to only 3500 back in january of 2022 lorenz posted a video explaining why it's
bad when the media dox is a person who is a private figure without getting a statement from them
a bunch of people are asking if i'm going to write about the west home caleb story no i'm on book
leave i can't keep writing pieces for the new york times i literally do have a lot of deadlines
but journalists who are writing about it please speak to people with experience and online
harassment i'm not gonna lie i've been pretty horrified by a lot of the media coverage of this
a lot of people are just aggregating some of the cruelest commentary online and whipping it all
up into a news story with absolutely no comment from caleb or nuance about the situation the top
story on google yesterday was literally this house beautiful story that dox's caleb puts his full
name in the story zero comment from this man after this whole article gleefully encourages this online
harassment and doxing campaign they literally use him to sell west elm furniture through affiliate
links once again commercializing a harassment and doxing campaign i think the media needs a
total wake-up call in the way that they cover online harassment and this is just the latest
example of it and reporters should be adding nuance not just piling on exactly what she did
to the owner of libs of tik tok um i think it's rare to see an account gain so much prominence
so quickly and be shaping these narratives in such an effective way especially against trans
people um so i was i mean my story was kind of long but i really wanted to make the case like
why this account mattered and i think it's incredibly important you know as someone that
covers the influence or industry to know who is exerting influence in in this way i mean for all
we knew this could have been a foreign actor right or someone we just didn't know and so i thought hey
look this account has massive power massive influence this woman is basically on an entire
right-wing media tour she gave interviews to the new york post tucker all of that um and registered
as a media company uh registered a trademark so yeah i wanted to i i thought it was quite
important and in the public interest to find out who was running it lorenz has given multiple
interviews where she talks about being harassed dox discovered and how absolutely harrowing it is
an online online harassment is such a is such a it's such a misnomer um i think it's a huge
problem because um you know harassment is is a is is it it's a tool to silence people especially
women and people of color people from marginalized um identities for speaking out and it there's a
very intentional like goal behind it it's it's obviously it's death threats and all of that and
rape threats on the daily and it's not just twitter it's like every single surface right like you know
my cell phone number getting out there people calling people harassing my family members
stalking me like all of that is incredibly terrifying and invasive um and it's bled out
into the physical world too which is even more terrifying right yeah but to me i think what
what especially the media needs to understand about this in terms of protecting their own
reporters is this is just a tool like harassment is a tool to kind of discredit and silence
journalists and the right-wing media plays along with it you feel like any little piece of
information that gets out on you will be used by the worst people on the internet to destroy your
life and it's so isolating and terrifying it's horrifying i'm so sorry it's overwhelming it's
really hard and after all of this ridiculous hypocrisy came to light lorenze hit up twitter
once again to talk about how she is the victim in the situation because the general public didn't
like how she docks the person behind libs of tiktok of course the washington post circled
the wagons around her reminding me a lot frankly of the special treatment that sarah john got back
in the day of course the individual behind libs of tiktok also got to speak to tucker carlson live
eventually as well they wanted to intimidate me into silence um and unfortunately for them
that's just never gonna happen well i'm grateful to hear that you're not intimidated were you a
little surprised to see of all people taylor rens who complained bitterly when we used her name on
the air several months ago who whined and cried on television because she had ptsd because people
were criticizing her on the line were you surprised that it was her who came after you
personally and tried to destroy your life yeah i thought that was really humorous i it added a
really nice nice layer of humor on top of the whole story um and i think that the fact that
it was taylor rens who is a known you know hypocrite and keen is known to dogs people
the fact that it was her that was doing all this um it i think it just helped people
rally with support for me have you noticed i mean i know you're not a psychiatrist or perhaps you
are i don't know who you are um but are you surprised that the people who are the most
deeply enmeshed in narcissism who talk about themselves the most are also capable of the
greatest cruelty have you noticed that trend um yes i've noticed that a lot i've noticed it with
a lot of tiktoks as well um i think it's a little bit of a trend it's not like the right was going
to simply let this kind of cultural phenomenon fade away without a fight but that's not really
all that important it's just libs of tiktok doing her own circuit in the media as a victim even if
it's well deserved it's still part of the game lorenz's criticism is that libs of tiktok is a
locus of influence in the culture war this is obviously correct but it's not entirely clear
to me that libs of tiktok is somehow the aggressor or the aggrieved party in this exchange from the
point of view of lorenz libs of tiktok is in the wrong because at the end of the day it's just
politically expedient lorenz's political agenda is better served without a watchdog pointing out the
subversion to the normies however from the point of view of libs of tiktok lorenz is in the wrong
because it's also politically expedient libs of tiktok's political agenda is better served by her
remaining anonymous and unimpeded in exposing subversion but how about from the point of view
of the normies themselves from that position it seems to be the case that lorenz is in the wrong
because the normies would undoubtedly object to a lot of the shit that libs of tiktok exposes
in the counter argument that libs of tiktok just takes things out of context and that with the
proper context normies would be more accepting of what's going on just doesn't seem to be true a lot
of the time to me it seems like neither party is acting in line with any sort of principled
anti-doxing stance libs of tiktok has no problem publishing faces names and jobs of people on her
platform hoping the public's wrath will fall upon them taylor lorenz has a history of doing the same
thing to advance her own career both have stretched the truth to make a point libs of tiktok is often
a lot meaner than she needs to be in her snide comments that she attaches to videos meanwhile
lorenz is absolutely a cry bully who plays the victim card to the max while still being cute and
cheeky when those same actions benefit her where libs of tiktok might be a little bit too edgy or
maybe even a little bit cruel for some people's tastes lorenz is absolutely a person who fake
cries and actively seeks out victimization as a method of furthering her career but most
importantly the way that each of them operates exposes a huge values difference libs of tiktok
thinks of exposing people as exposing their behavior even if she misses context or gets
something wrong or falls for fake news she is focused on the behaviors of these subversive prog
activists what they're doing with the power over children that they currently wield but lorenz
thinks of exposing people as exposing their identities there is no criticism of libs of tiktok's
behavior coming out of lorenz that actually holds up because lorenz is happy to do the same thing
when it's in her interest and striking all the hypocrisy from the record the only thing that
she has to say about libs of tiktok is right wing bad that might be a good virtue signal but it's
not a good argument where libs of tiktok points to bad behavior and says look at what these people
are doing lorenz points to a hidden identity and says look at who my political opponent is it's an
important distinction and to me it's at least partial evidence that the progs are scared of
the effectiveness of what libs of tiktok is doing they're using the same tactic they've always leaned
on for over a decade now docs intimidate defund or get fired somehow if possible in order to silence
political opponents if libs of tiktok stops posting they automatically win which is why
they're exploring every avenue to see it through but libs of tiktok has only grown not diminished
in influence they're even being cited as an inspiration in florida's recent don't say gay
law hate and homophobia is lurking right beneath the surface in american politics right now years
of increasing acceptance of gays and transgenders is provoking a backlash on right-wing talk shows
and in state houses that's the backdrop for this washington post piece about libs of tiktok a
twitter account that shares and sometimes ridicules public posts from progressive educators and others
deemed libs taylor lorenz's story revealed the identity of the conservative woman
running libs of tiktok and now there's a roiling debate about her story and the ethics of it
but there's no debating the influence of the libs of tiktok account it's even helped inform
florida's recent parental rights law deemed the don't say gay bill by opponents which is likely
one of the big reasons that taylor lorenz targeted her in the first place libs of tiktok isn't perfect
sure she sometimes stretches the truth make a point because sensationalism is what makes a
tweet go viral not necessarily the facts but at the end of the day she is shining a spotlight on
the behavior of some pretty bad people using nothing but their own words and if i had to choose
libs of tiktok is preferable to the naked opportunism and hypocrisy of taylor lorenz
here's a quick addendum that i'm recording during editing guys tim pool ended up taking out a
billboard in time square that says taylor lorenz docs libs of tiktok dude i bet most people walking
through time square have no fucking idea what's going on why did you think this would be a good
plan i mean it's funny but it's a giant waste of money but look at lorenz's reply this billboard
is so undeniably idiotic it's hilarious but don't forget that these campaigns have a much
darker and more violent side i'm grateful to be at a newsroom that recognizes these bad faith
politically motivated attacks as a strong security team the abuse that women over 40 have to deal
with this industry is horrifying make it make sense america you make it make sense taylor did
you not do the exact same thing you're whining about two libs of tiktok by showing up at her
home did she not suffer from the same horrifying abuse from you tim's reply was to say i'm not
describing your reporting i've repeatedly said it was justified in publishing a name we can argue
the merits i'm calling you out for lying when you and washington post denied linking to private
details you publish libs of tiktok's private address just own it i'm glad to hear you're
not upset and your friends and fans are also happy it's the way it should be you make a statement
i can test it we all made our points heard you on cnn me and time square now we move on completely
reasonable take tit for tat you both get the spotlight shown on you you hash it out welcome
to the public sphere of course taylor's not interested in any kind of mutual back and forth
she thinks that she has a license to simply harass whoever she wants and they shouldn't be able to
speak back my family and friends aren't happy they've been subject to non-stop stream of hateful
attacks doxing and violent attacks driven by this baseless campaign i'm happy to hear you're moving
on oh fuck right off you are loving this shit this is the most traction your career has ever
gotten you are going to milk this victimhood into a promotion and we both know it you're over here
whining over getting the clap back you deserve you are a crybully and i don't care how many
crocodile tears you shed over having done to you what you have built a career out of doing to others
you've been doxed you've been threatened you've been harassed by tucker carlson just for calling
out online harassment they'll threaten children they'll threaten my parents i've had to remove
every single social tie i had severe ptsd from this i i contemplated suicide it got really bad
you feel like any little piece of information
that gets out on you will be used by the worst people on the internet to destroy your life
and it's i bring a message from her majesty taylor lorenz freedom to any man who identifies the
slave known as libs of tiktok i'm libs of tiktok tiktok tiktok tiktok i'm lives of tiktok tiktok