You know, recently I feel like there's been a lot of tension between me and this website.
I'm just sensing a lot of conflict here, you know?
And I feel like it's creating a very angry and hateful environment.
And no one likes that, right?
I just have so much anger built up, you know?
With all the censorship and the demonetization
and the funding pedophiles
and the 2017 memes sucking complete dick.
It's all got me a little on edge.
I'm just so confused.
YouTube is so unstable.
YouTubers have no idea what's going on.
And I'm pretty sure YouTube has no idea what's going on.
The CEO of YouTube doesn't even know how to make a YouTube video.
I just don't understand what's going on anymore.
Why are washed up Disney Channel stars the face of this website again?
Nothing makes any sense.
I just have so many questions.
All I want are some answers.
All I need is some guidance.
And that's when I found it.
For on this momentous day, I was visited by a wise monk
by the name of YoloGuy929 the tooth.
At DankMeme929, this agent of divine intervention
provided me with the greatest epiphany of my YouTube career.
YoloGuy929 enlightened me to the almighty YouTube prophet, Montazon.
Now normally, I'm not a very spiritual person.
But that's just because I was blinded.
Blinded by greed and selfishness.
I was blind to Montazon's eternal and undying love for all of his children.
The children of YouTube.
If you look back through history, Montazon appears everywhere.
He is an omniscient and omnipresent being.
He transcends time and petty human conflict.
If you upload a video to YouTube, Montazon is watching.
Because Montazon loves you.
Now I know what you're thinking.
Montazon demonetizes and censors YouTubers.
So how can he love us?
Well allow me to deliver you all a sermon from the book of Montazon.
In the beginning, there were only four YouTubers.
Ellen DeGeneres provided us with hilarious funny comedy epic memes.
As she is a hilarious and funny female LGBT comedian.
The Rock provided us with incredible acting and thrilling motion picture cinematic action adventures.
Jimmy Kimmel made us all learn the powerful lesson
that all the world's problems are the fault of us weak and pathetic peasants.
And he reminds us that celebrities are strong,
brave and will solve all the world's problems by being a celebrity.
And finally, Taylor Swift Vivo provided us with the soundtrack of our lives
through her innovative and groundbreaking music
that has surpassed the quality of the greatest musicians in human history.
These four original YouTubers lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed when the evil, racist, sexist, homophobic, transphobic,
racist, fascist, racist, racist, racist, evil, racist video gamers attacked.
Led by their leader, PewDiePie, the gamers tried to destroy the harmony of YouTube
by being racist, sexist, homophobic, evil, racist, sexist, racist, racist.
Video games, evil, racist video games.
Racism is bad.
Racism was going to evilly destroy YouTube.
Who was brave enough to save Ellen DeGeneres, The Rock,
Jimmy Kimmel and Taylor Swift Vivo from the racist, sexist, homophobic,
transphobic, racist, racist, racist, racist, racist video gamers.
Then just when the racist video gamers were about to complete their plan
and turn YouTube into racist tube, Montazon sacrificed himself to save YouTube.
Montazon died for our racist sins.
Montazon made the greatest sacrifice of all because Montazon loves you and Montazon loves YouTube.
Montazon gave up his physical form so he can watch over all of us and protect us from evil racism.
Montazon made the greatest sacrifice of all.
So is it too much to ask for you to sacrifice a little bit of your ad revenue to Montazon?
I think not.
Every time your video gets demonetized, that is just Montazon protecting you from evil racists.
Montazon is gifting you with his protective touch and you should be grateful for his sacrifice.
That yellow dollar sign is just a sign that Montazon is watching over you
and keeping you safe from racism.
So don't get mad at YouTube anymore.
Instead, be thankful that Montazon sacrificed himself so that YouTube can exist at all.
So take this holiday season and give thanks to Montazon.
And always remember, Montazon is watching and Montazon loves you.