Steamed Hams is what every meme should strive to be.
This is a meme that's simply cut from a better cloth than the rest.
It's based on one of the best scenes of all time from one of the best TV shows of all time,
and you better believe it's one of the best memes of all time.
Steamed Hams is a logical progression of memes like The Nutshack and the We Are Number One edits that were popular in late 2016,
and it continues to advance and evolve the genre.
In an age where most memes have become predictable and stale,
Steamed Hams asks of its memers to think outside the box if they wish to find success.
Ironically, in order for a memer to make a popular Steamed Hams meme,
they must think as delightfully devilish as Skinner in the very scene they're editing.
The sheer variety and creativity displayed through this meme contributes to its longevity.
While most modern memes struggle to remain relevant for more than a week,
Steamed Hams has gradually risen in popularity over an entire year, and it's still going strong.
This meme actually reminds me a lot of the stew chocolate pudding meme from many years ago,
except Steamed Hams is even better.