Holy shit guys, I am so completely fucked right now.
YouTube heroes.
If you haven't heard the news yet, YouTube has announced new policy where you can earn points in a game!
For flagging people's videos!
Now I'm not here to explain the video, other YouTubers have done a much better job than I ever could...
But I'm just looking at this from my perspective and I'm here to say that...
IT'S ALL OVER PEOPLE! WE DON'T HAVE A PRAYER!
AAAAAAAAAAA
Guys, I've pissed off a lot of children over the years.
Oh, jeez, I don't really agree.
Suck a fucking dick, baguette.
And those are the people that are gonna be running this thing.
Because it's an unpaid job where all you get are virtual points.
So you're saying I should do your job for you at home for free?
I'd love it!
And the only people who will actually volunteer their time for this are fucking children who are too young to get a paying job.
I understand the metaphor that children run this website.
But now children are going to be literally running this website.
Well, it's been nice knowing you guys, but my time here is coming to an end.
I've pissed off too many kids over the years, and now they have the tools to get revenge.
Don't fix that shit!
Oh my god! Oh my god!
Terrorists win.
This is the end, beautiful friend.
Children! I wanna die!
What the fuck? What the fuck? What the fuck is this?
Just when I thought they couldn't get any stupider.
Where have all the good men gone, and where are all the gods?
YouTube!
Look at this photograph!
Look at it! Look at it! Look at it!
The only thing that's for sure about YouTube is fucking things suck!