SSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH
What's up everyone! It's your favorite cartoon reviewer...
here again!!
Doctor MLP BronyAnimeFan3000
back with another
Cartoon Rant!
So today, yeah, today everyone, I'm pissed.
I am angrier than I've ever been in, like, the past seven days, because I have found
one of the worst cartoons I have ever seen on the face of the Earth.
Like, nothing more important on Earth is happening right now than this cartoon, okay?
So I want you all to take a look at this.
I want you all to take a look at this program, right here.
This is Dr. Anime Brony Furry Fan 8000 here, with a special report.
A special report.
I had to drop everything once I saw this.
I was making waffles, I was making scrambled eggs, and I just, that stuff's burning on
the stove right now, because I had to drop everything and just make this rant for you
guys right here, because this is just urgent news.
Everyone needs to hear about this, okay?
So the topic of today's video is the Teletubbies reboot.
I mean, why would you reboot the Teletubbies, one of the most quintessential, just Emmy
award-winning programs for children and adults?
And a lot of people at school make fun of me for watching children's cartoons, but little
do they know that they're all actually idiots, and these cartoons are extremely deep, cinematic
masterpieces meant for adults.
So okay, let's look at the, let's review the new Teletubbies reboot, with, oh my god, why
does this even exist?
I can't even right now, oh my gosh, why do I even bother?
Oh my gosh, the Teletubbies reboot, alright, so let's just get it in.
Okay, so we got the, first of all, they completely ripped off and rehashed the original, like,
at least have some originality, this is the exact same opening as the original Teletubbies.
We got the, okay, first of all, they ruined the baby.
They ruined the baby, the baby's like, the baby's supposed to be, like clearly, the art
style of this new show is completely god-awful.
Oh, the art style, oh, the art style, I mean, look at how good the original looks, like,
you got the, the border of the sun is clearly defined between, like, the corona of the sun
and like, the solar winds, I guess, but here, with the reboot, you can't even tell, and
it's like, who is this ugly-ass baby face here that, why would they pick this baby actor?
Like, this hurts me to look at, and I know, I guess you could kind of argue that that's
a bit ingenious because you shouldn't, it's teaching kids not to look at the sun, but
it's like, I mean, they couldn't have picked a better actor for the sun, I mean, just look
at this, this actor is completely god-awful, compared to the original, who delivers an
Oscar-worthy, an Oscar-worthy performance as a son, I mean, you can't be serious with
this reboot, they're trying to show this stuff to kids, it's ridiculous, and then he looks
down and, no, just look at the art style, oh my god, the art style, it's like this disgusting
CGI blend with real elements, like, what is it, the first one, they just went to like
an old World War II bunker and painted it green, and then they shot this shit, and it
looks great, it looks great, why would anyone want to change this formula, why would you
not want to stray from this, at least if you're going to reboot the series, use this beautifully
designed original set, and it's like, oh look at that, it doesn't even, it's missing the
windmill, how can you make the Teletubbies intro without the windmill, the windmill is
the most important part of the Teletubbies, it's what gives them their powers to transcend
dimensions, you can't have the intro of the Teletubbies without the windmill, oh look
at that, look at that, they completely fucked up the order, they fucked up the order of
the Teletubbies, okay, everyone knows, oh shit, I gotta research the fucking Teletubbies,
which one's the blue one, alright, alright, so let's look at how much they completely
ruined this intro, alright, so Tinky Winky, the blue one, Tinky Winky comes out first,
everyone, alright, at least they're right until that point, but Dipsy, Dipsy comes out
second, no no no no, that's completely wrong, everyone knows, okay, everyone knows friggin'
Lala is supposed to come out second, but the reboot can't even get that right, they can't
even get the order of the Teletubbies right, so Dipsy comes out second, and then, and then
Lala, and then Lala, okay, at least Poe comes out last, so they did get that right at least,
way to completely copy the original, god, can this show be original for one second,
oh, and look at the disgusting 2D animated intro, intro title, compared to the, compared
to the groundbreaking, compared to the groundbreaking 3D balloon text of the original, and once
again, the windmill is completely missing, I mean, we've, we've just watched the intro
so far, and I've ranted about this for 8 minutes, and you can't be serious with this shit, this
show is so infuriating, how can they even broadcast this on television, another thing
I have to mention about the art style, the horrific art style, is, why did they make
this 16x9, who, who wanted the aspect ratio to be 16x9, it looks perfectly fine in the
original, perfectly fine in the 4x3 aspect ratio of the original, but these idiot producers
of the Teletubbies reboot, they couldn't even make it 4x3, like, like it was in my childhood
when it was perfect, they had a perfect formula, and they messed it up, and they need to pay
for this, they need to pay, they must pay for their sins against me, I am personally
insulted by the Teletubbies intro, oh, and finally, finally, a minute and 42 seconds
in to the new Teletubbies, they show the windmill, the windmill is, the windmill is instrumental,
how can you not show the windmill until later, are they relegating the windmill to a minor
character, how can they even do this to me, the windmill is the most important part of
the Teletubbies, and you're gonna relegate it to a minor character, they messed up, ok,
look at this, they messed up the PA system, the Orwellian PA system, they messed it up,
it's supposed to have 11 dimples, as clearly demonstrated by the original, 11 dimples,
right there, and the stupid idiots who made the show, there's only 10 dimples, there's
only 10 dimples on the PA system, like, how could this lack of attention to detail go
over everyone's head, it astounds me, 10 dimples, are you kidding me, the art style
of the show, look how few flowers there are, I mean, this is like looking at Shrek's acne
written back right now, where are the flowers, you gotta balance up the greens, like why
is the screen so green right now, it's repulsing me, it makes me want to vomit in a trash can
right now, all this green, you gotta balance out the colors, by putting flowers on the
side, but oh, I guess flowers are too hard to render in this disgusting CG, oh, the art
style guy, oh, the art style, it's just the worst, the art style, alright, what else is
there to talk about in the show, I mean, the footage speaks for itself folks, just
look how bad this is, they completely mischaracterize the characters too, okay, so it's like, Poe
is supposed to be the smaller, he's supposed to get shit on by all the others, the others,
shit on Poe, but it's supposed to teach kids a valuable lesson about bullying, yeah, so
I was bullied a lot in school, but because I watched the Teletubbies, I knew how to prevent
it, and kids today aren't gonna know that, because the character Poe is completely mischaracterized,
it's like, how can you not show Poe being just shit on by all the rest of the characters,
that's completely ridiculous, you're basically just making every character completely bland,
and what's the point of that, like children watch TV shows to empathize with the characters
and follow them through a coherent plot, why are you ruining these characters that
we love as a kid, you're physically insulting me right now, you're physically attacking
me because when I watch this show, I feel physically ill, and I just want you all to
know, like anyone behind this show, that you have just ruined my day for having to sit
through this and watch this content, it's just disgusting, and now Poe is leading, Poe
is leading, so you completely, so not only have you marginalized all these characters
into just completely bland cutouts of the original incredibly complex and dynamic Teletubbies,
you make Poe the leader, you've completely wrapped everything around, so they're like,
did these people even watch the original Teletubbies?
So they completely fucked up the design of the Windmill, so the original Windmill is
supposed to be this four pronged wind turbine system, and this one is just, the Windmill
in the rebuild is just like this pinwheel design, like what were they thinking, why
would you mess up the Windmill, the most important character is the Windmill, and maybe the Sun
baby, but they completely messed this up, and the art style, and the characters, it's
just atrocious, oh look at this, look at this, this is the worst, this is the worst thing
they could have possibly done, they made the Windmill sparkles green, everyone knows the
Teletubbies Windmill sparkles are supposed to be red, okay, it's supposed to be like
pinkish, light red, that's what gives them the power, it's because it's red, it's because
Poe, Poe's color is red, and Poe is the most important character, because he's the character
that gets bullied by all the rest of them, and it's showing that it was supposed to empathize
with Poe, that's a very important detail that they just tossed aside for this reboot, and
they made it green, why are the windmill sparkles green, why are the windmill sparkles green,
you made it the color of Dipsy, Dipsy, the brown Teletubby, is this some sort of affirmative
action, social justice nonsense, of course you make the windmill sparkles green, okay,
you helped out the dark skinned one, like why would this even need to be a thing, they
completely mischaracterized these characters, and they're trying to mess with the windmill
sparkle formula, and they're just completely missing the subtext, the brilliant subtext
of the original series, and okay, so let's talk about, let's talk about the real world
version of the Teletubbies, okay, because you know in the original they do these brilliant,
these seamless transitions into reality, and they show like a kid playing with these really
awesome toys that are really fun, so it's like look here, look in the original one,
they have this nice little farm place, and it's like really chill, and it's like oh my
god, toy horses, those are awesome, look at this, you can like race the horses, and it's
like oh look, I'm running a farm, but it's not, because it's in my imagination, and imagination
is like the most powerful thing, but it's like super chill, there's like lambs and sheep,
and it's like I got the tractor, the complete set, and it's like hell yeah, give me those
awesome toys I want to play, but in the new Teletubbies, in the Teletubbies reboot,
they completely messed this up, again, as usual like why am I not surprised at this point,
how could a show possibly be this incompetent, they mess up the kitty kid play time in the
bedroom floor, so now you got this kid in a wheelchair, like I don't want to learn about
kids in wheelchairs, like that just makes me sad, I just want to play with toys on a
farm, and it's like, you're putting them, look this is terrifying, he's in a wheelchair,
why is he even in this precarious predicament in the first place, like this is teaching
kids to just not fear high places, high places are terrifying, I don't want to be in a high
place, this kid's in a wheelchair, is it because he fell off a high place in the first place,
why is he even here, I want to go back to the little girl in the yellow shirts room,
and play with farm animal toys, I want to go to this horrifying, it's horrifying, it's
horrifying, why would they think this was appropriate to children, and I don't know,
from an adult perspective, it's completely, it's completely unattainable, like the horses
you got, the horses man, it's like, have you ever seen a horse in real life, they're all
over my favorite show, My Little Pony, Friendship is Magic, but have you ever just seen a horse
in real life, it's a majestic creature, okay, and she had like three horse toys, but what
the reboot can't get right, is that no kid wants to go up to a high place and like, nobody
cares about that shit, okay, everyone wants to play with farm animal toys, but who the
heck wants to go up to a horrifying place, where you might fall and just kill yourself
by hitting the ground too hard, you know, blatant Windows product placement here, like
how can you be, like I remember when cartoons were just cartoons, you know, and you could
just watch them without having a freaking Windows ad play on your screen every ten seconds,
and all of a sudden you got to integrate Windows to kid and Windows Phone and playing Minecraft,
Jesus Christ, this is some of the worst content I've ever seen, and I don't know, I think
it should just be taken off the air entirely, because I don't like it, like to hell with
all the kids who like it, like they're idiots, okay, this is the worst piece of programming
I've ever witnessed, and we should riot in the streets, and we should, we should just
like, we should go to Congress, we should go to Congress in whatever country, or just
go to your Congressman, go to your government, and just like, just like throw stones at them
or something, or I don't know, like yell at them, get like a megaphone, and like try to
scream at them, maybe they can hear you, and try to take this stuff off the air, like this
is completely disgusting, why would they allow this to air on television, they took
a great series in the Teletubbies, and they completely ruined it, and I think that's just
unacceptable, so yeah, thanks for watching this cartoon rant, make sure to subscribe
and like this video, and donate to me on Patreon, for the Patreon rewards, next week I'm going
to be reviewing Bugs Bunny, and talk about the problems with Bugs Bunny, and how it's
like one of the worst cartoons of all time, and I don't like it, and it's not as good
as My Little Pony, so yeah, thanks for watching, and make sure to like and subscribe, this
has been Anime Gamer BronyFurry3000, signing out here, with another important cartoon news
update, that's also my opinion, but it's actually fact, that's not my opinion, so yeah, make
sure to subscribe to me, and I will catch you guys on the flippy flip, so goodbye!
Thanks for watching, see you next time!
Thanks for watching!