Okay, guys, it is time for the next harvest.
This is the first week of July, the lettuce still isn't ready, but everything else is
definitely good.
I'll be getting kale and peas for tonight's salad.
Look at those peas.
Wait a second.
Naomi?
Yeah?
Can you throw down a bowl?
Damn it, Dad.
Ow!
God damn it.
Let's see if these peas can be pulled off.
Kinda, but kinda not.
I don't want to pull too hard.
You know what?
I guess I'll have to snip them.
Yeah, they're looking good.
And now for the kale trim.
Well, the bowl was a bit too small, but that's okay.
It is incredibly stormy out here right now.
The new deck set is getting drenched.
It's an extremely warm rain, though, and that's nice.
Good for the garden, too.
So where's all that water coming from?
Oh, Jesus.
That doesn't look very good.
Maybe I gotta fix that.
Oh my lord, this has been my entire summer.
Nothing but monsoon season, dude.
I don't know if you can see it down there, but the garden is flooding.
I still haven't fixed that, either.
It's blowing into the house.
Here we are.
It's nearing the end of July at this point, and this is how the garden looks.
There's Naomi doing some weeding, and there's actually a lot of weeding to do.
A combination of things prevented us from harvesting earlier.
There's a lot of kale, there's a lot of chard, there's a lot of lettuce, and a fair number
of peas.
However, I am noticing some problems with the current garden.
That was full of weeds.
Maybe it's weeds, but also, like, the cucumbers should have taken off by now, and they haven't.
There's not many tomatoes coming in.
I see, like, one tomato in there.
They're still flowering, bro.
They're still flowering, but, like, they're not really going the way that they were last
year.
The kale's doing well, and the kale's doing well.
However, also, I think the peppers should have started up earlier, too.
Maybe it's because of how wet it's been this summer?
Maybe it's because of how hot it's been this summer?
Who knows?
Hot and wet, and sometimes cold.
Wet, hot American summer.
Meh.
I have a feeling this might not be a great garden this year.
Nope.
But at the very least, tonight, we'll be able to-
Can you move the lettuce?
Wow, Naomi.
Can you just move it?
How many weeds have you thrown in there?
None, actually.
That was the first one.
I'm sure.
And I'll come back down tonight to collect peas for the salad.
Right now, I've got to harvest all this kale, man.
There's too much of it.
And look at that.
That's a lot of kale I've got to pick up now.
How many bags will that be?
Three or four?
I accidentally threw it, and even though it was so far away.
I moved it.
Are you kidding me?
I'm sorry.
It was a gentle toss.
Yeah?
You know what?
Don't-
Deserved.
What?
Don't.
That's good.
There we go.
Four bags of kale, ready to be frozen.
I'm going to eat this out of the garden now.
I'm going to help Naomi with the weeding.
There she is.
And you can see, there's a few small tomatoes coming in, but not really that many.
Also, the cucumbers are growing very slowly, and the roots, not the roots, but the early
part of the vine is very white.
I don't know what's going on there.
At the same time, it was like the same problems overtaking the peas, but at least they produced
more peas, and they lasted longer this year, you know?
There's one dead vine in there already.
They didn't grow as tall as they did, but they are producing more peas, and that's nice.
So I guess I'll look at all those weeds.
I'll get to weeding then.
Wait, Naomi, you're sitting on a plant?
No.
Just move your feed for a minute.
I'm not.
There's a really tiny plant that's barely alive in there.
Wait, did you pull it out?
No.
There's no plant here.
No, there actually is.
Seriously.
Okay.
Oh, no.
Yeah, it's right there.
See?
There it is.
It's a really tiny kale trying to recover.
There's a little bit of growth in there.
See that?
Don't step on the plants, Dev.
I won't.
I don't believe you.
Is this the second kale plant that you've murdered, Naomi?
Yes.
I hate kale secretly, even though I eat it all the time, so I just murder kale plants
because it brings joy to my life.
I have a feeling that one's not coming back at this point, eh?
Probably not.
Oh, well.
Okay, Naomi's going to get some water, and we're done.
Don't fall.
So, we're finished with weeding for the most part.
It looks a lot better.
We have all the kale.
I pushed some of the vines towards going up the lattice.
Hopefully, it'll be okay.
I don't know about the garden this year.
I don't know.
It might not be so good.
Maybe I put the tomatoes too close together.
The peas always seem to die.
I don't quite know why.
She accidentally dug up a root of the peas while weeding, so she theorized that maybe
what's going on with the peas is that we're not watering them deep enough so the roots
aren't going deeply.
Maybe that's the problem, but other things seem to be going very well.
We'll grab some of the Swiss chard and the peas tonight and the lettuce for salads, and
it'll be a-okay.
Can you see that?
That's a spider web in the garden.
I have not been around much this summer, and the garden has become, well, it's gotten away
from me a bit.
Anyway, here's what's been going on.
The lettuce is going crazy, but now the lettuce is bolting, and this is entirely my fault.
I just haven't trimmed it, haven't been around, but hopefully, if I cut it down again, it
should be okay.
It's time for another trim of the kale.
It's definitely time to start eating the chard.
There's a pepper coming in finally, and over there, see that red?
There's a tomato.
The cucumbers aren't doing so well.
There's one cucumber there, but generally the vines aren't going.
I don't know what happened this year.
There's still peas, and they're still growing, but they didn't really take off the way that
they did in previous years.
At least they got a lot of peas out of them though, so that's okay.
They actually lasted longer than previous years, which is surprising.
The garden overall is not doing nearly as well, hi Naomi, is not doing nearly as well
as previous years.
I don't quite know why.
The kale and the lettuce are the things that really, really worked out.
Everything else is kind of working out, but it's still worse than last year.
Also, look, that tiny kale is slowly coming back.
This time, I just brought a giant pot because there's too much to harvest.
Jesus, it's filled the whole pot.
Same thing with the chard.
I haven't trimmed one of these on camera before, so I think you just get in there, snip the
stalk, get a bunch of chard leaves.
That's a big leaf.
All right, well, I guess I'll just trim again like so and hope that it won't keep making
seeds.
You basically just cut it like grass if you're cutting your lawn with scissors.
These are all cut.
Let's hope they continue to grow back.
Maybe so I can pick off some of these lower leaves too.
These guys here.
Yeah.
That was a few blades of grass in there.
That's okay, we'll figure it out.
There it is.
Just a big pot of leaves.
Naomi, look at this.
That's a weird looking stew, Dev.
It's the first week of September, we're coming up to the end of the garden and it is not
looking good.
Peas always die around this time of year.
That's fine.
Expected.
We got our share of peas out of them.
The lettuce was a success for the most part.
The two chard plants worked out.
The kale, as always, was amazing.
We've got to cut it again.
We only got a few decently big peppers out of them this time, like this one, for example.
That one didn't take off at all.
The cucumbers just never grew and there's like one little tiny cucumber there.
I don't know what happened.
The tomatoes have been hit and miss.
Firstly, whenever there's a red one, not so much this time, but for the most part, whenever
there's a red one, an animal goes to eat it.
That one's been eaten by an animal, probably like a chipmunk or something.
Secondly, this small one fell on the ground, so I took it off, hoping it would ripen up.
But instead of ripen up, it just rotted from the inside.
If I pull off all those green tomatoes and if they don't rot, like this one did, we might
get half what we got last year.
We are in the second week of September.
Naomi's gathering up the kale right now.
You missed her feet.
She was changing her shoes.
You missed the Naomi feet pics.
Cut your toes off, Dev.
We have frost coming, so it's time to pull off whatever we can pull off.
This sucks because like, it's coming this week.
It's coming with all the rain.
I guess the garden just didn't work out this year, guys.
I'm not happy about it, but.
Kale did.
I guess if you live in Northern Ontario, there's gross shit tons of kale.
Yeah.
Kale always works out.
Dude, even that, that one that I stomped on like made a slight comeback.
Yeah.
You can get like four leaves out of that.
Got the, uh, the old snippers.
These are pretty dull at this point, but they're also like seven years old.
Yeah.
Yeah, I need one of those Pokemon bowls.
Pokemon.
I'll just, uh.
In this case, that means produce.
Produce?
We're catching produce?
Yeah.
Look at this.
This tomato got so fat, it bent the vine.
Nice.
Give us the big fat tomato.
There's actually a lot of tomatoes on here that is all green.
Yeah.
Except for that one over there.
Or a red one.
Like we did get a bunch.
This is way less than normal, but we still got a bunch of tomatoes.
So, like it's not a complete loss.
I just grabbed the only two peppers.
Naomi's here sniffing away.
And this is what I mentioned last week.
Some of them just rotted.
Some animals ate them.
Like, but there's still a bunch that are like okay.
I think we'll be fine.
Yeah, like there's a lot of hidden ones.
Like right here.
Yeah.
See, look at all those.
They're green, but they're big.
I just noticed this.
You see that?
There's like two little peas.
Even on this dead vine, you can still find like the final little bits.
I don't think I'd eat those.
They don't look very good.
But still.
Like, um, mines away.
So this is the final dregs of the lettuce.
As you can see.
They don't look good.
They've gone to seed.
Once it starts producing seeds, the lettuce gets more bitter.
I don't mind it.
Naomi doesn't complain, but it's still edible.
So we'll chop all these down.
Or Naomi will anyway.
And then we'll pick out all of the, uh, all the leaves.
Let me go to the kitchen.
And that'll be dinner tonight.
Along with this chard.
You know what those late chards that we bought?
They worked out too.
Oh yeah.
Cucumbers just didn't work.
I don't know why.
You can see in there, there's like two tiny ones and that's all we got.
I don't even know if there's three.
I don't even know if those are edible, but I'll get them just in case.
Maybe we'll let Dave be the guinea pig.
We'll just not tell him that they're dead.
There we go.
Like it's, the vine's already dead.
The vine's already dead.
There's a cucumber.
Jesus.
So there's five, five malformed cucumbers.
Hold up that teeny tiny round one.
It looks like an avocado.
So this is probably going to be the final haul from the garden.
Kind of disappointing.
We still got something, but it's not what I expected.
Here's our lettuce and our chard.
We've got our deformed cucumbers, three bowls of tomatoes and two final bags of kale.
Not Naomi's glasses.
We harvested Naomi's glasses.
No, no, no.
You lost them in the garden.
Eons ago.
No, I'm fixing those with the power of Flex Seal.
Not a paid promotion.
That looks pretty good, baby.
Give me all those plants.
Be careful balancing those, Naomi.
There's only so much room in the windowsill.
I got this.
It's fine.
Hey, look, this one is like, I know it's not, it's just really fat.
It almost looks like there was another one trying to grow.
It's going to fall.
No, no.
Look at that.
Put it somewhere else.
Fine.
We have more than one windowsill in the house.
Nope.
I'm going to fit them all here.
All right.
So let's try out one of these deformed cucumbers here.
I mean, it's pretty seedy in there.
Maybe it's okay.
Seeds taste good.
Yum.
All right.
I don't know how I feel about this.
It's like not any more bad than a regular grocery store cucumber.
Yeah, I guess.
It's probably still fine.
It's just a cucumber.
Oh, it's very mushy inside.
That's all very mushy.
But this stuff is still good.
And here we are, the third week of September.
Naomi is grabbing the stuff.
And we did basically what we did last year.
We knew that frost was coming,
so we just let the garden be to do whatever it wanted to do.
We didn't water it anymore.
We didn't do anything to it.
And we're going to get the final dregs,
and then we're going to pull it out,
because I want to do something to this garden
after you pull everything out that will prevent this disaster
from happening again.
Naomi's very tired.
We've got a couple more chard leaves.
The kale, I bet the kale could just grow in winter.
There's so much.
It just grows in the snow.
We'll grab the last few peppers,
and we'll grab the last few tomatoes,
and then we're going to just yank everything out.
How do you unlock this?
You have to, like, pull this down here.
I tried.
There it goes.
Oh, thank you.
I just noticed my disaster plant actually managed to come back.
Hooray.
We can definitely garden better than Chaz.
Yeah.
Naomi just grabbed the last pepper,
and I just realized of these six pepper plants,
we got, like, four peppers.
There's a baby one right here.
There's, like, a baby one right there, too, right behind you.
Like a baby baby?
Yeah, like a tiny little pepper.
And there it is, the final two bowls of dregs
at the end of the garden this year.
It's starting to get cold.
I think it's going to rain.
Yeah, it's supposed to rain this afternoon.
Basically, we're doing this right now
because, like, we had a little bit of minor frost,
but today's rain is going to be the actual beginning of fall
when the Canadian winter blows in
and just covers the entire landscape in a giant sheet of ice,
and we're basically racing against time
before the rain at 2 o'clock.
It doesn't happen till late October.
No, I think we're going to be basically frozen
inside of our house for the next five months.
You think so, eh?
We're going to do something a bit special this year
as Naomi clears out the garden.
I'm going to do it, too.
So first, we've got to get all this stuff out of here.
Come on.
It's hard to do this one-handed.
Ah.
The tomato cage, we'll store these away
until next year.
And there's the tomato plant.
Oh, it's still in.
And there you go.
All the plants are off.
Here's a big pile of plants.
Naomi, you think that there's a clover infestation
in the garden at this point, right?
Probably.
Can't see it anymore.
So we're going to rake off the top layer,
shove it into the compost, and hopefully that'll be okay.
What I wanted to do is to get some excess.
Open up again. Come on.
Why is this always giving me a hard time?
I'm going to grab that excess compost as well
and shove it in the garden after we've raked it off.
Hopefully, we can use it to rejuvenate the garden, maybe.
So here's all the weeds and plants and junk,
and I'll just grab it.
That's a lot of it.
And it's going to go in.
It's going to sit in the compost.
It's going to...
Grrr!
I'll just gigachat it.
It's real hard to rake one-handed.
Also, why am I using a leaf rake?
Okay, so there's a pile of the top layer
with all the clover bits in it,
and I'll just shovel it into the compost.
And hopefully, one year going through the composter
will make that soil okay again.
Top layer's been shoveled off?
Mostly.
There it is. It's all in there.
Now I think the plan is,
since we are missing a bunch of earth at this point,
I'm going to shovel out all that compost,
like I mentioned, right there.
We can get the lettuce bed,
and also there's a bag of manure.
You okay in there?
There it is.
I'm going to assume you can't dump it in?
Probably not.
Alright, I'll just dump it in, and Naomi can layer it around.
Jesus.
It's actually not that heavy when it's two-handed,
but I've got to hold the phone.
Come on.
An extra bag of manure right into the garden,
just to rejuvenate it over the winter.
Same with this thing.
Yep, there it goes.
Oh my god, look at all the roots at the bottom.
I didn't know that there'd be that many roots.
Of course there'd be a shit ton of roots.
We just put the land in it.
Oops.
It's compost time.
Look at all those eggs.
Eggshells are apparently pretty good for a garden.
Also, we eat a lot of eggs.
There we go.
Compost on my side, manure on Naomi's.
All the compost is gone, so we'll close this up.
Come on.
And then we'll mash all this stuff down to make room.
Oh god, this is going to take a while.
Wee hee hee hee hee hee hee.
Making a compostable, which is brutal.
Wee hee hee hee hee hee hee hee.
Yeah.
A beautiful-looking garden ready for next year.
Once the leaves really start coming down,
I'll cover this thing with leaves in October or so.
But we did a good job.
There's Naomi holding the rake.
Hey, do you want to like, because I'm holding the shovel,
do you want to like, recreate that picture of like,
those two farmers who are like, really sour looking?
They're like, holding their tools.
We'll see you next time.
We'll see you next year, hopefully.
Unless the garden fails again.
At which point, I just won't even upload it.
Well, if it fails again, why wouldn't you upload at least one video being like,
a failed goodbye?
Next year-
No more political videos.
Next year's video is just the garden on fire.
Thanks for watching.