Oh hey guys, you caught me at an awkward moment here.
I'm currently trying to tame this pet in World of Warcraft Classic.
That's right, World of Warcraft Classic.
Oh boy, I can't wait to get sucked in yet again, and completely destroy my small, burgeoning
YouTube career.
But at least this time I'll be able to do it with you guys.
I'm currently playing on the Mankrix server, Horde side, because what kind of pleb plays
Alliance?
Considering this is a scorpion pet, I think I know exactly what to name it.
Toxic Masculinity, well it doesn't fit, you know, good enough, good enough.
And I have an SFO guild going, named Final Fantasy XIV, but worse.
Yeah, everyone in Discord voted on names, and that was the name that won out.
It's a free to join guild, all you have to do is log in and message somebody in the guild,
they'll be able to invite you.
Or you can just ask on the SFO discord and I'm sure somebody will get you in.
I'm gonna try to be online most nights, maybe I'll stream it over on Twitch, maybe I'll
do dungeon runs with you guys.
You don't have to be a donator to the channel, or be a member of the five dollar club to
join the SFO guild, you can just come in, no problem.
I don't necessarily know how long this will last, I guess I'll basically keep the guild
going as long as there's interest from the community.
So come play with me guys, it'll be a lot of fun.
Also here, watch me solve the problem of Toxic Masculinity.
Yep, it's just that easy.
Gamers rise up.