What happens if the Earth suddenly stops rotating?
Anything that isn't attached to its surface remains at its initial speed.
Not just cars, buildings, and people, but also water and our atmosphere,
causing giant tsunami waves and global windstorms.
Areas near the equator where the Earth's rotational speed was the fastest would be affected the strongest.
There, everything would continue to move forward at 1,600 kmph.
Don't forget the long-term effects.
Over billions of years, centripetal forces have made Earth a bit wider at the equator.
Without rotation, these forces would vanish.
Oceans would migrate to the poles, which are closer to the center of the Earth and have stronger gravity.
So we're left with dry land around the equator.
Also, our usual day-night cycle would cease to exist.
Without rotation, one day lasts one year, with six months each of daylight and darkness.
And Earth's magnetic field, which is partly generated by the rotation of our planet,
might be altered once the Earth stops rotating.
As a result, we might face higher exposure to deadly solar radiation.
Quite dramatic changes, in case you've ever wondered.