Hello my friends, yes I've been gone for a while and I haven't been doing nothing
because of the YouTube situation even if I get my monetization back which there's still a fair
chance that I will. It's obvious that you can't really trust them anymore unless you're you know
a corporate YouTuber or something. So behind the scenes I've been doing the hard work of diversifying
re-uploading the old videos to other channels other platforms that sort of thing. So today I'd
like to point out my Bitchute channel. It is Bitchute.com slash shortfatotaku and if you're
subbed to that channel right now I've got about 5000 people subbed there so thank you very much.
You will over the course of today and probably the next few days start to see re-uploads of videos
that aren't on that channel. I want to make sure my entire catalog is on the SFO Bitchute channel.
I also started a Game Boomers Bitchute channel where I'm going to be uploading all of the various
game playthroughs. That's going to be a much more daunting task in my opinion because there's like
three or four thousand videos to upload. We've been doing let's plays for years long before I
started doing political content and I find it to be a fun side project that hey is actually helping
me pay the bills so thanks very much for watching it. But in any case that's what I'm doing right
now that's what I've been doing for the past little bit and after the entire SFO backlog is
up on Bitchute and functioning then I'm going to do an SFO Odyssey channel an SFO Rumble channel
and probably even an SFO Daily Motion channel. Because Styx is right it's time to get off
mainline tech. When those channels open and I start putting the backlog up there I will
advertise them here as well. But today it's Bitchute so head over to Bitchute.com
slash shortfatotaku and please consider subscribing there. I hope to see you there. I love you.