good morning my friends it's about uh it's about 9 30 in the morning here on august 22nd 2019
and some of you might recognize this ratty old couch um well only if you watch the gaming streams
anyway because this is the coach we sit on every single day when we do them but i thought i'd talk
to you guys about where i've been what i've been doing why there hasn't been an sfo video in in
basically a month there was the downvote video and then there was yesterday's jumping with scrump
and that's it now on the one hand i haven't just been vacationing i haven't been you know you know
being lazy or anything i've actually been doing a lot of behind the scenes stuff and it's stuff
that people might not necessarily um notice or even care about on first glance anyway
for example i decided to pick up um a new tv on prime day recently and what ended up happening
there's there's the green wall by the way just for those of you who care yeah this is our green
screen studio but what ended up happening was um to integrate this thing into the game boomer setup
for for my streams on twitch um it actually took a lot more work than i initially thought
mainly because i have a really jury-rigged system like if you if you watch the streams if you've
seen them before if you check them out or whatever um you'll know that it's it's not just a regular
face cam or a regular mic setup we do have something that's actually relatively unique
and relatively hard to maintain and i've kind of jury-rigged the whole thing so this is a storage
slash crawl space behind the green screen studio um and this is where i keep the now three computers
that run game boomers when i'm streaming um so this is this is the the gaming pc if we're playing
a pc game it plays on this the one in the back there um that's the show pc so the show pc runs
off that the one in the middle um that's actually an older pc it doesn't really need to be that good
because all it does is it handles the guest calls so for example if you if you donate a hundred
dollars to the channel you choose a game you come on a discord call and i put the calls on its own
pc because this thing it's a good pc but it's notoriously unstable i think i need to get a new
one at some point and before the guest calls would actually run off this when the game crashed we
would lose the guest so the easiest way to do it was to just add this older pc that we had kicking
around um i might upgrade that in the future too but it's not bad it's like you know it's like a
four-year-old pc but anyway to put this into the setup as well as the tv i had to basically rewire
everything and there's a lot of i don't know if you can tell back there there's a lot of wires i
might actually have to like make a vlog of how i do game boomers at some point because some people
have shown an interest yeah a lot of wires there's a like a 16 input hdmi hub back there
there's an hdcp stripper back there basically i've had to really figure out how to do all this stuff
um and there was a lot of work that i i had basically just been putting off and as soon as i
got the new tv as well as a new computer freed up in the house that i could use um i basically
said you know what now is the time to do all the work i'll do it all at once at the same time i
had to like run new electrical and i had to run some piping so so basically all the host stuff
i just took like a week and did that that was at the same time that i was framing all my artwork
by the way and you know what turned out pretty good but i'm also very aware that game boomers
just isn't as popular as sfo the twitch streams might see 30 people they might see 40 they might
see 20 you know they don't get the four or five figure views that that i get here on sfo i do wish
it was as popular yeah please feel free to check it out if you like but i also understand the
reality of the situation so i have been doing some other things as well for example i've been
dealing with some artists who are going to be making new sfo artwork for the various videos
and the various video series that i have planned for the main channel at the same time i've also
been getting some art done for my my uh my my grab bag channel on my anything goes channel
called the dev kit and what i've been doing on that channel is i've been recording a lot of
unboxings i have some relatively unique hardware like the nintendo 64 hdmi mod or stuff like the
super nt the mega sg i recorded an unboxing of that 64 inch uh tv as well as some rather weird
settings it has so if you actually happen to have that model of tv or any any similar tv by lg you
know how to set up a few things that might be hidden away in the menu i'm going to be recording
this soon this is uh this is a gamecube that i've i've pulled apart because this fan is look look
at that it's completely broken the fan's just gone man so i'm going to show how to replace a fan in a
gamecube if you happen to have um have to have an old gamecube kicking around it's not working
anymore i know that this is not strictly the politics sfo stuff that you guys subbed for
which is why i'm not putting it strictly on sfo i'm putting on the dev kit but i do want to try
my hand at doing something more techy more hands-on you know and hopefully it'll be
interesting enough and i have i have enough technological oddities around the house that i
think i can at least captivate your attention a little bit the dev kit is where all of the old
anime reviews from like 10 years ago went uh they're over there however youtube won't let
some of them go up there because of copyright issues and etc so every single old anime review
is up on the dev kit bit shoot channel and if there's ever any new anime reviews to be made
they'll probably go on the dev kit if there's ever any new unboxings or or hardware oddities
they'll go on the dev kit if maybe maybe i might even make that like the the sfo update channel in
a sense too where like if you want to know where i've been what i've been doing my side projects
some behind the scenes stuff some vlogs i can put those up there as well another project i did i've
filmed all the videos but i haven't released them yet and yeah they'll be up on the dev kit as well
because it's not political um there was an office nearby where they threw out something like five or
six computers they just dumped them on the side of the road so i i loaded them up i brought them
back to the house and i noticed that like i mean i don't need them all my computers are better but
they're still in good working order they're like three years old five years old they're not really
bad computers in a sense um and they still work i guess it was just office boomers throwing shit
away that they don't actually understand so what i did was i shot a video series and that'll be
coming out on the dev kit probably in in the coming month um where i repaired them i took
these broken computers repaired them put them in working order and once i had them all fixed up i
i actually raffled them off on my discord so there's like a few people who were students who
were going to school who had no money who couldn't afford a pc so i said here's what we'll do i'll
mail these pcs off to to the neediest people in the discord no offense but by needy or anything
guys but you know what i mean though guys i wanted to give them away to somebody who who couldn't
afford them but anyway they covered the shipping i repaired them i made a short video series out
of it and then i i mailed them off and it was um it was fun it was interesting i got to help a
few people but that took up a few days of my schedule in general though i will say uh join
the discord guys there's actually quite a lot of of community interaction in there um i am in there
sometimes not all the time because you know i'm i am busy too but i try to be in there as much as
i can it's also a good way to uh to be alerted as to when the next stream or the next video is coming
out for any of my projects whether that's sfo game boomers or dev kit they all get alerted there
so it's a it's a good place to hang out and honestly i i really like my community everyone
who's in there is um i wouldn't necessarily say wholesome but i would say good people
so basically what i've been doing is a lot of it has just been side projects and and organizational
stuff and irl stuff that i've just let get away from me frankly i'm not exactly proud to say it
but a lot of it has just um been stuff that's needed doing or stuff project that i've wanted
to do that i've put off for like a year and and i'm finally just doing them oh there's something
else too let me let me get this off the tripod my garden has been going wild dude look at all
those cucumbers here we are we're at the second floor window and uh look at that man i know i
showed you a video of it like a month ago um but it's really improved since then dude
oh yeah it turns out that those peppers they're actually jalapeno peppers i thought they were
green peppers oops they were mislabeled at the store the plant but anyway there's a kale there
there's some there's some gigantic tomato bushes at this point not even plants just bushes there's
like a hundred tomatoes in there the cucumbers are growing up the deck because there's just so much
of them it's a there's kale yeah there's there's peppers and there's there's like a a tiny basil
plant there's naomi's naomi's poor basil plant that didn't really take off but yeah man the garden's
been going great and i've been spending a lot of time doing this there's also been another
situation developing in that ever since e3 basically which was the electronics gaming
expo uh the start of june um i haven't been properly cataloging all the information sources
that i've been getting in through through dms and emails and facebook messages and through
just finding stuff on my own and i'll i'll get into why that is in a little bit but basically
it had built up to the point that i had nothing organized i had like one text file that was
something like 10 000 lines long with a bunch of unrelated yet still useful links and information
and it was my fault for letting it get that bad but i had to before i could make any videos at all
i had to sit down and basically go through each link one by one and divide them up into
basically into into scripts and into topics so i've done that now here's here's a picture
there's probably about 200 300 video topics right here and that took a long time like it took maybe
geez it probably took at least a week or two to do part of it was the fact that i let it get built
up in my head honestly there was so much and that i and i kept adding to it every day because people
kept sending me stuff every day i do appreciate it but it was my fault that i didn't get on top of it
um and then part of it was that opening this many links on a computer often bombs a computer so i
gotta like cut it out piecemeal and then in between doing everything else it just got to a point where
it um it became like one of those almost insurmountable tasks where the more you
avoid it the bigger it gets but the more you avoid it the more you want to avoid it
so eventually i just had to knuckle down and do it and you know eventually i did and now i can
actually make videos again because i actually have things ready to go i have scripts partially
written i have sources laid out i can actually make sfo videos again properly oh and while i've
been doing all this i've also been losing weight again i got back on the wagon and it honestly
feels pretty good at the start of the month i was 221.2 pounds now i am 209.8 it's not a major
victory but it is a victory and hopefully by i can reach my my goal by the end of the year of
getting to my goal weight i had set that as a new year's resolution the year is what two-thirds over
and i haven't really made any serious progress but i'm gonna do it that's enough screwing around
i'm gonna do it i'm gonna do all this stuff i've had so many projects fall apart i've i've missed
game boomer streams i've i haven't uploaded to sfo much recently this is what i want to do with
my life it is it is my dream and this community these people that you are my friends in a sense
and i've been irresponsible and i've let it kind of fall apart and there's no one to blame but
myself for this year's e3 i did overrun game boomers what a lot of of streamers do they
stream the entire uh the entire conference so they'll watch it they'll react to it i did it
with a bit more flair i think because we we had a couch and there was three of us you know
watching these conferences and having a good laugh at them and they really did pay off you know we
we capped out at about 210 viewers that's as high as i've ever gone on game boomers there's
a handful of names that i first noticed in the twitch chat during e3 they are now regular viewers
and i see them all the time on twitch whenever i go to stream and that and that's a that's
a great feeling you know things have in fact worked out in a sense but the amount of work
that e3 took was was pretty colossal i know i gained about 10 pounds just over that week
because i wasn't eating properly i wasn't doing any kind of cleaning or proper cooking in the
house um i wasn't doing anything any of my old good habits that had kind of got me through the spring
i basically let everything fall apart to do e3 and then i didn't really recover from that
basically until now at least on at least in some senses like just in terms of general house cleanup
i found myself without any time because i had to catch up with with game boomers with my own
health with sfo with with everything and i you know i didn't i just didn't have any time anymore
i honestly don't know how the bigger streamers do it maybe they're just better at this than i am
and by the time i did get everything you know good again in terms of my own personal habits in terms
of my workflow in terms of keeping things clean and eating right and and and being productive
again when i finally got everything back together um it was prime day frankly it took me that long
and then i got the tv and then i had to do all of that all of that like uh almost construction
style work and all that rewiring so that's you know as soon as i had my energy back and i was
good to go again um i had a massive project in front of me that wasn't sfo so that's basically
basically where i've been i've been doing a lot of things but it just hasn't been stuff that you
guys have been able to see yet it's almost entirely been behind the scenes or or projects
that i've shot that i haven't yet released and i am sorry about not not keeping you uh in the loop
there are some people in discord who were quite angry with me who said that i should have i should
have told them sooner what i was doing that i wasn't just vanishing on them like like like
spoonie or something but but that i was actually working because i was so yeah if you're in the
discord and you're watching this i will definitely try to to keep you more updated on what i've been
doing if i've been away for a while even if i just go on a vacation like if i leave for three or four
days and just go travel somewhere i'll at least let you know that i'm doing that i'm not just gonna
stay silent anymore and i don't know i don't want to get too much into the personal details of some
things but like my girlfriend naomi has been having a rough time with some stuff my roommate
dave he's been having a rough time with some stuff there's like work-related stress there's school
stuff there's there's health problems cropping up now um then with me i'm i'm fine in that sense but
it's the two closest people to me are having some serious difficulties in their lives right now
and sometimes i'm taking care of them as much as i'm taking care of myself or the channel
that there are days when it feels like i
i have a lot on my shoulders even though
i don't know sometimes it feels like i it shouldn't be that much or i shouldn't have
this much of a problem with it but there are days when it feels like i'm i'm carrying everything
doing these youtube channels these projects doing doing game boomers and and doing short parataku
it's my dream job it's my dream job and it's my passion but there are also people around me who
it seems like on some level they they they need me because i don't want to my own horn i don't
want to sound egotistical but i am more stable than them and they do have serious problems um
i don't want to toot my own horn or anything but but it does sometimes feel like
i'm i'm their rock in a sense and i'm happy to do it but there are days when it gets to you
i think if anybody's had to care for anybody else whether you're whether you have a family
or whether you're taking care of your parents or or whatever it is that you're doing
i think you i think you know what i'm talking about there are days when it gets to you there
are days when you it feels like you can't do everything or that you're letting or that no
matter what you do or that no matter what you prioritize you're letting somebody somewhere down
or that all the things that that have to be done there's just too many you know and from e3 until
prime day i mean from e3 until now but but to a greater extent from e3 until prime day it felt
like i was putting out a lot of fires all the time and not really getting ahead anyway i didn't
mean for this to to be this serious i didn't want to get you guys down or anything i just wanted to
explain to you what i've been doing and also to let you know that i will in fact be back
i have a new sfo video planned for tomorrow all of the behind the scenes work is finally done
i'm good to go you're gonna see videos again if you're one of the people who watches game boomers
you're gonna see streams again and if if any of my my unboxings or my vlogs or my technological
content or any of my other side projects sound interesting to you head over to my youtube
channel called the dev kit and check that out that that's going to be my anything goes channel
so if you are a supporter of me and of sfo and you're really only here for the political content
i understand why most of this video didn't really appeal to you because it's me explaining stuff
that's for the most part not related to the political content um if you do care about me
though as as a person or if you care about my side projects then well then that's what's been going
on and if you care to check out my side projects i would be very grateful because i put it just
as much work into them as i do into sfo um i stream pretty much six nights a week now
at twitch.tv slash game boomers the stream archive goes up at youtube.com slash game boomers
and as for that anything goes channel the the dev kit i'm actually considering starting to do stream
super cuts on that channel as well so if you can't actually sit down and watch multiple hours of
stream a day you can at least see like the highlights of of some of the games but that's
a project that i'll be working on maybe maybe when the fall rolls around well if you've made
to the end of this video thank you very much for sticking with me i do have to slightly disappoint
you by saying that this update video is in fact today's video on the sfo channel but you know what
i am back i am ready i have new videos coming you will see a new sfo video tomorrow a new proper one
tomorrow however right now as this video is playing for you immediately assuming that you're
watching it while it's uh it's coming out i'm gonna be streaming this on game boomers at twitch.tv
slash game boomers life is strange too this thing comes out at 12 noon today and man am i gonna be
ready for it i love making fun of this sjw piece of crap i know that you guys love it whenever we
do this game it's always hilarious so we're going to be doing that right now in fact if you
bop over to the twitch channel you'll probably see a screen something like this i mean probably lower
in timer that by the time you see it but you'll probably see a screen something like this because
we're going to be going live soon please consider swinging by and checking us out i will see you
there shortly i love you
so