On April 12th, 2018, two African-American men were arrested for loitering in a Starbucks.
This is a topic I covered in detail on my April 22nd video titled Starbucks and the
Belligerents of Black American Subculture, and I recommend you go back and watch that
one before checking this one out, if you haven't already.
And I'd just like to point out, most of the time I choose the title of these videos
after I've completed them, I really didn't think that one was going to be so spicy until
after I'd uploaded it.
In any case, due to this incident, on April 15th, Starbucks released a statement revealing
that all locations would be closed on May 29th for racial bias education training for
approximately 175,000 of the company's American employees.
It would later be revealed that this would not be limited to just the United States and
would include both managers and part-time staff.
Starbucks CEO at the time, Howard Schultz, described the four-hour training course as
just the beginning, offered the two rightfully-arrested men free tuition because they refused to either
make a purchase or leave the establishment when asked, and stated that, "...we're
living in a time in America where there is a fracturing of humanity."
Schultz would almost immediately step down as CEO of Starbucks after this incident, handing
the reins over to Kevin Johnson, who would continue in his predecessor's cuck steps
by personally flying to Philly to apologize to the two arrested men.
Johnson would reiterate Starbucks' commitment to Schultz's diversity training plan stating
that, "...closing our stores for racial bias training is just one step in a journey
that requires dedication from every level of our company and partnerships in our local
communities."
On May 29th, Starbucks locations across the US as well as Canada and other countries did
actually close for this racial bias training, and a viewer of the channel actually has a
partner who is a manager at a Starbucks here in Canada and has provided me with pictures
of the training package.
We'll go over this package in detail a little later, but for now let's see what this
viewer has to say about it from their own mouth.
Hey Dev!
Today is sensitivity training for every Starbucks employee in North America.
I think I've told you before, but my partner works at a Starbucks in Toronto.
Part of her job is doing schedules as well as managing employees.
Expect a lot of stories to come out of this, because people are not happy about this.
Everyone has to take the training on the retail end of Starbucks, and I mean everyone.
Even people who work three jobs are being made to take the training.
My partner's already had tons of people say things like, hey I can't make it but
I'm mixed race so I probably don't need it.
Management is forcing them to reschedule and take the sensitivity training later.
It doesn't matter if you're the blackest, gayest chick in the world, you have to take
it.
I'm surprised to see Starbucks not fold and let black people out of it.
My partner didn't have any recordings, but a lot of this stuff was done through video
files on iPads distributed by Starbucks.
100% chance that those files leak pretty damn fast.
Every store in North America had this lesson, and a lot of employees are pissed.
Even management hates this.
So the way this was presented was everyone was broken off into large groups and asked
to discuss every question as they answered it in the book.
They were presented with a video beforehand that I wish I had on hand to show you, but
my partner couldn't get her hands on it.
Some ridiculous propaganda video showing American civil rights footage and talking about making
America better even though this is Canada.
The booklet also clearly has stuff aimed at black people in it, just without saying black
people.
They were told that Canada would get an adapted version that focuses more on native problems,
but that wasn't true.
Okay, so she just gave me more details and we got a bit of a bombshell.
Starbucks not only wanted the pamphlets back after completion, but they also wanted people's
names on them.
It seems like they wanted to keep records of what people answered.
In fact, Starbucks is still asking for them back.
Some stores were better about getting them back right away, but her store is so big that
the management didn't really give a shit about hounding people down for theirs.
How predictably Orwellian of you, Starbucks, to want everybody to sign their names on their
answer sheets, so you know exactly who is guilty of wrongthink.
And it also sounds like there's a lot of misconduct, misinformation, and mismanagement
of the whole ridiculous program.
But there is one thing that really did stand out to me.
That Starbucks is really, really intent on having all the materials returned to them.
It seems like they may not want it to get out.
And I'm not surprised.
An article in the Daily Mail claims that employees were shown video after video of black people
being abused during racial sensitivity training, while USA Today reported that hip-hop artist
Common was in on the video sections, surely to maximize the cringe factor.
And the centerpiece of the entire presentation was an edited version of the documentary Story
of Access by Stanley Nelson.
Now, all of these videos and iPads described by the person who provided me with this info?
It turns out they're actually all privated videos on Starbucks' YouTube channel.
And the course content for this diversity training program?
It's all online, on the website StarbucksChannel.com, on a buried page inconspicuously titled The
Third Place.
This is just a hunch, I don't have any real evidence for this, but I have a feeling that
Starbucks knew it had to make this information public at some point, but decided to just
quietly publish it on a side site with privated materials in the hopes that nobody would actually
notice.
Thankfully, the SJW ghost town outlet known as Boing Boing stupidly embedded one of the
privated videos into an article, which is how I found all this hidden stuff in the first
place.
A video whose description linked back to The Third Place.
Why do I think they wanted to keep it quiet, though?
Because I've gone over the pamphlet, the videos, and the exam, and oh boy, it is all fucking
ridiculous.
But don't take my word for it.
Let's you and I take this diversity training course for ourselves, shall we?
So here's The Third Place, our commitment renewed.
It says it's a three minute read.
I have a feeling that it's probably not a three minute read.
On May 29th, we closed 8,000 Starbucks stores in the United States for four hours, so 175,000
Starbucks partners could come together for a conversation and learning session on racial
bias.
This was a foundational step in renewing Starbucks as a place where all people feel welcome.
Starbucks partners shared life experiences, heard from others, listened to experts on
bias and racial anxiety, reflecting on the realities of bias in our society and talking
about how all of us can work together to create public spaces where everyone feels like they
belong.
When they're talking about racial anxiety, I wonder if they actually brought up white
anxiety?
Our mission, because we want to uplift others, we exist.
No, what?
To inspire and nurture the human spirit, one person, one cup, and one neighborhood at a
Our values, because we want to deliver on our mission, we show up by creating a culture
of warmth and belonging where everyone is welcome, acting with courage, challenging
the status quo and finding new ways to grow our company and each other, being present,
connecting with transparency, dignity, and respect, delivering our very best in all we
do, holding ourselves accountable for results.
So far, this just seems like a regular training bullshit program that you have to go through
any time you're a new employee, but it does get a bit juicier later.
Our mission and values, ground rules, why we're here today, practice, seeing difference
is positive, who we are, who we aspire to be, practice reflecting on what belonging
feels like, understanding bias, practice becoming color brave, color brave, okay, structural
bias, practice envisioning belonging, making every customer feel they belong, practice,
see, respect, uplift, commitments, practice building new habits, okay, well, here's the
team guidebook, this guidebook was designed for groups of three to five Starbucks partners
to work through the relaying session at their own pace, okay, so basically what ended up
happening is they got groups of people together, they gave them an iPad and a team guidebook
and they had to basically follow a four hour training program and let's take a look at
this guidebook.
The first couple pages just seem to be the preamble redone, so there's 68 pages to this
thing, Jesus, okay, let's scroll through this here, there's our mission, the agenda, okay,
working together today, get into groups of three to five people, team up with people
you don't work closely with every day, team guidebook, one per team, iPad, please share
and be patient, come on now kids, you have to share and my notebook is 100% private except
when you hand in the my notebook to Starbucks management but we will get to the my notebook
section later, how to set up your iPad, find an available iPad, place it on the white rectangle
above, turn it on, so like they want you to actually insert the iPad into the book, okay,
also you have to lift the iPad to turn the page and it tells you right here, lift the
iPad, turn the page, so okay, let's keep going, ground rules, listen respectfully, speak your
truth and honour other people's truth, I'm not sure if they know the meaning of the word
truth, if your conversations get off track, pause and restart, yeah, don't have your own
thoughts here guys, just follow along, tips for getting back on track, say what you want
to pause, share what you're feeling, talk about it, in your working group for today
acknowledge it, we hear you, we hear you, we can't create a culture of warmth and belonging
if we don't first acknowledge that some of us deal with negative stereotypes every day,
we hear you, we can't connect with dignity and respect if we don't respect the different
starting points we all had in life, write it down in your notebook and revisit it later,
okay, this really feels like a grade 3 or a grade 4 social studies class man, video
1, Starbucks EVP Rosanne Williams, I'm showing your respect today, instructions, put an iPad
above, select video 1 on the iPad, so they want you to actually place the iPad in the
book and then play the video, I'm actually, I do have the videos down here, let's scroll
down a bit and here's video 1, let's watch it okay, just a YouTube embed, hello partners,
I wanted to share a few thoughts before you begin today, first of all, thank you in advance
for investing your time with one another, this is a needed conversation and one the
Starbucks family is more than capable of having, we are about creating a culture of warmth
and belonging where everyone is welcome, with that in mind, please remember a few things,
first listen respectfully, second speak with your truth and honour the truth of others,
third, if you need to take a moment, feel free to do so, conversations about race can
induce a feeling the experts call racial anxiety and when we're anxious, we can't always think
clearly, if this feeling starts to derail the conversation, there are a few things that
you can do as a group to get back on track, first let the group know you want to pause,
share what you're feeling in the most respectful way possible and then as a group, have a short
conversation about what was shared, remember to be present and listen with respect, this
is about you and your Starbucks family sharing this experience together, if you find you
need more support, please know that additional resources are available and more information
can be found at the bottom of this page in this guidebook, wow, ok, I don't know, racial
anxiety, ok, let's keep going here, why we are here today, this is just a second video
isn't it, yeah it is, Starbucks president and CEO Kevin Johnson, why are we here today,
video 2, video 3, artist, author and activist comment, oh here's the rapper, on making others
feel welcome, ok, ok, ok, so hold on, videos 2 and 3 have to be watched now, let's enjoy
this a little bit, ok, so let us begin, we are here to make Starbucks a place where everyone,
everyone feels welcome, full stop, even if you don't pay guys, you're still welcome,
there is the immediate reason we are gathering, and that is the disheartening situation that
unfolded in Philadelphia, where two young men were arrested in a Starbucks store, but
the issue of racial bias and discrimination isn't just about us as a company, it is about
us as a country, prejudice and public accommodation is deeply rooted in America, and core to our
mission has always been being that third place where everyone feels welcome, but the reality
is being that third place in 2018 is far more challenging, current year, homelessness, substance
abuse in our bathrooms, mental illness, these are all issues that a good portion, substance abuse in
your bathrooms, do you think that's going to get better or worse if you start allowing people in
who haven't bought anything, and you can just let them in, what do you think man, what do you think,
if you face each and every day, yet my hope in gathering us is that Starbucks can become a place
of welcoming, of warmth, and of inclusion for all, now given the state of race relations in this
country, it's easy to wonder if inclusion for all is even possible, here's my belief, growing up this
term called colorblind, described a learning behavior of pretending not to notice race, that
doesn't even make sense, so today we're starting a new journey, talking about race directly, what my
friend and Starbucks board member Melody Hobson calls being color brave, oh color brave, that's
what it means, okay, okay, okay, so here's, here's the deal, here's the deal, no longer are we expected
to treat people equally regardless of their skin color, we have to be color brave, we have to
understand that I guess the darkies need to be treated differently because they're not white,
is that what you're saying here, Starbucks CEO, so here is what we will do together today,
we'll begin by welcoming each other and by sharing who we are and having curiosity about others,
we will explore America's history of prejudice in public spaces and we will learn about bias,
where it comes from, and that it's a normal part of each person, and we'll talk about some ways
that we can work together to help others feel welcome, to feel included, to feel valued,
even in those situations where customers may not treat us in the same way,
and please keep this in mind, you are not alone, we know that for every, I'm just gonna stop here,
I've been to some gender studies classes in the past, this seems remarkably like that,
so let's move on to video three here, I do want to see what our rapper has to say about this,
I am grateful to be with you Starbucks partners today because this work is close to my heart,
helping people see each other fully, completely, respectfully, my role throughout this day is to
get us started in good conversation, let's start first by appreciating each other,
I know that for me welcoming people in my life starts first with sharing who I am and then
listening closely to where someone else is coming from, who they are, what they are proud of,
what makes them them, now usually when we do this kind of thing in our everyday lives in America,
we try to find similarity between people, we try to find ways in which we are alike,
and that's good, yet it turns out there's also great advantage in your work, in your life,
in your relationships, to learn to love what makes you different from someone else,
to seek out how someone is different, and that is what makes them interesting,
it's a life skill to make someone else in your presence feel welcome, you do that by not only
loving what makes them the same as you, but by appreciating what makes them different than you,
now you're going to hear from Starbucks partners who will guide you through the day,
to start building the life skill of appreciating people's differences,
get your notebook out and turn to what makes me, me, and you, you, it should be at the front of
your book, this guy really seems like he was told to do this or he was going to be fired,
yeah let's just get back to this, let's get back to the the actual pamphlet here that we got,
we have like 63 pages here Jesus, seeing what makes us unique and different, grab your notebook,
pair it with somebody in your group, this really is grade school shit,
open your notebook to page four to the activity what makes me, me, and you, you, when you're done
return to the team guidebook to discuss with the group, holy shit man I'm legit having childhood
flashbacks, discuss with your team which pair found the most differences, how did you find
so many, what questions did you ask, how did you ask them, now that you see the other person you
talk to more clearly, what new information do you appreciate about them, man what if someone
is like I don't want to talk about my personal life in this exercise, I came here to do a job,
I want to get paid and go home, are they going to be like no you must tell me about all your
differences, do you really got to get into this shit, take a 15-minute break it's been fucking
grueling guys, Starbucks who we are, who we aspire to be, oh god do you really want to watch all
these videos, how many videos are there, let me just see this here, three, four, five, what it
feels like to belong, seven, eight, now whole, holy shit, oh my, I can't believe actually having to
have done this, Jesus, I'm sorry Starbucks employees, these audio clips seem to be like
examples, okay hold on, confusion about a customer's gender, let's listen to this,
seems to be an audio sample of what to do, so I was working in the store one weekend and we were
a store that's on a transit line, the bus dropped off right in front of our store and then every
time every bus let out everybody'd come in, get some coffee, want to use the bathroom because
they're in the midst of a trip, we had one customer come in specifically who asked for
the men's restroom key and that's where we had two separate keys, one was blue for the men's and the
other one was pink for the women's, they asked for the men's key and we handed them the women's key
because although the individual identified male they looked female to us working behind the
counter, the customer then said no I really identify male and I've asked you for the men's key
so we handed them the men's key and said hey we're really sorry that that happened,
here's the key that you asked for, go ahead and you can go around the corner to the to the
bathroom, our bathroom was in a shared building so when the customer went into the main building
they were actually told by security that they weren't even allowed to access the men's room
because the building said that they didn't believe that they were a male either, which
point the customer came back in and became very irate, we told them we were really sorry
that we'd done the best we could at that point in time. Absolutely harrowing, I mean it does sound
like a terrible inconvenience that they might have to go to a restroom that they don't really
identify with and take their shit there. Women with dirty cup asks for refill, how, okay.
Okay so one morning a lady came in she was wearing a sweat and she had a paper cup our Starbucks cup
and she said she wants to get a coffee, a cup of coffee refill and
but the cup was really dirty and has like a lot of stains on it and so I said when did you,
when did you get this coffee, when did you get the first cup and she said this morning
but the fact that the coffee cup was really dirty I said to her that she cannot get a refill.
Okay that actually sounds reasonable because it seems like maybe this person had like found a cup
that was old or had a cup from several days ago that had kind of gone through the wear and tear
and was no longer entitled to a refill. Why is this part of this package?
Women in dirty sweatpants lingering near retail cups. There was a woman in dirty sweatpants
lingering near retail cups. There was a busy morning at my store back in downtown
where a lady came in and her sweatpants had stains in them and they also had holes
so I quickly told my partners like hey I'm gonna switch over to warming so that I can keep my eye
on her and I noticed her going back and forth back and forth from the retail cups it was during
Christmas so we had all the red box cups and she I assumed she was going to steal and I approached
her and I said would you like any help with anything and turns out that she wanted to buy one
as a gift. Okay as somebody who has worked retail in the past you do get to know the the body
language and the behaviors of people who are trying to shoplift. Recognizing those patterns
is not a bad thing. Jesus I can't believe this where do these where do all these clips show up
in this thing I gotta scroll back up and see this hold on hold on hold on hold on hold on
okay okay fuck the team guidebook here we go page 50 making every customer feel like they
belong at Starbucks listen to all the audios every human must be seen respected and uplifted
whether or not they're customers oh shit you have to like seen respected it like fill out one of
these for each for each scenario oh wow okay well here here's here's what we can do to make
these vagrants in our store feel welcome let's get back back to where we were a little bit here
I don't know if I want to go through all this guys like holy shit there's a lot of
nonsense here however however I did realize that video six is colorblind to color brave
so let's watch that one all right I want to get to it with the hard question how do you define
bias what is it so bias is our brains look at this incredibly diverse panel automatic association
and processing of negative stereotypes about certain groups of people so that sounds somewhat
clinical if you could break it down even further so when we talk about bias we're actually talking
about two kinds of bias there's explicit bias which is when we are very consciously do not
particularly care for a group the implicit bias is when our brains have made associations about
a particular group negative stereotypes about a particular group that have become embedded in our
brains over time so how do you know it when you're doing it how do you know it when you see it hold
on hold on hold on what matters here isn't necessarily the bias it's the behavior explicit
bias can obviously be a problem because it actually leads to explicit behaviors um implicit
bias almost never generates itself as behavior like if you if you feel a certain way about a
particular race or or a particular gender or a particular type of person and it's implicit
and you don't act on it and your behavior doesn't change then what what harm's been done are unless
of course you want to thoughtfully everybody you want to control what people think how about going
at it that way you often don't know it when you're doing it because if it's an implicit bias that
means you have it in the back of your brain you're not conscious of it and in fact it can be
completely inconsistent with your actual beliefs so oftentimes the risk is you in fact don't know
when you're making an automatic association do you think our company should be one of those
institutions that helps people understand their biases do you think that's the job of a of a
company like ours if we're going no we're going to have a business where we're interfacing with
the public i think we're responsible to help a workforce navigate these nuances and relationships
and human connection personally i've realized i have a big beard i have a line in my head
that that smile of hers back there that was her saying you just kept your job son i can be
capable i can be competent and i can lead people and i can you know be an individual an individual
as long as you think the right way compassion empathy i think those are great places to start
so a lot of people talk about being colorblind what is it about color blindness that creates
a problem here we go our brains can't not see people's different racial categories that's the
way we've grown up to evaluate people so we can't turn that off and this is something that fred
talked about beautifully it seems to me from what i hear from my friends who are people of color
they don't want me to not see them as their full selves and for many if it's something that we
can't change you can't be colorblind it is impossible for humanity or individual humans
to be colorblind then what's the point what's the point of any of this i mean if we are stuck as
these miserable wretches who are always destined to be racist then what is the point of all this
just just fucking give up people their full selves involves a sense of racial identity
help me understand as practitioners how you explain to people what implicit bias is so that
they can start to recognize it we usually start by having people understand how their
unconscious brain works so we have an exercise that we could do that would give us all a chance
to see what it means to have your unconscious brain overcome your conscious brain okay how does
it work sure okay okay i'm going to give you what is called a stroup test so in order to talk about
bias it's really important to understand how our brains operate unconsciously we're going to take
the stroup test which was invented by dr stroup in 1935 it's a group activity so i want you all
to state the color of the text let's try one together blue blue did you all say blue together
great let the test begin oh jesus it's gonna be one of these eh it's gonna be a thing where like
it it'll change yeah yeah see see what it's doing see what it's doing it's going faster and faster
and it's having a word but a different color so for example this says red but it's actually black
and you're reading you're not looking at color um what this has to do with fucking racism i have
no clue at my store i have a transit uh gentleman um his name is steve he comes in every day but
he's a customer um but his appearance um is that of somebody who lives on the street my initial
response was i don't know this guy uh he's not really supporting the atmosphere that i want to
have in here um but i had to check that and engage and just watch you know and and talk and and now
we're good friends um does steve buy anything because that's really what matters it doesn't
matter that you guys are friends it doesn't matter how he dresses what matters is that
he comes in with money and buys coffee that's it and he comes in there all the time this is
the type of moments that we're trying to create so tell me about the difference between personal
bias which i think which is a lot of people feel the weight of and feel the shame of
and structural bias if you think about kind of where someone lives where they go to school
the transportation system that helps them get there all of those systems all those places of
how we just navigate our daily life in today's very segregated society some people have been
afforded access other people haven't wait today's very segregated society one america has not been
segregated for some time now two with all this talk of not being colorblind and recognizing
differences that's creating segregation that rapper from earlier talked all about focusing
on differences and not how they're the same how is that not a segregating force in society you
talk about this idea of racial anxiety what is that racial anxiety is our our bodies are in our
brain stress response to cross-racial interaction and it shows up differently if i'm a person of
color and i'm engaging in across racial interaction i'm worried that whatever's coming towards me my
defense mechanism goes up right and if you're white it's showing up as a big fear that you
may confirm yourself as racist you may say something or do something okay oh oh oh so so
here here's racial anxiety if you're white you're afraid you're going to be outed as a racist if
you're a non-white or a person of color you fear for your life you fear i i don't know like it
couldn't it couldn't possibly be the other way around could it it couldn't it couldn't possibly
be that a white person fears a black person or that a non-white person fears being outed as racist
and really you're just talking about whites and non-whites like everything that's non-white is
just one giant category how how do jewish people fit into this how do asians fit into this how do
native people fit into this none of this really seems to make any sense but the racial anxiety
actually helps us understand that that interpersonal work that we need to do is really one of the key
things that's getting in the way why is bias bad for business if there are any groups who feel like
they're not treated as well who feel like they're being othered as our colleague john powell would
say and don't have that sense of belonging that starbucks talks about that's bad for business
something else you said that's really important is how the partners feel obviously well see that's
where capitalism steps in in a purely capitalistic system it would not matter your race or gender or
anything else the only thing that matters is whether or not you have the money to buy something
at starbucks so you can be a homeless man with money come in buy your coffee you're welcome there
you can be a black person come in buy your coffee you're welcome there you can be
any type of human if you have money you're welcome in the store those two black guys who were
arrested they didn't buy anything which is why this isn't a race issue which is why this entire
exercise is pointless starbucks actually has a very multi-racial multi-ethnic multi-religious
staff and so in order for the people who are partners to be their best selves they need to
feel supported so today when we close down our stores to get more training and hopefully come
away with more learnings around bias explicit and implicit structural and personal can we structurally
change the organization through something like this some are skeptical so i think we would say
the structural work is something that has to be done for far longer than the four-hour day
and that's policy that's the work the company has to do to support the partners in the individual
work and the teamwork that they do within here's what sjws often mean when they say structure when
they talk about structures they say this is something that needs to be constantly reinforced
and that's why it's going to take longer than this four-hour program it's an ideology that needs to
be hammered in every day because if it's not people are going to realize that it's bullshit
their institutions because one of the things we don't want to see is for each person to have
to bear this burden alone and also so the partners can themselves be treated respectfully by each
other because the partners can be on the receiving end of all this as well fred anything that you
think we could leave behind for our partners as they think about bias if they had one takeaway
that could help them be better assuming everyone wants to be better at this with the third place
in the human connections that we're trying to make when you feel like there's uh there's an
there's something uncomfortable happening let's listen let's take that moment that pause um to
listen and and sort of center ourselves the other piece is body language if we can feel comfortable
enough to come from around our counter um to actually connect with that person who is
disappointed or maybe we had a perceived bias about but we're going to listen we're going to
be present our body language is not going to be this but we're going to be here we're going to
be present for that conversation i think that begins to open up a world of opportunity when we
when we talk about connection and we want to be in a space that's respectful with them and not
come in with preconceived or structural or stereotypical notions about the individual
thank you thanks very much wow that told me nothing jesus christ i'm not going through
this pamphlet anymore there's a few things i want to check out though before we uh we finish up this
this training exercise today here guys i want to watch video eight because this is the stanley
nelson documentary and i do want to check out one more thing after this so let's watch this
documentary first a stanley nelson story of access this independently created film by stanley nelson
was underwritten by starbucks with the intent of educating our partners about the history of access
to public spaces for african americans this film explores the impact of bias within public
accommodations as well as the possibilities for a better future dear starbucks partners
i'm stanley nelson a documentary filmmaker my films are about race america and the decades long
struggle for all people to be treated as equals in public spaces our town squares our stores our
fields our parks our pools our restaurants congratulations you have it now and have had it
for some time i made this film to help us understand this important struggle in our country
so we can go forward together
when i go into stores sometimes i get followed which is really annoying and it just gives me
like it just makes me uncomfortable and sometimes i get anxiety so i have to leave
oh geez i'm i'm sorry that your anxiety your anxiety is what makes you leave i gotta be honest
i'm a white guy and sometimes i i've gone into stores and i've been followed too
and as a retail worker you know sometimes you you you notice somebody maybe maybe their body
language has been off maybe they're doing something odd maybe you at the very least
want to keep an eye on them to make sure that they're not going to steal and it's it's been
in my experience less about race and more about how people present themselves you know i've i've
seen white shoplifters and i've seen native shoplifters here in canada and and i've never
shoplifted however i have had employees of stores follow me around and it's it's obvious that they're
following me around because they're not really that sneaky but they're following me around
like they think i'm going to shoplift and it's not a race thing especially being a teen of color
they assume that you're doing something bad i feel like i'm disturbing people by just being there
like people feel uncomfortable when i walk in i guess i've kind of become numb to it after so
many years like this is just my life and it's just something that i've gotten used to unfortunately
i think all of us make that choice at some point of am i going to take the burden of this
interaction being comfortable or am i going to say you take the burden of this interaction
being comfortable who goes into a social interaction thinking that way really who starts
talking to somebody with the presumption that if you don't do something this is going to be
uncomfortable like holy shit because what i really want is a sandwich do you know what i mean i don't
want to fight i'm hungry right i don't want to get into this with you and i'm really not here to
teach you this but other time then why are you here it's like okay wait a minute lesson time
discrimination against african americans in public spaces has a long history in the 1960s
black and white students trying to desegregate buses were firebombed it was terrible thankfully
we've moved past it black patrons were routinely denied service in restaurants and hotels
it was terrible thankfully we've moved past it as long as you have the money to actually
pay for your stuff though not at starbucks apparently
and civil rights workers were dragged from lunch counters spat upon and beaten
we're willing to be beaten for democracy and you must use democracy the right to be respected in
public spaces was at the heart of the civil rights movement
they keep thinking we begging them for something we ain't begging for nothing we're telling them
see the difference between these clips and what's going on at starbucks is that these people are
actually confronting a legitimate problem in the society in which they lived the two guys at
starbucks went in didn't order anything and were asked to leave and then they didn't and then the
cops were called on them this is this is not illegal this is not a situation of them being
arrested because they're black this is not a situation of misuse of police power frankly it
almost denigrates the sacrifice of these people from the 1960s by comparing it to this ridiculous
bullshit happening today the freedom movement of the 1950s and 60s insisted that the united states
live up to its constitution and allow equal access for all
finally the civil rights act of 1964 was passed outlawing discrimination in public spaces
but changing the law doesn't always change
reality and being allowed in doesn't always mean being welcomed
to be welcomed as a customer means that not only do i allow you in but it means that i'm glad
you're here i i want to serve you i want your business and i don't draw distinctions between
you and other customers in terms yes yes yes i don't draw distinctions between you and other
customers not you and other people you and other customers the implication is that you've paid for
a good or a service in terms of your value but it's time we talk about what it means
to not be welcomed as an american citizen it's not like i can mute my actual physical blackness
right so i just i mean according to this chinese laundry commercial you you probably could
do
assume that people see a particular thing when they see the color of my skin so everything else
has to be like perfect and clean and as blended in as possible is no you just you just have to
have money you just have to go into a starbucks with money and be willing to buy something
that's all no nobody cares about anything else really just an arsenal of different masks
you know is one of those masks made of money um and it happens every time i
every time i leave my house when i leave my house regardless of where i'm going the
i'm just leaving my house just walking out the door i don't i'm not walking out the door thinking
what kind of hurdle am i going to run into today what kind of way am i going to be judged i walk
out a free man i just okay okay um on the one hand i see what this guy is saying because people
and i assume this is also the case for people who have not internalized their own goddamn racism
towards themselves so like you know kanye west for example people like that they probably just
walk out the door thinking yeah you know whatever i gotta go out and do something i'm gonna go out
and do it um at the same time everyone and i mean everyone regardless of race will go out the door
and think how they're going to be judged that's why you comb your hair well if you if you had
hair i assume you'd comb it that's why you don't wear dirty clothes that's why you shower before
you go outside you get judged for a lot more than race and and honestly you get judged for some
things way harsher than race man i mean jordan peterson said it best would you rather be ugly
or be an immigrant just do my thing i have to make sure that i have given enough space between
myself and another patron or another uh commuter on the train just ensure that i'm not making
someone uncomfortable i have to make sure they're my hand man man i do that too when i'm on the bus
unless the bus is packed i'm not going to just jam myself beside somebody it's not about your
skin color it's about not being rude things are visible when i walk into certain places so they
make sure i don't not stealing um i try to make sure i make eye contact with people who may or may
not be security or managerial staff just ensure that you know i'm not here to hide anything uh
i watch my tone to make sure that i don't come off as threatening just leaving the house some days you
know it's it's it sounds it sounds so terrible that you have to be a decent human being in public
you know because these are all things that i also do as a white person and that i assume
most decent people do it's called not being a dick don't just keep you at home and just keep
you away from everything for more than 50 years equal treatment has been the law yet as we know
from cell phone videos the nightly news and maybe our own experience we still have a long way to go
why are you following yeah yeah i mean it's it's really terrible there are individuals out there
who are assholes and if you want to like catch them on video put it on youtube and say this guy's
an asshole go ahead i'll probably laugh at it at some point when i come across it
but that's pretty much the extent of it this is not some kind of systemic problem
watch this
you think i'm stealing your card is fake you're going to jail that's what i kept
we just okay okay so some of these instances are going to be legitimate police brutality
and obviously that's not a good thing i mean we don't even have to really go down that road do we
but at the same time how many of these people do you think turned it into a race issue like the
police had a legitimate reason to arrest one of these people or at the very least talk to them
about something and they just said oh you're doing this because i'm black and then escalated it and
then it turned into a shit show like do you think that that might have happened once or twice indeed
that black people are navigating the public space differently than white people
and how much of that is their own choice really how many didn't do nothing do you think are
actually out there how many good boys just going to college that women are navigating the public
space differently than men and not use the shortcut that has been wired into your brain
because of the society that we live in that tells you when you see me you should be nervous
or you should be worried it i'm not nervous or worried i'm just stunned brought me such despair
to the day i recognized i had to explain this to my son that he was gonna that that this muddy
river of racism he was still gonna have to walk through it we hadn't damned it we hadn't dried
it up it was still there for him to go through and i've got to somehow try to tell him okay
off you go maybe if you didn't keep focusing on your differences maybe maybe if the black
community wasn't ridiculously belligerent when it came to police interaction maybe if black fathers
actually stuck around their families then you wouldn't have this muddy river of racism but you
know what at this point i think it's safe to say that at least a fair chunk of it is definitely the
black community's own doing the society i want to see is i want to be able to walk out the house
just as free feeling as that white guy who said he doesn't worry about a thing when he walks out
the door i want well that's on you isn't it how you feel isn't that your responsibility if you
were to say i want to walk out the door as free as a white guy well you have that now don't you
but free feeling well that's on you it's not anybody else's responsibility to make you feel
better want to have that same expectation today discrimination is against the law
it's the people and the systems that support our communities that must follow suit yes absolutely
changing the law is not enough we also must force people to change we must force a cultural change
everything is racist everything is sexist and you must point it all out no one's going to do it for
us what can you do to make our schools our parks our stores our restaurants as welcoming and as
inclusive as they can be um treat oh dude she's a cutie um treat people equally that is really why
capitalism is probably the best system for equality because it simply says if you have
money you are welcome and race and gender and none of that nonsense actually matters
what kind of country do we want to live in who do we want to be
okay well i regret doing this let's uh let's turn this piece of shit off the last thing i want to go
to is the my notebook now this is where employees have to actually fill this out a space for your
private thoughts however you're expected to give it back to starbucks management so it's not really
private is it what makes me me and you you this is the first exercise they had to do similarities
bond us together yet being able to perceive what makes us unique and different from each other
gives us the gift of seeing each other as full human beings pair up with somebody on your team
keep time using your phone how classless of starbucks to assume everyone has a phone try
to find as many ways as you can that you are different from each other okay so again focus
on differences generate that segregation in your life where do you feel a sense of belonging feeling
welcome feeling included feeling like yourself well really the only place where you have a right
to feel a sense of belonging is in your own house frankly that's pretty much it the first step to
becoming color brave read through the following pages take your time seeing how bias operates
takes reflection and introspection our unconscious brain processes 11 million bits of information a
second in that same time our conscious brain processes only 40 bits thus we process more
unconsciously than consciously well i'm sure that anybody can work out this math
without the third sentence there but uh this sounds like some ridiculous bullshit right here
okay 11 million bits from information a second let me just let me just work this out 11 11 million
bits in gigabytes okay it's 1.375 okay in in megabytes 1.3 megs okay so let's say that our
unconscious brain processes 1.3 megs of information a second only 40 bits in our conscious brain i i
don't think this is true forget about the the ridiculousness of measuring human brain capacity
in in a computer term like like bits but only 40 bits okay that's five bytes what can you store
in five bytes of memory if i can think of a word in my conscious brain that is say 15 letters long
some long ass word i'm already storing more than five bytes right if i can think of a song is is
one second of remembered song more than five bytes i think it might be look how stupid this
is already okay let's keep going though jesus christ our brains do this because they must if
we had to process everything consciously the day would be so exhausting we'd never get through it
to help us function our brains take shortcuts when shortcuts are applied to the characteristics
traits and behaviors of a certain group of people they are called stereotypes there's no way this is
scientifically accurate there is no way this is actually how the psychology works stereotypes are
shaped by the things we take in around us much of it comes through the media but also our experiences
and the broader culture we live in so is this starbucks admitting that stereotypes actually
have a basis of truth in them maybe the risk is that when we hold negative stereotypes unconscious
bias can arise when we're under pressure are short on time or don't pay attention unconscious
biases are triggered more easily we can hold biases about race and age and religion gender
and sexuality and body type ability and mental health and class and many other attributes
i just have to straight up agree here i mean my monk in dnd might be really really fat but
you can't have a bias based on his body type he can flip bears over man that's why it's important
that we learn about how our biases are framed what we can do to override them biases are not always
easy to identify they make us feel exposed maybe even critical of ourselves but they're worth
reflecting on this is basically where they say you might feel that hunch of rationality saying
this doesn't really uh this doesn't really make sense but it's important that you ignore that
for the greater good of social justice when we address our emotions as they relate to our biases
we build the muscle that helps us override them let's try it now the first time you recall when
you first experienced your racial identity it may have been when you were a child it may have been
last week if a scenario doesn't apply to you feel free to leave it blank and move on to the next one
when you notice your racial identity noticed how your race affected your beauty standards
felt your accent impacted people's perception of your intelligence or competence
altered your communication style to avoid playing into stereotypes what if i just said
i don't feel comfortable talking about this i mean these had to be collected right am i going to get
fired for that had a friend of a different race who regularly visited your home if your group
doesn't contain a token black person i guess you're a racist imagine you're meeting two
different people for the first time one of them is of your race the other one is of a different race
without thinking too much don't think about it guys just select the level of difficulty that
reflects how you might react in each instance i'm gonna assume that most people you know most
casual western liberals are gonna put the same marker for people of your race and people of not
not of your race oh there's a glossary in here let's let's check this shit out belonging an
authentic feeling of empowerment and participation in a group experienced in a person feels safe
valued and accepted discrimination the unequal treatment of members of various groups based on
race gender social class sexual orientation physical ability religion and other categories
now it doesn't really say whether or not that unequal treatment is good or bad whether it's
deserved or not whether it's proper or not because there are certainly instances where
discrimination is actually a good thing think about it this way the most discriminating act
that any one person can do is be in a monogamous relationship right because you're saying that
i'm only having sex with this person and you are discriminating against everybody else do
we want our sexuality to be equalized now too i mean at some point you do have to choose one
thing over another and if that's always going to be discrimination and that's always going to be
bad then society basically breaks down exclusion the process or state of being set apart from other
people or things well yes i mean i'm going to exclude you from my relationship with my girlfriend
i'm going to exclude you from my store if you don't buy things and therefore are not a customer
the terminology presented in this in this key terms page is simply presented like it's supposed
to be negative when it's actually quite neutral institutional racism the ways in which institutional
policies and practices create different outcomes for different racial groups creating unbalanced
advantages for whites along with oppression and disadvantages for people from groups classified
as non-white so would you say for example that when black fathers leave their kids in a single
parent household at alarming rates that's institutional racism because that would be a
practice of the black community you know an institutional almost practice of the black
community that creates a different outcome for a different racial group with the benefit of a
stable family that whites have being some form of privilege i guess you could say racial equity
the aspirational condition that would be achieved if one's racial identity no longer predicted in a
statistical sense how one fares so it's not it's not equality guys it's equity if it's equality
well then everyone gets a fair shake and then these various things like say black fathers not
sticking around to raise their kids well i mean that that's the choice of the black father and
well i guess that means that the black kids start a little bit behind in life but it is still equal
because they had the choice not to do that but racial equity means that society must fill in
those gaps no matter the cost well once you've filled out that private workbook and handed it
off to starbucks management for further inspection interrogation of any possible wrong think you can
then watch the final video called sticking with it to be color brave is to be brave period whether
it was easy or hard for you today above all thank you for choosing to be here we began some very
important conversations today but let's be clear this is just the beginning it's a start and now
more than ever the world needs the third place a place where everyone feels they can belong
and this starts by first understanding that we each have biases and then actively working to
address them but there's more that we can do to create the third place consistent with our mission
and values we can seek and eradicate bias and racism in our systems we can work to change our
policies and processes and we can each commit to work on ourselves the more you are aware of your
bias the more you can work to disrupt it and help all people who walk into a starbucks to feel seen
to feel respected to feel uplifted my biggest ask is that every single one of us commit to this
journey we won't get it right every single time but if we stay at this we will get it right more
and more so thank you for everything you brought to today i am so proud to call you my partner
and i'm especially proud that we are on this journey together
you know what after that i feel culturally enriched i feel like i should allow a bunch
of belligerent people into my local starbucks who have no interest in buying anything and
no reason to be there except to take a steaming shit on the tables because they've got the right
skin color i want to live my life safe and secure in the fact that if i ever get a job i'm going to
be led into a closed room strapped into a chair for four hours and spoon-fed videos on how racist
and sexist i am by the company's ceo this is the bright future that i want and starbucks's ceo is
paving the way for this to be a universal oh do you think i'm joking about that you know how
schultz resigned as ceo from starbucks right around the time this whole shit storm started
well written in an article by usa today is this passage schultz's ideology has dipped into the
political sphere too his outspokenness on issues such as gay rights and refugees has fueled
speculation that he's looking to run for office perhaps president starbucks didn't comment about
plans that he's seeking elected office in his letter he didn't rule it out saying i'll be
thinking about a range of options for myself from philanthropy to public service but i'm a long way
from knowing what the future holds yeah schultz doesn't know what the future holds my ass remember
when hillary said she wasn't going to run for 2016 way back when i do i can already see the campaign
slogan schultz 2020 diversity ipads in every home i'd end this by saying the usual vote with your
wallet in regards to starbucks but i don't think that's going to work this time the people at the
top of starbucks would rather open their doors wide like a homeless shelter instead of actually
exercising their rights all because somebody called them racist they've deliberately chosen
to lose money for the sake of social justice all we can do now is wait for the end
so