I said I'd do it, so here I am.
Hello ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to The Right Opinion, the home of a twat with too much free time.
And today I follow through on something that I have been planning for the whole year, the Top 25 Best Songs of 2017.
Now obviously this video isn't quite as objective as the title will imply, it's just the one that had the best ring to it.
I accept that there are probably better songs in many regards, and I'll probably expand on that in the video at certain points.
But these are the songs that I want to come back to, time and time again, because of some special quality not held in other songs throughout this year.
2017 itself was a weird year, a lot of mainstream pop became very bland, so I ended up in this weird, hybrid, alt music genre a lot of the time.
There was a lot of great music this year, and I want to emphasise that, and a lot of songs were very painful to cut because of their fantastic quality.
However, I had to make a decision to get 25 top quality songs out.
However, before we do that, let's look at what the music reviewers call the honourable mentions.
Hey, hey, so won't you open up the sunroof, yeah
Let you go
Because I'm 18, and I still live with my parents, yeah they're not like yours, well yours I'm understanding
You hang in line, you find it hard to define, but you do it all the time, when you do it again, looking for signs of light
Run around on me, oh my god, take me slow, get it fast, go
Now, when I started compiling this list, I originally intended it to cover the top 20.
However, that plan had to change when I realised that there were some songs just below 20 that did deserve more in-depth analysis.
This wasn't one of them, but I'm still glad it's here.
I'm facing my faults, overcoming my addictions, talking out loud, when I'm talking about love
I heard this one and sunroof back when I was entering the summer and I realised they were both really good pop rock songs
But I wasn't sure which one would edge it long term, this one did.
The bright guitar riffs with the pre-chorus before it kicks in with the bass on the first verse
As this loser sings about how his life is completely fucked with the chorus being this pop drop
Which is more likeable than it has any right to be, the buzzing bass synths on the second verse, the rhythmic bridge
All encompassed by this sheer desperation just to make for this really actually enjoyable listen
It's a song about losing your wits, but it has so much fun with it that it is just impossible to ignore
And that's why this one is at 25. Love it.
This song is a bit of an outcast from the other ones on the list, it has quite a dry sound
And when I started going over my year end favourites I didn't really consider it
But listen after listen, I realised it was pretty fucking great
Liam Gallagher brings this A game on the song which is essentially a diss track to people who always want more than they can have
By hook or by crook
Firstly the drum work is fantastic, it's pulsating, it drives a great groove with fantastic blending between acoustic and electric guitar
Before this massive chorus jumps in as he tells this twat that he has the Midas touch
And this is the thing, Liam Gallagher sells it, if anyone doesn't give a fuck it is Liam Gallagher
Which makes this song even more glorious
And this beautiful beautiful part towards the end with the horns and this conglomerate of guitars everywhere
It really is special, it's a song that goes places and knows how to use Liam Gallagher
He is gonna get this person and even I'm a bit scared
I don't mind Post Malone, I think he's a pretty great guy all round, he makes some decent songs
But if you told me I'd be including him in a year end list, yeah, sure mate
Probably would have chuckled
I mean this song isn't necessarily his song, it's a feature, but it counts enough
Counts enough
Ok so first things first, any song that uses a sliding chord structure sounds pretty fucking cool
With this smokey bass line that just eats up the song
Post Malone and Watts vocals couldn't be a better combination as they are both massive warblers
And it really does complement a beat like this
I love the melodic direction as well, there's variation in vocal delivery with every single line
It gives it a very unique personality
This is also reflected in the instrumental
Which varies impressively despite its seemingly limited range of inputs
Before launching into this fantastic guitar solo
And one that we definitely need a bit more of
I haven't spoken about the lyrics because there's not too much to say
They're kicking ass and hey ho, who needs deep shit when you're kicking ass
There are a few songs that are definitely better than their brand
Once again that's mainly because this video is quite personal to me
With that said it doesn't mean that songs can't be appreciated for their craftsmanship
And this next one is definitely an example of that
This song is an instrumental masterpiece
Really integrating a lot of the oriental inspiration for this song
With very glossy yet fleshed out synthesizers
With this shimmering piano and smooth backing vocals
And intermittent guitar work all composed together so well
It really lends for a particularly lingering atmosphere
There's this constant state of musical evolution throughout this five minutes
Going over musical bridges and transitions and so much more
It's really quite beautiful
The song itself is about envy and how the artist would love to have the clout to tour the world
It's a personal message, maybe one that doesn't quite resonate with me
Or with the mood of the song
But I can still admire it nonetheless
As number 22 proved, I do place emphasis on a song's instrumental work
I still prefer a complete piece even if some parts may be weaker on an individual basis
As contrast, number 21 proves incredibly strong in all categories
Hence why it's just above Tokyo
I mean, let's get something clear here
The instrumental work is still fantastic
You can never have too many guitar tones
But the mood of this is much deeper
Maybe too deep for some
As he cryptically and desperately searches for meanings and roots to his aforementioned pain
It is brooding, it is thoughtful
And it's interwoven with beautiful guitar work
It's all here
I think I counted at least three different guitar solos
The song just lets you slip away to it
Without revealing too much
It may not be a tearjoker
But it is one that just stops you
And leaves you in a very contemplative mood
And for that, it's really quite special
So, now the top 20, the tracks that we're always gonna beat here
This next track demonstrates how I value emotional resonance
As an important factor to how I enjoy a song
Arguably not as complex as the previous songs
But one that still touches me
Nonetheless
Ignore the part 2
They're both the same, just one without Kiara
Though Kiara is what makes the difference in this instance
The original wouldn't have made it
By providing a second perspective
It lends the song to significantly more depth
Than it has any right to have
And gives us this tone about two lovers
Reminiscing about their previous times together
And despite the track intimacy that it provides
You feel that they're not really talking face to face
Juxtaposing the lyrical symmetry
With the contemplation that they may never reunite
And that's a very bittersweet tone
The song's composition, which is this soft synth guitar mix
Really knows how to supplement the mood with that post-chorus drop
Almost being this catharsis of emotion that both these people feel
I don't know if it's what they went for
But it worked
So, props to them
Most of these songs aren't ones that have been released in the last month
Because normally I need some time to let them sink in
At the time of writing, this one was released in the last month
Because as soon as I heard it, I knew it was making my list
One way or another
This song perfectly encapsulates the euphoria in an admittedly slightly unhealthy obsession
But in a way, I think Gardner understands that
As these cascading synths and drums collapse around his quirky vocals
You feel the joy and the turmoil of having feelings for someone
There's that sentiment that the recipient of this love
May never even be aware of themselves
The desperation with lyrics such as
But there's nothing else I can do
And comparing this person to factors such as religion show that he is locked
As the synths fade away for one more percussive pre-chorus
You feel his vocals bare and honest as they come
As he lays everything down one more time
Some may say the overuse of the line
I can't stop thinking about you is annoying
And I understand that
However for me it's quite masterful because it perfectly reflects the tone and the lyrics in a way
Making it catches all hell as well
And pretty damn great
I had a great year with some excellent albums from rappers who I hadn't paid too much of mind in the past
Given the proportion of music that I listened to
You won't find too much rap in these lists
But when you do find it, you know it's good
A lot of people have been putting Temptation on the list
And yes, that's definitely another fantastic song
But I rooted for this one when it came down to The Wire
And there are a few reasons for that
Firstly, the production on this song is simply fabulous
And it's not a style that I've heard too often as well
Then you have the lyrics
And it's not about the content itself, but it's the delivery
Joey has moments towards the end of the second verse
Where you feel like he is wearing his heart on his sleeve
And we don't hear that enough in music
It's all so distant, yet here he's selling his emotions to us
I feel like he is close to crying
And that is powerful in my mind
What finally pushes this song over the top
Is the outro that feels like it was inserted to give the audience that moment for contemplation
And I used every second
It's a song that I fully appreciate
Some songs are just anthems
And we need more anthems
On the first listen, I did not add this song to my favourites
Heaven knows why
But it's a hell of a good thing I came back to it
This is a song that is just required in a year of such depressing mainstream radio
I have a respect for music that can make the normal sound incredible
This song is about doing fuck all with a takeaway
And the one you love
But the lead sells it
Partly thanks to the focus being more on togetherness
But also due to the incredible instrumentation and melodic work
Multiple guitar tones, harmonies
With the sheer pounding elation of a soaring chorus
So desperately yearned for this year
The Amazons did a fantastic job
And this was not their only song that I absolutely loved this year
However this one was the best of the bunch
With its unique topic and sensational delivery
There is simply not much more that can be said
Often there are a few songs that get lost in rotation throughout the year
But upon re-listen, find themselves gradually moved up the list
Until they hit a new high
This is a song that I had written off out of all the songs here
And yet when I came back to it
I realised that it was actually a priceless slice of musical gold
On the air shouting out that you're ready to change
Ready to change
You can say what you want
The song opens with the vocalist cooing with real contempt
As tender but menacing pianos grow into this huge chorus
With propulsive hand claps and building drums
Before throwing itself into this guitar and vocal driven drop
With the piano hanging over the mix
Once again there's a real evolution
Each chorus is unique
Really giving a feeling of progress and building on the emotion
How many songs this year have just fucking died halfway through
Or pulled away from a large chorus
This song pulls no punches
To sum up, this song is about someone who is a bit of a cunt
But fucking hell, Kodaline frame it like they're bloody evil
And I thought Liam Gallagher was brutal
But the lead singer sounds legitimately angry
And to be honest, if this was directed at me, I would not recover
Fantastic track, check it out
Sometimes there is a song that has no right to be as good as it is
That despite its simple and humble beginnings
Everything has just fallen into place
This is one of those
Let me tell you who I am
I'm your biggest fan
Got your picture on my phone
I got tickets to your show
Girl let me tell you
This song is about someone who is using a very unique technique to pick up a girl
To the point of sounding slightly creepy to be honest
It shouldn't work well, but it does
And there is a reason for that
Will Joseph Cook, he sells it
He is such a charismatic vocalist
Effortlessly conveying the sentiment of dizzying infatuation
You feel that it's out of an adorable naivety
Rather than anything sinister thanks to that
This mood is only furthered by the infectious guitarist
That has sprinkled all over the song
Some more acoustic, others more electric
Yet they blend together so fluently
All of this combined makes for a truly joyous song
And one of the best of the year
Great work Will, keep it up
I think out of all the choices on this list
This is the corniest choice
In a year of rap geniuses such as
Joyner Lucas, Kendrick Lamar, and Ty the Creator
Gracing us with their presence
Including this guy and not those
Seems a bit of an insult
But although I accept that they have made
Objectively better songs, this is my list
But still
I just wanna be free
Not a slave to the stereotype
All alone in my room in the middle of the night
I don't have the words but my stereo mic
I don't wanna be black, I don't wanna be white
I just wanna be a man today
I don't wanna be a
Yes, I'm aware that Logic mentions
He's biracial too much
Yes, I'm aware the song has this weird
Slowed down outro
And yes, I'm aware the lyrics are corny as hell
But I just can't help myself
I love this song
From the bright piano keys to
Damien Lamar Hudson's beautiful vocal
Performance over an interlude where he just
Belts his lungs out
It's a song that lifts me up
And as I said, the lyrics are corny
But at least they promote a positive message for once
A message where you can be proud of your achievements
Regardless of the qualities on face value
In a year swamped in negativity
And stereotypes
This was actually kinda necessary and meaningful
To me
And the fact that Logic can take a personal story
And speak to the masses with it
Is quite special in itself
And looking in the comment section of the YouTube video
It clearly reaches a lot of people
I'm gonna defend its choice here
Even though I accept that there may be other better ones
Some songs are on this list because they're evocative
Other songs are just too well made to ignore
However, this is one song that I can't really decide
Which build that fits
Maybe both
I could rain
Come and let me walk away
I won't look back
Geowolf made a masterpiece
This song's sweeping tone
Leaves me in the same
Contemplated mood every time
The soft electric guitars blending effortlessly
With this excellent synth
Which grow into the first verse
As the singer searches for a love among
Before blooming into this beautiful chorus
Where all the previous components come into play
And she confronts her love and his indecision
With these shimmering synths in the second verse
And this monumental bridge
Where she realises that she might have found some closure
The production is undeniable in helping that
And the lead singer could not be better suited to that production
Her airy vocals floating over the mix
Bathing in it without drowning in it
This song really is spotless
Albeit a bit alien to me
Amazing
Keep it up
Every year I'll find out about one or two artists
That I think deserve to be the next big thing
This year there was only one of those
Whose music I really consistently enjoyed
And it was only right that he be included in this list
Because there were plenty more songs of his to choose from
Cause I believe in Karma
And you believe in Karma
You should try a little harder
Oh Karma's gonna fall
As the stiff acoustic guitar line kicks in
Over some very dry drum work
Tom Walker sings aggravatively
About this naughty wench who's fucking around with him
And as the pre-chorus creeps in
This swell of synths around you
And you feel like something is going to happen
At a lot of points this year, nothing happens
It just does this disappointing drop
And you're left feeling like a fucking wet flannel
And yet with Tom Walker, you get that payoff
You get that massive chorus
And it's so refreshing because Tom Walker has managed to understand the art of the climax
With all the instruments synchronizing perfectly behind Walker's voice in this chorus
To give it real gravitas
Too many vocals have backed away from the chorus this year
Walker is no coward
The foreboding premise of Karma itself is pretty ingenious
And definitely aids the very sinister tone
And that final breakdown where Walker just lets loose on this girl
I'd just be as scared as her at that point
You don't really know exactly what Walker's promising you
But that ambiguity plays into the particularly uneasy aura
Menacing and brilliant truly masterful aspect of the song
Truly fucking great, thank you for this
Last year I placed my hood at the top of the year end list
It was a song that spoke from personal perspective
Yet appealed to a general audience
And that sort of juxtaposition of detail and universality always rivets me
Particularly if the message is one that resonates
This year, that artist Ray BLK didn't quite hit those highs
But with the help of upcoming singer Dan Kaplan
She found her way back onto the list
Living by the numbers cause you and me
Go through it like the others
And the highs don't feel the same
And you still get drunk and flushed as rain
As I've said earlier this video
A song about mediocrities of life being made surprisingly pleasurable
Is always appealing to someone like myself
As the hollow synths buzz in the background
Kaplan's frothy baritone reflects on the unhealthy but gratifying lifestyle
That he and Ray BLK lead
As the stiff piano kicks in on the chorus
We hit that sour high that Kaplan is trying to project
The dysfunctional exhilaration
Ray BLK fits perfectly to play that partner in crime
With the tender harmony on the second chorus
But let's face it
The reason that song is here
Is because of the bridge
That fucking bridge
As the synths and piano mesh together
In this apocalyptic, alcoholic, infused chaos
You realise that the protagonist
May never escape that state that they are in
You feel the joy in the euphoria
As it all falls down around them
And as the beat drops out
You feel yourself drowning with them
Before that final chorus
That is just the best culmination of the previous components
It's a great slice of contemporary music
And more than enough reason
That the song finds itself here
Halsey, an artist I never really got into
And I'm not sure I ever truly will
But on our last album
There was one song called Roman Holiday
Which was simply sensational
And it demonstrated a level of introspection
Not shown in a lot of modern pop cuts
I don't know if she'll ever hit that high again
And her latest album left me fairly indifferent
But damn, when she strikes gold
She strikes gold
Said that we're not lovers
We're just strangers
With the same damn hunger
Strangers is a hollow, hollow song
But from the industrial drum to the creeping synths
It really creates a brooding atmosphere of mystique
Which is well suited to this tune, must I add
The chorus itself is like a controlled explosion
It grows so much but stays so tight
With these Roman choir vocals dripping through the back of the mix
It engulfs the listener
Lauren Jauregui does a fantastic guest performance
Adding a very nice tinge of soul to her part
And the harmonisation on the choruses
Create moments to behold
The context about the attempts to move on from a relationship
And the passion that drives it
Dealing with separation from something that's not working out
But still having to live with feelings that linger
It's a simple message but very powerfully done
And the two person perspective definitely aids that
Preventing it from sounding petty or creepy
Fantastic song, check it out
There was a cut off this year
For songs that really emotionally moved me
These top 9 songs enter that new tier
A tier of emotional resonance for me personally
Songs that I could sit down to and emote over
This next song is the only massive hit on the list
And whereas many mainstream songs could wear out their welcome due to overplay
This one never got old
And I miss the way you make me feel
It's real when we watch the sunset
Over the castle only
Castle on the Hill opens with soft guitar tones
As Ed Sheeran's voice reminisces over the energetic but slightly reserved beat
As the drums and haunting vocals kick in on the pre-chorus
You feel the memories slowly returning
And then what makes this song? The chorus
This truly euphoric moment
Suddenly that soft guitar tone becomes the peak of a soaring mix
That captures so much raw emotion
With Ed putting in one of his greatest vocal performances to date
The joy and the pain
And all these powerful emotions that seem to desert some of us into adulthood
There is a uniqueness in being young
And the individual moments that we'll probably never be able to relive
And Ed Sheeran understands that
And then there's the bridge
And the fucking bridge man
Where there is this confrontation with the present
And the moment that not everyone has fully realised what they want to be
That bittersweet moment is a borderline tearjerk for me
The framing is something special
And although Ed Sheeran surprised me by selecting this as a single
It was the best surprise possible
Fantastic
I've never really rated All Time Low too much
They have had some very good songs
But a lot of their music doesn't leave a huge impact on me
Not bad by any means
But I wouldn't expect it to be putting it on my best list
So you know what this means
A contradiction
In many ways it makes sense to have this and cast on the hill back to back
Because they are very similar in this sentiment
The mature singer reflecting on the days when they had that youth
The wish to return to better days
I feel this song goes one step further than the previous
Delving into the emotional psyche of the lead singer
Addressing feelings of losing someone dear to you
Denial a regret that you can't return to that time
And then the resolve to accept that you have to grow up
The memories that you had with that person
Trying to tell yourself it was never going to work out
But still considering the possibilities if it did
The final line of the song alters the auxiliary verb for one final twist
And it's a nice little touch
The production and melody is a real step up
Really building up to this emotional high on the chorus
With this propulsive blend of guitar tones
With these liquid drums really pinning down a mix
That could have been too loose
The melody really lets the vocalist lay bare his feelings
While still retaining a lot of all time lows personality
That made them popular with the fans in the first place
It's a song that finds maturity and age
But still finds themselves in a lot of the roots that they base themselves in
It really disappoints me when I find an artist
Who barely any viewers have heard of
And for me it's so objectively clear how great they are
That I have to share
And so with this next song it is one of those moments
Princess in a castle you're a diva
Everybody said that I should leave you
Mood swing back in
Sony's Princess tells us the simple story
About an entitled female who is draining Sony's mental
And maybe even physical resources
The song opens with these delicate drums
And delicious layered vocals
With guitar work that would make angels cry
Sony's melodic composition is on point
As he delivers intonations and inflections with ease
And then the chorus just slides in
With all these components put together
And there are just these nice little tweaks
That could have been left out
But yet he chooses to insert
And they enhance the mix so much more
The drum dropout at the start of the second verse
The organ line in the second chorus
And the solo guitar that is just laced throughout the whole song
But really the cherry on the cake is Sony himself
Who has an unassailable vocal presence
It's really the performance of the year
There is no questioning that in my opinion
He had a heavy lumbering mix on the song
And yet pulled it off with this beautiful performance
So complete credit to him
This is a great song and he made it happen
When writing up the shortlist for this
I realised that I didn't have any grime songs
It wasn't that there aren't any good ones out there
They just didn't make the cut this year
I like my grime
Last year I had Holy Grime by WALL-E
And This Is England by Kano in my top 20
So in an attempt to see if I had missed any at all
I listened once more to a few grime albums
I didn't quite find a grime song
But I did find something
I don't think I ever considered myself to be including a religious song
Friends know that I'm fairly cynical towards religion
But unlike a lot of tunes this doesn't speak down to the listener
You feel like Stormzy is standing right beside you as he presents this
And it fortunately leans more on the spiritual side without being preachy
He is thanking God but I honestly couldn't care
He just sounds so grateful, so likeable, so genuine
It reaches out to anyone who hopes they can be lifted up with or without celestial means
The organ swell, the touch of the guitar
And Jesus Christ, MNEK's vocalisation and harmonies are unbelievable
He is on a completely different level in this song
And I'll tell you this much, the idea of God may not be one that I have in my heart
But the idea of thankfulness, for the support when all seems lost
Yeah I feel that, so thank you Stormzy for this song
So when Tom Walker released Karma earlier this year
I thought to myself, what a great tune
This is easily his best all year
Tom Walker, not to be outdone, decided to release another song
And fucking hell
I will leave the light on
It's crazy that we have to rely on indie artists for the best drops these days
The chiming synths hit like a ton of bricks
As Tom Walker roars with passion that no man can match
The song itself is essentially an open letter to a friend
Who is going through a hard time and turning to drug abuse
It's a dark topic but like the lighthouse that Tom Walker has set up
There is still a shred of hope
The soft piano building on the chorus is sentimental and potent
And the bridge where you feel that desperation in his voice and lyrics building
That he knows that his friend is in danger but he still refuses to give up
The determination of that is brilliant
The sheer belief and faith in Walker's delivery is truly outstanding
It sounds like he's been there and he sells it like he has
And I would say more but I don't know what to say
You just have to check it out for yourself
It is sensational
I love it when a band can take elements of the old and integrate them with the new
That's what Def Havana did this year
And I give them a lot of credit for it
They really transformed music to me
But to go one step beyond and make a damn masterpiece
They didn't have to but they fucking did
When my lungs collapse and my heart turns black
I'll bring my ashes to the cold
When actually writing this script I was listening to the songs
To make sure that I was getting all the points down
And this is where the emotions really did get the better of me
But I think I can keep it composed without the musical accompaniment here
In this song the lead vocalist deals with issues of isolation, depression, separation
And returning to the places of foregone memories to try and cleanse yourself of those feelings
The lyrics utilise anecdotes and metaphors to tell a story with incredible poetic depth
The singer goes through these issues systematically in the verses
Utilising an acoustic guitar before exploding into a huge chorus with bittersweet emotional highs
It is a moment of real musical transcendence
The piano bridge after the first verse is a great touch as well
And just when I thought I couldn't top all these swelling emotions
The bridge comes in and he confronts what he has lost as he sings
If I could find the legs to stand on or something
Maybe I could take control of my own life
You realise that he may never get that closure that he yearns for
Because he hasn't truly realised a problem
And then it just launches into this huge instrumental break
That just tries me every time
This song is brilliant
There's nothing more to be said
John Mayer
I don't know what the fuck happened
He's here
And what about this feeling
That I'm never good enough
Will it wash out in the water
Or is it always in the blood
Yes, John Mayer is an incredibly talented person
But his music never really had much of an effect on me
That was until mid 2017 when I heard this cut and dam
In this song, Mayer addresses a lot of his insecurities
And poses the ever important question of nature or nurture
The interesting thing is that a lot of his questions don't have clear answers
Are a lot of the feelings we have innate or can we circumvent them for the better of our health
This framing is particularly important
As it's quite rare that we have an artist frame himself with that much equivocation
In a way enacting a double blind because he's not even truly aware of the answer himself
All of this presented over some of the best production work in his career
Originating with the acoustic guitar
The slow introduction of more and more guitars throughout the mix
Is such a fantastic touch
It takes it in new directions every time
And all topped off with an appropriately soft
But an appropriately beautifully breezy guitar solo
Which just elevates the song more and more
It is easy going, it is John Mayer
But it's still emotionally very resonant
Honestly it is a brilliant tune
And I am so happy that it's here
And I'm so happy that John Mayer made it happen
Lorde had a commercially disappointing year
But it didn't prevent her from putting out a pretty damn great album
Now a lot of critics chose to insert Greenlight or Liability
Which are very strong songs as well
But I had to go for something a bit more personal
The song Perfect Places is about emotional catharsis
Through partying, alcohol and dubious substances
As emotional highs are becoming harder to find
She searches more and more desperately
Romantic things like kissing and taking off clothes
Are resigned to be mere functions
As the hollow drums pound in the background
And we reach the final outro with Lorde questioning the existence
Of these Perfect Places over these monumental synthesizer tones
We realise that Lorde has come full circle
And that everywhere she searches for those Perfect Places
All of the new highs lose their novelty
And no longer fulfil what was desired
That is one powerful message
The synth swell and melodic delivery in the chorus
Really highlight the double edged sword of the message
You feel the joy but you also feel a lot of the turmoil
The slight push on Lorde's vocals
As she herself reaches in vain to find the highs
Among an assumedly depressing existence
It is a tragedy, but one of the most poignant of that
Perfect Places is a beautiful cut of Lorde's album
The troublesome messages dealt with and addressed in such a nuanced way
It is really admirable, fantastic
I don't know what to say, check it out
For those who know me well, you'll likely know that my 2017 wasn't the easiest of years
I had a lot of things that just seemed to turn against me when I least needed them
Times have been challenging, but with the faith of many people close to me
I managed to stay afloat
Music is part of that, so these songs reflect me and who I am in many ways
And sometimes you don't need a bohemian rhapsody to speak the world to you
Sometimes the right song can come along and reach out to you
A mix of being personal enough and yet still being masterful about what it aims to achieve
So without further ado, here's your number one
The messages that the song Brother promotes are the sort of messages that keep me going
In the face of adversity, it's a simple message, but it's done so brilliantly
From the steel pan riff that opens up and anchors a lot of the song
To the sensitive vocals that address people going through hard times
To keep your head up over these soft, tropical synths that just envelop you
The washed out guitar fluttering over the back of the mix
Combined with the repetition of the aforementioned phrase
Make it a real compositional masterpiece
It's identifiable, it's unique, but it's still general in its address
There's this acknowledgement that it may not be working out
And it may not all just tie up immediately
But as they plead with the listener to carry on in spite of what's pulling them down
And they try to convey the hope of what they know may not be there
You feel it
I feel it
And that is for sure what really made this one reach out to me like no other song truly did
That's why it is here
Keeping your head up is not just about persevering and not letting yourself drown
It is about pride
It's about dignity
It's about loving yourself in spite of your own doubts
Brother is a lot deeper than it looks
Much like a lot of the water that we often find ourselves thrown into
The most important message from Brother is that it may be shit now
But it can get better
And I want to pass that message on to anyone going through tough times right now
It may be hard currently
You may feel the strain, the burden that life sometimes weighs us down with
But you're never alone
And you don't ever have to think you're alone
And if you ever do feel alone
Drop me a line
I'm always on Twitter
I'm always on Discord
No one's ever that far
2017 could have been better for a lot of us
Let's try and make 2018
A slight improvement
Anyway, I would love to hear your thoughts on what you believed were the best tunes
After all, my opinion is just one of many
I'm The Right Opinion
And I'll see you in the next one