About an hour after I uploaded the thing video YouTube took it down for a supposed TOS violation
They never gave me a specific reason. They just pressed a button and shut it down
While it was up the video was approved for all ads and seemed to be getting pretty heavily recommended
So it didn't appear that any of the metadata in the video was affecting performance
If I had to guess I would assume that the imagery depicted in the film must have tripped off one of YouTube scanners
Regarding graphic content, I guess Rob Bettine's effects were so realistic that they managed to fool YouTube's bots
The day before I actually uploaded a nearly identical version of the video while it was unlisted it too got removed for a TOS violation
I appealed the takedown and it got restored in about half an hour
I still ended up removing this video anyway, because I found a pretty major editing issue
But I figured after successfully appealing the takedown once the system would at least put me on some kind of white list and not
Takedown practically the exact same video just 24 hours later
I am now being held hostage for however long it takes a human being to actually review the content as of the time of recording this
It's been about three hours and they still haven't looked at my appeal
So I'm just gonna have to edit myself in later explaining what ended up happening to the video
So this is M from a few hours later and YouTube has finally responded to my appeal the video has been
Reinstated with an age restriction. So rather than being dead in the water
It's now just barely alive in a vegetative state
Keep in mind when I appealed the original version of this video it got reinstated with no age restriction
So it's just another example of YouTube's inconsistency and BS by the way after all this time
I still don't have an explanation as to what exactly is wrong with the video
I think it's safe to say that this video just might be cursed
I'm just gonna take what I can get at this point. This video has already been taken down twice
So I'm pretty sure re-uploading it will inevitably lead to the same outcome if you're having trouble viewing the age restricted video
I uploaded another version to story fire so you can watch it there
It's funny to me how I can spend a month writing researching and editing a detailed analysis and it's gonna get less views than this
PowerPoint slideshow I made in a day. Maybe this is just YouTube getting revenge on me for tank the rewind
I really don't care at this point
I'm moving on to the next project and hopefully YouTube won't also take that down for no reason
I guess it goes to show that this film analysis truly was too scary for YouTube
Anyway back to amp from three hours ago
The takedown doesn't even make much sense because if you look at YouTube right now
You'll find dozens if not hundreds of other videos reviewing the thing with most of them using the exact same clips
The film itself is also available on YouTube for purchase at the end of the day
There's really nothing I can even do about it
I'm at the complete mercy of YouTube and have no real power over the situation
I can hope that YouTube does the obvious no-brainer move of reinstating the video
But with this site you can never be sure it's honestly just a crapshoot
The big irony in this is that in choosing to make a video about a fictional horror story
YouTube has reminded me of the very real horror of simply uploading videos to this platform
YouTube's automated systems are really no different than the monster from the thing
It's an unfeeling inhuman entity that can just obliterate you without a moment's notice
Every time I go to upload a video on this platform. I live in fear that something like this could happen
It's as if I'm just a hapless victim in a horror movie waiting to get slaughtered over the past few years
I've made a good-faith effort to clean up my act and play by the rules and then something like this just
Blindsides me and I don't even know what I could have done differently
I guess just not talk about a film which dozens of other channels have already discussed on YouTube without any issues
Honestly, I have no idea and with each passing video
I get more and more paranoid about what I can and cannot talk about for fear of having this exact situation happen
The original title of the video was supposed to be terror in isolation and when it got taken down the first time
I thought it had something to do with YouTube's policy on sensitive issues and controversial events
I can't even mention the specific term
I'm referring to because I don't even know if it'll get this video taken down, too
I had to go back and forth over whether or not to include the AIDS epidemic in the video
It's obviously a very important real-life parallel to the film
But testing has shown that mentioning the term can get videos hard demonetized
Of course YouTube never actually gives you a specific reason for any of this
So it's just up to you to guess what one thing in this 20-plus minutes of content caused the system to remove your video
Are we just not supposed to talk about anything with slightly mature themes?
What I'm trying to do here is provide some nuanced discussion about these complex issues and I can't even begin to do that because
Autobot McTakeDown will nuke my video because it detected a word on YouTube's naughty list
There are now major historical events that every kid learns about in school that you cannot mention on YouTube
I find it astounding how YouTube's solution to
Conspiracy theorists denying these events is to make sure that no one on the platform can discuss them at all as if they truly never happened
Needless to say I'm pretty pissed off and disgusted with the state of the site right now
But hey same conversation three years later, I just want to say here that despite the inherent risks involved
I have no plans to dumb down my content into something that's more palatable for YouTube sanitized systems
I will not shy away from talking about mature themes and issues if they're relevant to the overall discussion
If YouTube's internal systems have a problem with that then so be it any human being will understand who's in the right
I may be forced to use code words or euphemisms or what-have-you to make sure the videos are seen
But I will continue to make the videos I want to make
Thankfully, I have the privilege of having consistent sponsorships patreon donations and merchandise sales so that I'm not dependent on YouTube's ad revenue
Alone, if you're interested in supporting the content, you can do so through any of these platforms in the meantime
I hope all of you can have a happy Halloween. It's probably going to be much less terrifying than mine
Oh, by the way, since YouTube killing my last video sort of jeopardized my sponsorship agreement
I'm just gonna do another plug for Manscaped here
Go to manscaped.com and use code mplemon for 20% off your order plus free international shipping and two free gifts
Also, I gotta give another shout out to the Kino Corner
He helped me with the thing video and got his big opportunity ruined
Go check him out if you like film analysis, and I will catch you guys in the next one