In 1943, the deadliest conflict in human history was taking place on the European continent.
Millions of poor souls from all walks of life were subjected to unspeakable horrors and rallied against unimaginable evil.
Many of these unfortunate people tried to forge what little goodwill they could through memes.
When humanity sunk to its lowest point, memes were there to pick us back up.
75 years later, the very descendants of those heroic forefathers who liberated the continent they inhabit are trying to ban memes entirely.
They will tell you the same lie that they have always told you when they take away your freedom.
They'll say that they're protecting people.
They won't tell you that those people are limited to themselves, the very powerful few.
Those who would have never had to go to war.
Those who instigated and orchestrated the conflict that killed 60 million innocent people.
They want to take away your memes not only because they don't understand memes, but also because they fear memes.
Memes are the most fundamental property of the common man.
They are unalienable.
They transcend language, culture, and religion.
They allow us to communicate without saying a single word.
But most importantly, they are the fastest way to put an idea in someone's head.
This includes ideas of unrest, dissidents, and rebellion.
Memes are the fastest way to undermine authority.
And if any corrupt dictatorship wishes to maintain its influence, the first thing it will do is stop the spread of information among the masses.
Because we can't start a revolution if we can't talk to each other.
Banning memes is always the first step.