It's time! Let's reveal the 12,024-human-era calendar with a big bang!
The Kurzgesagt calendar is special because we're adding 10,000 years to include all
of humanity no matter their culture or origin. 12,000 years ago, humans first started working
together on a larger scale, laying the foundation for civilization and the future of us all
– a much better representation of how far our species has come.
This year, we're looking at the cosmos and all the possible life that could be thriving
on myriads of worlds, hosting radically different animals and beings from the ones on Earth.
Where in the universe might life exist? And how would different cosmic environments affect
the basic rules of life? Join us in 12,024 and find out.
Explore strange cosmic habitats and extraterrestrial life forms on 12 awe-inspiring pages.
There's also lots of room for you to keep track of your life here on Earth. Add some
serious space magnificence to your home, but be careful – the extremely radiant cover
may blind you. Get the calendar now before it sells out.
We also have bundles and special calendar deals with some of your favorite products.
Thank you so much to all of the thousands of burbs who get the calendar every year.
With every purchase, you support the Kurzgesagt Division of Sparking Curiosity and inspiring
people all around the world. We wish you an epic year, 12,024.